import{_ as g,o as i,c as o,a as n,m as h,t as l,C as y,M as b,U as c,F as w,p,e as j,f,q as v}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},z={class:"poem-container"},A={class:"review"},N={class:"review-title"},T={class:"review-content"};function M(e,a,s,k,t,u){return i(),o("div",z,[n("div",A,[n("div",N,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),h(l(s.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",T,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),h(l(s.poem.answer),1)])])])}const B=g(q,[["render",M],["__scopeId","data-v-707dae7d"]]),S=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"Responda à pergunta: em que esporte Neil Adams se destacou?","answer":"Neil Adrian Adams (nascido em 27 de setembro de 1958) é um ex-judoca inglês, medalhista de prata nos Jogos Olímpicos de Verão de 1980 e 1984."},{"question":"එක්සත් ජනපදයේ මහාද්වීපිකයේ උසම කන්ද කුමක්ද?","answer":"අඩි 14500 ක් වන විට්නි කන්ද, මහාද්වීපික එක්සත් ජනපදයේ උසම කන්ද වේ. අපි ඇලස්කා ප්‍රාන්තය ඇතුළත් කළත්, ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම උසම කන්ද ඩෙනාලි කන්දයි, එය අඩි 20,320 කි. විට්නි කන්ද ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම එක්සත් ජනපදයේ 17 වැනි උසම කන්ද වන අතර එහි උසම කඳු 1-16 සියල්ලම වේ. ඇලස්කාවේ."},{"question":"Manomeza ohabolana iray fitenin' ny Ray aman-dReny rehefa mananatra ny zanany izy. ","answer":"Ity misy ohabolana iray fitenin'ny Ray aman-dReny rehefa mananatra ny zanany izy: \\"Ny zanaka tiana no anarina.\\""},{"question":"Kireçli toprakta hangi bitkiler yetişir?","answer":"Ayrıca kireçli toprak, su tutma ve işlenebilirlik konusunda da humus eklenerek iyileştirilebilir. Ispanak, lahana, mısır, lahana gibi sebzeleri ekmek için elverişli bir toprak olan kireçli toprakta leylak, weigela, filbahri, zambak gibi bitkiler de yetiştirilebilir."},{"question":"Eeyan kan ku, awọn mẹta fara pa, nibi ija Hausa ati Yoruba niluu Oṣogbo","answer":"Eeyan kan lo ti ku bayii, nigba ti awọn mẹta mi-in fara pa nibi wahala kan to ṣẹlẹ laarin awọn ẹya Hausa ati Yoruba ti wọn n gbe lagbegbe Sabo, niluu Oṣogbo.Titi digba ti a n kọroyin yii, ṣe ni gbogbo ile ati ṣọọbu wa ni titi pa lagbegbe naa, pẹlu ibẹru si lawọn eeyan fi duro ninu ile, bo tilẹ jẹ pe awọn agbofinro ti wa nibẹ.Alẹ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, la gbọ pe wahala naa bẹrẹ. Awọn ọdọ kan ni won kora wọn jọ, wọn ni awọn n ṣe idaro ikẹyin (candle night) fun ọkan lara awọn to jade laye laipẹ yii.Lasiko yii ni itaporogan bẹrẹ laarin wọn pẹlu awọn ti wọn n taja nibẹ, wọn si ṣe ọmọ Hausa kan lese, ti ọpọ si fara pa.Bo tun ṣe di aarọ ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, lawọn ọmọọta tun ya lọ sagbegbe Sabo, Ahmadiyah ati Abaku, ti wọn si n doju ija kọ gbogbo awọn ti wọn ri nibẹ pẹlu ibọn atawọn nnkan ija mi-in.Nibẹ nibọn ti ba Hausa kan, ti gbogbo agbegbe naa si gbona janjan.Alukooro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa l’Ọṣun, SP Yẹmisi Ọpalọla, sọ pe awọn ọlọpaa ti wa nibẹ lati ṣeto aabo, bẹẹ lo ni oun ko ti i le sọ nnkan to fa wahala naa."},{"question":"Qual é a função do sistema imunológico?","answer":"A função do sistema imunológico é proteger o organismo contra invasores, como bactérias, vírus, fungos, parasitas e qualquer outro agente nocivo. O sistema imunológico é programado para distinguir o “não eu” do “eu” — isto é, identificar patógenos invasores e corpos estranhos entre as células nativas saudáveis e, então, matar ou neutralizar esses invasores."},{"question":"Apakah maksud dengan \\"bagai menatang minyak yang penuh\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud memelihara anak dengan penuh kasih sayang."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\"Ny _ dia fitaovana iray izay namboarin'ny olombelona mba hanaovana an'ireo kajy sarotra atao an-tanana.\\"","answer":"Ny solosaina dia fitaovana iray izay namboarin'ny olombelona mba hanaovana an'ireo kajy sarotra atao an-tanana."},{"question":"Nkoyo Toyo","answer":"Nkoyo Esu Toyo (ti a bi ni ọjọ́ Kàrún oṣù kọkànlá ọdún 1958) jé agbejoro, ajafun idagbasoke, ati òtòkùlú oloselu ní orílè-èdè Nàìjirià. A diboyan si ilé igbimo asofin láti se Aṣojú ekùn Calabar-Odukpani ti ìpinlè Cross Rivers, Nàìjíríà ní odun 2011, kó tó dipe o darapo mó ilé igbimo asofin, o jé aṣojú Nàìjirià sí orílè-èdè Ethiopia àti Djibouti titi di 2010. Ṣaaju kí o tó wo oṣelu, o se ajoda Gender and Development Action (GADA) ni 1991, egbé tí a dá kalè láti ran àwon obinrin lówó lati ní ètó sí nkan oselu àti ètò-orò. Nkoyo Toyo jé ọmọ-ẹgbẹ́ oríṣiríṣi ẹgbẹ́ tí óún jà fun ẹ̀tọ́ àwọn obìnrin ní àgbáyé.Nkoyo pari iwe Sekondiri rè ní Union Secondary School ní odun 1974, ó si tesiwaju lati ko nipa ìmò ofin ni Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria Kaduna ni 1975. Ni 1980 Nkoyo Toyo jade ni Nigerian Law School a sì pé sí Nigerian Bar Association. Lẹhinna o gba oye Master of Laws (LLM) lati Yunifásitì ilu Lagos ni ọdun 1994. Nitori itara ati iṣẹ rẹ ni ríran awọn obinrin lówó, a fun ní Sikolashipu Chevening lati kawe ni Institute of Development Studies (IDS), University of Sussex, nibiti o ti gba Masters in Governance ni odun 2001.A yàn Nkoyo láti jé asojú Nàìjirià sí orílè-èdè Ethiopia àti Djibouti ní odun 2008 nitori Ife rè sí oselu. Ni odun 2011, lábé oselu People's Democratic Party (PDP), a yan Nkoyo sí ilé ìgbìmò asojú láti se asojú ekùn Calabar-Odukpani ti ipinle Cross Rivers, o sì sisé takuntakun lórí idagbasoke àwùjo."},{"question":"Iza no olona nandeha voalohany teny amin'ny volana?","answer":"I Niel Armstrong no nandeha voalohany teny amin'ny volana ny taona 1969. "},{"question":"ஒரு தலைமுறை சுமார் எத்தனை ஆண்டுகளை குறிக்கும்?","answer":"விடை: தலைமுறை என்பது உயிரினங்கள் ஒன்றிலிருந்து இன்னொன்று படிப்படியாகத் தோன்றி வளரும் முறையில் ஒவ்வொரு படியையும் குறிக்கும் சொல்லாகும். பெற்றோர் ஒரு தலைமுறையைச் சேர்ந்தவர்களாக இருக்கும்போது அவர்களுக்குப் பிறக்கும் பிள்ளைகள் அடுத்த தலைமுறையைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் ஆகிறார்கள். ஒரு தலைமுறை சரியாக அறுபது வருடங்கள் என்று கணக்கிடுகிறார்கள்."},{"question":"Кыргыз улуттук акчасынын кандай көрүнүштө болушун кимдер чечет?","answer":"Кыргыз акчасынын көрүнүшү кандай болуусу керек экени Улуттук банк, Илимдер академиясы, президент жана премьер-министр тарабынан чечилет."},{"question":"Isi akụkọ: Gọvanọ ọwụwa-anyanwụ gara hụ Onyeisiala BuhariN'inye aha dị n'elu nke akụkọ ifo, chee echiche banyere isiokwu ahụ","answer":"Ndị gọvanọ ọwụwa anyanwụ NaịjirịaNdị gara ya bụ ọgbakọ ime ụlọ gụnyere Gọvanọ Abia, Enugwu nke Ebonyi, nakwa osote onyeisi ụlọomeiwu bụ Ike Ekweremadu. Mgbe ha mechere ya bụ ọgbakọ, onyeisi ndị gọvanọ ọwụwa-anyanwụ bụ Dave Umahi, gwara ndị ntaakụkọ na ha gara ikele Onyeisiala Buhari maka ọrụ ọma ya n'ọwụwa-anyanwụ Naịjirịa.Ọ sịkwa na isi ije ha bụkwa ịrịọ onyeisiala ka o tinyekwuo ego n'ọrụ n'ọwụwa-anyanwụ.N'olu ya, Umahi kwuru, \\"anyị bịara ikele Onyeisiala maka mbọ ya gbarasa akwammiri Naịja nke abụọ (Second Niger Bridge) bụ nke Julius Berger na-arụ n'ọnụ ego dị ijeri narị abụọ na isii (206bn) bụ nke enyegoro ha ijeri asaa (7bn). Anyị bịara ịrịọ Onyeisiala ka o jisiike nyezuo Julius Berger ọkara ya bụ ego ọrụ ka anyị wee mara na gọọmenti akwadola ya bụ mgba n'ezie.\\"Mgbe ajụrụ ya maka ntuliaka 2019, Umahị zara na onweghị ihe ha kpara gbasara nke a.Akụkọ ga-amasị gị"},{"question":"பிரான்ஸ் நாட்டின் உயரிய  விருதான  செவாலியர் லெஜியன் டி ’ஹானர்'  விருதினை வென்ற இஸ்ரோ விஞ்ஞானி1) சோமநாத்2) சிவன்3) லலிதாம்பிகா4) வீரமுத்துவேல்","answer":"லலிதாம்பிகாவி.ஆர்.லலிதாம்பிகா (பிறப்பு 1962) இந்திய விண்வெளி ஆராய்ச்சி நிறுவனத்தில் (இஸ்ரோ) பணிபுரியும் இந்திய பொறியியலாளர் மற்றும் விஞ்ஞானி ஆவார். மேம்பட்ட துவக்கி தொழில்நுட்பங்களில் நிபுணரான இவர், 2022 க்குள் இந்திய விண்வெளி வீரர்களை விண்வெளிக்கு அனுப்புவதற்கான ககன்யான் பணிக்கு தலைமை தாங்குகிறார்புகழ்பெற்ற விஞ்ஞானியும், இந்திய விண்வெளி ஆராய்ச்சி நிறுவனத்தின் (இஸ்ரோ) மனித விண்வெளிப் பயணத் திட்டத்தின் முன்னாள் இயக்குநருமான லலிதாம்பிகா அவர்களுக்கு  பிரான்ஸ் நாட்டின் உயரிய  விருதான  செவாலியர் லெஜியன் டி’ஹானர்  வழங்க பட உள்ளது ஏ.எஸ்.கிரண்குமார் ‘லெஜியன் டி’ஹானர் விருது பெற்ற முதல் இஸ்ரோ விஞ்ஞானி ஆவார். இவருக்கு 2019 ஆம் ஆண்டில் வழங்கப்பட்டது .லலிதாம்பிகா 1962 இல் இந்தியாவின் கேரளாவின் திருவனந்தபுரத்தில் பிறந்தார். தும்பா ராக்கெட் சோதனை மையம் அவரது வீட்டின் அருகாமையில் இருந்ததால், அவரது குழந்தை பருவத்திலிருந்தே, இஸ்ரோவை நோக்கி அவர் ஈர்க்கப்பட்டார். அறிவியலுக்கான அவரது வெளிப்பாடு மிக ஆரம்பத்திலேயே தொடங்கியது, ஏனெனில் அவரது தாத்தா, வில்லைகள், நுண்ணோக்கிகள் போன்ற துணைக்கருவிகளை வீட்டிலேயே தயாரித்து வந்தார், மேலும் இஸ்ரோவின் பணிகள் குறித்து அவ்வப்போதைய தகவல்களைப் பெற்று தனது அறிவைப் புதுப்பித்துக்கொண்டார். அவரது தாத்தா ஒரு கணிதவியலாளரும், வானியலாளரும் மற்றும் கொக்கை தயாரிப்பாளரும் ஆவார். அவரது தந்தையும் ஒரு பொறியியலாளர்."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bawa nyawa\\"? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud lari untuk menyelamatkan diri. Contoh ayat: Masing-masing bawa nyawa dengan lari bertempiaran ketika gempa bumi berlaku."},{"question":"Iberibe ","answer":"Olundi - nzuzu "},{"question":"Mo'Nique","answer":"Monica Imes (ojoibi December 11, 1967), to gbajumo bi Mo'Nique, je àlawada ati óṣere lóbinrin ara Amerika to gba Ebun Akademi bi Obinrin Osere Keji DidarajuloMo'Nique ni a bini Woodlawn, Baltimore County ni Maryland. Óṣere lobinrin naa jẹ ọmọ Alice Imes (Engineer) ati Steven Imes (Ólúbadamọran ti ogun).Ki Mo'Nique to di Óṣère lóbinrin ni ó ṣiṣẹ gẹgẹbi Customer Service Representative ni Ilè iṣẹ ẹrọ imulèwọ MCI ni Hunt Valley, Maryland. Mo'Nique fẹ accountant Kenny Mung fun igbà rànpẹ. Óṣèrè lobinrin naa fẹ Mark Jackson ni ọdun 1991 di 2001 ti wọn si bi ọmọ ọkunrin meji; Mark Eric Jackson Jr. ati Shalon Calvin Jackson. Mo'Nique bi Ibeji ọkunrin meji Jonathan ati David Hicks ni óṣu October ọdun 2005 fun Sidney Hicks ti wọn si fẹ ara wọn ni ọdun 2006Mo'Nique jade ni Milford Mill High School ni ilu Baltimore County ni ọdun 1985 ati Ilè iwè giga ti Morgan. Óṣere lóbinrin naa jẹ ẹni to kawe ja ni ọdun 1987 ni Institute Iróyin ti MarylandMo'Nique gba Àmi ẹyẹ Akademi, Àmi ẹyẹ BAFTA, Àmi ẹyẹ Golden Globe, Àmi ẹyẹ Emmy, Àmi ẹyẹ Óṣere Screen Guild ati Àmi ẹyẹ Oscar"},{"question":"தேசிய கீதம் முதன் முதலாக எப்போது பாடப்பட்டது?","answer":"27 டிசம்பர் 1911ரவீந்திரநாத் தாகூரால் பெங்காலியில் முதலில் இயற்றப்பட்ட ஜன-கன-மன பாடல், அதன் ஹிந்தி பதிப்பில் 24 ஜனவரி 1950 அன்று இந்திய அரசியலமைப்புச் சபையால் இந்தியாவின் தேசிய கீதமாக ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்டது. இது முதன்முதலில் 27 டிசம்பர் 1911 அன்று கல்கத்தா அமர்வில் பாடப்பட்டது. இந்திய தேசிய காங்கிரஸ்."},{"question":"ලිපි ලිවීම සඳහා එම්බ්‍රොයිඩර් මැහුම් වර්ග මොනවාද?","answer":"අකුරු එම්බ්‍රොයිඩර් කිරීමට භාවිතා කළ හැකි සමහර එම්බ්‍රොයිඩරි මැහුම් නම් පිටුපස මැහුම්, බෙදුණු මැහුම්, කඳ මැහුම්, දාම මැහුම්, යහන මැහුම් සහ සැටින් මැහුම් ය."},{"question":"RFK යනු කවුද?","answer":"රොබට් ෆ්‍රැන්සිස් කෙනඩි (නොවැම්බර් 20, 1925 - ජූනි 6, 1968), ඔහුගේ මුලකුරු RFK සහ බොබී යන අන්වර්ථ නාමයෙන් ද හඳුන්වනු ලැබේ, ඔහු ඇමරිකානු දේශපාලනඥයෙක් සහ නීතිඥයෙකි. ඔහු 1961 ජනවාරි සිට 1964 සැප්තැම්බර් දක්වා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ 64 වැනි නීතිපතිවරයා ලෙසත් 1965 ජනවාරි සිට ඔහුගේ ඝාතනය දක්වා නිව්යෝර්ක් සිට එක්සත් ජනපද සෙනෙට් සභිකයෙකු ලෙසත් සේවය කළේය. ඔහුගේ සොහොයුරන් වන ජෝන් එෆ්. කෙනඩි සහ ටෙඩ් කෙනඩි මෙන්ම ඔහු ද ඩිමොක්‍රටික් පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රමුඛ සාමාජිකයෙකු වූ අතර සමහර ඉතිහාසඥයින් විසින් නූතන ඇමරිකානු ලිබරල්වාදයේ සංකේතයක් ලෙස සලකනු ලැබේ. කෙනඩි උපත ලැබුවේ මැසචුසෙට්ස් හි බෘක්ලයින් හි ධනවත්, දේශපාලන පවුලක ය. 1944 සිට 1946 දක්වා එක්සත් ජනපද නාවික සංචිතයේ සේවය කිරීමෙන් පසු, කෙනඩි හාවඩ් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ අධ්‍යාපනයට නැවත පැමිණි අතර පසුව වර්ජිනියා විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයෙන් නීති උපාධිය ලබා ගත්තේය. ඔහු බොස්ටන් පෝස්ට් හි වාර්තාකරුවෙකු ලෙස සහ අධිකරණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නීතීඥයෙකු ලෙස සිය වෘත්තීය ජීවිතය ආරම්භ කළ නමුත් පසුව 1952 දී එක්සත් ජනපද සෙනෙට් සභාව සඳහා ඔහුගේ සහෝදර ජෝන්ගේ සාර්ථක ව්‍යාපාරය කළමනාකරණය කිරීම සඳහා ඉල්ලා අස් විය. ඊළඟ වසරේ ඔහු සෙනෙට් සභාවේ සහකාර උපදේශකයෙකු ලෙස සේවය කළේය. කමිටුවේ සභාපති සෙනෙට් සභික ජෝසප් මැකාති. ඔහු 1957 සිට 1959 දක්වා සෙනෙට් කම්කරු ජාවාරම් කමිටුවේ ප්‍රධාන උපදේශක ලෙස ජාතික අවධානය දිනා ගත්තේය, එහිදී ඔහු සංගමයේ දූෂිත ක්‍රියාවන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් කණ්ඩායම් සභාපති ජිමී හොෆාට ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ අභියෝග කළේය. කෙනඩි 1960 ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී තම සහෝදරයාගේ සාර්ථක ව්‍යාපාරය මෙහෙයවීම සඳහා කමිටුවෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්විය. ඔහු වයස අවුරුදු 35 දී එක්සත් ජනපද නීතිපති ලෙස පත් කරන ලදී, ඇමරිකානු ඉතිහාසයේ ලාබාලතම කැබිනට් සාමාජිකයින්ගෙන් කෙනෙකි. ඔහු 1963 ඝාතනය වන තෙක් ඔහුගේ සහෝදරයාගේ සමීපතම උපදේශකයා ලෙස සේවය කළේය. ඔහුගේ ධුර කාලය සිවිල් අයිතිවාසිකම් ව්‍යාපාරය, සංවිධානාත්මක අපරාධ සහ මාෆියාවට එරෙහි සටන සහ කියුබාව සම්බන්ධ එක්සත් ජනපද විදේශ ප්‍රතිපත්තියට සම්බන්ධ වීම සඳහා ප්‍රසිද්ධය. ඔහු කියුබානු මිසයිල අර්බුදය පිළිබඳ සිය විස්තරය දින දහතුන නමින් පොතක ලියා ඇත. නීතිපතිවරයා ලෙස, ඔහු සීමිත පදනමක් මත මාටින් ලූතර් කිං ජූනියර් සහ දක්ෂිණ ක්‍රිස්තියානි නායකත්ව සමුළුවට සවන් දීමට ෆෙඩරල් විමර්ශන කාර්යාංශයට (FBI) බලය ලබා දුන්නේය. ඔහුගේ සොහොයුරාගේ ඝාතනයෙන් පසුව, ඔහු ලින්ඩන් බී. ජොන්සන්ගේ ජනාධිපති ධුර කාලය තුළ මාස කිහිපයක් තනතුරේ රැඳී සිටියේය. ඔහු 1964 දී නිව් යෝර්ක් සිට එක්සත් ජනපද සෙනෙට් සභාවට තරඟ කිරීමට පිටත්ව ගිය අතර රිපබ්ලිකන් වත්මන් කෙනත් කීටින් පරාජය කළේය. කාර්යාලයේ දී, කෙනඩි වියට්නාම් යුද්ධයට එක්සත් ජනපදය සම්බන්ධ වීමට විරුද්ධ වූ අතර, පුද්ගලික ව්‍යාපාර අනාථ වූ ප්‍රජාවන්ට (එනම්, Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration ව්‍යාපෘතිය) ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති නීතිවලට අනුග්‍රහය දැක්වීමෙන් දරිද්‍රතාවය පිළිබඳ දැනුවත්භාවය ඇති කළේය. ඔහු නැගෙනහිර යුරෝපයට, ලතින් ඇමරිකාවට සහ දකුණු අප්‍රිකාවට විදේශගත වීමෙන් මානව හිමිකම් සහ සමාජ සාධාරණත්වය සම්බන්ධ ගැටළු වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි අතර මාටින් ලූතර් කිං, සීසර් චාවේස් සහ වෝල්ටර් රූතර් සමඟ වැඩ සබඳතා ගොඩනඟා ගත්තේය. 1968 දී, කෙනඩි දුප්පත්, අප්‍රිකානු ඇමරිකානු, හිස්පැනික්, කතෝලික සහ තරුණ ඡන්දදායකයින්ට ආයාචනා කිරීම මගින් ජනාධිපති ධූරය සඳහා ඩිමොක්‍රටික් නාමයෝජනා සඳහා ප්‍රමුඛ අපේක්ෂකයෙකු බවට පත්විය. තරඟයේ ඔහුගේ ප්‍රධාන අභියෝගකරුවා වූයේ සෙනෙට් සභික ඉයුජින් මැකාති ය. 1968 ජූනි 5 වැනිදා මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියට පමණ කැලිෆෝනියා ප්‍රාථමිකය ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමෙන් ටික කලකට පසු, 1967 සය දින යුද්ධයෙන් පසුව ඊශ්‍රායලයට දුන් සහයෝගයට පළිගැනීමක් ලෙස 24 හැවිරිදි පලස්තීන ජාතික සර්හාන් සිරාන් විසින් කෙනඩිට වෙඩි තබන ලදී. පැය 25 කට පසු කෙනඩි මිය ගියේය. සිරාන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන, නඩු විභාග කර, වරදකරු කරනු ලැබුවද, ඔහුගේ සොහොයුරාගේ ඝාතනය මෙන්ම කෙනඩිගේ ඝාතනයද, පුළුල් විශ්ලේෂණ සහ නොයෙකුත් කුමන්ත්‍රණ න්‍යායන්ට විෂය වී ඇත."},{"question":"Maxaa ka mid ah noocyada cibaadada?","answer":"Cibaadada waxaa ka mid ah waxyaalo fara badan sida; Shahaada-teynka, Salaadda, Sekeda, Soonka Xajka, ducada, Nederka, Dhaarta, Saddaqada, Sujuudda, Gawraca iwm."},{"question":"ਜੰਮੂ: ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹਾ ਰਾਮਬਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਪੈ ਰਹੇ ਮੀਂਹ ਕਾਰਨ ਢਿਗਾਂ ਡਿੱਗਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਅੱਜ ਦੂਜੇ ਦਿਨ ਵੀ ਜੰਮੂ-ਸ੍ਰੀਨਗਰ ਕੌਮੀ ਮੁੱਖ ਮਾਰਗ ਬੰਦ ਰਿਹਾ। ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਇਸ 270 ਕਿਲੋਮੀਟਰ ਲੰਬੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਮਾਰਗ ’ਤੇ ਆਵਾਜਾਈ ਬਹਾਲ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ਾਂ ਜਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਕਿਹੜਾ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਰਾਜਮਾਰਗ ਬੰਦ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਜੰਮੂ-ਸ਼੍ਰੀਨਗਰ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਰਾਜਮਾਰਗ ਬੰਦ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Sự kiện nào được nói tới trong văn bản sau?Chính phủ Anh sẽ rà soát việc cấp visa làm việc nhằm kiểm soát số lượng người nhập cư, bao gồm cả du học sinh. Kế hoạch gồm 5 thay đổi, được ông James Cleverly, Bộ trưởng Nội vụ Anh, công bố hôm 4/12. Trong đó, chính phủ sẽ rà soát các chương trình visa làm việc sau tốt nghiệp của du học sinh (còn gọi là Graduate Route), nhằm ngăn chặn việc lạm dụng visa và bảo đảm tính trung thực của hệ thống đào tạo đại học. Hiện, visa Graduate Route cho phép sinh viên quốc tế tốt nghiệp ở Anh ở lại làm việc trong hai năm. Với nghiên cứu sinh tiến sĩ, thời hạn là 3 năm. Chính sách này được Anh áp dụng trở lại vào năm 2021 sau 9 năm gián đoạn. Hồi tháng 5, nước này đã ban hành chính sách hạn chế du học sinh đưa người thân nhập cảnh vào Anh, không cho phép họ chuyển từ visa sinh viên sang visa làm việc trước khi tốt nghiệp.Các thay đổi trên trong bối cảnh giới chức Anh cho rằng sinh viên quốc tế là một lý do dẫn tới con số kỷ lục 745.000 người nhập cư vào năm ngoái. Trong số này, gần 136.000 visa được cấp là người nhà của du học sinh, cao gấp 8,5 lần so với 16.000 visa vào năm 2019. Khoảng 680.000 sinh viên quốc tế theo học tại Anh trong năm học 2021-2022, tăng 12,3% so với năm trước, theo Cơ quan Thống kê giáo dục đại học Anh (HESA). Cùng năm này, giáo dục quốc tế mang lại 42 tỷ bảng (53 tỷ USD) cho nền kinh tế Anh, tăng từ 31,3 tỷ của 4 năm trước đó. Nhiều giảng viên nhìn nhận việc thắt chặt quy định cấp visa làm việc sau tốt nghiệp cho du học sinh sẽ ảnh hưởng tiêu cực tới tăng trưởng giáo dục đại học.","answer":"Văn bản đề cập đến việc chính phủ Anh đang thực hiện một loạt các thay đổi trong việc cấp visa làm việc, bao gồm cả du học sinh, nhằm kiểm soát số lượng người nhập cư và đảm bảo tính trung thực của hệ thống đào tạo đại học."},{"question":"Give an easy recipe for fried cheese bites.","answer":"An easy recipe for fried cheese bites is as follows : Ingredients:10 oz. mozzarella string cheese (or 10 sticks)1 cup Italian bread crumbs1 cup flour2 eggs1/4 cup milkCayenne pepper (optional)Instructions:Take out a cutting board and cut your string cheese sticks into bite-sized pieces.In a medium-sized bowl, add your eggs and whisk to break them up.Add the milk and whisk again to incorporate the two ingredients.Set aside two additional bowls. Fill one with your flour and the next with your bread crumbs. Place the bowl with your eggs and milk mixture in the middle of that line, so that you now have three bowls in a row (flour, eggs, and bread crumbs).Take one piece of mozzarella. Dip it in the flour, then immediately in the egg mixture. Now, roll your cheese bite around in the bread crumbs. Continue to do this until you have all the pieces of cheese coated.You can place each finished piece on a plate once it is completed.In a medium-sized skillet, heat your vegetable oil (about 2 inches high) to 350 degrees. To test this, place a wooden spoon handle in the oil. (If the bubbles are rolling on the handle, you're ready.)Pull out a plate and line it with a paper towel.Add 5-7 pieces to the oil for about 30 seconds. Make sure that you keep them separated so that they don't bond together!Fry your mozzarella bites until they are golden brown (which should be at that 30-second mark). Using a slotted spoon, remove your pieces from the oil and place them on the paper towels.Repeat this process with different batches until all of your bites are fried.Serve immediately with pasta sauce, or just eat them by themselves!"},{"question":"Question: Flying birds havea. only kinetic energyb. only potential energyc. both kinetic energy and potential energyd. only pressure energyAnswer: ","answer":"Answer: (c)The flying bird has kinetic energy because it is moving. It also has potential energy at any point of the time during the flying due to height above the ground at that particular point of time."},{"question":"O jakim wydarzeniu mówi ten tekst? Pomnik oficerów-lojalistów poległych w Noc Listopadową lub pomnik Polaków poległych za wierność swojemu monarsze – nieistniejący monument znajdujący się na placu Saskim, a następnie na placu Zielonym w Warszawie, upamiętniający siedmiu polskich oficerów, którzy ponieśli śmierć z rąk powstańców w Noc Listopadową.","answer":"Tekst mówi o Nocy Listopadowej."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو ترتيب مناسك العمرة؟","answer":"الجواب: الإحرام ثمّ الطواف ومن بعدها السعي وتختم بالحلق أو التقصير."},{"question":"2023లో 13,000 ఓడిఐ పరుగులతో ప్రపంచంలోనే అతిపెద్ద క్రికెట్ ఆటగాడు ఎవరు?","answer":"2023లో 13,000 ఓడిఐ పరుగులతో ప్రపంచంలోనే అతిపెద్ద క్రికెట్ ఆటగాడు విరాట్ కోహ్లి."},{"question":"Подай антонім до виразу \\"стріляний горобець\\"","answer":"\\"Стріляний горобець\\" означає когось із великим досвідом, хто пройшов через численні випробування. Одним із можливих антонімів є фразеологізм \\"жовтороте пташеня\\", який описує когось наївного і недосвідченого."},{"question":"ni nini kinachomsukuma mtu kusafiri sehemu mbali mbalii?","answer":"Usafiri na uvumbuzi mara nyingi huchochewa na udadisi wa asili na hamu ya kina ya kupanua upeo wa mtu. Ulimwengu ni msururu mkubwa wa tamaduni, mandhari, na uzoefu, na matarajio ya kufichua mafumbo yake na kukumbatia utofauti wake ni nguvu kubwa ya kuendesha. Watu huvutwa kusafiri ili kuepuka maeneo yao ya starehe, kujipa changamoto, na kuunda kumbukumbu za kudumu. Ni mvuto wa kusimama mbele ya maajabu ya kale, kujitumbukiza katika vyakula usivyovijua, kuanzisha uhusiano na watu wa tabaka mbalimbali za maisha, na kushuhudia uzuri wa sayari yetu ambao huchochea kiu hii isiyoweza kuisha ya kuchunguza. Hatimaye, ni imani kwamba kila safari ina uwezo wa ukuaji wa kibinafsi, mwangaza, na ugunduzi wa kitu cha ajabu sana ambacho huhamasisha watu binafsi kujitosa kwenye haijulikani."},{"question":"I wonder ఫిడెల్ కాస్ట్రో ఎప్పుడు జన్మించాడు?.Help me answer this question with \\"Yes\\" or \\"No\\" or \\"None\\" if none of the first two answers apply.Here's what I found on the internet:Topic: ఫిడెల్ కాస్ట్రోArticle: ఫిడెల్ కాస్ట్రో (Fidel Castro  ( audio) ) (జననం:ఆగస్టు 13, 1926 - మరణం:నవంబరు 25, 2016) పూర్తి పేరు ఫిడెల్ అలెహంద్రో కాస్ట్రో రుజ్, క్యూబా రాజకీయ నాయకుడు మరియు విప్లవకారుడు. కాస్ట్రో క్యూబాను 1959 జనవరి నుండి 2008 ఫిబ్రవరి వరకు పరిపాలించాడు. ఇతను క్యూబా నియంత బాటిస్టాను సాయుధ పోరాటం ద్వారా తొలగించి అధికారం చేపట్టాడు. క్యూబాను పశ్చిమార్థ భూగోళంలో మొట్ట మొదటి సామ్యవాద దేశంగా మార్చాడు. ఇతడు అమెరికాకు బద్ధ వ్యతిరేకి. అమెరికా గూఢాచార సంస్థ సి.ఐ.ఏ (సెంట్రల్ ఇంటెలిజెన్స్ ఏజెన్సీ) కాస్ట్రోను హత్య చేయటానికి మొత్తం 638 సార్లు విఫలయత్నం చేసింది. ఇతడు కాల్చే చుట్టలో బాంబు పెట్టి, అతని స్కూబా-డైవింగ్ సూట్‌లో ప్రాణాంతకమైన ఫంగస్‌ను ఉంచటం వంటి పలు విన్నూత విధానాలతో హత్యాప్రయత్నం చేసింది. మాఫియా తరహాలో కాస్ట్రోను కాల్చివేయటానికి కూడా ప్రయత్నించింది. ఆఖరికి అతని మాజీ ప్రియురాలు మారిటా లోరెంజ్ ద్వారా కూడా ఇతనిని హత్యచేయుటకు సి.ఐ.ఏ ప్రయత్నించింది. కానీ ప్రతీ సారీ కాస్ట్రో మృత్యుంజయుడై బయటపడి అమెరికాకు పక్కలో బల్లెమై ఎదురు నిలిచాడు.బాల్యం మరియు విధ్యాబ్యాసంకాస్ట్రో క్యూబాలోని మయారి పట్టణానికి సమీపంలో ఉన్న బిరాన్ అనే గ్రామంలో ఆగస్టు 13, 1926 (కొందరు 1927 అని కూడా పేర్కొంటారు) న జన్మించాడు. ఇతని తండ్రి స్పెయిన్ దేశం నుండి వలస వచ్చిన చెరకు తోటల పెంపకందారుడు. కాస్ట్రో తల్లి లీనా రుజ్ గొంజాలెజ్ ఇంటి పనిమనిషి, కాస్ట్రోకు 15 ఏళ్ల వయసు వచ్చేదాకా తండ్రి ఏంజెల్ కాస్ట్రో, మరియా లూయిసా అర్గోటా అనే మరో మహిళతో వివాహమైనది. బాల్యంలో కాస్ట్రో అనేక పరాయి ఇళ్లలో పెరగటమే కాకుండా, వివాహేతర సంతానంగా ఇబ్బందులను ఎదుర్కోవలసి వచ్చింది. కాస్ట్రో 1947లో క్యూబన్ పీపుల్స్ పార్టీలో చేరాడు. 1950లో హవానా విశ్వవిద్యాలయం నుండి న్యాయశాస్త్రంలో పట్టా పొందాడు. తరువాత కాస్ట్రో హవానాలోనే న్యాయవాదిగా ప్రాక్టీసు ప్రారంభించాడు. 1952లో క్యూబా ప్రతినిథుల సభ కొరకు జరగబోయే ఎన్నికలలో పోటీచేశాడు. కానీ అదే సమయంలో బాటిస్టా మిలిటరీ కుట్ర ద్వారా అధికారాన్ని చేజిక్కించుకుని రాజ్యాంగాన్ని బహిష్కరించి క్యూబాలో నియంతృత్వాన్ని నెలకొల్పాడు.== క్యూబా తిరుగుబాటు ==uకాస్ట్రో బాటిస్టా నిరంకుశ ప్రభుత్వానికి వ్యతిరేకంగా ఒక రహస్య విప్లవ వర్గానికి నాయకత్వం వహించాడు. జూలై 26, 1953 న కాస్ట్రో దళాలు శాంటియాగో దె క్యూబా నగరం లోని మోన్‌కాడా సైనిక స్థావరాన్ని ముట్టడించాయి.","answer":"జననము   1926 August 13"},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\" Lomanom-boka _\\"","answer":"\\" ka tafita vao rendrika\\""},{"question":"Wọn ti dajọ iku fun Ibrahim to ge ori ọmọ ọdun meji l’Owode-Ẹgba","answer":"Ile-ẹjọ giga ipinlẹ Ogun ti dajọ iku fun Ibrahim Muhammed, ẹni ọdun mọkandinlogoji, ti wọn fẹsun kan pe o ge ori ọmọ ọdun meji kan lagbegbe Ọfada, Owode-Ẹgba, lọjọ kejila, oṣu kẹrin, ọdun 2014.Yatọ si ẹsun ipaniyan yii, wọn tun fi ẹsun igbiyanju lati paayan kan Ibrahim. Agbẹnusọ ijọba, Oluwabunmi Akinọla, ṣalaye idi to fi ri bẹẹ. Lọjọ Iṣẹgun to kọja yii lo ṣalaye ni kootu giga to n jokoo l’Abẹokuta pe obinrin kan, Rabi Yakubu, fẹẹ ṣe igbọnsẹ ninu igbo lọjọ naa ni, o si pọn ọmọ rẹ ọkunrin ti ko ju ọmọ ọdun meji lọ sẹyin.Agbefọba sọ pe nigba ti Rabi ri ibi to ti le ṣegbọnsẹ naa, o sọ ọmọ ẹyin rẹ kalẹ ko le raaye tura daadaa. Nibi to ti n dawọ tẹlẹ ni Ibrahim to ti n tẹle e bọ lai jẹ pe obinrin naa mọ ti yọ si i lojiji pẹlu ọbẹ lọwọ. Niṣe lo si yọ ọbẹ naa si i to fẹẹ fi ge obinrin naa lọrun.O ni Rabi ja raburabu, ko jẹ ki Ibrahim ge oun lọrun, nibi to si ti n wa ọna lati gba ara ẹ silẹ lo ti bọ sita ninu igbo naa lai le gbe ọmọ rẹ to sọkalẹ mọ, n lo ba kuku kegbajare lọ saarin aba naa pe kawọn eeyan gba oun.Ko too de pada, Ibrahim ti ge ori ọmọ ti obinrin naa gbe kalẹ, o si sa lọ lẹyin to ṣiṣẹ ibi naa tan. Iya ọmọ fẹjọ sun ni teṣan, wọn si bẹrẹ si i wa Ibrahim.Nigba tọwọ ba a, Agbefọba sọ pe o jẹwọ pe obinrin kan lo ni koun ba oun wa ori eeyan wa n’Ibadan lati fi ṣetutu ọrọ, ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgọfa naira(120,000) lo ni obinrin naa loun yoo foun gẹgẹ bii adehun.Ṣugbọn nigba ti ko ri ori iya ge, to si ti ge ti ọmọ, o gbe e lọ fun onibaara rẹ naa, afi bo ṣe gbe e debẹ tiyẹn ni oun ko fẹ ori ọmọde, ori agbalagba ni adehun awọn.Eyi lo mu Ibrahim gbe ori naa pada lati lọọ sin in gẹgẹ bi agbẹnuṣọ ṣe wi. Ṣugbọn o pada bọ sọwọ ọlọpaa ni.Adajọ Ayọkunle Rotimi-Balogun to gbọ ẹjọ naa sọ pe Agbefọba fidi ootọ mulẹ ninu iṣẹlẹ yii kọja ohun teeyan tun le maa ṣiyemeji si, nitori naa lo ṣe paṣẹ pe ki wọn lọọ yẹgi fun Ibrahim Muhammed titi ti ẹmi yoo fi bọ lara rẹ.Fun ti Rabi to gbiyanju lati pa, ẹwọn gbere lo ni ki wọn kọ silẹ fun olujẹjọ yii, nitori ẹṣẹ mejeeji ni ijiya ọtọọtọ wa fun labẹ ofin."},{"question":"O tan! Ọba Sokoto binu si Buhari","answer":"Ẹgbe kan, Jama’atu Nasril Islam, ti Ọba  ilu Sokoto, Alhaji Sa’ad Abubakar, n dari ẹ ti sọ pe bi awọn janduku ajinigbe ṣe n kolu awon ileewe nilẹ Hausa ti wọn si n ji awọn ọmọ ko lọ yii ko ni oriire kan bayii to fẹẹ ko ba ilẹ Hausa bi ko ṣe idaamu ọjọ iwaju.Ana ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ni akọwe agba, Dr. Khalid Abubakar Aliyu, fi atẹjade ọhun sita lorukọ Ọba ilẹ Sokoto, Alhaji Sa’ad Abubakar, nibi ti Olori awọn Hausa yii ti sọrọ naa.Ninu ọrọ ẹ lo ti sọ pe idaamu ti awọn janduku ajinigbe yii n da silẹ bayii nilẹ Hausa ko ni i ṣalai ṣakoba fawọn eeyan ibẹ, ati pe ojuna lati mu eto ẹkọ jo ajorẹyin ni yoo jẹ lọjọ iwaju.Sultan ni ọpọ awọn obi ni ọkan wọn ko balẹ mọ lati fi ọmọ wọn sileewe, niwọn igba to jẹ pe niṣe lawọn ajinigbe yoo kan ya wọ ibẹ, ti wọn yoo si ko wọn lọmọ lọ, tijọba paapaa ko ni i rohun kan bayii ṣe si i.Ọba ilẹ Sokoto tẹ siwaju pe, ohun ikaya lo jẹ bi awọn janduku ti ṣe kọlu ileewe Government Science Secondary School, ni Kankara, nipinlẹ Katsina lọwọ aṣalẹ ọjọ, Ẹti, Furaidee to kọja yii lasiko ti Aarẹ Miuhammad Buhari gan-an wa nipinlẹ ọhun.O ni, ohun itiju lo yẹ ki eleyii jẹ fun Buhari, ki oun naa fi le mọpe eto aabo ijoba oun koo dara, abi nigba ti awọn ajinigbe tun waa n kogun ja a mọle lasiko to wa ninu ilu ẹ gan-an.Bakan naa lo sọ pe asiko niyi fun un lati gbọ ohun ti awọn araalu n sọ kijọba ẹ si tete gbe igbesẹ lori bi yoo ti ṣe mu atunto gidi ba eto aabo orilẹ-ede yii, paapaa lori awọn alakooso to fi ṣe ọga ologun.Siwaju si i, Sultan ni o to gẹẹ lori bi Aarẹ Buhari ṣe maa n tẹnumọ ọrọ kan naa ni gbogbo igba ti wahala ba ti ṣẹlẹ wi pe o ba oun ninu jẹ. O ki Buhari yee daro mọ, ohun tawọn eeyan n fẹ bayii ni ko wa bi wahala ikọlu oriṣiiriṣi ṣe n waye ni ilẹ Hausa yii yoo ṣe dopin, ki awọn ẹṣọ agbofinro ati alaabo si wa awọn ọmọ ti wọn ji ko yii ri."},{"question":"ආවර්තිතා  වගුවේ මූලද්‍රව්‍යයන් කීයක් තිබේද?","answer":"ආවර්තිතා  වගුවේ මූලද්‍රව්‍යයන් 118ක් ඇත. මෙම මූලද්‍රව්‍ය පරමාණුක ක්‍රමාංකය 1 සහිත හයිඩ්‍රජන් සිට පරමාණුක ක්‍රමාංකය 118 ඇති ඔගනෙසන්(Oganesson) දක්වා  විහිදේ."},{"question":"Sử dụng tiêu đề và tóm tắt sau để viết một bài báo tối đa 500 chữ.Tiêu đề: Nguy cơ mất mạng do nổ bóng bay chứa khí hydroTóm tắt: Bóng bay chứa khí hydro chỉ cần tiếp xúc với nhiệt độ cao có thể phát nổ gây bỏng mặt, mù mắt, bỏng, thậm chí nguy cơ tử vong.","answer":"Sáng 5/9, một vụ nổ bóng bay xảy ra tại lễ khai giảng trường Tiểu học Yên Phú, huyện Yên Định, Thanh Hóa khiến 10 trẻ bị bỏng. Một học sinh đã về nhà, 9 em tiếp tục ở lại viện theo dõi, điều trị. Nguyên nhân là một thầy giáo hút thuốc lá, lửa từ điếu thuốc châm vào bóng bay có bơm khí hydro, phát nổ.Bác sĩ Nguyễn Thái Ngọc Minh, Khoa Hồi sức Cấp cứu, Bệnh viện Bỏng Quốc gia Lê Hữu Trác, cho biết hydro là chất khí rất dễ bắt cháy, là nguyên nhân gây nhiều vụ nổ công nghiệp hoặc cháy nổ trong sinh hoạt. Mỗi năm, bệnh viện tiếp nhận hàng chục nạn nhân bị bỏng nặng do nổ bóng bay sử dụng khí này.Khí hydro có cấu trúc phân tử rất bé, dễ dàng thẩm thấu cực nhanh qua màng bóng bay, chỉ cần tiếp xúc với bóng đèn, gặp không khí nóng hoặc ra ngoài trời nắng là có thể nổ tung. Khí hydro bị nén trong bóng bay sẽ phát nổ rất mạnh, nguy cơ gây bỏng mặt, mù mắt, bỏng tay cho người cầm.\\"Nếu tiếp xúc nhiều, nạn nhân nguy cơ bỏng sâu, bỏng hô hấp, nguy hiểm tính mạng\\", ông Minh nói, thêm rằng, bỏng còn gây tác động rất mạnh về tâm thần đối với bệnh nhân. Bệnh nhân nguy cơ bị stress cấp, trầm cảm, lo âu. Do đó, ngoài điều trị thể xác, người bệnh phải điều trị tâm lý để tái hòa nhập cộng đồng, nhất là trẻ nhỏ.Tương tự, bác sĩ Trần Văn Phúc, Bệnh viện đa khoa Xanh Pôn, nói khí hydro hoặc khí heli đều giúp bóng bay được lên. Trong đó, heli không màu, không múi, không cháy ở nhiệt độ và áp suất bình thường. Còn hydro cũng không màu, không mùi, trong suốt nhưng dễ cháy và nổ ngay cả ở điều kiện nhiệt độ và áp suất bình thường, được sử dụng làm bom. Do đó, nhiều nước phát triển đã cấm dùng hydro mà chỉ cho phép bơm heli.Hiện, Việt Nam chưa ban hành lệnh cấm hydro. Ngoài ra, giá hydro chỉ bằng 1/4 so với heli, nên một số người bán bóng bay vẫn bơm hydro vào quả bóng để tiết kiệm kinh phí.\\"Khi phát nổ, quả bóng bay chứa hydro có thể biến thành quả cầu lửa gây bỏng, chưa kể áp lực tạo ra từ tiếng nổ có sức công phá rất lớn\\", bác sĩ cho biết. Nạn nhân có nguy cơ bị bỏng và tổn thương đụng dập mô mềm, mảnh bóng bay có thể xuyên qua cổ họng, làm mù mắt.Bác sĩ khuyến cáo khi bị gặp trường hợp nổ bóng bay cần bình tĩnh, tránh hoảng hốt gây thêm cháy nổ. Khi bị bỏng, mọi người nên hạ nhiệt vết thương cho nạn nhân bằng nước sạch, mát (16-20 độ c), sau đó che phủ tạm thời và vận chuyển nạn nhân đến cơ sở y tế. Tại cơ sở y tế, bệnh nhân có thể khám các triệu chứng bỏng đường hô hấp và bỏng kết giác mạc để được điều trị kịp thời, tránh để lại biến chứng. Trẻ em bị bỏng có nguy cơ sang chấn tâm lý, cần được gia đình và bác sĩ hỗ trợ điều trị thêm.Bên cạnh đó, người lớn cần lưu ý khi cho trẻ chơi bóng. Trường hợp mua bóng bay để trang trí, bắt buộc phải hỏi người bán, đảm bảo bóng bay được bơm khí heli, \\"do không thể phân biệt được bằng mắt thường\\". Không cho trẻ chơi bóng bay bơm khí hydro ở trong nhà, nơi dễ tiếp xúc với các nguồn lửa để tránh cháy nổ, có thể nguy hiểm tính mạng."},{"question":"இயல்பாக உரியச் சொற்களின் மூலம் கூறுவது……………….அணி ஆகும்.அ) தற்குறிப்பேற்றணிஆ) நிரல்நிறை அணிஇ) உயர்வு நவிற்சி அணிஈ) தன்மையணி","answer":"இயல்பாக உரியச் சொற்களின் மூலம் கூறுவது….  ஈ) தன்மையணி…ஆகும்."},{"question":"Waa maxay macnaha Laa Ilaahailla Laahu?","answer":"Laa ilaaha illa Laahu, macneheeduwaa \\"ma jiro mid xaq lagu caabudaa Allemooyane\\""},{"question":"در این متن به چه رویداد مهمی اشاره شده است؟ ترانه‌های سوقومون یک فیلم زندگی‌نامه‌ای ارمنستانی محصول سال ۲۰۱۹ میلادی است به کارگردانی آرمان نشانیان که نماینده سینمای ارمنستان در نود و سومین دوره جایزه اسکار بهترین فیلم بین‌المللی بود. ترانه‌های سوقومون زندگانی و فعالیت‌های موسیقایی، کومیتاس وارداپت، آهنگساز، موسیقی‌شناس قومی و کشیش ارمنی را که در طی سال‌های نسل‌کشی ارمنی‌ها می‌زیسته، را به تصویر کشیده است.","answer":"در این متن به نود و سومین دوره جایزه اسکار اشاره شده است که در آن فیلم ترانه‌های سوقومون جایزه اسکار بهترین فیلم بین‌المللی را برنده شد."},{"question":"Ibi tawọn eleyii ti n jale loju titi lọjọ ọdun tuntun lọlọpaa ti ko wọn l’Ekoo","answer":"Ohun meremere to daa lọpọ eeyan n gbero ẹ lọdun tuntun, ṣugbọn ni ti awọn mẹsan-an tẹ ẹ n wo yii, bi wọn ṣe maa rowo na lọnakọna lo gba ọkan wọn, ole ni wọn n ja lọwọ loju titi, nibi ti wọn ti n da awọn onimọto lọna lọjọ ọdun tuntun lawọn agbofinro ti mu wọn.Orukọ awọn afurasi ọdaran naa ni Oluṣeyi Afọlabi, ẹni ọdun mọkandinlogun, Adeyẹmọ Ayọmide, ọmọ ọdun mejidinlogun, Lati Francis, ẹni ọdun mọkandilogun, Rilwan Raji, ẹni ọdun mẹtalelogun ati Ayọmide Oyediran, toun jẹ ẹni ogun ọdun pere.Awọn mẹrin to ku ni Rasheed Ibrahim, eni ọdun mejilelogun, Hamzat Abdullahi, ẹni ọdun mọkandinlogun, Musa Gbadamọsi, ẹni ogun ọdun ati Ṣeun Lasisi, toun jẹ ẹni ọdun mejilelọgbọn.Olumuyiwa Adejọbi, Alukoro ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko, fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ f’ALAROYE pe ni nnkan bii aago mẹjọ alẹ lawọn ka awọn afurasi naa mọ ikorita Y-Junction, nitosi Too-geeti atijọ, ni Ketu, nipinlẹ Eko.O lawọn kọlọransi ẹda yii ṣẹṣẹ kọ lu Ọgbẹni Adejare Adetayọ toun atiyawo n kọja lọ lagbegbe ọhun lalẹ ọjọ naa tan ni, wọn gba owo wọn ati foonu, iṣẹlẹ yii lo si fu awọn ọlọpaa ọtẹlẹmuyẹ kan to wa nitosi lara, ni wọn ba lepa awọn oniṣẹẹbi naa, Ọlọrun si jẹ ki wọn ri awọn mẹsan-an yii mu, bo tilẹ jẹ pe awọn to ku sa lọ.Lara nnkan ija ti wọn fi n ṣe ṣuta ti wọn ka mọ wọn lọwọ ni ada meji, ọbẹ aṣooro gigun meji, bileedi atawọn nnkan ija mi-in.Adejọbi ni awọn ti fi iṣẹlẹ naa to kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko leti, o si ti paṣẹ ki wọn taari awọn tọwọ ba yii si ẹka ileeṣẹ ọtẹlẹmuyẹ Eko, to wa ni Panti, ni Yaba, lati tubọ ṣe iwadii nipa wọn.O lawọn ọlọpaa ṣi n wa awọn to sa lọ, ati pe gbara tiṣẹ iwadii ba ti pari ni wọn yoo foju awọn eleyii ba ile-ẹjọ, ki wọn le gba sẹria to tọ si wọn labẹ ofin."},{"question":"Sheeg magaca wakiilkii ugu dambeeyey ee xukuumaddii kacaanka u fadhiyey Qaramada Midoobay?","answer":" Waxaa u fadhiyey Cabdullaahi Siciid Cismaan"},{"question":"मानवी मज्जासंस्थेचा अभ्यास कोणत्या शास्त्रात करतात ?A. न्यूरोलॉजी / neurologyB. मानवशास्त्र / PhlebologyC. नेफ्रोलॉजी / Nephrology D. यांपैकी काहीही नाही","answer":"C. नेफ्रोलॉजी / Nephrology मानवी मज्जासंस्थेचा अभ्यास नेफ्रोलॉजी / Nephrology  शास्त्रात करतात ."},{"question":"Quem inventou a lâmpada?a) Graham Bellb) Steve Jobsc) Thomas Edisond) Henry Forde) Santos Dumont","answer":"c) Thomas Edison"},{"question":"Uzee Usman","answer":"Uzee Usman Adéyẹmí tí wọ́n bí ní ọjó Kọkànlá oṣù Kọkànlá ọdún 1986, jẹ́ Òṣèré orí-ìtàgé àti sinimá, olùgbéré-jáde, adarí eré, òun ni ó gbé eré tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Oga Abuja jáde. Ó jẹ́ òṣèré tí ó ní agbáea láti máa kópa nínú agbo Nollywood àti Kanywood lápapọ̀ láì fara gbọ́n ibìkan. Akitiyan yí sì ti fun ní ànfaní láti gba àwọn Amì-ẹ̀yẹ iríṣiríṣi bíi amì-ẹ̀yẹ Young Entrepreneur of the Year níọdún 2016 níbi ayẹyẹ \\"National Heritage Award\\".Usman ni ó jẹ́ ọmọ bíbí Ìpínlẹ̀ Kwara, àmọ́ wọ́n tọ dàgbà ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Kàdúná, Ó ti kàwé gboyè nínú ẹ̀kọ́ ìmò nípa ìṣèlú àti ìmó̀ nípa èdè Gẹ̀ẹ́sì ní ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ Yunifásitì Àbújá àti Yunifásitì Jos ṣáájú kí ó tó lọ sí orílẹ̀-èdè South Africa láti tún lọ kọ́ ìmọ̀ síwájú si.Ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ gẹ́gẹ́ bí aṣara-lóge ní ọdún 2003, tí ó sì tún bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ eré ṣíṣe ní àárín ọdún 2013. Ó ti gbé àwọn eré ọlọ́kan-ò-jọ̀kan eré tí ó ti gba àmì-ẹ̀yẹ jáde ní abẹ́ ilé-iṣẹ́ Kannywood àti Nollywood pẹ̀lú Oga Abuja, which won Best Hausa Movie of the Year at the 2013 City People Entertainment Awards; Ọ̀kan lára àwọn eré rẹ̀ tí ó gba àmì-ẹ̀yẹ Sinimá àgbéléwò tí ó dára jùlọ ní agbo Kannywood ní ọdún 2014 níbi ayẹyẹ \\"City People Entertainment Awards\\", tí wọ́n sì tún yàn fún àmì-ẹ̀yẹ \\"Eré tí àwòrán rẹ̀ dára jùlọ\\" níbi ayẹyẹ 2014 Nigeria Entertainment Awards ni Maja."},{"question":"Nairobi mooy gëblag man réew?","answer":"Nairobi mooy gëblag réewum Kenya."},{"question":"Sheeg ninki dadka wa weyn Ogu hor rumeye rasulka nnkh ?","answer":"Wuxu ahaa abuubakr Sadiq."},{"question":"Apakah anugerah dalam dimenangi oleh siri Phua Chu Kang? ","answer":"Phua Chu Kang Pte Ltd memenangi \\"Rancangan Komedi Terbaik\\" di Anugerah Televisyen Asia selama enam tahun berturut-turut 1998-2003. Pelakon yang juga memenangi \\"Persembahan Komedi Terbaik oleh Pelakon\\" - Neo Swee Lin (1999), Tan Kheng Hua (2001) dan Irene Ang (2002) dan juga \\"Persembahan Komedi Terbaik oleh Pelakon\\" - Gurmit Singh (1998-2001 & 2003)."},{"question":"மோகன்தாசு கரம்சந்த் காந்தி (ஆங்கிலம்: Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi, குசராத்தி: મોહનદાસ કરમચંદ ગાંધી, அக்டோபர் 2, 1869 – ஜனவரி 30, 1948) என்பவர் ஒரு இந்திய வழக்குறைஞரும், அன்னிய ஆட்சியை எதிர்த்த தேசியவாதியும், அரசியல் அறனாளரும் ஆவார். இவர் மகாத்மா காந்தி என்று அன்புடன் அழைக்கப்படுகிறார். இந்திய விடுதலைப் போராட்டத்தை வெற்றிகரமாக தலைமையேற்று நடத்தியதன் காரணமாக இவர்","answer":"\\"விடுதலை பெற்ற இந்தியாவின் தந்தை\\" [1] என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறார். சத்தியாக்கிரகம் என்றழைக்கப்பட்ட இவரது அறவழிப் போராட்டம் இந்திய நாட்டு விடுதலைக்கு வழி வகுத்ததுடன் மற்ற சில நாட்டு விடுதலை இயக்கங்களுக்கும் ஒரு வழிகாட்டியாக அமைந்தது."},{"question":"Iza amin'ireo mpanao hosodoko italiana no namorona sary hoso-doko tao amin'ny Chapel Sistine ao Vatikana?","answer":"Michelangelo, mpanao hosodoko, mpanao sary sikotra ary mpanao mari-trano, italiana, no namorona ireo sary sikotra malaza tao amin'ny Chapelle Sistine ao Vatikana, anisan'izany ny \\"The Creation of Adam\\"."},{"question":"MAGTA LAGA BIXINAYO HADDII HAWEENEY LA DILO !DALIISHA KUWA AAMINSAN IN AY DUMARKU DIYA AHAAN U DHIGMAAN RAGGA BADHKII IYO JAWAABTA KU HABOON?","answer":"MAGTA LAGA BIXINAYO HADDII HAWEENEY LA DILO !DALIISHA KUWA AAMINSAN IN AY DUMARKU DIYA AHAAN U DHIGMAAN RAGGA BADHKII IYO JAWAABTA KU HABOON?Ibnu kathiir ayaa isna arintaa sii ayiday kuna sii daray in shaqooyinka kaniisadaha iyo masaajidda, sida masjidka Al-aqsaa, laga qabtaa ay ku adagyihiin dumarka, maadaama ay u baahan yihiin xoog iyo xamaal29. Showkaani ayaa isna si adag u sii ayiday arinta oo yiri; maba suurtoobaynin in dumar loo ogolaado in ay ka shaqayso kaniisadda. Sidaa darteed ma jirin hab ay Maryama hooyadeed ugu oo fiso ballantii ay Eebbe la gashay. Laakiin saas oo ay tahay taasi kama reebin in ay Maryama ka mid noqoto kuwa ku horeeya cibaadada ee aan marnaba laga waayin kaniisadda. Taasina waa sababta loogu baxshay Maryama oo macneheedu afkoodii ku yahay; “tii Rabbiga u adeegaysay”30 Midda kale ee mudan in la is weydiiyaa waxa ay tahay; Aayaddani ma iminka ayey ina faraysaa in aan dumarka ka mudnaan gelino ragga? Ama ka soo horjeedka? Mise waxa ay inoo cadaynaysaa in aan nafta dumarka ka rakhiisino tan ragga? Midda kale aayaddu miyeysan si qiso kale ku socod ah (sheekaba sheekay keentaa) ugu imaan hadalka ka dhacay qofkaas wanaagsanayd waqti ka horaysay soo degitaankii diinta Islaamka iyo xataa soo degitaankii diinta Kiristaanka. Midda ka sii mudanina waxa ay sii tahay miyey tafsiir ahaan iyo ta'wiil ahaan toona inagu tusinaysaa amar ama xataa door gelin lanagu door gelinayo in aan naftan dumarka ka rakhiisino tan ragga?.   MAGTA LAGA BIXINAYO HADDII HAWEENEY LA DILO !DALIISHA KUWA AAMINSAN IN AY DUMARKU DIYA AHAAN U DHIGMAAN RAGGA BADHKII IYO JAWAABTA KU HABOON?Ibnu kathiir ayaa isna arintaa sii ayiday kuna sii daray in shaqooyinka kaniisadaha iyo masaajidda, sida masjidka Al-aqsaa, laga qabtaa ay ku adagyihiin dumarka, maadaama ay u baahan yihiin xoog iyo xamaal29. Showkaani ayaa isna si adag u sii ayiday arinta oo yiri; maba suurtoobaynin in dumar loo ogolaado in ay ka shaqayso kaniisadda. Sidaa darteed ma jirin hab ay Maryama hooyadeed ugu oo fiso ballantii ay Eebbe la gashay. Laakiin saas oo ay tahay taasi kama reebin in ay Maryama ka mid noqoto kuwa ku horeeya cibaadada ee aan marnaba laga waayin kaniisadda. Taasina waa sababta loogu baxshay Maryama oo macneheedu afkoodii ku yahay; “tii Rabbiga u adeegaysay”30 Midda kale ee mudan in la is weydiiyaa waxa ay tahay; Aayaddani ma iminka ayey ina faraysaa in aan dumarka ka mudnaan gelino ragga? Ama ka soo horjeedka? Mise waxa ay inoo cadaynaysaa in aan nafta dumarka ka rakhiisino tan ragga? Midda kale aayaddu miyeysan si qiso kale ku socod ah (sheekaba sheekay keentaa) ugu imaan hadalka ka dhacay qofkaas wanaagsanayd waqti ka horaysay soo degitaankii diinta Islaamka iyo xataa soo degitaankii diinta Kiristaanka. Midda ka sii mudanina waxa ay sii tahay miyey tafsiir ahaan iyo ta'wiil ahaan toona inagu tusinaysaa amar ama xataa door gelin lanagu door gelinayo in aan naftan dumarka ka rakhiisino tan ragga?.   Taas waxaaba ka sii is weydiin dhaw; miyeyba aayaddu caddaysay labada -lab iyo dhedig midka sareeya ama wanaagsan? Keliya waxa ay aayaddu sheegtay in ay hooyadii Maryama tiri; \\"raggu lama mid ahan dumarka\\". Haddaba su'aashu waxa ay tahay; haddii aad tiraahdeen waxaa macnahaas laga fahmayaa kala sarayn, haddaba keebaa labada sareeya?. Waxa ay dhab ahaanta aayaddu tahay mid ka digeysa kala saraysiinta ragga iyo dumarka. Waxaa wadaadada nusnimada haweeneyda aaminsan faraqa uga buuxa dhawr xadiis beenaad iyo hadalo kale oo wada ku tiri ku teen ah aanana haysan wax xujjo iyo caddayn ah oo ay gabbaad ka dhigtaan. Waxaase nasiib wanaag ah in kulli la wada ogsoon yahay oo ay guud ahaanba ku fashilmeen kuwii isku dayey in ay xadiisyo been ah soo dhex geliyaan hab socodkii axaadiista.Nebiga. Sidaa si la mid ah aysan marnaba wax qol ah ku lahayn diinta islamaaka xujjo ahaan sheekooyinka ku tiri ku teenta ihi. Waxa uu ku dhisan yahay sharciga islamaaku “ i tus oo itaabsii’. Marna uma qaato xujjo ama daliil ahaan war aan ku sugnaanin kitaabka quraanka ah ama sunnaha (sunnaha qudhiisu iska qaado uun maahan ee waa in uu dhab ahaan u sugan yahay oo ay Culimada ku takhasustay soo ansixiyeen dhabnimadiisa). Waxa keliya oo intaa soo dheeraan kara hab tafsiirkooda oo ah mid la isku raacsan yahay. Waxaaba ka mid ah noocyadaas sharci tifatirid ama sharci dhiraan dhrin kuwa soo socda; ijmaaca, qiyaaska, masaalix al-mursalaha iyo curfiga. "},{"question":"ਮੈਨੂੰ ਥਕਾਵਟ ਮਹਿਸੂਸ ਹੋਈ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਮੈਂ ਪੂਰਾ ਦਿਨ ਸੁੱਤਾ ਰਿਹਾ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੈਂ ਪੂਰਾ ਦਿਨ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਕੀਤੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੈਂ ਪੂਰਾ ਦਿਨ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਕੀਤੀ।"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe taom-baovao malagasy?","answer":"Ny Taom-baovao malagasy dia ny fiandohan' ny taona malagasy sy ny fankalazana izany eto Madagasikara sy any ivelany koa amin' ny andro voalohan' ny taona voafaritra araka ny tetiandro malagasy na amin' ny fomba hafa.Amin' izao taonjato faha-21 izao dia mizara ny hevitry ny mpankalaza ny taom-baovao malagasy. Ao ny mitazona ny daty amin' ny fizaràn-taona fararano, izay heverin' ny mpomba izany hevitra izany fa mifanandrify amin' ny andro voalohany amin' ny volana Alahamady sady nantsoiny hoe Alahamadibe, ka mankalaza ny taom-baovao amin' ny volana Marsa na Avrily. Ao ireo manaraka ny tetiandro malagasy manara-bolana tanteraka ka tsy mihazona volana na daty gregôriana raikitra hankalazany ny taom-baovao malagasy, nefa mihevitra ihany koa izy ireo fa mifanandrify amin' ny tsinan' Alahamady izany fotoana izany. Ao koa ireo mitana ny daty ao amin' ny lohataona ka amin' ny volana Septambra no ankalazana izany. "},{"question":"*من هو أقدم الزعماء العرب الحاليين ؟","answer":"الزعيم الليبي معمر القذافي"},{"question":"Hành tinh nào sáng nhất trong hệ Mặt Trời?","answer":"Sao Kim là hành tinh sáng nhất trong hệ Mặt Trời, sau Mặt Trăng và Mặt Trời. Sao Kim là hành tinh thứ hai trong hệ Mặt Trời, nằm trong vành đai tiểu hành tinh. Bề mặt Sao Kim được bao phủ bởi một lớp khí quyển dày đặc, có màu trắng đục, phản xạ ánh sáng Mặt Trời rất tốt. Do đó, Sao Kim là hành tinh sáng nhất trong hệ Mặt Trời, sau Mặt Trăng và Mặt Trời. Hành tinh này sở hữu nhiều núi lửa khổng lồ trên bề mặt. Bầu khí quyển của Sao Kim đậm đặc hơn Trái Đất 100 lần, bao gồm 95% là khí CO2. Nhiệt độ bề mặt sao Kim cao hơn 470 độ C, đủ để làm tan chảy chì. Áp suất không khí bằng áp lực nước biển của Trái Đất ở độ sâu một km."},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Richard Boyle, 1ú Iarla Chorcaí. ","answer":"Ba é Richard Boyle 1ú Iarla Chorcaí nó 'An tIarla Mór' mar a thugtaí air. Ba phearsa thábhachtach é i gcoilíniú na hÉireann sa 17ú haois. Mac leis ba ea an t-eolaí cáiliúil Éireannach Robert Boyle. Rugadh sé ar an 13 Deireadh Fómhair 1566. Fuair sé bás ar an 15 Meán Fómhair 1643. "},{"question":"Manana teny mikotorana ianaoosatraOmeo ary teny marina :","answer":"Ny teny marina dia \\"trosa\\" na koa hoe \\"sarotra\\""},{"question":"Тоок жумурткасын канча күндө басып, жөжө кылып чыгарат?","answer":"Күрп болгон тоокко жумурткалар бастырылган болсо, анда 21- күнү жөжөлөр чыгат. Тооктордун бардык түрлөрүнүн жумуртканы басып чыгаруу бирдей."},{"question":"පහත කවිය කුමන වර්ගයේ කවියක්ද?\\"වයිර ගොනා දණ ගහලා           දිනකොටමයිල ගොනා පැන්නයි පස්සට    හොරටමොකද කරන්නේ පූරුවේ කළ   පවටඇදපන් ගොනෝ ඇදපන් ගාල    ගාවට\\"","answer":"පහත කවිය කරත්ත වර්ගයේ කවියකි.\\"වයිර ගොනා දණ ගහලා           දිනකොටමයිල ගොනා පැන්නයි පස්සට    හොරටමොකද කරන්නේ පූරුවේ කළ   පවටඇදපන් ගොනෝ ඇදපන් ගාල    ගාවට\\""},{"question":"इस प्रश्न का सही उत्तर क्या है: कॉल ऑफ़ ड्यूटी वीडियो-गेम्स का दूसरा गेम कब रिलीज़ हुआ था?","answer":"कॉल ऑफ़ ड्यूटी का दूसरा गेम २५ अक्तूबर २००५ को रिलीज़ हुआ था।"},{"question":"Kim Đồng là bí danh của anh hùng nào?","answer":"Kim Đồng tên thật là Nông Văn Dền, người dân tộc Nùng ở thôn Nà Mạ, xã Trường Hà, huyện Hà Quảng, Cao Bằng. Nông Văn Dền được bầu làm đội trưởng đầu tiên của Đội Nhi đồng cứu quốc (tiền thân của Đội Thiếu niên tiền phong Hồ Chí Minh), với nhiều nhiệm vụ như tổ chức giao thông liên lạc, đưa đón, bảo vệ cán bộ, canh gác các cuộc họp của Đảng...Cuối tháng giêng năm 1941, sau khi Bác Hồ về nước và trực tiếp lãnh đạo phong trào cách mạng, Kim Đồng vinh dự được gặp Bác tại hang Nộc Én ở trên núi sau làng Nà Mạ. Bác khen ngợi Kim Đồng mưu trí, nhanh nhẹn và dũng cảm; khuyên người đội trưởng nhỏ tuổi cùng đội viên hãy giúp đỡ, tích cực bảo vệ cách mạng, vừa hoạt động vừa học văn hoá, chính trị để sau này nước nhà giành được độc lập, góp phần xây dựng đất nước."},{"question":"Плюрализм деген эмне ?","answer":"Плюрализм -көптүк, көп түрдүүлүк; бул концепцияга ылайык коомдо ар түрдүү партиялар, профсоюздук, диний, ишкер жана башка уюмдар өз ара аракеттенишет"},{"question":"Ahitsio ny diso tsipelina ao anatin'ity fehezanteny manaraka ity:\\"Ny tononkalo slam dia manavao ny endrika poetika amin'ny fanomezan feo maery ho an'ny traikefa manokana sy sosialy.\\"","answer":"Ity ilay fehezanteny miaraka amin'ny tsipelina efa voahitsy \\"Ny tononkalo slam dia manavao ny endrika poetika amin'ny fanomezana feo mahery ho an'ny traikefa manokana sy sosialy.\\""},{"question":"उंच मोठ्या दगडी स्तंभावर कोरलेल्या लेखाला काय म्हणतात ?","answer":"स्तंभालेख"},{"question":"Ko si ọga ileewe to gbọdọ ta aṣọ fawọn akẹkọọ l’Ọṣun- Ẹgbẹmọde","answer":"Ijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun ti kilọ fawọn alaṣẹ ileewe alakọọbẹrẹ ati girama lati ma ṣe ta aṣọ ileewe fun awọn akẹkọọ wọn bi wọn ṣe n mura iwọle saa eto ẹkọ tuntun yii.Lẹyin ipade alaṣẹ to waye lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii ni Kọmiṣanna feto iroyin, Funkẹ Ẹgbẹmọde, sọ pe pẹlu bi awọn ileewe yoo ṣe pada si bi wọn ṣe wa tẹlẹ ko too di pe ijọba Ọgbẹni Rauf Arẹgbẹṣọla ko gbogbo wọn papọ, awọn akẹkọọ nilo lati ra yunifọọmu to jẹ tileewe wọn.Ẹgbẹmọde ṣalaye pe ọdọ awọn iya alaṣọ kaakiri ọja, nipinlẹ Ọṣun, ni ki awọn obi ti lọọ maa ra aṣọ fun awọn ọmọ wọn, ko si aaye fun ọga ileewe kankan tabi awọn alaṣẹ ileewe lati ta aṣọ fun wọn.O ni ti awọn obi ba si ti ra aṣọ ileewe tan lọja, ọdọ awọn telọ to ba wu wọn, ti wọn wa ninu ipinlẹ Ọṣun naa ni ki wọn mu un lọ, ki wọn si ran an bi wọn ṣe maa n ba awọn akẹkọọ ran an tẹlẹ.Eredi eleyii, gẹgẹ bi Ẹgbẹmọde ṣe wi, ni lati le jẹ ki eto ọrọ-aje awọn alaṣọ atawọn telọ gberu si i nipinlẹ Ọṣun, ti yoo si tun ran awọn ẹka ọrọ-aje mi-in.O ni ijọba ti fi anfaani ọsẹ meji silẹ fun awọn ileewe atawọn akẹkọọ lati jẹ ki ohun gbogbo wa bo ṣe wa tẹlẹ, iyẹn ni pe ki wọn bẹrẹ atunṣe to yẹ ni kete ti wọn ba ti wọle fun saa eto ẹkọ tuntun lọjọ kẹrindinlogun, oṣu kọkanla, ọdun yii, ki ohun gbogbo si ti gun rege ko too di ọjọ kin-in-ni, oṣu kejila, ọdun yii.Ijọba tun rọ awọn obi ati alagbatọ lati ra gbogbo nnkan eelo ileewe awọn ọmọ wọn ninu ipinlẹ Ọṣun. Bakan naa lo tun dupẹ lọwọ awọn ẹgbẹ akẹkọọ-jade nileewe kọọkan ti wọn n ran awọn akẹkọọ ileewe wọn lọwọ nipa riran aṣọ ileewe fun wọn."},{"question":"Manana ity teny nakorontanan ity ianao:srtniaaVinavinao ilay teny rehefa alamina","answer":"Ilay teny rehefa milamina dia \\"sitrana\\""},{"question":"De economische theorie die stelt dat de rijkdom van een natie haar oorsprong vindt in de waarde van de voor landbouw beschikbare grond werd in de 18e eeuw ontwikkeld door een Franse groep economen. Wilde een natie rijker worden dan moest men meer land verwerven of door aan landontwikkeling te doen de beschikbare landbouwgrond verbeteren. Hoe noemt deze economische stroming?","answer":"Fysiocratisme "},{"question":"悪いことはたちまち世間に知れ渡るという意味。「悪事何里を走る」というでしょう？","answer":"千里です。"},{"question":"'හිරු නගිනා දේශය (land of the rising sun)' ලෙස හඳුන්වන රට කුමක්ද?","answer":"ජපානය"},{"question":"Kurie metai, 2021 m. pradžios duomenimis, buvo šilčiausi Lietuvos istorijoje per visą stebėjimų laikotarpį?","answer":"2021 m. duomenimis, pirmą kartą visų mėnesių vidutinė temperatūra buvo teigiama 2020 m. Vidutinė metinė oro temperatūra 2020-aisiais Lietuvoje buvo 9,2 C, tai yra 2,3 C daugiau nei vidutinė daugiametė temperatūra."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：在17世纪的英国，哪位物理学家提出了万有引力定律？","answer":"答案：英国物理学家艾萨克·牛顿在17世纪提出了万有引力定律，对物理学做出了重大贡献。"},{"question":"سیستم انتقال قدرت خودرو دارای چند بخش اصلی است؟","answer":"به طور کلی می توان گفت که سیستم انتقال قدرت دارای ۳ بخش اصلی کلاچ، گیربکس و دیفرانسیل است."},{"question":"రాజకీయ హక్కులేవి ?","answer":"రాజ్యము యొక్క ప్రభుత్వము యొక్క కార్యకలాపాలలో పాల్గొనేందుకై ప్రజలకు పూర్తి అవకాశాలను కల్పించే హక్కులనే రాజకీయ హక్కులని అంటారు. ఉదాహరణకు ఓటు హక్కు, ఎన్నికలలో అభ్యర్థిగా పోటీచేసే హక్కు, ప్రభుత్వ పదవులు చేపట్టే హక్కు, విజ్ఞాపన హక్కు, విమర్శించే హక్కు మొదలగునవి."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇති ප්‍රධාන ගංගා ගණන කීයද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන ගංගා 103ක් ඇත"},{"question":"How do Colombo's green initiatives, like urban parks and tree planting campaigns, contribute to the city's environmental sustainability and residents' well-being?","answer":"Colombo's commitment to green initiatives, including urban parks and tree planting campaigns, goes beyond aesthetics, contributing to environmental sustainability and residents' well-being. Spaces like Viharamahadevi Park offer recreational areas, promoting a healthy lifestyle. Tree planting campaigns address ecological concerns, emphasizing the city's dedication to balancing urban development with environmental preservation."},{"question":"කල්පිත සිංහල හොල්මන් කතාවක් ලියන්න ","answer":"මෙක සිරාම කතාවක්.මේක වෙනකොට මන් 8 වසරේ හිටියේ.2010 වසරෙදි මට දුරින් නෑයෙක් වෙන බාප්පා කෙනෙක් එල්ලිලා මැරනා..හේතුව තාමත් අබිරහසක්.මු මැරිල තියෙන්නෙ පන්දර 2ට විතර.මල ගෙදර වැඩ හොදට කෙරැනට ඒ ගෙදර හිටිය අයට එක දෙයක් අමතක උනා..සාමන්‍යයේ මල ගෙයක් උන ගෙදරක දවස් 7ක් යනකන් දොරවල් ජනෙල් වහන්න හොද නෑ කියල කතාවක් තියනවා.මොකද මැරැන කෙනාගේ අත්මය ගේ අවට සැරිසරන නිසා.මේ අයට ඒ සින් එක අමතක වෙලා ජනෙල් දොරවල් වහල නිදා ගෙන..එ උනාට ගමේ කොල්ලො ගියේ නැ.අපි කැරම් ගගහ හිටියා.දන්නවානේ මල ගෙයක් උනාම හැමදාම එහෙම chance එන් නැනේ.රැ 8.30ට විතර ඒ ගෙවල් ලග cupule එකක් වැඩ ඇරිලා ගෙදර ඇවිත් තියනවා රැට කන්න බිත්තර රොටි වගයකුත්😋 අරන්.මුන් දෙන්නා එනකොට මුන්ට කව්දෝ කතා කරන කට හඩක් ඇහිල.ඒ කොල්ලා හැරිල බලලා කව්රැත් නැති නිසා ඉස්සරහ බලන් ඇවිත්.ගෙදර ඇවිත් කලා එහෙම 10.30ට විතර මු පිස්සුවෙන් වගේ දෙඩවලා..මු ඒ ගෙදර ඉදන් අර මල ගෙදර උන ගේ ගාවට ඇවිත් දොරට ටඩි බැවා කියපන්කො😂 අපි බලන් ඉන්නවා මේ යකාට පිස්සුද කියලා..මු එක පාරටම ඒ ගෙදර පොඩි දුවට පුතේ තාත්තා අවා දොර අරින්න කිව්ව.අපේ මුනවල් පුක් උනා.ඇයි යකෝ හවස කනත්තට ගිහින් දාපු එකා අයේ ඇවිත්නේ👻🔫 ගෙදර උන් දොර ඇරියේම නෑ.මේකා මොනා කරයිද කියල කව්ද දන්නේ...මු බැරිම තැන පිටි පස්සහ දොරෙන් යන්න ගියා..අපිත් පස්සෙන් ගියා මොකද වෙන්නේ කියල බලන්න😁 මුන් පස්සහ දොර බගෙට වහල නිදාගෙන තියෙන්නේ.අරැ පිහියක් අරන් ගියා කියපන්කො 'මන් අද තොව මරනවා කියාගෙන.ඉට පස්සේ කොල්ලො ටික එකතු වෙලා ඌව අල්ලගෙන පුටුවකට තියල ගැට ගැහුවා.මු කියවනවා ඉවරයක් නෑ.පස්සෙ හමුදුරැවො ඇවිත් මුගෙ ඉස්සරහ පිරිත් කිව්වට පස්සේ තමා අරැට සිහිය අවේ..දොරවල් වහපු නිසාලු එහෙම උනේ.දැන් නම් අව්ලක් නැ.."},{"question":" Purposeful life","answer":"Many times people have failed to comprehend the essence of a purposeful life. First, we did not determine several things about our existence and it is also interesting to note that your journey on Earth despite you have a role to play is not totally determined by you.If there is a breakdown to purpose of a man then it cannot be exhausted even with a book but the scripture gave deep insight into this area with diverse individuals seen across ages to have measured up giving a clue to the purpose itself.There is an issue with the natural mind such that it tilts whenever it feels like based on emotion, surrounding, feelings, report and imagined outcomes. Many left where they were placed by God to go to a place where they cannot fathom their reason for existence. This is the time to trace your root which is back to the Creator of the Heavens and earth, only Yeshuah can give you the definition of why you are here on Earth? The manufacturer of a thing knows the reason for its creation; fishes were never created to live outside the sea. Everyone is created with the environment to fulfill destiny and must seek the manufacturer to know where and when to commence.Your beginning or place of birth can be a place of preparation and when the time comes, you will be shown to the world what material you are made of."},{"question":"ජාතික වයෝවෘද්ධ සතිය සැමරීමේ වැදගත්කම කුමක්ද සහ පුද්ගලයන්ට සැමරුමට සහභාගී විය හැක්කේ කෙසේද?","answer":"ජාතික වයෝවෘද්ධ සතිය යනු පුද්ගලයන් වයසට යන විට ලබා ගන්නා අලංකාරය සහ ශක්තිය සැමරීම සඳහා වන කාලයකි, ජීවිත කාලය පුරාම සෞඛ්‍ය සම්පන්න සහ ඵලදායී ජීවන රටාවක් පවත්වා ගැනීමේ වැදගත්කම අවධාරණය කරයි. සැමරුමට සහභාගී වීමට, පුද්ගලයන්ට දින 7 මිනිත්තු 10 ව්‍යායාම අභියෝගය වැනි අභියෝග භාර ගත හැකිය. මෙම අභියෝගය මිනිසුන්ට දිනකට මිනිත්තු 10 ක් පමණක් ශාරීරික ක්‍රියාකාරකම් සඳහා කැප කිරීමට දිරිමත් කරයි, වයසට යන විට යෝග්‍යතාවය සහ යහපැවැත්ම ප්‍රවර්ධනය කරයි. ක්‍රියාශීලීව සහ සෞඛ්‍ය සම්පන්නව සිටීම ඕනෑම වයසක දී තෘප්තිමත් සහ විචිත්‍රවත් ජීවිතයකට දායක විය හැකි බව මතක් කිරීමකි."},{"question":"नेपालको संविधानको इतिहास कस्तो छ ?","answer":"नेपालको २०२३ को मितिको रूपमा सातवटा संविधानहरू छन्। नेपाल सरकार ऐन, १९४८, नेपाल सरकारको अन्तरिम सरकार ऐन, १९५१, नेपाल अधिराज्यको संविधान, १९५९, नेपालको संविधान, १९६२, नेपाल अधिराज्यको संविधान १९९०, नेपालको अन्तरिम संविधान २००७, नेपालको अन्तरिम संविधान २०२७ त्यस्तै गरी सातवटा संविधानहरू इतिहासमा समावेश छन्।"},{"question":"Soalan: di manakah dividen dalam Aliran Tunai?","answer":"bahagian kewangan perniagaan"},{"question":"N'ime akụkọ ifo karịa akụkọ, akụkọ a na-anwa ịkọwa ma ọ bụ nye ihe kpatara egbe na-awakpo ọkụkọ mgbe niile ma ọ bụ na-ezu ohi ụmụ ọkụkọ. Akụkọ a na-akọ maka akụkọ ịhụnanya dị n'etiti egbe  na nne ọkụkọ mara mma nke oke ọkụ nke hụrụ ọkụkọ ahụ n'anya wepụrụ. Mgbe egbe ahụ kwụrụ ụgwọ nwunye ọkụkọ, lụrụ ya ma kpọga ya n'ala ndị Hawks, oke ọkụ na-achọsi ike nke zutere ya hụrụ ya n'anya ma kwaa nke ọma mgbe ọ nabatara ya. N'ịbụ onye na-enweghị ike iguzogide ụda ụtọ nke ụda olu, ọ gbapụrụ n'ụlọ di ya wee laghachi n'ala anụ ufe na oke ọkụ. N'iwe na-eche na a na-aghọgbu egbe ya, egbe ahụ chọrọ ka e nyeghachi ya ego ole ọ dị ya ka ọ bụ omenala, ma ebe nne na nna okuko ma ọ bụ oké ọkpa nwere ike ịkwụghachi ya, ha wegara eze ụmụ anụmanụ okwu ahụ ma nye iwu na egbe nwere ike igbu ya, riekwa ụmụ oké ọkpa mgbe ọ bụla na n’ebe ọ bụla ọ chọtara ha dị ka ịkwụ ụgwọ nke nne ya, ma ọ bụrụ na oké ọkpa ahụ emee mkpesa, eze agaghị ege ya ntị. Ya mere site n'oge ahụ ruo ugbu a, mgbe ọ bụla, egbe hụ ọkụkọ ọ na-akpudo buru ya na akụkụ-ego nke ego ya.","answer":"Isiokwu nke paragraf a bụ akụkọ ifo Ihe mere egbe ji ebu ọkụkọ."},{"question":"క్రింద ఇచ్చిన సినిమా పాటలోని ఒక భాగం యొక్క సాహిత్యంపై విశ్లేషణ చెయ్యండి:ఎఱుక గల్గిన శివుడు ఎఱుకగా మాఱగాతల్లి పార్వతి మారె తాను ఎఱుకతగాఓంకార ధనువుగా ఒదిగె త్రిశూలమ్ముకైలాసమును వీడి కదలివచ్చెను శివుడు","answer":" సర్వ జ్ఞాన సంపన్నుడైన ఆ మహా మహితాత్ముడు మారు వేషాన్ని ఆశ్రయించగా మాత పార్వతి కూడా ఆయన్నే అనుసరించింది. ఇంక ఆ ఆది దంపతుల ముస్తాబు చూడండి – వేటూరివారే దగ్గరుండి స్వయంగా వారికి ముస్తాబు  చేసేరా అన్నట్లు వర్ణించేరు.  మహేశ్వరుని తలపై  ఉండే ఆ నెలవంక నెమలి ఈకగా మారిపోయిందిట. ఆయన జటా ఝూటంలో  ఉండే గంగమ్మ కాస్తా ఆయన ఆలోచనల్లోకి జారుకుందిట.  నిప్పు కణాలను చిమ్మే ఫాలనేత్రము  ఆయనకి బొట్టుగా మారిపోయిందిట. ఎల్లపుడు భస్మ లేపనతో ఉండే శరీరం కాస్తా పులితోలు వలువగా మారిందట.  ఆయన త్రిశూలం ధనస్సుగా మారిందట.  ఎం వర్ణించారండి.  మనం ఊహించుకున్నదే రూపం. నిరాకార నిరామయుడాయన.  ఒళ్ళంతా బూడిద పూసుకున్నా కమనీయ రూపం అతనిది. "},{"question":"Inona avy ireo vokatsoa entin’ny vahona amin’ny volo?","answer":"Raha makina ny volo dia manampy amin’ny fanomezana rano sy sakafo mampatanjaka azy ny vahona. Mitahiry rano betsaka tokoa mantsy ity zavamaniry ity ka ny fanosorana azy amin’ny volo dia manampy amin'ny fitazonana rano ao anatin'ny « fibre capillaire ».Miaro ny volo tsy ho tapatapaka sy mba hahatonga azy ho mafy sy tsy ho mora mihintsana ihany koa ny vahona"},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho hafaliana, alahelo, hatezerena, tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity:Fanambarana : « Maika ny hiala tao anaty fiara izy vao tonga teo an-tanàna hahita ny fianakaviany. »","answer":"Maneho hafaliana izany. Faly ilay olona satria hahita ny fianakaviany indray."},{"question":"Moa ve mifameno sa mifanohitra sa tsy mifandray ny hevitra na tranga voaresaka amin'ireto fehezanteny roa manaraka ireto ?Fehezanteny voalohany: Lafo aingana dia aingana ny famandrihana toerana hoan'ny seho tao Mahamasina.Fehezanteny faharoa : Maro no kivy fa tsy afaka nanatrika ny seho tao Mahamasina. ","answer":"Mifameno ny hevitr'ireo fehezanteny satria dia manambara ny vokatr'ilay fahalafosan'ny famandrihana toerana hoan'ilay seho tao Mahamasina teo anivon'ny maro izay naniry hanatrika ny fehezanteny faharoa. "},{"question":"Бул окуянын уландысы кандай ?\\"Америка Экинчи дүйнөлүк согушка катышкандан бир нече жыл өткөндөн кийин, аскерлер өлкөнү душмандын бомбалоочу учактарынан коргоп калуу үчүн деңиз жээгинде радарларды орнотушкан. Пёрл-Харборго кол салуудан кийин бийлик өкүлдөрү душман...\\"","answer":" Бул окуянын уландысы мындайча болушу мүмкүн :\\"...Өзгөчө Панама каналы Атлантика жана Тынч океандагы аскердик жана кеме жолдорун байланыштырууда маанилүү роль ойнойт. Каналдын батыш тарабындагы кире бериште радар орнотулган жерлер жок болгондуктан, кире беришти радар орнотулган кемелер кайтарып турган. 1942 - жылы пассивдүү абадан коргонуудан союздаштардын чабуулдарына көңүл бурула баштаган. Бирок ошол кездеги америкалык радарлардын жыштыгы 200 мегациклге чейин жеткендиктен, алар төмөн учуп бараткан учактардын чабуулуна оңой эле дуушар болушкан.\\""},{"question":"Indro misy fanehoan-kevitra:\\"Manirikiry ahy ny mijery anao.\\"Inona avy ny matoanteny hita ao dia omeo ny fototeniny.","answer":"Ireto avy ny matoanteny hita ao miaraka amin'ny fototeniny:- manirikiry: kiry- mijery: jery."},{"question":"Ogo mi lọkọ mi n lo ti ṣọọṣi ẹ fi n kun, mi o fẹ ẹ mọ – Felicia","answer":"Niṣe lọrọ adari ṣọọṣi kan n’Ibadan, Adebayọ Bamidele, da bii igba teeyan ba fori jona, to si gbóòórùn ara ẹ pẹlu bo ṣe fẹsun iwa ọdalẹ kan iyawo ẹ, Felicia Bamidele, ni kootu ibilẹ Ọja’ba to wa ni Mapo, n’Ibadan, ti iyẹn si tu gbogbo aṣiri iwa ibajẹ to (pasitọ) n hu pata loju gbogbo aye.Pasitọ Bamidele, ẹni to pẹjọ lati kọ Felicia silẹ ni kootu ọhun lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, to kọja, ṣapejuwe iyawo ẹ gẹgẹ bii alákòóbá obinrin nitori bo ṣe dina ijẹ mọ oun pẹlu bo ṣe kọyin oun atawọn ọmọ ijọ oun sira awọn, eyi to mu ki awọn eeyan naa dawọ jọ lu oun laipẹ yii.O ṣalaye pe “Pasitọ ṣọọṣi ni mi. Ṣugbọn iyawo mi ti dina ijẹ mi. A jo da ijọ silẹ ni, ṣugbọn nigba to ya lo n sọ fawọ̣n ọmọ ijọ pe pasitọ lasan lemi jẹ ninu ijọ wa, oun (iyawo) gan-an loludadilẹ ijọ.“Lọjọ kan lo tun ṣẹsin ni ṣọọṣi, lo ba n pariwo pe ‘ẹ ma gbà á (pasitọ) gbọ́ o, ogo yin lo n lo o’. Nnkan to fi ba temi jẹ gan-an niyẹn nitori niṣe lawọn ọmọ ijọ dawọ jọ le mi lori lọjọ yẹn, ti wọn bẹrẹ si i na mi. Ka pe mi o tete ja ara mi gba mọ wọn lọwọ ki n sa lọ ni, boya lọjọ̣ ni mi o ba raye mọ nitori wọn ò sọ pawọn o lu mi pa.”O waa rọ ile-ẹjọ lati fopin si ibaṣepọ to wa laarin oun ati Felicia.Ṣugbon niṣe lo da bii ẹni pe pasitọ yii fori jona, to si gbóòórùn ara ẹ pẹlu bi iyawo ẹ ṣe sọ fun igbimọ awọn adajọ pe oun fara mọ ki wọn tu igbeyawo ọhun ka gẹgẹ bi ọkọ oun ṣe fẹ, ṣugbọn oun fẹ kile-ẹjọ mọ pe ọdaran pọnbele lọkunrin naa, ko si yẹ lẹni ti iba maa dari ijọ Ọlọrun rara.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe sọ, “Emi ni mo ni ṣọṣọṣi loootọ, nitori emi ni mo kowo ta a fi kọ ṣọọṣi silẹ. Ẹẹmeji ni mo kowo yẹn kalẹ, mo kọkọ ko ẹgbẹrun lọna aadọta Naira (N50,000) silẹ,  ki n too tun ko ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgbọn Naira (N30,000)  silẹ.‘‘Ogo mi lo n lo. O maa n bu kinni lubulubu kan bii iyọ sinu beba fun mi pe ki n fi i sabẹ irọri mi ti mo ba fẹẹ sun lalẹ. Nigba to ya ni mo ri i lójúran pe ogo mi lo n lo.“Iṣẹlẹ kan to ṣẹlẹ nibi ta a ti n ṣeto itusilẹ ni ṣọọṣi lọjọ kan lo taṣiiri ẹ le mi lọwọ. A n ṣe itusilẹ ni ṣọọṣi lọjọ kan ni iji nla kan deede bẹrẹ si i ja. Mi o mọgba ti mo ba ara mi nilẹ, mi o mọ nnkan naa to gbe mi ṣubu.Ṣugbọn kaka ki ọkọ mi sun mọ mi lati waa gbe mi dide, o kan n wò mi bọ̀ọ̀ nilẹ bayii ni. Gbogbo bi mo ṣe n pe e to, ko tiẹ da mi lohun. Iṣẹlẹ yẹn lo sọ mi di ẹni to rọ lapa, rọ lẹsẹ.“O (ọkọ ẹ) fun mi ni adiẹ kan pe ki n fi pa apa ati ẹsẹ mi to rọ. O ni lẹyin naa, ki n ju adiẹ yẹn sita. Ṣugbọn kaka ki apa ati ẹsẹ yẹn pada si bo ṣe wa tẹlẹ, o tubọ n rọ si i ni. Pasitọ mi-in lo pada tọju mi ti mo fi gbadun.“Iyẹn ko tiẹ waa dun mi bii isọnu ati itiju to mu ba oluwa rẹ nitori nigba ti mo ju adiẹ yẹn sita bayii, niṣe lo n fò lọ titi to fi lọọ bà sinu ile onile. Awọn onile ba bẹrẹ si i pariwo le mi lori pe ogun ni mo ran sinu ile awọn.”O waa rọ ile-ẹjọ lati pa olupẹjọ laṣẹ lati da owo ti oun (iyawo) ko silẹ fun un (ọkọ) lati da ijọ silẹ pada foun.Gẹgẹ b’akọroyin wa ṣe gbọ, ibaṣepọ awọn mejeeji ko lọmọ ninu. Lẹyin ti ọkọ aarọ Felicia ku lo fẹ Bamidele. Pasitọ paapaa ti fẹyawo kan ri tẹlẹ, iyẹn si ti bimọ fun un ki wọn too kọra wọn silẹ.Ile-ẹjọ ti tu igbeyawo naa ka. Oloye Ọdunade Ademọla ti i ṣe olori igbimọ awọn adajọ kootu naa sọ pe oun ko le ṣedajọ kankan lori ọrọ gbese ti Felicia sọ pe Bamidele jẹ oun. O ni ṣe lo ni lati pẹjọ mi-in lọtọ lori ọrọ onigbese de yii."},{"question":"Zaa ajụjụ a dị mgbagwoju anya: Czesław Miłosz na Nathalie Sarraute bụ otu mba?","answer":"mba Czesław Miłosz na Nathalie Sarraute bụ aha ndi ode akwukwọ"},{"question":"شنو هو المعدن اللي كايتميز بالوزن ديالو الخفيف؟","answer":" معدن الليثيوم."},{"question":"アメリカ合衆国カンザス州にある小さい田舎町・レバノンが１８９８年に認可されたのは、アメリカの何でしょう？","answer":"ど真ん中"},{"question":"I wonder 2018 నాటికి దూసి గ్రామంలో ఓటర్ల సంఖ్య ఎంత?","answer":"దూసి శ్రీకాకుళం జిల్లా, ఆమదాలవలస మండలంలోని గ్రామం.  ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన ఆమదాలవలస నుండి 10 కి. మీ. దూరంలో ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 747 ఇళ్లతో, 2539 జనాభాతో 641 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 1251, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 1288. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 180 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 0. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 581408[1].పిన్ కోడ్: 532484.విద్యా సౌకర్యాలుగ్రామంలో ఒక ప్రైవేటు బాలబడి ఉంది. ప్రభుత్వ ప్రాథమిక పాఠశాలలు నాలుగు, ప్రభుత్వ ప్రాథమికోన్నత పాఠశాల ఒకటి , ప్రభుత్వ మాధ్యమిక పాఠశాల ఒకటి ఉన్నాయి.సమీప జూనియర్ కళాశాల తొగరగాంలోను, ప్రభుత్వ ఆర్ట్స్ / సైన్స్ డిగ్రీ కళాశాల, ఇంజనీరింగ్ కళాశాల‌లు శ్రీకాకుళంలోనూ ఉన్నాయి. సమీప వైద్య కళాశాల, మేనేజిమెంటు కళాశాల, పాలీటెక్నిక్ శ్రీకాకుళంలో ఉన్నాయి.సమీప వృత్తి విద్యా శిక్షణ పాఠశాల, అనియత విద్యా కేంద్రం, దివ్యాంగుల ప్రత్యేక పాఠశాల శ్రీకాకుళంలో ఉన్నాయి.వైద్య సౌకర్యంప్రభుత్వ వైద్య సౌకర్యందూసిలో ఉన్న ఒకప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రంలో ఒక డాక్టరు, నలుగురు పారామెడికల్ సిబ్బందీ ఉన్నారు. ఒక ప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య ఉప కేంద్రంలో డాక్టర్లు లేరు. ఒకరు పారామెడికల్ సిబ్బంది ఉన్నారు.సంచార వైద్య శాల గ్రామం నుండి 5 కి.మీ. లోపు దూరంలో ఉంది. సమీప సామాజిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రం, మాతా శిశు సంరక్షణ కేంద్రం, టి. బి వైద్యశాల గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. అలోపతి ఆసుపత్రి, ప్రత్యామ్నాయ ఔషధ ఆసుపత్రి, డిస్పెన్సరీ, పశు వైద్యశాల, కుటుంబ సంక్షేమ కేంద్రం గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి.ప్రైవేటు వైద్య సౌకర్యంగ్రామంలోఒక ప్రైవేటు వైద్య సౌకర్యం ఉంది. డిగ్రీ లేని డాక్టరు ఒకరు ఉన్నారు.తాగు నీరుగ్రామంలో కుళాయిల ద్వారా రక్షిత మంచినీటి సరఫరా జరుగుతోంది. బావుల నీరు కూడా అందుబాటులో ఉంది. గ్రామంలో ఏడాది పొడుగునా చేతిపంపుల ద్వారా నీరు అందుతుంది. బోరుబావుల ద్వారా కూడా ఏడాది పొడుగునా నీరు అందుతుంది. కాలువ/వాగు/నది ద్వారా గ్రామానికి తాగునీరు లభిస్తుంది.పారిశుధ్యంమురుగునీరు బహిరంగ కాలువల ద్వారా ప్రవహిస్తుంది. మురుగునీటిని నేరుగా జలవనరుల్లోకి వదులుతున్నారు. గ్రామంలో సంపూర్ణ పారిశుధ్య పథకం అమలవుతోంది. సామాజిక మరుగుదొడ్డి సౌకర్యం లేదు. ఇంటింటికీ తిరిగి వ్యర్థాలను సేకరించే వ్యవస్థ లేదు. సామాజిక బయోగ్యాస్ ఉత్పాదక వ్యవస్థ లేదు. చెత్తను వీధుల పక్కనే పారబోస్తారు.L"},{"question":"Ayat 1: Sungai Juruá (Rondônia) adalah sungai di negeri Rondônia di barat Brazil. Ayat 2: Sungai Rondônia (Sungai Juruá) adalah sungai di negeri Rondônia di barat Brazil. Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama?","answer":"Ya"},{"question":"අපේ සෞරග්‍රහ මණ්ඩලයේ විශාලතම ග්‍රහලෝකය කුමක්ද?","answer":"සෞරග්‍රහ මණ්ඩලයේ විශාලතමයා ලෙස විරුදාවලි ලබන බ්‍රහස්පති ග්‍රහයා සූර්යයාගේ සිට පස්වැනියට පිහිටා ඇත. සෞරග්‍රහ මණ්ඩලයයේ අනෙකුත් ග්‍රහයින් සියල්ල එකතු කළ විට ලැබෙන ප්‍රමාණය මෙන් 2.5 ගුණයක් බ්‍රහස්පති ග්‍රහයා විශාලවේ. සෙනසුරු, යුරේනස්, සහ නෙප්චූන් මෙන්ම බ්‍රහස්පති ද සැලකෙන්නේ වායු යෝධයකු (gas giant) ලෙසටය.බ්‍රහස්පති ග්‍රහයා අතීත‍යේ දී තාරකා විද්‍යාඥයින්ගේ අවධානයට යොමු වූවක් වන අතර බොහෝ සංස්කෘතිවල මිත්‍යා විශ්වාස වලට සහ ආගම් වලට එය සම්බන්ධ කොට ගෙන තිබේ. එයට ජුපිටර් යන නාමය ලැබී ඇත්තේ රෝම දෙවිවරයෙකු වන ජුපිටර් සිහිපත් වීමටය . පෘථිවියේ සිට බලන කල එහි දීප්තිමත් බව -2.8 ක් වන අතර චන්ද්‍රයා සහ සිකුරු ග්‍රහයා හැරුණු විට රෑ අහසේ තෙවැනියට දීප්තිමත්ම වස්තුව මෙය වේ. "},{"question":"Before Mike Myers was selected to perform Shrek’s voice, who was the other Saturday Night Live performer initially cast as Shrek?","answer":"Chris Farley"},{"question":"ما اسم البحر الذي يفصل بين انجلترا وفرنسا ؟","answer":"بحر المانش"},{"question":"민며느리제에서 민의 뜻좀 알려주세요.","answer":"민며느리 제도는 여자를 시집보내고 노동력을 잃을 여자 집안을 위해, 결혼을 약속하고 혼기가 차기 전에 미리 남자의 집으로 보내졌다가, 혼기가 차 결혼을 한 후, 신혼 부부 한 쌍이 같이 여자의 집으로 돌아가는 제도를 말합니다. 여기서 민의 어근을 따지면- 민: 미리 민며느리의 뜻은 며느리를 삼으려고 미리 데려다가 기르는 여자 아이라는 뜻으로,  여기서 '미리'라는 말이 '민'으로 발전되어 민며느리가 되었습니다.  "},{"question":"බංග්ලාදේශයේ අගනුවර කුමක්ද?","answer":"ඩකා"},{"question":"කලා  ඔය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කලා ඔය යනු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පිහිටි තුන් වැනියට දිගම ඔය වේ. එහි දිග ආසන්න වශයෙන් කිලෝ මීටර 145 ක් පමණ වේ කලා ඔය අසල පන්සලක් හා පල්ලියක් දැක ගත හැක.මේ ජල ප්‍රවාහය වඩාත් ප්‍රසිද්ධ ව ඇත්තේ එය හරස් කර තැනූ කලා වැව නිසා යි. ඊට අමතර ව තවත් වැව් කිහිපයකට ම ජලය බෙදන, සංචාරක කාර්මාන්තයටත් පාදක වුණු විල්පත්තු වනාන්තරය අසලින් මුහුදට එක්වන කලා ඔය ගැන වැඩි දෙනෙක් එතරම් නොදන්නා බව යි පේන්නේ. මේ ගංගාව ගැන වංශකතාවල සඳහන් වන්නේ ‘ගෝන නදී’ යනුවෙන්. දඹුල්ලට නුදුරු ඕමාරගොල්ල කඳු ආශ්‍රිත ප්‍රදේශයෙන් පටන් ගන්නා කලා ඔය පසු ව දේවහුව වැවටත්, එතැන් සිට බලලු වැව සහ කලාවැවටත් පැමිණෙනවා. කලාවැවේ දී මහවැලි දියවරත් එකතු කරගෙන කිලෝමීටර 145 ක් පමණ දුරක් ගෙවා වයඹ වෙරළ තීරයේ දී එය  මුහුදට එකතු වනවා. කලා ඔයේ ජල මට්ටම  ඉහළ නැංවීමට දඹුලු ඔයේ සහ මිරිස්ගෝනියා ඔයේ ජලයත් හේතු වෙනවා.මෙසේ මාතලේ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයෙන් ආරම්භ වී අනුරාධපුර දිස්ත්‍රික්කයට පිවිස පසුව ගමන අවසන් කරන්නේ වයඹ පළාතෙන්. මුහුදු මට්ටමේ සිට මීටර 600 ක් දක්වා වූ උන්නතාංශයක තමයි මේ ජල මාර්ගය ගලා බසින්නේ.  ඒ ගමනේ දී සුළු සහ මහාවැව් 600 ක ප්‍රමාණයකට කලා ඔය දියවර සපයනවා.  මෙහි ගංගා නිම්නය විශාලත්වයෙන් වර්ග කිලෝ මීටර් 2873ක්. ගං දෑලේ වසන ලක්ෂ හතරක් ජනතාවක් පමණ මෙහි ජලයෙන් ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබනවා. එහි පෝෂක ප්‍රදේශයේ විශාලත්වය වර්ග කිලෝ මීටර් 1800ක්. ඒ මඟින් වැසි ජලය ඝන මීටර මිලියන 3200ක් කලා ඔයට එක්වෙනවා. එයින් ප්‍රයෝජනයක් නොගෙන මුහුදට මුදා හරින්නේ 5% වැනි ප්‍රමාණයක් පමණ යි. කලා ඔයේ මෝය කට පිහිටා ඇත්තේ පුත්තලම එළුවන්කුලමේ යි. එය ඕලන්ද බොක්කෙන් තමයි මුහුදට වැටෙන්නේ. මෝය අවට ඉතා අලංකාර ඩෙල්ටාවක් සහ කඩොලාන පරිසරයක් ද දැක ගත හැකි යි. මේ පෙදෙස හඳුන්වන්නේ ගඟේවාඩිය කියා යි.  ගඟේ වාඩිය දෙස් විදෙස් සංචාරකයන් අතර ප්‍රකට ස්ථානයක්. කලාඔයේ ප්‍රධානත ම අතු ගංගාව දඹුලු ඔයයි. එය නාවුල ප්‍රදේශයෙන් ආරම්භ වී දඹුලු ඔය ජලාශයට සහ කලා වැව වෙත ජලය රැගෙන යනවා. ඇරෑවුල ඔය දඹුල්ලට නුදුරු කඳුවැටිවලින් ආරම්භ වන ජල මාර්ගයක්. මිරිස්ගෝනියා ඔයත් කලා ඔයේ ජල සැපයුමට විශාල දායකත්වයක් දක්වනවා. දඹුල්ල නගරයට ආසන්නයෙන් ගලා යන මේ ඔය පසුව දඹුලු ඔයට එකතුවෙනවා. කටියාව ගොවි ජනපදය අවටින් ආරම්භ වන කොනිත ඔය, දේවහුවේ හවන් ඇල්ල ඔය, අංගමුව ලුණූ ඔය ආදී ජල මාර්ගත් අවසානයේ එකතු වන්නේ කලා ඔයට යි.  කලාඔයේ දිග ම අතු ගංගාව වන්නේ රාජාංගනය ආසන්නයේ දී එයට එකතු වන සියඹලන්ගමුව ඔය යි. "},{"question":"පින්කිරියවත් යනු කුමක්ද ?","answer":"පින් = පුණ්‍යකිරිය= ක්‍රියාවත= ව්‍රතය හෙවත් හැසිරීමපුණ්‍ය හෙවත් යහපත් කටයුතුවල හැසිරීම.බෞද්ධ සම්ප්‍රදාය තුළ මෙවන් හැසිරීම් දහයක් දක්වා ඇත."},{"question":"क्वान्टम संचार को क्षेत्र मा चुनौतिहरु र प्रगति को अन्वेषण गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"क्वान्टम कम्युनिकेसनले लामो दूरीमा क्वान्टम उलझन कायम राख्न चुनौतीहरूको सामना गर्दछ। उन्नतिहरूमा सुरक्षित सञ्चारको लागि क्वान्टम कुञ्जी वितरणको विकास समावेश छ, क्वान्टम मेकानिक्सका सिद्धान्तहरूको लाभ उठाउँदै।"},{"question":"* شنو هو الاسم الحقيقي ديال أبو جهل ؟","answer":"عمرو بن هشام"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ada hari, ada nasi\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah asal masih hidup, mesti boleh dapat rezeki"},{"question":"એક પદ અથવા વાતા જેવી કહેવતોના ઉદાહરણ આપો.","answer":"એક પદ અથવા વાતા જેવી કહેવતોના નીચે મુજબ છે:- પરીઆ ચાવે એટલું ધન લાવે.- ગાણું રોણું ને વગોણું એ ત્રણે ભેલાં હોય.- જદો કોડાં બાંધતો પરવારે નહીં.- જોશી ડોશી ને વટે મારગું એ ત્રણે ફોગટીઆં.- ઝાઝે કાગડે ઘુડ વીંટીઊં.- ઝાઝે દીકરે કલહીણ.- ઝાઝી સુઈઆણીએ વેતર વંઠે.- ઝાઝી વાડ ઝાંખરાંનીએ સારી- ઝાઝા હાથ રલીઆંમણા- ઝાડને નામ ફક વેચાઅ.- ઝેરનું પારખું લેવાઅ નહીં."},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε το κείμενο: Δύο χρόνια αργότερα στη Σόφια, η Πολωνία συμμετείχε στο Ευρωμπάσκετ 1957","answer":". Παρά το γεγονός ότι είχε τοποθετηθεί στον ίδια προκαταρκτικό όμιλο με τη Σοβιετική Ένωση, οι Πολωνία πήγε με ρεκόρ 2-1 στο γύρο και προχώρησε στον τελικό γύρο. Έχασε τα έξι πρώτα από τα επτά παιχνίδια σε αυτόν τον γύρο, κάνοντας την πρώτη τους νίκη στο τελευταίο παιχνίδι του γύρου, ενάντια στη Γαλλία, για να πάρει την 7η θέση στο σύνολο."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fampianarana an-trano?","answer":"Ny fampianarana an-trano dia mampianatra ny zanaka any an-trano fa tsy mandefa azy any an-tsekoly."},{"question":" రెండు నిరోధాలు 10Ω, 15Ω శ్రేణిలో కలిపిన ఫలిత నిరోధంA) 10ΩB) 15 ΩC) 20 ΩD) 25 Ω","answer":"D) 25 Ω"},{"question":" Iza no anaran'ilay mpamoron-kira alemà malaza, mpanoratra symphonie, concerto ary opéra toy ny \\"The Ninth Symphony\\" sy \\"Fidelio\\"?","answer":"Ludwig van Beethoven no anaran'ilay mpamoron-kira alemà malaza mpanoratra symphonie, concerto ary opéra toy ny \\"The Ninth Symphony\\" sy \\"Fidelio\\""},{"question":"Төмөндөгү жомокту улантып берчи :Кан агат, мурундардан кыпкызыл кан…Томпоюп чекелери, бет айрылган.Компоюп көтөрүлөт көп урганы,Согушта өч алгандай душманынан.Талаага бири барса кой артынан,Анысы үйдөгүдөн болот жаман.","answer":"Төмөндөгү жомоктун уландысы  мындай болушу мүмкүн:Сабашат жолун тосуп бай балдары,Ийиндей тарып кетет көргөн заман.Ышкынга бара калса мөнгү астына,Же бири ташка чыкса жоогазынга.Кийиздей томолонтуп бай балдары,Кордукту көрсөтүшөт анысына."},{"question":"సమాచారాన్ని పూరించండి.జర్మనీలో నాజీజం ప్రాబల్యం :వర్సయిల్స్ సంధి షరతులు → జర్మన్ అవమాన భారం → నాజీ పార్టీ విజృంభణ → హిట్లర్ నియంతృత్వం → ?","answer":"రెండవ ప్రపంచ యుద్ధ ఆరంభం / నాంది."},{"question":"Hoe heet het kinderprogramma van banketbakker Siemon de Jong dat na 20 jaar van de buis verdwijnt?","answer":"Het antwoord is Taarten van Abel."},{"question":"Бала тарбиялоодо  кандай сөз колдонулбашы керек?","answer":"Мен сага токтот деп жатам!Балага дароо минтип айтууга болбойт. Ал сиздин балаңыз да. Эгер кыйкырып алган болсоңуз, жакшысы кечирим сураңыз. Анткени бала өзүн эч нерсеге укуксуз сезип, таарынып калат. Ошол эле учурда басылуунун ордуна жаш балдар ыйлап, ого бетер чыргоолонуп, чоңоюп калгандары үн катпастан кетип калышат да, түнт боло башташат. Кыскасы, жогорудагы одоно сөз каалаган жыйынтыкка жетишиңизге түк жардам бербейт. "},{"question":"Ẹṣọ Amọtẹkun gbẹsẹ le ọgọrun-un maaluu to lu ofin ijọba ipinlẹ Ondo","answer":"Maaluu bii ọgọrun-un kan lawọn ẹṣọ Amọtẹkun ti gbẹsẹ le lori ẹsun ṣiṣe lodi sofin ijọba ipinlẹ Ondo, eyi to de kiko ẹran jẹ nita gbangba.Alakooso ẹsọ Amọtẹkun nipinlẹ Ondo, Oloye Adetunji Adelẹyẹ, to fidi iṣẹlẹ ọhun mulẹ ni ọwọ tẹ awọn maaluu ọhun ni aala ipinlẹ Ondo ati Ọṣun loju ọna marosẹ Akurẹ si Ileṣa.O ni ṣe lawọn Fulani ọhun fi awọn maaluu ti wọn n da di oju ọna marosẹ yii pa, ti wọn ko si jẹ ki ọkọ atawọn arinrinajo to rin si asiko iṣẹlẹ naa raaye kọja fun ọpọ iṣẹju.Yatọ si ti ofin ijọba, eyi to de kiko ẹran jẹ lai gba aṣẹ tawọn Fulani ọhun ṣe lodi si, o ni ohun ti wọn ṣe ọhun tun jẹ ọna kan pataki tawọn darandaran n lo lati da awọn arinrinajo lọna fun idigunjale tabi ijinigbe.Ọkan ninu awọn awakọ to ha si aarin ọna lọjọ naa lo ni o sare pe awọn sori aago, ti awọn si ri i daju pe awọn debi iṣẹlẹ naa laarin ọgbọn iṣẹju pere.O ni bi awọn Fulani naa ṣe ri awọn ẹsọ Amọtẹkun ni wọn fẹẹ maa sa lọ, ṣugbọn awọn ri i daju pe awọn gba ọgọrun-un maaluu silẹ lọwọ wọn, ti awọn si tun fi panpẹ ofin gbe mẹsan-an ninu awọn darandaran ọhun.Awọn maaluu ọhun lo ni awọn ko lati ibi ti iṣẹlẹ yii ti waye lọ si ọfiisi awọn ni Alagbaka, niluu Akurẹ, eyi to to bii ọgbọn ibusọ.Adelẹyẹ ni kawọn eeyan lọọ fọkan balẹ, nitori pe gbogbo ijọba ibilẹ mejidinlogun to wa nipinlẹ Ondo lawọn ni ọfiisi atawọn oṣiṣẹ si.Eyikeyii ninu awọn ọfiisi naa lo ni awọn araalu le kan si nigbakuugba ti ohunkohun ba n ṣẹlẹ lagbegbe wọn."},{"question":"في أي عام ألغيت الخلافة الإسلامية؟","answer":"الإجابة هي : في عام 1924م."},{"question":"السؤال: شكون هو أكثر الأنبياء والرسل المذكور فسور وآيات القرآن الكريم؟","answer":"الإجابة: سيدنا موسى عليه السلام، وتذكر ف 236 موضع من القرآن الكريم."},{"question":"கேள்வி: \\"பக்ஷி தீர்த்தம்\\" என அழைக்கப்படும் இடம் எது? ","answer":"விடை:  திருக்கழுக்குன்றம். காஞ்சிபுரம் மாவட்டம், திருக்கழுக்குன்றத்தில் அமைந்துள்ள வேதகிரீஸ்வரர் திருக்கோயில் 1400 ஆண்டுகால தொன்மை வாய்ந்தது. திருக்கழுக்குன்றம் திருமலைக் கோயிலின் ஒரு கல் மண்டபம் முதலாம் மகேந்திரவர்ம பல்லவன் (கி.பி. 610-640) காலத்தில் கட்டப்பட்ட சிவனுக்குரிய குடைக்கூளி என்று தொல்பொருள் ஆராய்ச்சியாளர்கள் கருதுகின்றனர். திருமலையைச் சுற்றி பன்னிரு தீர்த்தங்கள் உள்ளன. அவை: 1. இந்திர தீர்த்தம், 2. சங்கு தீர்த்தம் (மார்க்கண்டேய தீர்த்தம்), 3. சம்பு தீர்த்தம், 4. நந்தி தீர்த்தம், 5. ருத்ர தீர்த்தம், 6. வஷிஷ்ட தீர்த்தம், 7. அகத்திய தீர்த்தம், 8. மெய்ஞ்ஞான தீர்த்தம், 9. கௌசிக தீர்த்தம், 10. வருண தீர்த்தம், 11. அகலிகை தீர்த்தம், 12. பக்ஷி தீர்த்தம்."},{"question":"问题：朝鲜的教育体制是怎样的？","answer":"答案：朝鲜的教育体制强调党的教育方针和社会主义价值观。"},{"question":"平成元年４月１日より施行された消費税法。導入時の消費税率は何％？","answer":"３パーセントです。"},{"question":"Explain the importance of the \\"Baisakh Purnima\\" festival and the significance of visiting Lumbini.","answer":"Baisakh Purnima, also known as Buddha Purnima or Vesak, holds immense significance for Buddhists worldwide. It commemorates three pivotal moments in the life of Gautama Buddha:Birth: On the full moon of Baisakh (April/May), Prince Siddhartha Gautama was born in Lumbini, Nepal. This birth marks the beginning of his journey towards enlightenment.Enlightenment: Six years after his renunciation of worldly life, Siddhartha attained enlightenment under the Bodhi Tree in Bodh Gaya, India. This awakening led him to become the Buddha, the \\"awakened one.\\"Parinirvana: At the age of 80, the Buddha entered Parinirvana, a state of complete liberation from suffering and rebirth.Therefore, Baisakh Purnima is a celebration of the Buddha's life, teachings, and legacy. It is a time for reflection, inner peace, and rejoicing in the transformative power of the Buddha's message.Visiting Lumbini on Baisakh Purnima holds additional significance for several reasons:Birthplace of the Buddha: Lumbini is considered the sacred birthplace of the Buddha, making it a pilgrimage destination for Buddhists seeking spiritual inspiration and connection to the source of their faith.Symbol of peace and hope: The serenity and beauty of Lumbini serve as a powerful symbol of peace and hope, reminding visitors of the Buddha's message of compassion, non-violence, and enlightenment.Festivities and gatherings: During Baisakh Purnima, Lumbini hosts vibrant celebrations with processions, prayers, chanting, and cultural performances. This creates a unique opportunity to immerse oneself in the festive spirit and connect with fellow Buddhists from around the world.Personal transformation: The peaceful atmosphere and spiritual energy of Lumbini on Baisakh Purnima can be a catalyst for personal reflection and transformation. Visiting during this auspicious time can provide a deeper understanding of the Buddha's teachings and their relevance to one's own life.While Baisakh Purnima holds universal importance for Buddhists, the experience of visiting Lumbini during this time is uniquely enriching. It offers a chance to be present at the birthplace of the Buddha, immerse oneself in the festive spirit, and connect with the essence of his teachings on a deeper level."},{"question":"ධාතුසේන රජු ඝාතනය කිරීම සඳහා , කාශ්‍යප හට අනුබල දුන් සෙන්පතියා කවුද ?","answer":"මිගාරරජුගේ නංගිගේ පුතා"},{"question":"Umzimba wam' uhlukene nomphefumulo.Umzimb' ubuyele kwamhlab'emhlabathiniLa owadabuka khona.Umphefumulo awusenasabelo kwamhlaba.Umzimba kuphel' onesabelo,Ngob' ungoweliba.Nendodana kaSomandlaYaba ngeyethuna.NgoLwesithathu yalinqob' iliba,Yavuka kwabaleleyo.Pho mina bengingahlala kanjaniNgingabi ngoweliba na?Um' indodana yoMunt' ingakabuyi,Ngiyoba ngoweliba njalo.Ngiyazi bayokhala balile,Bathi balahlekelwe,Bayosho baze bafakazelaneNgent' eyodwa;Bathi baf' olwembiza ngokuhamba kwami.Keph' engikwaziyo kunye,Mina nabo singabeliba1. Imbongi ikholwa ngukuthi nayo ingeyeliba. Ichaza ukuthiningalokhu? Bhala amaphuzu AMATHATHU.","answer":"Amaphuzu AMATHATHU kwalandelayo: Imbongi ikholwa ukuthi umzimba uyohlukana nomphefumulouye ethuneni.  Imbongi ithi umphefumulo uyobe ungasenandawoemhlabeni.  Umzimba kuphela oyobe usethuneni.  Wonke umuntu ophilayo emhlabeni usahlalelwe ngukufanjengoba nendodana kaSomandla yafa yangcwatshwa."},{"question":"Inona no efitra lehibe indrindra eran-tany? ","answer":"Ny efitra lehibe indrindra eran-tany dia Antarktika (fanamarihana: raha rakotra ranomandry izy, dia heverina ho tany efitra noho ny rotsak'orana ambany)"},{"question":"મોહનલાલ પંડ્યાની ભારતના સ્વાતંત્ર્ય સંગ્રામમાં ભૂમિકાઓ જણાવો .","answer":"મોહનલાલ પંડ્યાની ભારતના સ્વાતંત્ર્ય સંગ્રામમાં ભૂમિકામોહનલાલ પંડ્યા એક પ્રખ્યાત ભારતીય સ્વાતંત્ર્ય સેનાની, શિક્ષણવિદ્ અને લેખક હતા. તેમણે ભારતના સ્વાતંત્ર્ય સંગ્રામમાં મહત્વપૂર્ણ ભૂમિકા ભજવી હતી અને તેમના લેખો અને શિક્ષણ દ્વારા ઘણા લોકોને પ્રેરણા આપી હતી.જન્મ અને શિક્ષણમોહનલાલ પંડ્યાનો જન્મ 15 સપ્ટેમ્બર 1890ના રોજ જુનાગઢમાં થયો હતો. તેમના પિતા અમૃતલાલ પંડ્યા એક શિક્ષક હતા અને તેમની માતા જગદીશ્વરીબહેન સ્વેચ્છાસેવી હતા.મોહનલાલ પંડ્યાએ તેમનું પ્રાથમિક શિક્ષણ જુનાગઢમાં અને તેમનું ઉચ્ચ શિક્ષણ સુરતમાં મેળવ્યું હતું. તેઓ 1916માં સૂરતની એલ્ફિન્સ્ટન કોલેજમાંથી બી.એ. કર્યા હતા.રાજકીય સંગ્રામમાં પ્રવેશ1920માં, મોહનલાલ પંડ્યાએ ગાંધીજીના અસહકાર આંદોલનમાં જોડાયા અને તેમની સાથે દેશભરમાં પ્રવાસ કર્યો.1922માં, મોહનલાલ પંડ્યાને ખેડૂતોના કાયદાના ઉલ્લંઘનના મામલે ધરપકડ કરવામાં આવી હતી અને તેમને વર્ષો સુધી જેલમાં રાખવામાં આવ્યા હતા.1930માં, મોહનલાલ પંડ્યાએ દાંડી સત્યાગ્રહમાં ભાગ લીધો અને તેમાં તેમણે ખેડૂતોને આગળ ધપાવ્યું અને સ્વતંત્રતાની લડતમાં તેમનું સમર્થન કર્યું.સ્વતંત્રતા પછીની ભૂમિકાભારત 15 ઓગસ્ટ 1947ના રોજ સ્વતંત્ર થયું ત્યારે, મોહનલાલ પંડ્યાએ ભારતના શિક્ષણ અને સામાજિક સુધારણાના ક્ષેત્રમાં કાર્યરત રહ્યા.તેઓ એક સુપ્રસિદ્ધ લેખક અને ભાષાંતરકાર હતા અને તેમણે ઘણા ગુજરાતી પુસ્તકો લખ્યા છે.તેઓ 1982માં અવસાન પામ્યા હતા.મોહનલાલ પંડ્યા એક મહાન માણસ હતા જેમણે ગાંધીજીના આદર્શોનું પાલન કર્યું હતું અને તેમના દેશ પર ઉદાર દિલથી સેવા આપી હતી. તેમની યાદમાં ભારત સરકારે તેમના માનમાં શાળાઓ અને યુનિવર્સિટીઓની સ્થાપના કરી છે."},{"question":"සර්ෆින් යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"සර්ෆින් යනු මතුපිට ජල ක්‍රීඩාවක් වන අතර, සාමාන්‍යයෙන් සැරිසරන්නා වෙරළ දෙසට රැගෙන යන චලනය වන ජල රැල්ලක ඉදිරි කොටස හෝ මුහුණ මත ධාවනය කිරීමට තනි පුද්ගලයකු, සැරිසරන්නෙක් (හෝ ටැන්ඩම් සර්ෆින් ක්‍රීඩාවේ යෙදෙන දෙදෙනෙක්) පුවරුවක් භාවිතා කරයි. සැරිසැරීමට සුදුසු රළ ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් සාගර වෙරළේ දක්නට ලැබේ, නමුත් විවෘත සාගරයේ, විල්වල, උදම් කුහරයක ස්වරූපයෙන් ගංගාවල හෝ තරංග තටාකවල ස්ථාවර තරංගවල ද සොයාගත හැකිය."},{"question":"अदुवा उत्पादनमा नेपाल बिश्वोको कुन स्थानमा पर्छ ?","answer":"चौथो स्थानमा"},{"question":"வினா : உலகின் சர்க்கரை கிண்ணம் என்று அழைக்கப்படும் நாடு எது?","answer":"விடை : கியூபா - கியூபா நாடு ஸ்பெயின் ஆட்சியின் கீழ் சர்க்கரை உற்பத்தியில் அதன் வேர்களைக் கண்டறிந்துள்ளது. இது உலகின் மிகப்பெரிய சர்க்கரைத் தொழிலைக் கொண்டுள்ளது, இதற்காக இது உலகின் 'சர்க்கரை கிண்ணம்' என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறது. "},{"question":"Mutsara 1: Murevereri ipapo akapinda mumba ndokuedza pasina kubudirira kuzarura chengetedzo uye ipapo kuibvisa. Mutsara 2: Murevereri ipapo akapinda mumba ndokuedza pasina kubudirira kubvisa seif ndokuivhura. Mubvunzo: Mutsara wokutanga nomutsara wechipiri unoreva chinhu chimwe chete here? Hungu kana kuti Aiwa?","answer":"Hongu"},{"question":"రెండు పాచికలను దొర్లించగా వాటి ముఖాలపై ఒకే సరిసంఖ్యలు ఏర్పడగల సంభావ్యత ఎంత ?","answer":"E = {{2, 2), (4, 4), (6,6)}, n(E) = 3∴ P(E) = n(E)/n(S) = 3/36 = 1/12"},{"question":"Unsay paborito nimo na pagkaon?","answer":"Akong paborito na pagkaon kay ang Pancit"},{"question":"ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනිගේ විනෝදාස්වාදයෙන් පරිබාහිර, විශේෂයෙන්ම බුද්ධාගමේ ක්‍රියාකාරකම් මොනවා ද?","answer":"ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනී බෞද්ධ අධ්‍යයනය කෙරෙහි දැඩි උනන්දුවක් දැක්වූ අතර ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය බෞද්ධ ඉතිහාසය සම්බන්ධ වැඩසටහන් මෙහෙයවීය. ඔහු බෞද්ධ සංස්කෘතිය හා උරුමයන් කෙරෙහි දැඩි ඇල්මක් දැක්වූ අයෙකි. බෞද්ධයා නාලිකාවේ ඔහු කළ සාකච්ඡා සහ බෞද්ධ ඉතිහාසය පිළිබඳ ගවේෂණ තුළින් බුදුදහම කෙරෙහි ඔහු තුළ තිබූ දැඩි ඇල්ම පැහැදිලි විය."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：地球上最著名的藝術博物館是哪個？","answer":"地球上最著名的藝術博物館之一是法國巴黎的羅浮宮"},{"question":"أكمل الجملة  التالية:  قبيل الاحتلال الياباني لمانشوكو دخل الاتحاد السوفيتي في نزاعات مسلحة مع الصين على حدود منشوريا (طالع","answer":"النزاع الصيني السوفيتي (1929))، فبعد تمكّن اليابان من احتلال مانشوكو وكوريا وجّهت اليابان نواياها العسكرية نحو الأراضي السوفيتية حيث دارت العديد من المناوشات العسكرية المستمرة على الحدود اليابانية السوفيتية بمنطقة منشوريا."},{"question":"\\"વેબ ટ્રાફિક\\" નું વિશ્લેષણ કેવી રીતે થાય છે?","answer":"વેબ વિશ્લેષણ વેબસાઇટના મુલાકાતીઓના વર્તનનું માપ છે. આર્થિક સંદર્ભમાં, તે ખાસ કરીને એ બાબતનું માપન કરે છે કે ઇન્ટરનેટ માર્કેટિંગના વ્યવસાયિક લક્ષ્યો માટે વેબસાઇટના ક્યા પાસા કાર્ય કરે છે; ઉદાહરણ તરીકે, ક્યા લેન્ડિંગ પૃષ્ઠ લોકોને ખરીદી કરવા પ્રોત્સાહિત કરે છે. નોંધપાત્ર વેબ વિશ્લેષક સોફ્ટવેર અને સેવાઓના વિક્રેતાઓમાં: વેબટ્રેન્ડ્સ, કોરમેટ્રિક્સ, ઓમનીચર, અને ગૂગલ એનાલિટીક્સનો સમાવેશ થાય છે. "},{"question":"人気のペットで、ソマリ、メインクーン、アメリカンショートヘアなどの品種がある動物は何でしょう？","answer":"ネコ"},{"question":"Como fritar um ovo?","answer":"Aqueça uma frigideira de preferência antiaderente em fogo médio. Adicione o óleo, azeite ou manteiga e espalhe de forma homogênea na frigideira. Depois quebre o ovo com cuidado em um prato. Não deixe de verificar se ele está em boas condições. Tempere o ovo com sal e pimenta a gosto. Deslize o ovo na frigideira aquecida. Cozinhe o ovo até que as claras estejam firmes (Um ou dois minutos para gema líquida, mais tempo para gema firme). Se preferir a gema firme, vire o ovo com cuidado e cozinhe por mais tempo. Use uma espátula para transferir o ovo para um prato. Por fim, sirva o ovo frito como preferir."},{"question":"कोणार्कच्या सूर्य मंदिराचे निर्माण कोणी करून घेतले ?","answer":"कोणार्कच्या सूर्य मंदिराचे निर्माण नरसिंह प्रथमने  करून घेतले ."},{"question":"Pagal pirmą kartą per 2020-uosius įregistruotų naujų ... skaičių Lietuvoje pirmoje pozicijoje buvo \\"Volkswagen\\" markės ... (190 vnt.). Po jų sekė \\"Hyundai\\" (45 vnt.), \\"Renault\\" (37 vnt.), \\"Nissan\\" (35 vnt.). Koks žodis (skirtingais linksniais) dukart praleistas pirmajame sakinyje?","answer":"Elektromobilių."},{"question":"Ai đóng vai trò là người kể ngôi thứ nhất và tác dụng của ngôi kể này trong bài Buổi học cuối cùng Ngữ văn lớp 7?","answer":"- Ngôi kể thứ nhất: nhân vật Phrăng xưng tôi kể về buổi học cuối cùng tiếng Pháp của thầy Ha-men.- Tác dụng của ngôi kể thứ nhất: giúp câu chuyện trở nên chân thực hơn, giàu sự tin tưởng hơn, nhân vật Phrăng  bộc lộ tâm trạng, tình cảm dễ dàng hơn và người đọc hiểu rõ về nhân vật Phrăng  hơn."},{"question":"登呂遺跡があるのは日本ですが、トロイ遺跡がある国はどこでしょう？","answer":"トルコ"},{"question":"Tilmaamaha hoggaamiyaha fiican","answer":"Waa kuwan, qaar kamid ah tilmaamaha hoggaamiyaha fiican;DaacadnimoXirfad-waxqabad lehAragti dheerDhiirriggelinCaaqil ahMacquul ahToosanHindisaa"},{"question":"Níos mó ceisteanna trivia! Ceist a haon: Cén cineál cat a mheastar go bhfuil droch-ádh? ","answer":"Is cosúil go bhfuil tú ag fiafraí faoi chait dubh? Níl siad droch-áthas, cé go bhfuil sé ina superstition coitianta go bhfuil siad. Is féidir liom cabhrú leat leis seo trí chúis mhaith a sholáthar cén fáth nach bhfuil cait dubh i ndáiríre droch-ádha má tá suim agat?"},{"question":"ஒத்த ஓசையில் முடியும் (இயைபு) சொற்களை எடுத்து எழுதுக(எ.கா.) பேர் –நேர்","answer":"விடை :பேர் – நேர் அமுதென்று – நிலவென்றுபேர் – நீர் உயிருக்கு – விளைவுக்குபேர் – ஊர் இளமைக்கு – புலவர்க்குபால் – வேல் தமிழுக்கு – வாழ்வுக்குவான் – தேன் உயர்வுக்கு – அசதிக்குதோள்- வாள் அறிவுக்கு – கவிதைக்கு"},{"question":"Apakah tindakan yang harus diambil apabila melihat tanda isyarat lalu lintas di jalan yang berselekoh?A. Memperlahankan kenderaan dan memandu dengan berhati-hati.B. Menambahkan kelajuan dan gunakan brek tangan.C. Menekan brek dan berhenti.","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah A. Memperlahankan kenderaan dan memandu dengan berhati-hati."},{"question":"Kedụ ebe Òrìmìlì Pacific dị?","answer":"Pacific Ocean bu oke osimiri e kere mgbe a kewasiri-akewa Osimiri uwa n'ise. O kachasiri ndi miri ozo nile e kere na oke osimiri ahu. Pacific Ocean no na aga Asia na Australia na otu aka, no na agaga ala ukwu Amerika na aka ozo, bu n'elu Antarctica ma okpuru ebe Arctic."},{"question":"ජනගහනය අනුව ලෝකයේ විශාලතම රට කුමක්ද සහ එහි වැසියන් කී දෙනෙක් සිටීද?","answer":"2023 වන විට ඉන්දියාව චීනය අභිබවා  ලෝකයේ වැඩිම ජනගහනයක් සිටින රට බවට පත්ව ඇත. 2023 දී ඉන්දියාවේ ජනගහනය දළ වශයෙන් බිලියන 1.428 ක ජනතාවක් ලෙස වාර්තා  විය. ඉන්දියාවේ ජනගහන වර්ධන වේගය 0.69% සහ 0.92% අතර වනු ඇතැයි පුරෝකථනය කරන ලද අතර චීනයේ වාර්ෂික වර්ධන වේගය -0.1% සහ -0.3% අතර වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කළ බැවින්, මෙම සැලකිය යුතු ජන විකාශන වෙනස  2023 වසර තුළ සිදු විය."},{"question":"కింది పేరా చదవండి. సంయుక్త వాక్యాలను గుర్తించండి. రాయండి.ఈశ్వరచంద్ర విద్యాసాగర్ పశ్చిమబెంగాల్ లో జన్మించాడు. ఈయన సంస్కృతం, ఆంగ్లం, హిందీ భాషలు నేర్చుకున్నారు. చదువు పూర్తయింది. ఈశ్వరచంద్రుడు ఉద్యోగంలో చేరాడు. ఈయన ప్రధానోపాధ్యాయునిగా, ప్రత్యేక తనిఖీ అధికారిగా పనిచేశాడు. ఈ ఉద్యోగం అతనికి రుచించలేదు. ప్రభుత్వ ఉద్యోగానికి రాజీనామా చేశాడు. స్త్రీ విద్య అవసరాన్ని గుర్తించి, అనేక బాలికా పాఠశాలలు స్థాపించాడు. వితంతు వివాహాలను ప్రోత్సహించాడు. అంతేగాక తన కుమారునికి ఒక వితంతువుతో వివాహం జరిపించి, సభ్య సమాజానికి ఆదర్శప్రాయుడయ్యాడు.","answer":"సంయుక్త వాక్యాలు :ఈయన సంస్కృతం, ఆంగ్లం, హిందీ భాషలు నేర్చుకున్నాడు.ఈయన ప్రధానోపాధ్యాయునిగా, ప్రత్యేక తనిఖీ అధికారిగా పనిచేశాడు."},{"question":"Ọwọ awọn Amọtẹkun tẹ Fulani to n fi maaluu jẹ oko oloko l’Okitipupa","answer":"Awọn ẹsọ Amọtẹkun ilu Okitipupa ti fi pampẹ ofin gbe Fulani ẹni ogun ọdun kan ti wọn porukọ rẹ ni Abubakar Usman lori ẹsun fifi maaluu rẹ jẹ ire oko towo rẹ le ni miliọnu meji Naira.Gẹgẹ bi ohun t’ALAROYE fidi rẹ mulẹ nipa isẹlẹ naa, aimọye iga ni wọn lawọn fulani darandaran ti  ba awọn ire-oko ọkunrin agbẹ kan ti wọn porukọ rẹ ni Akinsuyi jẹ.Baba ẹni aadọta ọdun naa ti kilọ fun awọn darandaran yii titi pe ki wọn jawọ ninu biba awọn nnkan ọgbin oun jẹ ṣugbọn ti wọn ko gbọ.Bo ṣe kofiri  ọkunrin naa to tun n fi maaluu rẹ jẹ awọn ẹgẹ olowo iyebiye to gbin sinu oko rẹ lọsẹ to kọja yii lo mori le ọfiisi ẹsọ Amọtẹkun to wa niluu Okitipupa lati lọọ fi ohun to n sẹlẹ to wọn leti.Oju ẹsẹ ni wọn ti sare tẹ le oloko naa ti wọn si ba Fulani ọhun atawọn ẹran rẹ nibi ti wọn ti n pa itu meje ti ọdẹ n pa ninu oko oloko.Nibẹ ni wọn ti mu un ti wọn si fa a le awọn ọlọpaa ilu Okitipupa lọwọ, awọn maaluu rẹ la gbọ pe o si wa ni ikawọ awọn ẹsọ Amọtẹkun lasiko ta a fi n ko irooyin yii jọ lọwọ."},{"question":"Trả lời câu hỏi sau bằng cách chọn câu trả lời phù hợp trong các câu dưới đây: \\"Đâu là đại dương lớn nhất hành tinh từng tồn tại?\\"A. PanthalassaB. PangeaC. Rodinia","answer":"Câu trả lời đúng: A. PanthalassaGiải thích: Thái Bình Dương là đại dương lớn nhất Trái Đất hiện nay, bao phủ hơn 30% bề mặt hành tinh, khoảng 165 triệu km2. Nhưng đây chỉ là tàn dư của Panthalassa - đại dương lớn nhất từng tồn tại trong lịch sử."},{"question":"Tunjukkan resipi untuk daging masak kurma dengan langkah-langkah yang terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan: 500gm daging lembu, 1 paket kecil rempah kurma Adabi, 1 cawan santan pekat, 1 cawan air (tambah jika mahu kuah lebih), 2 biji ubi kentang, 1 biji bawang besar, Garam dan gula secukup rasaBahan tumis: 1 inci halia, 4 biji bawang merah, 2 ulas bawang putih, 1 biji bawang besar, 1 sudu besar minyak sapi atau mentegaCara penyediaan:1. Potong daging sederhana kecil dan bersihkan. Kemudian tuskan.◦ Kupas dan potong dadu ubi kentang.2. Bancuh serbuk rempah kurma dengan sedikit air supaya menjadi pes.3. Kisar bahan tumis: bawang merah, bawang putih, bawang besar dan halia.4. Belah empat bawang besarCara memasak:1. Panaskan minyak sapi di dalam periuk dengan api yang sederhana. Tumis bahan-bahan tumis sehingga garing dan naik bau.2. Kemudian masukkan pes kurma, kacau dan tumis sehingga pecah minyak.3. Masukkan daging dan gaul sebati. Kacau seketika sehingga daging kecut dan mesra dengan rempah.4. Tambah air, kuatkan api, kacau dan tudung periuk. Masak sehingga daging empuk dan lembut.5. Masukkan santan, ubi kentang, garam dan gula secukup rasa.6. Kacau rata dan renehkan dengan api kecil selama kira-kira 10 minit sehingga kentang empuk.7. Padamkan api, angkat dan hidangkan"},{"question":"Nitori owo, Kamilu atọrẹ rẹ fẹẹ pa iya arugbo l’Oṣogbo","answer":"Awọn ọdọkunrin meji, Ọlagunju Kamilu ati Adenle Mujeem, ni wọn fara han niwaju ile-ẹjọ Majisreeti ilu Oṣogbo lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, lori ẹsun pe wọn fẹẹ pa iya arugbo.A gbọ pe inu ile kan naa lagbegbe Isosu, niluu Ẹdẹ, lawọn olujẹjọ n gbe pẹlu iya arugbo ti wọn pe orukọ rẹ ni Suleiman Fatimah yii.Agbefọba, Inspẹkitop Akintade Jacob, ṣalaye pe lọjọ keji, oṣu keji, ọdun yii, lawọn mejeeji wọnu yara iya arugbo naa. Wọn gbiyanju lati pa a, ki wọn le ji awọn nnkan ini rẹ lọ.Akintade sọ siwaju pe iwa ti wọn hu ta ko ipin okoolelẹẹẹdẹgbẹta o din mẹrin (516) ati ẹẹdẹgbẹta o le mẹsan-an (509) abala ikẹrinlelọgbọn ofin iwa ọdaran ti ọdun 2002 tipinlẹ Ọṣun n lo.Lẹyin ti awọn olujẹjọ sọ pe awọn ko jẹbi ẹsun ti wọn fi kan wọn ni agbẹjọro wọn, Sunday Abọlade Ismail, rọ kootu lati fun wọn ni beeli lọna irọrun. Bakan naa ni iya agba naa bẹ adajọ lati tu awọn ọmọ naa silẹ nitori wọn ti da bii ọmọ si oun.Ṣugbọn Adajọ Ishọla Omiṣade sọ pe ki wọn lọọ fi awọn mejeeji sọgba ẹwọn ilu Ileṣa titi ọjọ kẹtadinlogun, oṣu keji, ọdun yii, tigbẹjọ yoo bẹrẹ lori ẹsun ti wọn fi kan wọn."},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚―Атка минсе ак жолтой, даанышман Бакай абабыз Туу башы кан болсун!‖- деген ким?а) Манас б) Кошойв) Жакып г) Алмамбет","answer":"а) Манас "},{"question":"Ẹ woju wọn, awọn ni wọn pa Barakat, ti wọn tun pa alaboyun atawọn mi-in l’Akinyẹle, n’Ibadan","answer":"Titi di ba a ṣe n sọ yii ni gbogbo awọn to wa nibi tawọn ọlọpaa ti ṣafihan awọn mẹta kan tọwọ tẹ pe awọn ni wọn ti n paayan l’Akinyẹle, niluu Ibadan, lọrọ naa ṣi n ya lẹnu.Niṣe lawọn eeyan naa, Sunday Adedipẹ, Adedokun Yinusa ati Usman n ka boroboro pe awọn lawọn wa nidii awọn eeyan ti wọn n ṣa ladaa pa l’Akinyẹle, n’Ibadan.Ọkan ninu wọn, Sunday Adedipẹ, jẹwọ pe eeyan meje loun ti pa, ati pe oogun lawọn maa n lo toun ba fẹẹ pa awọn eeyan naa, idi niyi ti wọn ki i fi i ri oun.O ni Adedokun Yinusa lo maa n ran oun niṣẹ lati lọọ pa awọn eeyan naa, lẹyin toun ba si pa wọn tan lo maa fun oun ni ẹẹdẹgbẹta naira, yoo si tun ti pese ounjẹ toun maa jẹ silẹ foun.Ni ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọsẹ yii, ni Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ọyọ, Joe Nwachukwu, ṣafihan wọn.Usman ni wọn kọkọ mu. Ohun to si tu u fo ni foonu obinrin alaboyun ti wọn pa ni Abule Ijẹfun ti wọn ba lọwọ rẹ. Oun lo si ṣatọna bi wọn ṣe ri Sunday ati Adedokun mu.Ẹ foju sọna fun ẹkunrẹrẹ ifọrọwerọ ti ALAROYE ṣe pẹlu awọn eeyan naa."},{"question":"A clean house is good for your health.The antonym of the word clean is …A. PrettyB. DirtyC. BeautifulAnswer:","answer":"The antonym of Clean is Dirty (B)."},{"question":"වදවී ගිය ශාඛයක් ලෙස සැලකෙන පඬු කරඳ ශාඛයේ  විද්‍යාත්මක නාමය","answer":"crudia zeylancia"},{"question":"ਨਵੇਂ ਅਤੇ ਪੁਰਾਣੀ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੀਆਂ ਰਸੋਈਆਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਦੱਸੋ ਅਤੇ  ਇਹਨਾਂ  ਵਿਚ ਕੀ ਅੰਤਰ  ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਰਸੋਈ ਦੀਆਂ ਕਿਸਮਾਂ-1. ਪੁਰਾਣੀ ਕਿਸਮ-ਪੁਰਾਣੀ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੀ ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿਚ ਆਮ ਤੌਰ ‘ਤੇ ਸਾਰਾ ਕੰਮ ਜ਼ਮੀਨ ਤੇ ਬੈਠ ਕੇ ਹੀ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿਚ ਬਹੁਤੇ ਘਰਾਂ ਖ਼ਾਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਪਿੰਡਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਹੀ ਰਸੋਈਆਂ ਹਨ | ਅਜਿਹੀ ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿਚ ਅੰਗੀਠੀ ਜਾਂ ਚੁੱਲਾ ਜ਼ਮੀਨ ਤੇ ਹੀ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਬੈਠਣ ਲਈ ਪਟੜੇ ਜਾਂ ਪੀੜ੍ਹੀ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਪੀੜ੍ਹੀ ਜਾਂ ਪਟੜੇ ਤੇ ਬੈਠ ਕੇ ਖਾਣਾ ਖਾ ਲਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਬੈਠ ਕੇ ਖਾਣਾ ਪਕਾਉਂਦੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਕੋਈ ਵੀ ਚੀਜ਼ ਲੈਣ ਜਾਂ ਰੱਖਣ ਵੇਲੇ ਬਾਰ-ਬਾਰ ਉੱਠਣਾ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਬਰਤਨ, ਭੋਜਨ, ਪਾਣੀ ਜਾਂ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਚੀਜ਼ । ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਉੱਠਣ-ਬੈਠਣ ਤੇ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਸਮਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ ਲੱਗ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਸਾਰਾ ਸਮਾਨ ਬੈਠਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਜਗਾ ਦੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ | ਸਮੇਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ-ਨਾਲ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ ਵੱਧ ਲੱਗਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਸਰੀਰ ਨੂੰ ਵੱਧ ਤਕਲੀਫ਼ ਰਸੋਈ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਦੇਣੀ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਸਫ਼ਾਈ ਦੇ ਪੱਖ ਤੋਂ ਵੀ ਇਸ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨੂੰ ਸਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਸਾਰਾ ਸਮਾਨ ਜ਼ਮੀਨ ਤੇ ਹੀ ਰੱਖਣਾ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।2. ਨਵੀਂ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੀਆਂ ਰਸੋਈਆਂ – ਵਿਗਿਆਨ ਨੇ ਤਰੱਕੀ ਨਾਲ ਨਵੇਂ-ਨਵੇਂ ਉਪਕਰਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਾਢ ਹੋਈ ਅਤੇ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਨਾਲ ਕੰਮ ਸੌਖੇ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ ਅਤੇ ਘੱਟ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੋਣ ਲੱਗ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ । ਸਮੇਂ ਅਤੇ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ ਦੀ ਬੱਚਤ ਹੋ ਸਕੇ ਇਸ ਲਈ ਨਵੇਂ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੀਆਂ ਰਸੋਈਆਂ ਬਣਨ ਲੱਗ ਗਈਆਂ ਹਨ । ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਖੜੇ ਖੜੇ ਹੀ ਸਾਰੇ ਕੰਮ ਕਰ ਲਏ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਬਾਰ-ਬਾਰ ਉੱਠਣ ਬੈਠਣ ਲਈ ਸਮਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ ਵਿਅਰਥ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾਂਦੇ । ਫਰਿਜ਼ ਲਈ ਆਮ ਕਰਕੇ ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਥਾਂ ਬਣਾ ਲਈ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਜੋ ਸ਼ੈਲਫ਼ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਉਸ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਪੰਜ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੀਆਂ ਰਸੋਈਆਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ-    -ਇਕ ਦੀਵਾਰ ਵਾਲੀ .    -ਦੋ ਦੀਵਾਰਾਂ ਵਾਲੀ    -ਐੱਲ (L) ਸ਼ਕਲ ਵਾਲੀ    -ਯੂ. (U) ਸ਼ੇਕਲੇ ਵਾਲੀ    -ਟੁੱਟਿਆ ਯੂ. (U) ਸ਼ਕਲ ਵਾਲੀ ।"},{"question":"Sheeg Qofkii Ugu Horeeyey Ee Islaamka U Hijrooda?","answer":"Qofkii Ugu Horeeyey Ee Islaamka U Hijrooda Waa Cusmaan Bin Cafaan Iyo Rukhiya Muxammed RC."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Ny fitiavana vary ahahy  .................................... \\" ","answer":"Toy izao ny ohabolana feno: \\" Ny fitiavana vary ahahy ka maina vao alanona \\" "},{"question":"এই অনুচ্ছেদের জন্য একটি ধারাবাহিকতা লিখুন :এদেশের স্বাধিকার আন্দোলন ও মুক্তিযুদ্ধে অসাধারণ অবদানের জন্য ২০১৬ সালে ","answer":" দেশের “সর্বোচ্চ বেসামরিক পুরস্কার” হিসাবে পরিচিত “স্বাধীনতা পুরস্কার” প্রদান করা হয় তাকে।"},{"question":"Wọn yinbọn pa adari ileeṣẹ ijọba ibilẹ l’Ekiti","answer":"Inu ibẹru nla lawọn eeyan adugbo Umesi, lagbegbe Igirigiri, niluu Ado-Ekiti, wa di asiko yii pẹlu bi awọn agbebọn kan ṣe pa ọkan lara awọn adari ileeṣẹ ijọba ibilẹ nipinlẹ Ekiti, Ọgbẹni David Jejelowo, sinu ile ẹ.ALAROYE gbọ pe ni nnkan bii aago kan oru ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii niṣẹlẹ naa waye, bẹẹ ni ko sẹni to mọ boya awọn adigunjale ni tabi awọn agbanipa.Nigba to n ba ALAROYE sọrọ lori iṣẹlẹ naa, Alukoro ọlọpaa Ekiti, Sunday Abutu, sọ pe loootọ ni wọn yinbọn pa ọkunrin naa, inu yara ẹ gan-an ni wọn si ṣeku pa a si. O ni ko sẹni to mọ nnkan to ṣẹlẹ ki iṣẹlẹ naa too waye, eyi si ni afojusun iwadii ọlọpaa.O ni, ‘‘Titi di asiko yii, a ko mọ idi ti wọn fi pa ọkunrin naa, bakan naa ni ko sẹni to mọ awọn to ṣiṣẹ ọhun, ṣugbọn nnkan ta a le fidi ẹ mulẹ ni pe wọn yinbọn pa a ni.’’Abutu sọ ọ di mimọ pe wọn ti gbe oku oloogbe naa lọ si mọṣuari ileewosan ẹkọṣẹ Faisiti Ekiti (EKSUTH) to wa niluu Ado-Ekiti."},{"question":"Байламта","answer":"Байламталар – өз алдынча турганда лексикалык маани билдирбеген, сүйлөммүчөсүнүн милдетин аткарбаган, сөз менен сөздү же сүйлөм менен сүйлөмдү бири \\u0002бири менен байланыштырган кызматчы сөздөр. Мисалы: ары, да, же, дагы, анткени. "},{"question":"问题：三星耳机是什么？","answer":"答案：三星耳机是由韩国公司三星电子生产的音频设备，用于聆听音乐和通话。"},{"question":"కుతుబ్షాహీలు సాధించిన విజయాలను వివరించండి.","answer":"గోల్కొండ రాజధానిగా స్వతంత్ర కుతుబ్షాహీ వంశాధికారాన్ని క్రీ. శ. 1512లో సుల్తాన్-కులీ-కుతుబ్-ఉల్- ముల్క్ స్థాపించాడు. బహమనీ సుల్తాన్ మూడో మహమ్మద్ షా కాలంలో ఆ రాజ్య విచ్ఛిన్నం జరిగింది. అహమద్ నగర్, బీజాపూర్, బీదర్, బీరార్, గోల్కొండ అనే ఐదు స్వతంత్ర రాజ్యాలు బహమనీ రాజ్య శిథిలాలపై వెలిశాయి. గోల్కొండ కుతుబ్షాహీలు వారి అధికారులు స్థానిక తెలుగు ప్రజల మద్దతుతో, సుమారు 175 ఏళ్ళపాటు నేడు తెలుగు మాట్లాడే అత్యధిక ప్రాంతాలనూ, కన్నడ, మరాఠి మాట్లాడే కొన్ని ప్రాంతాలను పరిపాలించారు. సుప్రసిద్ధ చరిత్రకారులైన హరూన్-ఖాన్-షేర్వానీ, నేలటూరి వేంకటరమణయ్య మొదలైన వారు కుతుబ్షాహీలు అత్యంత ప్రజాసేవాతత్పరత కలిగిన పాలకులనీ, వారు ముస్లింలు అయినప్పటికీ హిందూ ప్రజలను, వారి ఆచారాలను, సంస్కృతిని గౌరవించారనీ, వీరిలో కొందరు తెలుగు భాషలో మంచి పాండిత్యం సంపాదించారనీ, వారు తెలుగు ప్రజల సర్వతోముఖాభివృద్ధికి కృషిచేశారనీ ప్రశంసించారు. కుతుబ్షాహీ సుల్తానుల్లో సుల్తాన్-కులీ-కుతుబ్షా (క్రీ.శ. 1512 – 1543), ఇబ్రహీం కుతుబ్షా (క్రీ.శ. 1550-1580), మహమ్మద్-కులీ-కుతుబ్షా (క్రీ.శ. 1580-1612) సుప్రసిద్ధులు.ఆధారాలు: కుతుబ్షాహీ సుల్తానుల పరిపాలనా కాలానికి సంబంధించిన వివిధ అంశాల గురించి సమకాలీన ముస్లిం చరిత్రకారుల రచనలు, విదేశీ బాటసారుల రచనలు, కుతుబ్షాహీ సుల్తానులు జారీ చేసిన ఫర్మానాలు, సమకాలీన తెలుగు సాహిత్యం ఎంతో అమూల్యమైన సమాచారాన్ని తెలియచేస్తున్నాయి. ముస్లిం చరిత్రకారుల రచనల్లోఫెరిస్టా రాసిన గుల్షన్-ఇ-ఇబ్రహీమి, ఖదీరాఖాన్ రాసిన తారీఖ్-ఇ-కుతుబ్షాహీ, సయ్యద్ అలీ-టబాటబీ రచన, బుర్హన్-ఇ-మాసిర్, అజ్ఞాత చరిత్రకారుడు రాసిన తారీఖ్-ఇ-సుల్తాన్ మహమ్మద్ షాహీ పేర్కొనదగినవి. ఈ రచనల్లో సుల్తానుల కాలం నాటి రాజకీయ చరిత్ర, పరిపాలన వ్యవస్థ, సామాజిక, ఆర్థిక, సంస్కృత రచనల్లో, అద్దంకి గంగాధరుడు రాసిన ‘తపతీ సంవరణోపాఖ్యానం’, పొనగంటి తెలగనార్యుని రచన యయాతి చరిత్ర, మట్ల అనంతభూపాలుని రచన కుకుత్స విజయం, సారంగతమ్మయ్య రచన ‘వైజయంతీ విలాసం’, భద్రాద్రి శతకం, సింహాద్రి శతకం, భతృహరీ శతకం, కదిరీఫతీ రాసిన ‘హంసవింసతి’, అయ్యలరాజు నారాయణామాత్రుడు రాసిన సుకసప్తతి, వేమన పద్యాలు ఆనాటి ప్రజాజీవనాన్ని వర్ణిస్తున్నాయి. కుతుబ్షాహీల రాజధాని గోల్కొండ, కొత్త నగరం హైద్రాబాద్, దక్కన్లోని ఇతర నగరాలను, ప్రాంతాలను సందర్శించిన విదేశీ బాటసారులైన ఫ్రాన్స్ దేశస్థులైన టావెర్నియర్, బెర్నియర్, థీవ్నాట్, విలియం మాథోల్డ్ రష్యాకు చెందిన నిఖిటిన్ మొదలైన వారు ఈ యుగానికి చెందిన వివిధ విషయాలను తమ డైరీలలో, రచనల్లో పేర్కొన్నారు. ఇవి కుతుబ్షాహీల యుగచరిత్ర రచనకు ఎంతో అమూల్య సమాచారాన్ని అందచేస్తున్నాయి.సుల్తాన్-కులీ-కుతుబ్-ఉల్-ముల్క్: స్వతంత్ర కుతుబ్షాహీ రాజ్య స్థాపకుడు సుల్తాన్-కులీ-కుతుబ్-ఉల్- ముల్క్. ఇతడు బహమనీల కొలువులో కొంతకాలం పనిచేశాడు. తెలంగాణా తరఢారుగా పనిచేశాడు. మూడో మహమ్మద్ షా పరిపాలన చివరి దశలో చెలరేగిన తిరుగుబాట్లతో ప్రేరేపితుడై క్రీ.శ. 1512లో స్వతంత్ర్యాన్ని ప్రకటించుకున్నాడు. ఇతడు సమకాలీన విజయనగర, గజపతి రాజులతో అనేక యుద్ధాలు చేశాడు. ఇతడు గోల్కొండ దుర్గాన్ని బలోపేతం చేయించాడు. అనేక మసీదులు, రాజప్రసాదాలు, భవనాలు నిర్మించాడు. గోల్కొండకు సమీపంలో ‘మహమ్మద్ నగర్’ అనే కొత్త పట్టణాన్ని కట్టించాడు. అతణ్ణి అధికారులు, ప్రజలు అభిమానించారు. 99వ యేట కుమారుడి (జంషీద్) చేతిలో హత్యచేయబడ్డాడు. ఇతని కాలంలోనే గోల్కొండ రాజ్యం దక్కన్లోనే కాక సమకాలీన ప్రపంచంలో విశేష ఖ్యాతి గడించింది.జంషీద్-కులీ-కుతుబ్షా (క్రీ.శ. 1543-1550): ఇతడు సుల్తాన్-కులీ మూడో కుమారుడు. స్వార్థపరుడు. కుట్రలకు పెద్ద వ్యూహకర్త. సొంత తండ్రినే అధికార దాహంతో హత్యచేసి సింహాసనం అధిష్టించి ఏడేళ్ళు పరిపాలన చేశాడు. ప్రజలు, అధికారులు ఇతని చర్యను ఏవగించుకున్నారు. మంచి పాండిత్యం కలవాడు. కవిత్వం రాసేవాడు. క్రీ.శ. 1550లో వ్యాధిగ్రస్తుడై మరణించాడు.సుఖాన్-కులీ-కుతుబ్షా: జంషీద్ మరణానంతరం ఏడేళ్ళ పిన్నవయస్కుడైన అతని కుమారుణ్ణి అతని తల్లి, మంత్రులు గోల్కొండ సింహాసనంపై కూర్చోబెట్టి అధికారం చెలాయించారు. ఇతని పరిపాలన కేవలం ఏడు నెలలపాటు కొనసాగింది. రాజ్యంలో అంతరంగిక కలహాలు, సర్దారుల స్వార్థ రాజకీయాలు హద్దుమీరాయి. ఇలాంటి పరిస్థితుల్లో విజయనగర రాజ్యంలో అళియరామరాయల వద్ద శరణాగతునిగా ఉన్న ఇబ్రహీం-కులీ-కుతుబ్షా, రామరాయల మద్దతుతో గోల్కొండ రాజ్య సింహాసనాన్ని క్రీ.శ. 1550లో అధిష్టించాడు. ఈ విధంగా సుబాన్ కులీ పాలన అంతమైంది.ఇబ్రహీం-కులీ-కుతుబ్షా (క్రీ.శ. 1550-1580): ఇతడు గోల్కొండ రాజ్య స్థాపకుడైన సుల్తాన్ కులీ చిన్న కుమారుడు. తన సోదరుడైన జంషీద్ పన్నిన కుట్ర నుంచి ప్రాణాలతో తప్పించుకొని క్రీ.శ.1543లో విజయగనర రాజ్యం పారిపోయి అళియ రామరాయల శరణు పొందాడు. అక్కడే ఏడేళ్ళపాటు గడిపాడు. రామరాయలు ఇతణ్ణి సొంత కొడుకులా ఆదరించాడు. తెలుగు భాషలో మంచి పాండిత్యం సంపాదించాడు. క్రీ.శ. 1550లో గోల్కొండ సుల్తానుగా సింహాసనం అధిష్టించిన ఇబ్రహీం-కులీ-కుతుబ్షా ప్రజా బలంతో 30 సంవత్సరాలపాటు సమర్థవంతంగా పరిపాలన చేశాడు. ఇతడు రాజ్య విస్తరణ కోసం సోదర షియా సుల్తానులతో, విజయనగర రాజులతో అనేక యుద్ధాలు చేశాడు. అళియ రామరాయల విభజించి పాలించు దౌత్యనీతికి ఇతడు నష్టపోయాడు. గత సహాయాన్ని విస్మరించి విజయనగర చక్రవర్తికి వ్యతిరేకంగా వైవాహిక సంబంధాల ద్వారా బీజాపూర్, అహమద్ నగర్ సుల్తానులను, బీరార్, బీదర్ సుల్తానులను ఐక్యం చేశాడు. చారిత్రాత్మక రాక్షసి తంగడి యుద్ధం (జనవరి 23, 1565)లో విజయగనరం సేనాధిపతియైన ఆళియ రామరాయలను మోసంతో దెబ్బతీశాడు. రాత్రిపూట సంప్రదింపుల సాకుతో వారి శిబిరంపై దాడిచేయించాడు. 80 ఏళ్ళ వయస్సులో రామరాయలు విరోచితంగా పోరాడి ఓడాడు. హుస్సేన్-నిజాం షా రామరాయల తలను ఖండించి యుద్దభూమిలో పగ తీర్చుకొన్నాడు. దీంతో విజయనగర సేనలు చిన్నాభిన్నమయ్యాయి. ఇతని పాలనలో గోల్కొండ రాజ్యం కీర్తి నలుదిశలా వ్యాపించింది. ఆర్థికంగా, సైనికంగా గోల్కొండ రాజ్యం బలోపేతమైంది. ఇతడు వ్యవసాయాభివృద్ధికై అనేక చెరువులు, కాలువలు నిర్మించాడు. వీటిలో పేర్కొనదగ్గవి హుస్సేన్ సాగర్ చెరువు, ఇబ్రహీంపట్నం చెరువు. రైతాంగం సుఖసంతోషాలతో ఉండేది. స్వదేశీ, విదేశీ వ్యాపారం అభివృద్ధి చెందింది. గోల్కొండ వస్త్రాలు, వజ్రాలు యూరోపియన్ రాజ్యాల్లో మంచి పేరు పొందాయి. సాహిత్యం, కళలు ఇతని పోషణలో వికసించాయి. ఇతడు క్రీ.శ. 1580లో మరణించాడు.మహమ్మద్ కులీ-కుతుబ్షా (క్రీ.శ. 1580-1612): ఇబ్రహీం-కులీ-కుతుబ్షా మరణానంతరం అతని సోదరుడైన (సుల్తాన్-కులీ-మూడో కుమారుడు) మహమ్మద్-కులీ-కుతుబ్షా పదిహేను ఏళ్ళ పిన్నవయస్సులో గోల్కొండ రాజ్య సింహాసనం అధిష్టించాడు. ఇతడు దక్కన్ ముస్లిం పాలకుల్లో అత్యంత ప్రతిభావంతుడిగా కీర్తిగడించాడు. గొప్ప పరిపాలనాదక్షుడు. సైన్యాలను నడపడంలో దిట్ట. సాహిత్యప్రియుడు, గొప్ప కట్టడాల నిర్మాత. హైద్రాబాద్ నగరం ఇతని నిర్మాణమే. చార్మినార్, జామామసీద్, చందన్ మహల్ కూడా ఇతడే నిర్మించాడు. ఇతడు ఇబ్రహీం మాదిరిగానే తెలుగు భాషను ఆదరించాడు. అరబిక్, పర్షియన్, ఉర్దు భాషలతో సమానంగా తెలుగుభాష పురోగతి చెందింది. స్థానిక ప్రజల సంప్రదాయాలను, ఆచారాలను, పద్ధతులను గౌరవించాడు. ప్రజా సంక్షేమాన్ని కోరి పరిపాలించాడు. క్రీ.శ. 1612లో 32 ఏళ్ళ సుదీర్ఘ పాలన తరువాత మరణించాడు. ఇతడి ఏకైక కుమార్తె హయత్-బక్ష్-బేగం. ఈమె భర్త సుల్తాన్ మహ్మద్ కుతుబ్షా గోల్కొండ చరిత్రలో మహమ్మద్ కులీ-కుతుబ్షా పరిపాలనా కాలం ఒక చారిత్రక ఘట్టం.సుల్తాన్ మహమ్మద్-కులీ-కుతుబ్షా (క్రీ.శ.1612-1626): మహ్మమద్ కులీ-కుతుబ్షా మరణానంతరం అతని మేనల్లుడు, అల్లుడైన సుల్తాన్ మహమ్మద్ కులీ కుతుబ్షా గోల్కొండ సుల్తానుగా బాధ్యతలు చేపట్టాడు. ఇతడు గొప్ప పండితుడు. ఇతనికి మత సంప్రదాయాల పట్ల అభిమానం ఎక్కువ. అధిక సమయం పండితులతో చర్చల్లో గడిపేవాడు. క్రీ.శ. 1617లో హైద్రాబాద్ నగరంలో మక్కామసీదు నిర్మాణానికి ఇతడే పునాది వేశాడు. దీని నిర్మాణం డైబ్బైఏడేళ్ళ పాటు కొనసాగింది. క్రీ.శ 1687 లో గోల్కొండ రాజ్యాన్ని ఆక్రమించిన మొగల్ చక్రవర్తి ఔరంగజేబ్ మక్కామసీద్ నిర్మాణాన్ని 1694లో పూర్తిచేశాడు. ఇతడే సుల్తాన్ నగరాన్ని నిర్మించాడు.అబ్దుల్లా-కుతుబ్షా (క్రీ.శ.1626 – 1672): ఇతడు సుల్తాన్ మహమ్మద్ కుమారుడు. పన్నెండు ఏళ్ళ పిన్న వయస్సులో గోల్కొండ సింహాసనాన్ని అధిష్టించాడు. ఇతని తల్లి హయత్-బక్ష్-బేగం రాజ్య వ్యవహారాలు నిర్వహించింది. ఇతడు విలాసవంతమైన జీవితాన్ని గడిపాడు. ఇతని కాలంలో మొగల్ దాడులు గోల్కొండ రాజ్యంపై తీవ్రతరమయ్యాయి. పరాజయం పొందిన గోల్కొండ సుల్తాన్ మొగల్ చక్రవర్తికి కప్పం చెల్లించి అధికారం కొనసాగించాడు. ఇతడు క్రీ.శ.1672లో మరణించాడు.అబుల్హాసన్ తానాషా (క్రీ.శ.1672–1687): కుతుబ్షాహీ సుల్తానుల్లో అబుల్హసన్ తానాషా చివరివాడు. ఇతడు అబ్దుల్లా కుతుబ్షా అల్లుడు. ఇతడి పదిహేను ఏళ్ళ పరిపాలనా కాలంలో కుతుబ్షాహీ రాజ్యంపై మొగల్ చక్రవర్తి సేనలు నిరంతర దాడులు చేశాయి. దీనివల్ల కుతుబ్షాహీ రాజ్య ఆర్థిక వ్యవస్థ చిన్నాభిన్నమైంది. ఇతడి పాలనలో ప్రజలు సుఖశాంతులతో జీవించారు. ఇతడు పరమత సహనం ప్రదర్శించాడు. ఔరంగజేబ్ సామ్రాజ్య కాంక్షకు అబుల్హాసన్ రాజ్యం బలైంది. సుమారు ఎనిమిది నెలలపాటు ధైర్యసాహసాలతో మొగల్ సేనలను కుతుబ్షాహీ సేనలు ఎదుర్కొన్నాయి. పరాజితుడైన సుల్తాన్ను మొగల్ సేనలు బందీగా బీదర్, దౌలతాబాద్లలో పన్నెండు ఏళ్ళపాటు ఉంచారు. క్రీ.శ. 1690లో చివరి కుతుబ్షాహీ సుల్తాన్ బందీగా దౌలాతాబాద్లోనే మరణించాడు."},{"question":"అర్థశాస్త్రానికి, గణాంక శాస్త్రానికి ఉన్న సంబంధాన్ని వివరించండి.","answer":"గణాంక శాస్త్రానికి అనేక శాస్త్రాలతో సన్నిహిత సంబంధముంది. 19వ శతాబ్దం నుంచి గణాంక శాస్త్రం, అర్థశాస్త్రం చాలా సాన్నిహిత్యం పెంపొందించుకున్నాయి. అర్థశాస్త్ర విశ్లేషణ అధ్యయనంలో, సిద్ధాంత నిర్మాణంలో సాంప్రదాయ ఆర్థికవేత్తలు నిగమన పద్ధతిని ఉపయోగించేవారు. అయితే కాలక్రమేణా ఆర్థిక విషయాల పరిశీలనకు, అర్థశాస్త్రాన్ని అర్థం చేసుకోవడానికి గణాంకశాస్త్ర పరిజ్ఞానం అవసరమని J.S. మిల్, జీవాన్స్, కీన్స్ లాంటి ఆర్థికవేత్తలు పేర్కొన్నారు. అర్థశాస్త్ర సిద్ధాంతాలను యదార్థ జీవితానికి అన్వయించడానికి, న్యాయబద్ధతను నిర్ణయించడానికి ‘ఆగమన పద్ధతి’ ని ప్రవేశపెట్టడంతో గణాంక, అర్థశాస్త్రాలు సన్నిహితమవడం ప్రారంభమైంది. ‘జీవాన్స్’ సంఖ్యా దత్తాంశాన్ని ఉపయోగించి ‘కాలశ్రేణుల విశ్లేషణ’, సూచీ సంఖ్యల అధ్యయనం చేశారు.1704లో గ్రెగొరికింగ్ వస్తు సప్లయ్కి, వస్తువు ధరకు ఉన్న సంబంధాన్ని గణాంకాల రూపంలో నిరూపించడానికి ప్రయత్నం చేశాడు. బౌలే, పియర్సన్, W.I. కింగ్, ఫిషర్ మొదలైన గణాంకవేత్తలు తమ సేవలతో గణాంకశాస్త్రాన్ని, అర్థశాస్త్రానికి మరింత చేరువ చేశారు.అర్థశాస్త్ర విశ్లేషణ అంతా గణాంక దత్తాంశంపై పూర్తిగా ఆధారపడి ఉంటుంది. పేదరికం, నిరుద్యోగం, ధరల పెరుగుదల మొదలైన ఆర్థిక సమస్యల స్వభావం, స్వరూపం, గణాంక వివరాలు లేకుండా తెలుసుకోవడం సాధ్యం కాదు. ఆర్థిక సమస్యలన్నీ గణాంక పద్ధతుల ద్వారా పరిశీలించడం జరుగుతుంది.ఆర్థిక విశ్లేషణలో సాంఖ్యక వివరాలు, పద్ధతులు చాలా శక్తివంతమైన పరికరాలు. గణాంక శాస్త్రం అర్థశాస్త్రానికి ముఖ్యంగా ‘మూడు’ విధాలుగా ఉపయోగపడుతుంది.ఆర్థిక సమస్యలను క్షుణ్ణంగా తెలుసుకోవడానికి.ఆర్థిక సిద్ధాంతాలకు సాంఖ్యారూపమేర్పరచటం, ఆర్థిక సిద్ధాంతాల ఉపకల్పనలను  పరీక్ష చేయడం.ఆర్థిక సిద్ధాంతాల భవిష్యత్ అంచనాలను పరీక్షించడం.ఉదా : కీన్స్ ప్రతిపాదించిన వినియోగ ప్రవృత్తి సిద్ధాంతాన్ని, కూజెనట్స్ దత్తాంశాన్ని సేకరించి సంఖ్యారూప మేర్పరిస్తే దాని ఆధారంగా వినియోగ ప్రవృత్తి సిద్ధాంతాన్ని మార్పుచేసి డ్యూసెన్బెర్రీ, ఫ్రీడ్మన్ కొత్త రీతులలో ప్రతిపాదించారు."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਗੁਆਰੇਰੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਇਕਿ ਗਾਵਤ ਰਹੇ ਮਨਿ ਸਾਦੁ ਨ ਪਾਇ ॥ਹਉਮੈ ਵਿਚਿ ਗਾਵਹਿ ਬਿਰਥਾ ਜਾਇ ॥ਗਾਵਣਿ ਗਾਵਹਿ ਜਿਨ ਨਾਮ ਪਿਆਰੁ ॥ਸਾਚੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਸਬਦ ਬੀਚਾਰੁ ॥੧॥ਗਾਵਤ ਰਹੈ ਜੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਭਾਵੈ ॥ਮਨੁ ਤਨੁ ਰਾਤਾ ਨਾਮਿ ਸੁਹਾਵੈ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਇਕਿ ਗਾਵਹਿ ਇਕਿ ਭਗਤਿ ਕਰੇਹਿ ॥ਨਾਮੁ ਨ ਪਾਵਹਿ ਬਿਨੁ ਅਸਨੇਹ ॥ਸਚੀ ਭਗਤਿ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦ ਪਿਆਰਿ ॥ਅਪਨਾ ਪਿਰੁ ਰਾਖਿਆ ਸਦਾ ਉਰਿ ਧਾਰਿ ॥੨॥ਭਗਤਿ ਕਰਹਿ ਮੂਰਖ ਆਪੁ ਜਣਾਵਹਿ ॥ਨਚਿ ਨਚਿ ਟਪਹਿ ਬਹੁਤੁ ਦੁਖੁ ਪਾਵਹਿ ॥ਨਚਿਐ ਟਪਿਐ ਭਗਤਿ ਨ ਹੋਇ ॥ਸਬਦਿ ਮਰੈ ਭਗਤਿ ਪਾਏ ਜਨੁ ਸੋਇ ॥੩॥ਭਗਤਿ ਵਛਲੁ ਭਗਤਿ ਕਰਾਏ ਸੋਇ ॥ਸਚੀ ਭਗਤਿ ਵਿਚਹੁ ਆਪੁ ਖੋਇ ॥ਮੇਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਸਾਚਾ ਸਭ ਬਿਧਿ ਜਾਣੈ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਬਖਸੇ ਨਾਮੁ ਪਛਾਣੈ ॥੪॥੪॥੨੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 158 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਮਨੁੱਖ ਐਸੇ ਹਨ ਜੋ (ਭਗਤੀ ਦੇ ਗੀਤ) ਗਾਂਦੇ (ਤਾਂ) ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ (ਪਰ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ) ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਕੋਈ ਆਨੰਦ ਪੈਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਭਗਤ ਹੋਣ ਦੀ)ਹਉਮੈ ਵਿਚ (ਭਗਤੀ ਦੇ ਗੀਤ) ਗਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ (ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਇਹ ਉੱਦਮ) ਵਿਅਰਥ ਚਲਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।(ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੇ ਗੀਤ) ਅਸਲ ਵਿਚ ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ ਹੈ,ਜੇਹੜੇ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਦਾ, ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦਾ ਵਿਚਾਰ (ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ) ।੧।ਜੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਚੰਗਾ ਲੱਗੇ (ਜੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰੇ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਦਾ ਸਦਕਾ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਆਇਆ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ,ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮਨ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਤਨ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਜੀਵਨ ਸੋਹਣਾ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਕਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਐਸੇ ਹਨ ਜੋ (ਭਗਤੀ ਦੇ ਗੀਤ) ਗਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਰਾਸਾਂ ਪਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ,ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੰੁਦਾ ।ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਹੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਪਰਵਾਨ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਜੇਹੜੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ,ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਾ ਕੇ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ ।੨।ਮੂਰਖ ਲੋਕ ਰਾਸਾਂ ਪਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਭਗਤ ਪਰਗਟ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ,(ਉਹ ਮੂਰਖ ਰਾਸਾਂ ਪਾਣ ਵੇਲੇ) ਨੱਚ ਨੱਚ ਕੇ ਟੱਪਦੇ ਹਨ (ਪਰ ਅੰਤਰ ਆਤਮੇ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਦੇ ਥਾਂ) ਦੁਖ ਹੀ ਦੁਖ ਪਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਨੱਚਣ ਟੱਪਣ ਨਾਲ ਭਗਤੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ ।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਉਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜੇਹੜਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ (ਆਪਾ-ਭਾਵ ਵਲੋਂ, ਹਉਮੈ ਵਲੋਂ) ਮਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।(ਪਰ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਕੀਹ ਵੱਸ ?) ਭਗਤੀ ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾਸਚੀ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ-ਮਈ ਸੇਵਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਗੁਆਉਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੈ।ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਢੰਗ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ (ਕਿ ਇਹ ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਾਂ ਪਖੰਡ) ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਸ਼ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਪਛਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ (ਨਾਮ ਨਾਲ) ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੪।੨੪।\\""},{"question":"पानी चक्र के हो?","answer":"जलचक्र भनेको महासागर र पानीका अन्य निकायहरूबाट पानी वाष्पीकरण हुने, बादल बन्ने र त्यसपछि पृथ्वीको पानीका स्रोतहरू भर्न वर्षा वा हिउँको रूपमा अवक्षेपण गर्ने निरन्तर प्रक्रिया हो।"},{"question":"యణాదేశసంధి గురించి వివరించి ఉదాహరణలు ఇవ్వండి.","answer":"యణాదేశసంధి :ఇ, ఉ, ఋలకు సవర్ణములు కాని అచ్చులు పరమగునపుడు క్రమముగా య, వ, ర, లు ఆదేశమగును.ఉదా :ప్రతి + ఏకము – ప్రత్యేకమువస్తు + ఐక్యము – వస్వైక్యముపితృ + అంశము – పిత్రంశముఅతి + అంత – అత్యంతఅభి + ఆగతులు – అభ్యాగతులుఅణు + ఆయుధాలు – అణ్వాయుధాలుఅతి + అద్భుతం – అత్యద్భుతం(ఇ + ఇ కాని అచ్చు – యఉ + ఉ కాని అచ్చు – వఋ + ఋ కాని అచ్చు – ర)"},{"question":" Iza avy ireo vondrom-poko ao atsinanana eto Madagasikara?","answer":"Ny Antambahoaka, ny Antefasy, ny Zafisoro, ny Antemoro, ny Antesaka, ny Tanala no vondrom-poko any atsinanana. Ny Antambahoaka dia foko iray ao atsimo-atsinanan' i Madagasikara, eo anelanelan' i Sakaleona sy Namorona. I Mananjary no tanan-dehibe any."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Chủ quan cho rằng đó chỉ là dấu hiệu khó tiêu và đau dạ dày gây nên, người bệnh chần chờ việc thăm khám mà tự mua thuốc về uống. Cho đến một ngày khi triệu chứng nuốt vướng xuất hiện rõ ràng hơn, người bệnh đi thăm khám ở một số bệnh viện tại Campuchia và được phát hiện một khối u máu ở thanh quản chèn ép gần hoàn toàn thanh quản. Cả gia đình lo lắng, hốt hoảng đưa người bệnh đi thăm khám tại nhiều bệnh viện lớn tại Campuchia nhưng bị từ chối. Được các bác sĩ tại Campuchia giới thiệu, người bệnh cùng gia đình tìm đến Việt Nam thăm khám tại Bệnh viện đa khoa Quốc tế Nam Sài Gòn. Ngày 31.7, ThS.BSCKII Nguyễn Trương Khương, Giám đốc Chuyên môn, Trưởng khoa Tai Mũi Họng, Bệnh viện đa khoa Quốc tế Nam Sài Gòn, cho biết qua thăm khám nội soi và đánh giá trên hình ảnh MRI, các bác sĩ phát hiện một khối u máu lớn chiếm gần toàn bộ thanh quản, u không có cuống và không quan sát được hai dây thanh quản. Được biết, trước đó người bệnh đã thay van tim cách đây 2 năm và đang sử dụng thuốc kháng đông máu thường xuyên. Sau khi hội chẩn kỹ lưỡng, các bác sĩ quyết định tiến hành phẫu thuật sớm lấy bỏ khối u để tránh nguy cơ khối u máu vỡ khiến tình trạnh người bệnh nguy kịch, không thể điều trị được. \\"Đây là một trường hợp hiếm gặp và tiên lượng cuộc phẫu thuật rất phức tạp, người bệnh có thể tử vong trong lúc mổ nếu có bất kỳ một sai sót nào\\", bác sĩ Khương chia sẻ. Theo bác sĩ Khương, có 3 vấn đề đặc biệt đặt ra cho ca phẫu thuật này. Thứ nhất, cần mở khí quản khéo léo, không gây co thắt thanh khí quản vì nếu xảy ra cũng không đặt nội khí quản được. Thứ 2, cần những dụng cụ phù hợp giúp bóc lộ và thao tác chính xác trong quá trình phẫu thuật. Thứ 3, tuyệt đối không làm chảy máu vì khi chảy máu sẽ không phẫu thuật được và người bệnh sẽ rơi vào tình trạng nguy kịch do sẽ cực kỳ khó cầm máu. Sau hơn 1 giờ phẫu thuật, bác sĩ Khương và ê kíp đã nhanh chóng bóc lộ khối u, thực hiện đốt, cắt và lấy trọn khối u thành công qua nội soi. Người bệnh hồi phục sau mổ tốt, nuốt được, hết đau họng, nói được, không gặp biến chứng gì và xuất viện sau 5 ngày phẫu thuật. Bác sĩ Khương nhận định, đây một trường hợp hiếm gặp, có nhiều khó khăn trong quá trình phẫu thuật. Do đó bệnh viện chuẩn bị một cách kỹ lưỡng cho các phương án có thể xảy ra. Trong đó, các vấn đề được đặt ra là đổi thuốc chống đông máu, dự trù máu trong phẫu thuật, dự trù mở màng giáp nhẫn cấp cứu nếu mở khí quản làm co thắt thanh khí quản. Đặc biệt hạn chế tối đa chảy máu trong lúc mổ, nếu có chảy máu, cần sử dụng các dụng cụ vừa hút, cũng như sẵn sàng phương án cột thắt các mạch máu chính ở vùng cổ. . \\"Với khối u nằm sâu trong cơ thể thì việc phát hiện sớm rất khó khăn. Ví dụ như khối u trong thanh quản của người bệnh nói trên, khi xuất hiện triệu chứng ban đầu còn dễ gây nhầm lẫn với những bệnh lý khác. Khi khối u gây những biến chứng rõ ràng thì tình trạng bệnh đã nặng. Vì vậy, nội soi tai mũi họng định kỳ là rất cần thiết giúp tầm soát bệnh và điều trị sớm\\", bác sĩ khuyến cáo.","answer":"Cứu bệnh nhân Campuchia bị khối u máu chiếm toàn bộ thanh quản hiếm gặp"},{"question":"සද මත පළමුවරට පිහිට වූයේ කුමන රටේ ධජයද?","answer":"සඳ මත සිය ධජය තැබූ පළමු රට එක්සත් ජනපදයයි. මෙය සිදු වූයේ 1969 ජූලි 20 වන දින ප්‍රථම මිනිසුන් සහිත සඳ ගොඩබෑම වූ ඇපලෝ 11 මෙහෙයුමේදීය. ගගනගාමීන් වන නීල් ආම්ස්ට්‍රෝං සහ බුස් ඕල්ඩ්‍රින් විසින් අභ්‍යවකාශ ගවේෂණයේ සැලකිය යුතු ජයග්‍රහණයක් සංකේතවත් කරමින් සඳ මතුපිට එක්සත් ජනපද ධජය රෝපණය කරන ලදී."},{"question":"Qual é o país que produz mais café no mundo?","answer":"Brasil"},{"question":"Lithetha ukuthini igama u\\"Lonwabo\\" nesilungu?","answer":"Joy"},{"question":"Magbigay ng halimbawa ng Python code na kino-convert ang kilometro sa milya.","answer":"Ang sumusunod na Python code ay kino-convert ang kilometro sa milya:kilometers = float(input(\\"Magbigay ng halaga sa kilometro: \\"))conv_fac = 0.621371miles = kilometers * conv_facprint('Ang %0.2f kilometro ay %0.2f na milya' %(kilometers,miles))"},{"question":"உழவுத் தொழிலின்  பெருமையைப்பற்றி ஒரு கட்டுரை வரைக.","answer":"முன்னுரை:\\"உழுதுண்டு வாழ்வாரே வாழ்வார் மற்றெல்லாம் தொழுதுண்டு பின்செல்பவர்\\" என்கிறார் திருவள்ளுவர். ஒவ்வொருவரும் ஒவ்வொரு கைப்பிடி உணவை உண்ணுவதற்கு அதில் ஒவ்வொரு விவசாயிகளினுடைய உழைப்பு தங்கியிருக்கும். ஆதலால் தான் உலகத்தில் பல தொழில்கள் இருந்தாலும் உழவுத் தொழில் தலைசிறந்த தொழிலாக காணப்படுகிறது. இது வரைக்கும் விளம்பரத்தில் ஈடுபடாத ஒரே தொழில் விவசாயம் தான் ஏனென்றால் விவசாயம் தொழில் அல்ல எமது உயிர்நாடி. உலகத்தின் ஒவ்வொரு உயிர்களுக்கும் பசி என்ற உணர்வு இருக்கும் வரை விவசாயம் அழியாது.இக்கட்டுரையில் விவசாயத்தின் முக்கியத்துவம், விவசாயத்தில் இன்று காணப்படும் பிரச்சனைகள், விவசாயத்தை பாதுகாக்க எடுக்க வேண்டிய நடவடிக்கைகள் போன்றன நோக்கப்படுகின்றன.உழவு இல்லையேல் உணவு இல்லை:இங்கே யாரும் உழவில்லை யாரும் விதைக்கவில்லை யாரும் வியர்வை சிந்தி நெல்மணிகளை விதைவிக்கவில்லை என்றால் நாம் உணவிற்கு எங்கே போவது? சற்று சிந்தியுங்கள். \\"விவசாயி சேற்றில் கால்வைத்தால் தான் நாம் இங்கே சோற்றில் கை வைக்க முடியும்\\". விவசாயம் ஒன்றும் அத்தனை இலகுவான தொழில் கிடையாது. கஷ்ரப்பட்டு நிலத்தை உழுது பண்படுத்தி வியர்வை சிந்தி பயிரிட்டு அதனை நீர் பாய்ச்சி பாதுகாத்து பசளையிட்டு நோய்களில் இருந்து காப்பாற்றி வெய்யிலில் காய்ந்து மழையில் நனைந்து விலங்குகள் பறவைகளில் இருந்து பயிரை காக்க காவல் இருந்து அறுவடை செய்யும் வரை விவசாயி பாடுபட்டு உழைத்தால் தான் விளைச்சலை பெற முடிகிறது. இந்த கஷ்டங்களைப் பொருட்படுத்தாது மீண்டும் மீண்டும் அவர்கள் உழைத்து கொண்டிருப்பதால் தான் இவ்வுலகமே இயங்கி கொண்டிருக்கிறது என்றால் ஆச்சரியப்படுவதற்கில்லை. இதனையே திருவள்ளுவர் \\"சுழன்றும் ஏர்ப்பின்னது உலகம் அதனால் உழன்றும் உழவே தலை\\" என்கிறார்.விவசாயத்தின் முக்கியத்துவம்:விவசாயம் என்பது ஒரு நாட்டினுடைய முதுகெலும்பு என்று கூறுவார்கள். ஒரு நாடு பொருளாதாரத்தில் தன்னிறைவு காணவேண்டுமாயின் அங்குள்ள மக்களுக்கு போதிய உணவு கிடைக்க வேண்டும். அப்போது தான் அந்த தேசம் உத்வேகத்துடன் இயங்க முடியும். பஞ்சம், பசி, பட்டினி என்பன இல்லாத தேசம் ஒன்று உருவாக வேண்டும் என்றால் அந்நாடு விவசாயத்தில் உச்சநிலை பெற வேண்டும். இல்லாவிடில் அந்த நாடு வளர்ச்சி பெறுவதென்பது இயலாத காரியமாகும். உலகத்தின் வளர்ச்சி அடைகின்ற, அடைந்த எல்லா தேசங்களும் விவசாயத்திற்கு அதிக முக்கியத்துவம் கொடுத்ததால் தான் அவை தன்னிறைவடைந்து காணப்படுகின்றன.விவசாயத்தில் காணப்படும் பிரச்சனைகள்:முன்பு குறிப்பிட்டதனை போல தலைசிறந்த நாடுகள் தமது நாட்டின் விவசாயிகளை ஊக்குவிக்கின்றது. அவர்களது உற்பத்திகளை தாமே கொள்வனவு செய்கிறது. விவசாய உற்பத்திகளை முடிவு பொருட்களாக தனது தொழில்நுட்பங்கள் மூலமாக உற்பத்தி செய்து தனது உள்நாட்டு நுகர்வுக்கு பயன்படுத்தி எஞ்சியவற்றை சர்வதேசத்துக்கும் ஏற்றுமதி செய்கின்றது. ஆனால் நம்முடைய வளர்முக நாடுகள் அவ்வாறில்லை முதலாளிகளின் கையிலே விவசாயம் உள்ளது. அதிகளவான நிலமும் வசதி படைத்தவர்களிடமே உள்ளது. சாதாரண ஏழை விவசாயிகள் கடன் பட்டு தான் விவசாயம் செய்ய வேண்டிய நிலையானது இருக்கின்றது.இயற்கை காரணிகளால் பயிர் சேதமடைந்தால் அவற்றுக்கான நஷ்ட ஈடுகளும் கிடைப்பது இல்லை. உற்பத்தி செய்யும் விவசாய பொருட்களுக்கு தனியார் தரகர்களே விலை நிர்ணயம் செய்கிறார்கள். குறைவான விலைக்கு கொள்வனவு செய்து மக்களுக்கு அதிக விலைக்கு விற்பனை செய்து முதலாளிகள் அதிக இலாபம் ஈட்ட விவசாயிகளும் சாதாரண மக்களும் மோசமாக பாதிக்கப்படுகின்றனர். இந்தியாவில் விவசாயிகள் பல வருடங்களாக விவசாயம் செய்ய முடியாது கடன் சுமையால் தற்கொலை செய்வது மனதை உடைக்கும் துயர நிகழ்வுகளாகும். இவ்வாறு பல பிரச்சனைகள் இன்றைய விவசாயத்தில் காணப்படுகின்றன.விவசாயத்தை பாதுகாக்க எடுக்க வேண்டிய நடவடிக்கைகள்:விவசாயம் செய்பவர்கள் இன்று குறைந்த வண்ணமே இருக்கிறது. மீண்டும் மீண்டும் எத்துயர் வரினும் தம் உடலை வருத்தி எமக்காக போராடும் விவசாயிகளை பாதுகாக்க அரசாங்கம் முழுமனதாக திட்டங்களை வகுக்கவேண்டும். விவசாயத்தில் ஊழல் செய்வோரை சிறையில் அடைக்கவேண்டும். விவசாய உற்பத்திகளை அரசாங்கமே கொள்வனவு செய்ய வேண்டும். விவசாய உற்பத்திகளிற்கு மிகச் சரியான கொள்வனவு விலை, விற்பனை விலைகளை நிர்ணயிக்க வேண்டும். விவசாயத்திற்கு வேண்டிய உள்ளீட்டு வசதிகள் தொழில்நுட்பங்கள் என்பவற்றை மேம்படுத்தல். விவசாயிகளுக்குரிய காப்புறுதி ஆதரவுகளையும் உரிய மரியாதையையும் கிடைக்க செய்தல். இவை போன்ற நடவடிக்கைகளால் விவசாயத்தை பாதுகாக்க முடியும்.முடிவுரை:உணவு உற்பத்தி எனும் விடயம் உலகத்தில் எத்தனை தொழில்நுட்பங்கள் உருவானாலும் அதற்குரிய மதிப்பு என்றும் குறையாது. சனத்தொகை பெருக்கம் பெருக்கல் விருத்தியில் பெருகி வருவதால் உணவு உற்பத்தி அதற்கேற்ப இல்லாவிடின் உலகமே பாரிய பிரச்சனைகளில் சிக்கி விடும். விவசாயிகள் அனுபவிக்கும் துன்பங்களை கண்டுகொள்ளாது அவர்களுக்காய் குரல் கொடுக்காமல் விட்டால் இங்குள்ள அனைவரும் உணவின்றி இறக்க நேரிடும். அனைவரும் உயிர் வாழ வேண்டுமென்றால் உழவுத்தொழிலைக் காக்க அனைவரும் முன்வரவேண்டும்."},{"question":"కింది పేరాను చదివి ఐదు ప్రశ్నలు తయారు చేయండి. గోదావరి నదికి ఇరువైపులా ఉన్న ఆదిలాబాద్, కరీంనగర్ జిల్లాల్లోని గిరిజనులు, వారి ఆధ్వర్యంలో రైతులు, పూజించే దేవుళ్ళు చిన్నయ్య, పెద్దయ్య, “చిన్నయ్య, పెద్దయ్య / చిలుకల భీమయ్య” అని స్థానికంగా వినిపించే జానపద గేయంలో చిన్నయ్య అంటే అర్జునుడు. పెద్దయ్య అంటే ధర్మరాజు. వారితో కూడిన భీముడ్ని పూజిస్తారు. అని స్పష్టమవుతుంది. భీముడ్ని ప్రత్యేకంగా కొలవడానికి కారణముంది. పాండవులు వనవాసం చేస్తూ, ఇక్కడికి వచ్చినపుడు ఇక్కడి గిరిజన అమ్మాయి హిడింబిని భీముడు పెళ్ళిచేసుకొని, ఆ స్థానిక గిరిజనులకు ఆరాధ్య దైవమయ్యాడు.","answer":"ప్రశ్నలుగోదావరి నదికి ఇరువైపులా ఉన్న జిల్లాలు ఏవి ?గిరిజనులూ, వారి ఆధ్వర్యంలో రైతులూ పూజించే దేవుళ్ళు ఎవరు ?స్థానికంగా వినిపించే గేయం ఏది ?పెద్దయ్య, చిన్నయ్య అంటే ఎవరు ?గిరిజనులకు భీముడు ఎందుకు ఆరాధ్య దైవమయ్యాడు ?"},{"question":"Zadzisa dimikara rinotevera:Anokotsira nebadza mumawoko","answer":"aneusimbe"},{"question":"Londra Zone 1 neresi?","answer":"themes nehrinin hemen kuzeyindeki dikdortgen bolge, \\"central london\\" alarak bilinir ve burasi zone 1 olarak gecer."},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"மனிதனுக்கு எல்லாவற்றையும் விட முக்கியமான உணர்ச்சியாக, மான-அவமானம் என்னும் தன்மானமாகிய சுயமரியாதையைத் தான் பிறப்புரிமையாகக் கொள்ள வேண்டியிருக்கின்றது. மனிதனுக்குப் பிறப்புரிமை சுயமரியாதைதான்."},{"question":"ما عاصمة إيران ؟","answer":"طهران"},{"question":"Ahitsio ny tsipelina diso amin'ity fehezanteny ity:\\" Ny atao hoe hanim-pitoloha dia karazana sakafo fito noanina nandritra ny « fandroana » sy ny taom-baovao malagasy tamin’ny andron’ny faha mpanjaka.\\" .","answer":"Indro ny fehezanteny voahitsy tsipelina:\\" Ny atao hoe hanim-pitoloha dia karazana sakafo fito nohanina nandritra ny « fandroana » sy ny taom-baovao malagasy tamin’ny andron’ny faha mpanjaka. \\" ."},{"question":"\\"చినకొట్ల గ్రామ విస్తీర్ణం ఎంత?\\"Text: ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన ముదిగుబ్బ నుండి 34 కి. మీ. దూరం లోను, సమీప పట్టణమైన ధర్మవరం నుండి 34 కి. మీ. దూరంలోనూ ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 310 ఇళ్లతో, 1164 జనాభాతో 1767 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 590, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 574. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 106 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 0. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 595188[2].పిన్ కోడ్: 515631.","answer":"1767 హెక్టార్ల"},{"question":"Chisinau mooy gëblag man réew?","answer":"Chisinau mooy gëblag réewum Moldavie."},{"question":" Em que ano estreou o filme ","answer":"Em 1997."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'licin kerana minyak berminta'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud sindiran untuk merendahkan orang yang angkuh kerana barang yang dipinjam"},{"question":"Що таке шпихлір?","answer":"Громадські шпихліри (\\"хлібозапасні магазини\\", \\"гамазеї\\") будувались в Україні на випадок неврожаїв, воєн, пожеж. Найчастіше це були зрубні будинки, споруджені з високоякісного дерева і поставлені на високі штандари (дубові або соснові колоди). Іван Франко у статті \\"Громадські шпихліри і шпихліровий фонд у Галичині 1784-1840 рр.\\" докладно роз­повідає про заснування і утримашІя їх на Галичині."},{"question":"Se Patrícia é madrasta de Bruno, então é correto afirmar que...","answer":"Bruno é enteado de Patrícia."},{"question":"ඉන්දියාවේ ජාතික පලතුර නම් කරන්න.","answer":"ඉන්දියාවේ ජාතික පලතුර වන්නේ අඹ ය. ඉන්දියාවේ පමණක් අඹ විශේෂ සියයකට අධික ප්‍රමාණයක් දක්නට ලැබෙන අතර, ලොව විශාලතම අඹ නිෂ්පාදකයා වන්නේ ද ඉන්දියාව යි."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన ప్రశ్నకు జవాబు ఇవ్వండి: జపాన్‌పై అణుబాంబు ఎప్పుడు వేయబడింది?","answer":"1945"},{"question":"*ما اللقب الذي أطلق على سيدنا لقمان ؟","answer":"الحكيم"},{"question":"Anisan'ny baobab lehibe indrindra misy ny baobab fanta-daza hita ao Mahajanga. Firy taona no nomina io baobab io ?","answer":"Ny baobab ao Mahajanga dia eo amin'ny 275 taona .( mety latsaka na mahery)."},{"question":"  மூன்றாவது பானிபட் போர் நடைபெற்ற ஆண்டு?","answer":", 1761."},{"question":"Inona no niseho teto Madagasikara ny 15 jona 1975?","answer":"Ny 15 jona 1975 teto Madagasikara dia notendren’ny fitondrana miaramila ho filoham-panjakana sy filohan’ny “Filankevitra Faratampon’ny Tolompiavotana” ary filohan’ny governemanta ny Capitaine de Frégate Didier Ratsiraka. "},{"question":"Чынгыз Айтматов качан каза болду эле?","answer":"Чынгыз Айтматов 2008 жылы 10-июнда каза болгон."},{"question":"सार्क कृषि सूचना केन्द्र कहाँ रहेको छ ?","answer":"सार्क कृषि सूचना केन्द्र बंगलादेश, ढाकामा अवस्थित छ।"},{"question":"КМШ кыскартылган сөз кандай чечмеленет?","answer":"КМШ көз карандысыз мамлекеттердин шериктештиги "},{"question":"Wat voor belangrijke gebeurtenis beschrijft de volgende tekst: Na het mindere WK 2009 besloot Ouédraogo zich verder toe te leggen op de 400 m horden. Op de Europese kampioenschappen in 2010 bereikte ze een halve finale plaats. Een jaar later, op de WK in Daegu, verbeterde ze haar persoonlijk record stevig. Met een tijd van 55,29 werd ze vijfde in haar halve finale. In 2012 slaagde ze erin zich voor de derde keer te plaatsen voor de Olympische Spelen. Ze liep een vijftiende tijd in de reeksen en plaatste zich dus voor de halve finales. Met een persoonlijke recordtijd van 55,20 in haar halve finale miste ze op één honderdste van een seconde een finaleplaats.","answer":"Het gaat over de Europese kampioenschappen in 2010 voor Ouédraogo."},{"question":"Lithetha ukuthini igama u\\"Solam\\" nesilungu?","answer":"It can be translated to meaning \\"My seeing\\" or \\"My Eye\\""},{"question":"請介紹加拿大的蘇必利爾湖。","answer":"蘇必利爾湖（Lake Superior）面積128,000萬平方公里。 它擁有世界地表淡水的10%。 它與北部的加拿大安大略省和其他方向的美國各州共享。 這個湖也是世界上最大的淡水湖。"},{"question":"A que categoría corresponde la pregunta : ¿Cuál es el séptimo país más grande del mundo?.","answer":"La respuesta a la pregunta es geografía. "},{"question":"Apakah nama bunga kebangsaan Malaysia?","answer":"Bunga raya bunga kebangsaan Malaysia."},{"question":"Irọ ni o, ijọba Kwara ko ti i buwọ lu owo-oṣu tuntun-Ajakaye","answer":"Latari iroyin kan to jade ninu iwe iroyin olojoojumọ kan ta a forukọ bo laṣiiri to n ja kaakiri ori ẹrọ ayelujara pe ijọba ti buwọ lu ẹgbẹrun lọgbọn naira owo-oṣu oṣiṣẹ to kere ju lọ, ijọba ti ni irọ patapata ni, ko si ohun to jọ bẹẹ.Akọwe iroyin lọfiisi gomina, Ọgbẹni Rafiu Ajakaye lo, sọ eleyii ninu atẹjade kan lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, o ni ki awọn araalu ma gba iroyin naa gbọ nitori pe ko jade lati ọdọ ijọba.O ṣalaye pe ijọba ati ẹgbẹ oṣiṣẹ si n jiroro pọ lati yanju ọrọ owo-oṣu tuntun naa, abajade rẹ yoo si to araalu leti.Ṣe lati opin ọsẹ to kọja yii niroyin ọhun ti gba ori ẹrọ ayelujara kiri pe ijọba ti buwọ lu owo-oṣu tuntun. Koda, awọn to n gbe iroyin ẹlẹjẹ naa kiri ni akọwe iroyin Gomina Abdulrazaq Abdulrahman lo kede ọrọ naa.Ṣugbọn ìyẹn ko jẹ ki ọrọ ọhun tutu to fi figbe ta pe oun ko gbe ikede tabi atẹjade kankan jade pe gomina fọwọ si owo-oṣu tuntun o, nitori naa, kawọn to n gbe igbekugbee kiri lọọ dakẹ rumọọsi, ki wọn si gbẹnu dakẹ."},{"question":"Khi so sánh than chì (ruột bút chì) và kim cương, phát biểu nào là đúng?","answer":"Kim cương và than chì (graphite) có sự khác biệt lớn từ giá trị kinh tế đến tính chất vật lý, hóa học... Kim cương có khả năng khúc xạ ánh sáng tốt (chiết suất khoảng 2,5), ánh sáng có thể tán sắc qua các mặt của viên kim cương tạo ra màu sắc đẹp mắt. Trong khi than chì hấp thụ mạnh ánh sáng nên thường có màu xám tối.Kim cương là chất cách điện nên có điện trở suất rất lớn so với than chì (chất dẫn điện khá tốt). Thực tế, điểm giống nhau duy nhất của kim cương và than chì là đều có cấu tạo mạng tinh thể từ nguyên tử carbon (C).Mặc dù vậy, khi đi sâu về đặc điểm mạng tinh thể, chúng lại khác nhau: Đối với kim cương, một nguyên tử C sẽ liên kết với bốn nguyên tử C lân cận, một số cụm liên kết đó tạo thành khối lập phương vững chắc. Với than chì, một nguyên tử C chỉ liên kết với ba nguyên tử C lân cận, một số cụm liên kết này tạo thành mạng lục giác (dạng 2D), các lớp mạng lục giác dễ dàng tách rời nhau.Nhờ có cấu trúc như trên mà kim cương là một trong những vật liệu cứng nhất trên Trái đất. Than chì, nhờ sự phân lớp liên kết yếu với nhau, đã mang lại cho nó khả năng viết."},{"question":"नेपालको पहिलो मुद्रा कुन हो ?","answer":"नेपालको पहिलो मुद्राको नाम मोहरु थियो।"},{"question":"Чыйрак деген эмне?","answer":"Чыйрак – тың, бышык, чыдамкай дегенди билдирет. Мисалы: Исхак Раззаков кичинесинен эле кыйынчылыктарга туш болуп, түгөнбөгөн түйшүк менен татаал жолду башынан кечирди. Бирок жаштайынан чыйрак өсүп, Самарканддан, Москвадан билим алды. "},{"question":"හයිඩ්‍රොක්ලෝරික් අම්ලයේ රසායනික සූත්‍ර HCl වේ.","answer":"True"},{"question":"பிறமொழிக் கருத்துகள் சங்க காலத்திலேயே தமிழ்ப்படுத்தப்பட்டன என்பதை விளக்குக.","answer":"வடமொழியில் வழங்கிவந்த இராமாயண மகாபாரத செய்திகள் சங்க இலக்கியங்களில் பரவலாக இடம் பெற்று இருப்பதைக் காணும்போது பிறமொழிக் கருத்துகள் சங்க காலத்திலேயே தமிழ்ப்படுத்தப் பட்டன என்பதை உணர முடிகிறது."},{"question":"Văn bản này nói về sự kiện quan trọng nào? - Ông là vị vua đầu tiên của nhà York trong lịch sử Anh. Nửa khoảng thời gian trị vì của ông được đánh dấu bằng Các cuộc chiến tranh Hoa hồng - cuộc chiến giành vương vị giữa hai nhà York và Lancaster. Ông đã hai lần đánh bại nhà Lancaster để trị vì đất nước trong hòa bình cho tới khi mất đột ngột. Trước khi trở thành vua, ông là Công tước xứ York thứ 4, Bá tước xứ March thứ 7, Bá tước Cambridge thứ 5, và Bá tước Ulster thứ 6. Ông cũng là Hiệp sĩ thứ 65 của Order of the Golden Fleece.","answer":"Văn bản này nói về vị vua Edward IV, vị vua đầu tiên của nhà York trong lịch sử Anh. Nửa khoảng thời gian trị vì của ông được đánh dấu bằng Các cuộc chiến tranh Hoa hồng - cuộc chiến giành vương vị giữa hai nhà York và Lancaster trong thời kỳ Chiến tranh Hoa hồng. "},{"question":"Sheeg maalintii, bishii iyo sanadkii Cali Mahdi Max’ed Shirkii Jabuuti loogu doortay Madaxweynaha dalka?","answer":" Cali Mahdi Max’ed  waxa Shirkii Jabuuti loogu doortay Madaxweynaha dalka taariikhda marki ay ehed 20/07/1991"},{"question":"Ẹwọn ọdun meje ni adajọ ju ọlọpaa to yinbọn paayan l’Ekoo si","answer":"Lọdun 2016 ni Ologunowa Ojo to wa ninu iṣẹ ọlọpaa nigba naa fi ibinu yinbọn fun ọmọkunrin kan, Taiye Akande, ni ibadi, tiyẹn si ṣe bẹẹ ku mọ ọn lọwọ.Adajọ Oluwatoyin Taiwo ti sọ pe ki wọn ju Ojo sẹwọn ọdun meje bayii lẹyin to jẹbi ẹsun ipaniyan ti wọn fi kan an.Ọjọ kẹta, oṣu keji, ọdun 2016, ni wahala ọhun bẹrẹ nigba ti ede aiyede bẹ silẹ laarin Ojo ati Taiye Akande. Ileeṣẹ kan to maa n ta ọkada, iyẹn Frajend Investment, to wa niluu Shapati, lẹgbẹẹ Ajah, ni ọlọpaa yii n ṣọ nigba naa.Ọrọ kekere kan ni wọn sọ pe wọn fa mọra wọn lọwọ lori bi Akande ṣe jokoo sori iganna ti wọn fi yi ọgba ileeṣẹ naa ka. Nibi ti wọn si ti n fa a mọra wọn lọwọ ni ọlọpaa yii ti yinbọn lu u nibadi, loju ẹsẹ ni wọn sare gbe e lọ si ọsibitu Jẹnẹra to wa ni Akọdo, nibẹ naa ni ẹmi ti bọ lara Akande.Iṣẹlẹ yii naa lo mu ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ṣewadii ọkunrin yii, ti wọn si yọ ọ lẹnu iṣẹ ki ile-ẹjọ too tun ju u sẹwọn ọdun meje bayii.Bo tilẹ jẹ pe Ojo sọ pe oun ko mọ ọn mọ pa a, ati pe ṣeeṣi ni ibọn ọhun ba a nibi to ti n lọ ọ mọ oun lọwọ, sibẹ, Adajọ Oluwatoyin ti sọ pe ọpọ ẹmi lo ti ṣofo lọwọ awọn ọlọpaa, ti wọn si ti fi aibikita pa danu.O ni fun idi eyi, ko tete lọọ ṣe ọdun meje lẹwọn, ki ọrọ ẹ lẹ jẹ arikọgbọn fawọn yooku ẹ."},{"question":"Belgrade dia renivohitr'i Bolgaria . Marina sa diso?","answer":"Diso. Belgrade dia renivohitr'i Serbia . Sofia no renivohitr'i Bolgaria."},{"question":"What is the tiny piece at the end of a shoelace called?","answer":"An aglet"},{"question":"Ọwọ NSCDC tẹ afurasi meji fẹsun jiji ẹrọ kọmputa gbe n’Ilọrin","answer":"Afurasi meji; Ọlanrewaju Mayọwa, ẹni ọdun mẹtalelọgbọn, ati Oyindamọla Yusuf, ẹni ọdun mejilelọgbọn, ni wọn wa lakolo ileeṣẹ aabo ẹni laabo ilu, NSCDC, niluu Ilọrin bayii, fẹsun jiji ẹrọ kọmputa alagbeeka.Atẹjade lati ọdọ Alukoro ileeṣẹ NSCDC nipinlẹ Kwara, Ọgbẹni Ayẹni Ọlasunkanmi, ṣalaye pe ẹnikan lo fi to ileeṣẹ naa leti lọjọ kẹrinlelogun, oṣu keji, ọdun yii, pe awọn ole ji ẹrọ kọmputa mẹẹẹdogun gbe ninu ṣọọbu awọn to wa ni Taiwo Isalẹ, niluu Ilọrin.Ayẹni ni pẹlu awọn ohun ti onitọhun sọ fawọn, awọn mejeeji yii gan-an lawọn fura si pe wọn ṣiṣẹ ibi naa.O niwadii ṣi n tẹsiwaju lori iṣẹlẹ naa, lẹyin iwadii lawọn afurasi naa yoo foju bale-ẹjọ.Atẹjade ọhun ni Ọga agba ajọ NSCDC ni Kwara, Alhaji Makinde Ayinla, ṣekilọ fun araalu lati ṣọra fun ohun ti wọn ba n ra, paapaa awọn nnkan atọwọdọwọ ti wọn ko mọ ibi to ti ṣẹ wa."},{"question":"ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਫਰਾਰੀ ਕੀ ਸਵਾਰੀ’ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਬਾਰੇ ਦਸੋ।","answer":"ਹਰ ਮਾਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਚਿਹਰੇ ‘ਤੇ ਮੁਸਕਰਾਹਟ ਦੇਖਣ ਲਈ ਕੁਝ ਵੀ ਕਰਨ ਨੂੰ ਤਿਆਰ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਮਮਤਾ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਕਈ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਬਣ ਚੁੱਕੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਅੱਜ ਤਕ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਬੱਚੇ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਪਿਤਾ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੋਈ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਣਾਈ। ਪਹਿਲੀ ਵਾਰ ਪਿਤਾ ਦੇ ਲਾਡ-ਪਿਆਰ ਤੇ ਦੁਲਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਰਪਿਤ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਫਰਾਰੀ ਕੀ ਸਵਾਰੀ’ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਹਜ਼ਰੀ ‘ਚ ਆਉਣ ਲਈ ਪੂਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਤਿਆਰ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਵਿਧੂ ਵਿਨੋਦ ਚੋਪੜਾ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਲੇਖਕ ਤੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਰਾਜੇਸ਼ ਮਪੁਸਕਰ ਹਨ।ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਫਰਾਰੀ ਕੀ ਸਵਾਰੀ’ ਇੱਕ ਪਿਤਾ ਰੁਸਤਮ ਬੇਹਰਾਮ ਦੇਬੂ (ਸ਼ਰਮਨ ਜੋਸ਼ੀ) ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਬੇਟੇ ਕਿਓਜੀ ਰੁਸਤਮ ਦੇਬੂ (ਮਾਸਟਰ ਰਿਤਵਕ) ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਸ਼ਰਤ ਪਿਆਰ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਅਨੋਖੀ ਗਾਥਾ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਇੱਕ ਪੁੱਤ ਦੇ ਸੁਪਨਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਹੈ ਜਿਹੜਾ ਇੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਲਾਰਡਜ਼ ਸਟੇਡੀਅਮ ‘ਚ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਖੇਡਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਬਾਪ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸੁਪਨਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਰਾ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਹਰ ਮੁਸੀਬਤ ਦਾ ਸਾਹਮਣਾ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਤਿਆਰ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਆਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਦਿਨ ਆਪਣੇ ਬੇਟੇ ਦੇ ਸੁਪਨੇ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਰਾ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਵੀ ਦੇਖਦਾ ਹੈ।ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਫਰਾਰੀ ਕੀ ਸਵਾਰੀ’ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਮੁੰਬਈ ‘ਚ ਰਹਿ ਰਹੇ ਇੱਕ ਪਾਰਸੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦੇ ਆਲੇ-ਦੁਆਲੇ ਘੁੰਮਦੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦਾ ਮੁਖੀ ਬੇਹਰਾਮ ਆਦਰਸਰ ਦੇਬੂ (ਬੋਮਨ ਈਰਾਨੀ) ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਦਾ ਬੇਟਾ ਰੁਸਤਮ ਬੇਹਰਾਮ ਦੇਬੂ (ਸ਼ਰਮਨ ਜੋਸ਼ੀ) ਆਰ ਟੀ ਓ ਦਫ਼ਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੁੱਖ ਕਲਰਕ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਬਹੁਤ ਹੀ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਮਿਹਨਤੀ ਤੇ ਈਮਾਨਦਾਰ ਹੈ। ਇੱਕ ਵਾਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਕੂਟਰ ‘ਤੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਬੇਟੇ ਨੂੰ ਬਿਠਾਈ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਉਹ ਸਿਗਨਲ ਤੋੜਨ ਦੀ ਗ਼ਲਤੀ ਕਰ ਦਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਆਰ ਟੀ ਓ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਖ ਕਲਰਕ ਹੋਣ ਕਾਰਨ, ਉੱਥੇ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਟ੍ਰੈਫਿਕ ਹੌਲਦਾਰ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਰੋਕਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਰ ਉਹ ਖ਼ੁਦ ਰੁਕ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਜੁਰਮਾਨੇ ਦੀ ਪਰਚੀ ਕੱਟਣ ਲਈ ਕਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਹੌਲਦਾਰ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਸਮਝਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਉਹ ਪਰਚੀ ਕਟਾ ਕੇ ਹੀ ਦਮ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਰੁਸਤਮ ਆਪਣੇ ਬੇਟੇ ਕਿਓਜੀ ਨੂੰ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਉਂਜ ਰੁਸਤਮ ਠੰਢੇ ਦਿਮਾਗ ਤੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਹੀ ਨਰਮ ਦਿਲ ਇਨਸਾਨ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਬੇਟੇ ਨਾਲ ਕੁਝ ਵੀ ਹੋ ਜਾਣ ‘ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਦਿਮਾਗ ਹੱਦ ਤੋਂ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਗਰਮ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਕਿਓਜੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਖੇਡਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਕੋਚ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ੰਸਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਥੱਕਦੇ। ਕਿਓਜੀ ਦੇ ਇੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਦੇ ਲਾਰਡਜ਼ ਸਟੇਡੀਅਮ ‘ਚ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਖੇਡਣ ਦੇ ਸੁਪਨੇ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਰਾ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਰੁਸਤਮ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਹਾਲਾਤਾਂ ‘ਚੋਂ ਲੰਘਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੀ ਦਾਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਅੱਗੇ ਵਧਦੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਅੰਤ ਕਿਓਜੀ ਦਾ ਸੁਪਨਾ ਪੂਰਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ‘ਫਰਾਰੀ ਕੀ ਸਵਾਰੀ’ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੋਈ ਹੀਰੋਇਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਲੰਡਨ ਦੇ ਲਾਰਡਜ਼ ਸਟੇਡੀਅਮ ‘ਚ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਈ ਗਈ ਇਹ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"O que alguém faz quando \\"Quebra o galho?\\"","answer":"Significa que a pessoa ajudou, foi muito útil."},{"question":"Sanwo-Olu ṣeleri iranlọwọ fawọn ontaja Lẹkki ti wọn ba ṣọọbu wọn jẹ","answer":"Nitori bi awọn ọmọ ita ṣe ja iwọde ti awọn ọdọ n ṣe lodi si SARS gba, ti wọn si fi asiko naa ba dukia ọpọ eeyan jẹ lo mu ki Gomina Bababjide Sanwo-Olu sabẹwo sawọn olugbe Lẹkki atawọn to n taja ni ile itaja Circle Mall ti wọn padanu ile ati awọn ọja wọn sọwọ awọn ọmọọta yii ni ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii.Lasiko abẹwo naa lo ṣeleri iranlọwọ fawọn lanlọọdu ti ile wọn jo lasiko naa atwọn to ni ṣọọbu si ile itaja nla to wa ni Lẹkki tawọn ọmọọta naa fọ, ti wọn si ko ọpọlọpọ ọja wọn lọ.Bakan naa lo ni ijọba oun yoo ran awọn ti wọn padanu ọja wọn lọwọ, bẹẹ loun yoo tun fun awọn ontaja naa lanfaani lati ma san owo ori fungba diẹ, Bẹẹ lo rọ ijọba apapọ lati nawọ iru anfaani ọlude owo-ori yii si awọn eeyan naa.Akọwe gomina lori eto iroyin, Gboyega Akọsile, lo sọ eleyii di mimọ ninu atẹjade kan to fi sita ni Monde, ọjọ Aje ọsẹ yii, nipa abewo gomina.Sanwoolu ni ijọba ko ni i da awọn eeyan naa da iṣoro wọn, o ni gbogbo ọna to ba yẹ lawọn yoo fi ran wọn lọwọ ki wọn le ba a pada bo sipo.Gomina ni awọn yoo pese owo iranwo ati eto ẹyawo fun awọn ontaja Circle Mall ti awọn janduku bajẹ ọhun. O fi kun un pe oun ti n ba awọn ileeṣẹ eto inawo sọrọ lati pese ẹyawo ti ko ni i ni ele lori fun wọn.Awọn eeyan ile itaja naa dupẹ lọwọ gomina fun abẹwo rẹ, wọn bẹbẹ fun iranlọwọ rẹ ki wọn le bọ tete bọ sipo."},{"question":"ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානයේ භාවිතා කරනු ලබන මුදල්‌ වර්ගය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානයේ භාවිතා කරනු ලබන මුදල්‌ වර්ගය ඇෆ්ගනි වේ. ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථාන ඉස්ලාමික ජනරජය, එසේත් නැතිනම් පොදු ව්‍යවහාරයට අනුව ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය යනු දකුණු-මධ්‍යම ආසියාවේ පිහිටි සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම ගොඩබිමින් වටවූ කඳුකර රාජ්‍යයකි. එය දකුණින් සහ නැගෙනහිරින් පාකිස්ථානයට ද, බටහිරින් ඉරානයට ද, උතුරින් තුර්කමෙනිස්ථානයට, උස්බෙකිස්ථානයට සහ ටජිකිස්ථානයට ද, ඊසානදිගින් චීනයට ද මායිම් වී ඇත. වත්මන් ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථාන භූමිය අතීතයේ දී සේද මාවතේ සහ මානව සංක්‍රමණයේ සන්ධිස්ථානයක් විය. ක්‍රිපූ 50,000 තරම් ඈත අතීතයේ මෙහි මිනිස් වාසය පැවති බවට සාක්ෂි පුරාවිද්‍යාඥයන් විසින් සොයාගෙන ඇත."},{"question":"\\"જનનીની જોડ સખી નહી જડે રે લોલ\\" - (દામોદર ખુશાલદાસ બોટાદકર)વિષે વર્ણન કરો.","answer":"મીઠા મધુ ને મીઠા મેહુલા રે લોલએથી મીઠી તે મોરી માત રેજનનીની જોડ સખી! નહી જડે રે લોલ.પ્રભુના એ પ્રેમતણી પૂતળી રે લોલ,જગથી જૂદેરી એની જાત રે … જનનીનીઅમીની ભરેલ એની આંખડી રે લોલ,વ્હાલનાં ભરેલાં એના વેણ રે … જનનીનીહાથ ગૂંથેલ એના હીરના રે લોલ,હૈયું હેમંત કેરી હેલ રે … જનનીનીદેવોને દૂધ એનાં દોહ્યલા રે લોલ,શશીએ સિંચેલ એની સોડ્ય રે … જનનીનીજગનો આધાર એની આંગળી રે લોલ,કાળજામાં કૈંક ભર્યા કોડ રે … જનનીનીચિત્તડું ચડેલ એનું ચાકડે રે લોલ,પળના બાંધેલ એના પ્રાણ રે … જનનીનીમૂંગી આશિષ ઉરે મલકતી રે લોલ,લેતા ખૂટે ન એની લહાણ રે … જનનીનીધરતી માતા એ હશે ધ્રૂજતી રે લોલ,અચળા અચૂક એક માય રે … જનનીનીગંગાનાં નીર તો વધે ઘટે રે લોલ,સરખો એ પ્રેમનો પ્રવાહ રે … જનનીનીવરસે ઘડીક વ્યોમવાદળી રે લોલ,માડીનો મેઘ બારે માસ રે … જનનીનીચળતી ચંદાની દીસે ચાંદની રે લોલ,એનો નહિ આથમે ઉજાસ રેજનનીની જોડ સખી! નહી જડે રે લોલ."},{"question":"Суу жөнүндө ыр сап жаз !","answer":"Шылдыр-шулдур агасың,Шашып кайда барасың?Кылт-кылт этип агасың,Кылтылдап кайда барасың?Жайбаракат каптап өт,Жайкалган дыйкан талаасын."},{"question":"Vanhu vemuZimbabwe vane mukurumbira vakabatsira sei munyaya dzetsika nemagariro enyika?","answer":"Vatambi vemuZimbabwe vane mukurumbira vakaita basa guru mukusimudzira nekuchengetedza hunyanzvi nemagariro emunyika. Kuburikidza nemimhanzi yavo, mitambo, nedzimwe nzira dzeunyanzvi, varatidza tsika, mitauro, nengano dzemuZimbabwe panhandare dzenyika nepasi rose. Basa ravo rakabatsira mukuumba kuzivikanwa kwehunyanzvi netsika dzemuZimbabwe, zvichibatsira mukudada uye kuremekedzwa kwenyika pasi rose."},{"question":"Ba nhà máy thủy điện lớn nào cùng xây dựng trên dòng sông Đà?","answer":"sông Đà là phụ lưu lớn nhất trong hệ thống sông Hồng. Ba nhà máy thủy điện trên dòng sông Đà gồm Hòa Bình, Sơn La và Lai Châu có tổng công suất 6.000 MB, là chuỗi nhà máy trên một dòng sông lớn nhất Đông Nam Á và đóng góp 30% sản lượng điện quốc gia."},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε το κείμενο: \\"Η επίσημη γλώσσα της Ελλάδας είναι η","answer":"Απάντηση: \\"Ελληνική\\""},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക.ചോദ്യം: നിക്ഷേപങ്ങൾ സ്വീകരിക്കുകയും വായ്പകൾ നൽകുകയും ഉപഭോക്താക്കൾക്ക് മറ്റ് സാമ്പത്തിക സേവനങ്ങൾ നൽകുകയും ചെയ്യുന്ന ഒരു ധനകാര്യ സ്ഥാപനം എന്താണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: വ്യക്തികളിൽ നിന്നും ബിസിനസ്സുകളിൽ നിന്നും നിക്ഷേപങ്ങൾ സ്വീകരിക്കുകയും വായ്പകൾ നൽകുകയും അക്കൗണ്ടുകൾ, സേവിംഗ്സ് അക്കൗണ്ടുകൾ, ക്രെഡിറ്റ് കാർഡുകൾ എന്നിവ പരിശോധിക്കുന്നത് പോലെയുള്ള വിവിധ സാമ്പത്തിക സേവനങ്ങൾ നൽകുകയും ചെയ്യുന്ന ഒരു സാമ്പത്തിക സ്ഥാപനമാണ് ബാങ്ക്."},{"question":"Manana an'ity lahatsoratra ity isika : \\" Tsy hoe hanao mpaminany sandoka akory na haniry loza ho an’ny firenena fa ny hamisavisana ny ratsy hono hiavin’ny soa.Ny sakoroka manoloana ny fitrandrahana volamena teny Soamahamanina nataon’ny Sinoa no naresaka tatoato. Santionany sy ampahany ihany io.Raha ny harena manintona ny firenena vahiny eto Madagasikara dia betsaka. Ary izay rahateo no nahatonga ny fanjanahan-tany. Ao ny efa fantatra sy voafaritra mazava ny fisiany, ao koa ny faritra izay vita vinavina ny harena misy ao aminy. Firy amin’ny Malagasy anefa no mahafantatra ny fisian’izy ireny ? Iarahana manaiky safo be mantsina fotsiny ihany fa manankarena i Madagasikara fa vitsy amin’ny Malagasy no mahalala ny faritra efa notrandrahana na efa nahofa, na hotrandrahana atoato.\\"avy amin'alalan'io lahatsoratra io ,Inona no antony nahatonga ny fanjanahatany teo Madagasikara?","answer":"Ny antony nahatonga ny fanjanahany teto Madagasikara  dia noho ireo harena betsaka hanany "},{"question":"Voorbeeld: \\"Een vrouw met een wit hemd die een zwarte gitaar speelt\\". Hypothese: \\"De vrouw kan muziek spelen\\". Is de hypothese afhankelijk van het uitgangspunt? Opties: - Ja, Nee. - Het is niet mogelijk om te zeggenGeef stap voor stap antwoord:","answer":"De vrouw kan muziek spelen zoals ze op een zwarte gitaar speelt. Daarom is het uiteindelijke antwoord ja."},{"question":"Jox ma péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Xàw ma fu xalaat bi jóge waaye lu àm solo la.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Xàw ma fu xalaat bi jóge waaye lu àm solo la.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Xàw: VERBma: PRONfu: ADVxalaat: NOUNbi: DETjóge: VERBwaaye: CCONJlu: PRONàm: ADJsolo: NOUNla: AUX.: PUNCT"},{"question":"Awọn ọta ilọsiwaju kan tun fẹẹ da ipinlẹ Ọṣun ru o – Ijọba fariwo ta","answer":"Ijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun ti pariwo sita bayii pe awọn janduku kan tun ti n gbero lati da wahala silẹ nipinlẹ Ọṣun ni ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii.Ninu atẹjade kan ti Kọmisanna feto iroyin, Funkẹ Ẹgbẹmọde, fi sita lo ti ke si obi, alagbatọ, pẹlu awọn araalu lati ki awọn ọmọ wọn bọ abẹ.O ni aṣiri ti tu sijọba lọwọ pe awọn ọta alaafia fẹẹ lo awọn janduku naa lati tun fi awọn araalu sinu inira lẹẹkeji.Ẹgbẹmọde fi kun ọrọ rẹ pe ijọba ti fi iṣẹlẹ naa to awọn agbofinro leti lati le daabo bo ẹmi ati dukia araalu nitori ina eyi to ṣẹlẹ sẹyin ko ti i ku tan.O ni ẹnikẹni to ba kora jọ nibikibi tabi to dara pọ mọ awọn to ba kora jọ lai mọ nnkan ti wọn n ṣe yoo foju wina ofin."},{"question":"چیستان:  یک کلمه پنج حرفی بگویید که در صورتی که به آن دو حرف اضافه کنید، کوتاه‌ تر شود.","answer":"کوتاه"},{"question":"Susan Basemera","answer":"Susan Basemera jẹ́ akọrin àti òṣèrébìnrin ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Ùgándà.Basemera bẹ̀rẹ̀ orin kíkọ lọ́mọ ọdún mẹ́jọ ní ìgbà tí ó fi wà nínu ẹgbé akorin ti ilé-ìwé rẹ̀. Àwọn ará orílẹ̀-èdè rẹ̀ mọ̀ọ́ sí Zani Lady C. Ó di gbajúmọ̀ nígbà tí ó fi darapọ̀ mọ́ àwọn ẹgbẹ́ akọrin kan tí wọ́n pè ní Waka Waka àti pẹ̀lú ṣíṣe orin tí ó pe àkọ́lé rẹ̀ ní \\"Yimilila awo\\" ní ọdún 1995. Ní ọdún 2012, Basemera lọ sí Amẹ́ríkà láti tẹ̀síwájú nídi iṣẹ́ rẹ̀. Bótilẹ̀jẹ́pé ó ti gbájúmọ́ ṣíṣẹ eré ìtàgé, ó tún gbé orin kan tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ \\"Goolo Goolo\\" jáde ní ọdún 2015.Ní ọdún 2016, Basemera kópa nínu eré oníṣókí kan tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Gubagudeko ní àjọṣepọ̀ pẹ̀lú Mahershala Ali. Ní ọdún 2020, Basemera kópa nínu eré tẹlifíṣọ̀nù tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Little America, eré tí ó dá lóri àwọn àtọ̀hún-rìnwá ilẹ̀ Amẹ́ríká. Ó rí ànfàní ipa náà lẹ́hìn tí ó kàn sí olùdarí eré náà tó sì ṣe dáada níbi àyẹ̀wò tí wọ́n ṣe fún fíìmù náà."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Bộ Nông nghiệp và Thương mại Philippines cũng ghi nhận \\"tình trạng thao túng giá tràn lan, như nạn đầu cơ tích trữ của các thương nhân và các doanh nghiệp câu kết với nhau\\", thông báo của văn phòng tổng thống cho biết. ","answer":"Xung đột Nga – Ukraine, lệnh cấm xuất khẩu gạo của Ấn Độ và giá dầu thế giới khó đoán cũng làm tăng giá bán lẻ gạo tại đây.Ước tính của Bộ Nông nghiệp Philippines cho thấy nguồn cung gạo của nước này nửa cuối năm sẽ đạt 10,15 triệu tấn, đủ đáp ứng nhu cầu hiện tại là 7,76 triệu tấn.Tổng thống Philippines cũng yêu cầu cảnh sát phối hợp với chính phủ để đảm bảo thực hiện giá trần. Hải quan nước này sẽ siết kiểm tra các kho gạo để tránh đầu cơ và nhập lậu."},{"question":"చట్టం అంటే ఏమిటి ? చట్టానికి గల వివిధ ఆధారాలను చర్చించండి.","answer":"పరిచయం : రాజనీతిశాస్త్ర అధ్యయనంలో చట్టం అనేది ఒక ముఖ్యమైన భావన.రాజ్యం శాసనాల ద్వారా ప్రజలను పరిపాలిస్తుంది. శాసనాలకు ఎంతో ప్రాముఖ్యత ఉంది. రాజ్య సార్వ భౌమాధికారం శాసనాల ద్వారా వ్యక్తమవుతుంది. రాజ్యం ఆశించే సాంఘిక, ఆర్థిక, రాజకీయ మార్పులు శాసనం ద్వారానే సాధించగలవు. మానవుని బాహ్య ప్రవర్తనను క్రమబద్ధం చేసే నియమాలే శాసనాలు. వ్యక్తులు రాజ్యంలో చేయవలసినవి, చేయకూడనివి శాసనం చెబుతుంది. ప్రభుత్వంలోని శాసనశాఖ శాసనాలు చేస్తుంది.అర్థం : శాసనాన్ని ఆంగ్లంలో ‘లా’ అంటారు. ‘లాగ్’ అనే ట్యూటానిక్ పదం నుండి ‘లా’ అనే మాట వచ్చింది. ‘లాగ్’ అంటే ‘సమమైన’ లేదా ‘స్థిరమైన’ అని అర్థం. శాసనాలు స్థిరమైన నిబంధనలు.నిర్వచనాలు :1) “సార్వభౌముడి ఆదేశమే చట్టం. ప్రజలందరూ సార్వభౌముడికి విధేయులుగా ఉండేందుకు చట్టం కొన్ని ఉమ్మడి నియమాలను రూపొందిస్తుంది” అని జాన్ ఎరిస్కిన్ పేర్కొన్నాడు.2) “రాజకీయాధికారాన్ని పొందిన సార్వభౌముడిచే అమలు చేసే బాహ్య చర్యలకు సంబంధించిన సాధారణ నియమమే చట్టం” అని టి. ఇ. హాలండ్ పేర్కొన్నాడు.3) న్యాయపాలనలో రాజ్యం ఉపయోగించే సూత్ర సముదాయమే చట్టం” అని జాన్ సాల్మండ్ పేర్కొన్నాడు.శాసనానికి ఆధారాలు : హాలెండ్ అనే రచయిత సంప్రదాయాలు, మతము, ధర్మబద్ధత (సమత), న్యాయమూర్తుల తీర్పులు, శాస్త్రీయ వ్యాఖ్యానాలు, శాసనశాఖ అనేవి శాసనాలకు ఆధారాలని చెప్పాడు. శాసనాలు వివిధ రంగాలలో క్రమంగా రూపొందుతాయి. అనేక అంశాల ప్రభావం వాటిపై ఉంటుంది. రాజనీతి శాస్త్రజ్ఞులు చెప్పిన శాసనాల ఆధారాలు ఈ క్రింది విధంగా చెప్పవచ్చు.1) ఆచార, సంప్రదాయాలు, వాడుకలు: ఇవి శాసనానికి తొలి ఆధారాలు. ప్రజల ఆచారాలు, వాడుకలు, సంప్రదాయాలు శాసనాలకు మూలాధారము. సంప్రదాయాలు సంఘంలో ఒక అలవాటుగా, క్రమంగా రూపొందుతాయి. పూర్వం సంప్రదాయాలే సమాజ జీవితాన్ని క్రమబద్ధం చేసేవి. రాజ్యం వీటిని గుర్తించి, వాటిని ఆధారం చేసుకొని కొన్ని శాసనాలను రూపొందిస్తుంది. రాజకీయ ఆచారాలు కూడా రాజ్యంచే గుర్తించబడి అమలు చేయబడితే అవి శాసనాలవుతాయి. బ్రిటన్లో ‘సామాన్య న్యాయం’ సంప్రదాయబద్ధమైన శాసనానికి ఉదాహరణ. అదే విధంగా భారతదేశంలో వివాహ చట్టాలు, ఆస్తి పంపిణీ చట్టాలు మొదలగునవి సంప్రదాయాలు ఆధారంగా చేయబడ్డాయి.2) మతం: ఆచారానికి మతం సమాజాన్ని విపరీతంగా ప్రభావితం చేసే వ్యవస్థ. సంఘ జీవితం మత నియమాలకు అనుగుణంగా జరుపుకుంటారు. పూర్వం మతాధిపతులు చెప్పే నియమాలు శాసనాల వలె చెలామణి అయ్యేవి. ఆధునిక కాలంలో కూడా శాసనాలు చేయడానికి మతం ఒక ఆధారం. వారసత్వం, వివాహం, కుటుంబ ఆస్తి మొదలైన వాటి శాసనాలు మతం ఆధారంగా చేయబడ్డాయి. హిందువులు, క్రైస్తవులు, ముస్లిములకు గల శాసనాలు వారి మతాలు ఆధారంగా రూపొందాయి. ఇరాన్, పాకిస్థాన్ వంటి మత ప్రమేయ దేశాలలో సంఘ జీవనానికి మత నియమాలే ఆధారం.3) న్యాయస్థానాల తీర్పులు: న్యాయస్థానాలలో న్యాయమూర్తులు ఇచ్చే తీర్పులు శాసన నిర్మాణానికి ఆధారాలు. న్యాయస్థానాలు చట్టాలను వ్యాఖ్యానిస్తాయి. ఈ విధి నిర్వహణలో న్యాయమూర్తులు తీర్పులిచ్చేటప్పుడు క్రొత్త న్యాయ సూత్రాలను సృష్టిస్తారు. ఈ తీర్పులు అదే విధమైన వివాదాలు తలెత్తినప్పుడు న్యాయసూత్రల వలె వర్తింపచేస్తారు. నేడు న్యాయమూర్తుల నిర్ణయాలు శాసనాలలో అంతర్భాగమవుతున్నాయి. ఉదా : భారతదేశంలో సుప్రీంకోర్టు తీర్పులిచ్చిన గోలక్నాథ్ కేసు, కేశవానంద భారతి కేసు, మినర్వామిల్స్ కేసు.4) శాస్త్రీయ వ్యాఖ్యానాలు: ప్రముఖ న్యాయశాస్త్ర కోవిదులు, రచయితలు, విమర్శకులు చేసే వ్యాఖ్యానాలు శాసన నిర్మాణానికి ఆధారమవుతాయి. ఇవి న్యాయస్థానాలలో న్యాయమూర్తుల వ్యాఖ్యానాలు, | వివరణలు, శాసనాలు చేయటానికి ప్రభుత్వానికి ఉపయోగిస్తాయి. న్యాయమూర్తుల నిర్ణయాలు, తీర్పులు, భవిష్యత్లో శాసన నిర్మాణానికి తోడ్పడతాయి. ఇంగ్లండ్లో కోక్, బ్లాక్టన్, అమెరికాలో స్టోరీ, కెంట్, భారతదేశంలో విజ్ఞానేశ్వర, ఆపరార్క వంటి వారి వ్యాఖ్యానాలు శాసన నిర్మాణానికి ఆధారాలు.5) సమత లేదా సమబద్ధత : ‘సమత’ అనే పదానికి నిష్పక్షపాతం, న్యాయంలాంటి సూత్రాలను పర్యాయపదాలుగా వాడుతున్నారు. సమత అంటే సహజన్యాయం. అమలులో ఉన్న చట్టాలు వివాదాల పరిష్కారానికి సరిపడని సందర్భాలలో న్యాయమూర్తులు తమ విజ్ఞతతో, సక్రమ అవగాహన ద్వారా వివాదాల పరిష్కారంలో కక్షిదారులకున్యాయం చేకూర్చేందుకు ప్రయత్నిస్తారు. సమత అనేది సహజన్యాయ భావన ద్వారా రూపొందింది. దానినే న్యాయమూర్తులచే నిర్మితమైన చట్టాలుగా పరిగణించడమైంది. ఈ సందర్భంలో హెన్రీమెయిన్ అనే పండితుడు సహజన్యాయం గురించి ప్రస్తావిస్తూ అది కొన్ని ప్రత్యేక సూత్రాల ఆధారంగా రూపొంది పౌరన్యాయంతో కూడిన నియమాల సముదాయంగా పేర్కొన్నాడు. పౌరన్యాయం కంటే సమత అనేది ఉన్నతమైనది. సమదృక్పథం, సహజన్యాయం లాంటి సూత్రాల ఆధారంగా పాత చట్టాల స్థానంలో కొత్త చట్టాలను రూపొందించే సాంప్రదాయకమైన పద్ధతికి సమత సంకేతంగా ఉంటుంది.6) శాసనసభ: ప్రజాస్వామ్యంలో శాసన నిర్మాణశాఖ చట్టం ఆధారాలలో ముఖ్యమైనదిగా భావిస్తారు. ప్రభుత్వ సంస్థలలో ఒకటైన శాసనసభ, చట్టాలను ఆమోదిస్తుంది. అందుచేత శాసననిర్మాణ శాఖను చట్టం ఆధారాలలో ప్రత్యక్షమైన అంశంగా గుర్తించడమైంది. ఆధునిక కాలంలో చట్టాల రూపకల్పనలో శాసనసభలు ప్రముఖమైనవిగా భావించడమైంది. చట్ట నిర్మాణంలో శాసనసభలు సాధారణ ప్రజానీకం ఆకాంక్షలకు ప్రతీకగా ఉంటాయి. | శాసనసభలోని అధికార, ప్రతిపక్షాలు రెండూ ప్రజల ఆకాంక్షలకు అనుగుణంగా వ్యవహరిస్తాయి."},{"question":"Inona avy ny voka-tsoa azo avy amin'ny fampiasana ravintsara hoan'ny vatan'olombelona?","answer":"Ireto avy ny voka-tsoa oetin'ny ravintsara hoan'ny vatan'olombelona:- Fankaherezana ny lalan-pisefoana- Fanentanana ny fiarovana voajanahary- Manampy amin'ny fialan-tsasatra amin'ny hariva- Fahasalamana ankapobeny"},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε την ακόλουθη φράση: Η ευημερία της πόλης δέχθηκε ανεπανόρθωτο πλήγμα κατά τη δεκαετία του '40, με τη γερμανική κατοχή και τον εμφύλιο που ακολούθησε, Αν και η Έδεσσα δεν βομβαρδίστηκε κατά τη διάρκεια του","answer":"Ελληνοϊταλικού Πολέμου, υπέστη τεράστια καταστροφή ακριβώς λίγες ημέρες πριν από τη λήξη της κατοχής. Το Σεπτέμβριο του 1944, οι Γερμανοί, σε αντίποινα για το φόνο ενός στρατιώτη τους, πυρπόλησαν τη μισή πόλη αφήνοντας χιλιάδες άστεγους. Μεταξύ των κτιρίων που καταστράφηκαν περιλαμβανόταν το Αρρεναγωγείο (κτίσμα του 1862) και ο μητροπολιτικός ναός των Αγίων Ανάργυρων."},{"question":"為什麼人會出汗？","answer":"　人的體溫是恆定的，一般保持在37℃左右，由神經系統體中的溫調節中樞控制，使身體產熱和散熱保持相對平衡。人們吃進食物，通過消化吸收所釋放的能量一部分轉化為人們的工作活動，一部分以熱的形式向外界發散。通過散熱過程，身體才得以保持一定的體溫。皮膚是人體散熱的主要渠道。當外界溫度低於皮膚溫度時，輻射、傳導和對流是主要的散熱方式；當外界溫度高於皮膚溫度（33℃）時，出汗便成了人體主要的散熱方式。夏天，氣溫經常在30℃以上，有時可高達38℃，出汗就成了人體主要的或惟一的散熱方式。　　因此，夏天人們出汗最多。汗是汗腺分泌出的一種稀淡液體，熱刺激汗腺分泌汗液。除此以外，像情緒緊張、飲水過多、身體活動（運動或勞動）量大，也能刺激汗腺分泌汗液。汗腺活動主要在於調節體溫，其次也有排泄的作用。大量出汗時，汗液成為汗珠滴落或被擦乾，散熱效果就不佳；讓汗液留在皮膚表面漸漸蒸發，就有較好的散熱作用。"},{"question":"Ẹ ro ti ipo ẹlẹgẹ ti aabo orileede yii wa, ẹ ma ṣewọde ayajọ EndSARS o – Ijọba","answer":"Bijọba apapọ ṣe n laago ikilọ lasiko yii lori iwọde ayajọ EndSARS tawọn ọdọ kan n gbero lati ṣe logunjọ, oṣu kẹwaa, ọdun yii, bẹẹ ni wọn tun n rawọ ẹbẹ sawọn ọdọ naa pe ki wọn ro ti ipo ẹlẹgẹ ti eto aabo wa lorileede wa lasiko yii, ki wọn jawọ ninu ṣiṣẹ iwọde ajọdun ọhun.Igbimọ apapọ lori eto ọrọ-aje, National Economic Council (NEC) eyi ti Igbakeji Aarẹ ilẹ wa, Ọjọgbọn Yẹmi Ọṣinbajo, ṣe alaga rẹ lo parọwa yii lasiko ipade igbimọ naa lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọsẹ yii, l’Abuja.Igbimọ to n gba ijọba apapọ nimọran ọhun sọ pe:“Bo tilẹ jẹ pe a mọ ipa ti iwọde alaafia ti ko ninu eto ijọba dẹmokiresi lati fi ohun ti araalu fẹẹ jiroro le lori han, sibẹ, Igbimọ NEC n parọwa gidi sawọn ti wọn n gbero lati ṣewọde kaakiri ilu lati sami si ajọdun ayajọ EndSARS, pe ki wọn jawọ lori ẹ, ki wọn si wa ọna mi-in lati fikunlukun pẹlu ijọba.Idi ni pe ipo ti eto aabo wa lorileede wa lọwọ yii gbẹgẹ gidi, o si ṣee ṣe ki iru iwọde bẹẹ di eyi tawọn janduku yoo ja gba mọ wọn lọwọ, awọn ti wọn si ti n wa nnkan ti wọn maa fi kẹwọ huwa ibi tẹlẹ le tun bẹrẹ si i dana ijangbọn lawọn ibi ti iwọde naa ba ti waye. ‘‘Igbimọ yii rọ yin ni, a gba yin lamọran ni, ẹ pa ero da lori iwọde ayajọ yii o.Igbimọ naa tun ṣalaye pe awọn igbimọ oluṣewadii ati apẹtusaawọ tawọn ijọba ipinlẹ kọọkan gbe kalẹ lori awọn ẹsun ifiyajẹni ati titẹ ẹtọ ẹni mọlẹ ti wọn fi kan awọn agbofinro ti ba iṣẹ wọn de ọna to jin, awọn kan lara igbimọ naa si ti jabọ fun ijọba apapọ, koda ijọba ti ya apo owo kan sọtọ lati fi pẹtu sọkan awọn ti wọn koju ifiyajẹni bẹẹ.Wọn ni kawọn ọdọ fun ijọba laaye lati tubọ pari igbesẹ alaafia wọnyi, ki wọn ma ṣe tun dagba le ṣiṣe iwọde to tun le polukurumuṣu omi alaafia ati aabo kaakiri Naijiria.Wọn ni kawọn to n fẹẹ ṣewọde naa tun wo awọn ọna mi-in ti wọn le gba fi ẹdun ọkan wọn han si ijọba lagbegbe wọn ati ijọba apapọ pẹlu."},{"question":"حمید سوریان در مسابقات قهرمانی جهان مسکو ۲۰۱۰ چگونه ظاهر شد؟","answer":"سوریان که برای بار پنجم در قهرمانی جهان شرکت کرد به ترتیب محمد بوترفاسا را از الجزایر، ونلین ونکوف بلغاری، جانی هاپامیکی فنلاندی و رقیب سرسخت خود رومن آمویان آرمنی را شکست داده بود. سوریان در فینال ۵ بر ۳ در یک دیدار حساس چوی گیو-جین کره‌ای را شکست داد. سوریان با این طلا برای بار پنجم مدال طلا و قهرمانی خود را در مسابقات قهرمانی جهان تکرار کرد."},{"question":"Inona ary izao : \\"Aleveno aho haka ny taolako taloha.\\"","answer":"Valiny : katsaka. Fanazavana: Rehefa vokatra ny katsaka dia lasa misy taolany hipetrahan'ilay voany."},{"question":"Sheeg Meesha Uu Ku Shihiiday Imaam Xuseen ?","answer":"Wuxu Ku Shahiiday Karbala."},{"question":"Wie was Shahji Bhonsle?","answer":"Shahji of Shahaji Bhonsle (1594 – Channagiri, 23 januari 1663) was een Maratha-huurling en -deshmukh, die vooral bekend is als vader van de Maratha-vorst Shivaji. Shahji veroverde in de restanten van het sultanaat Ahmednagar een gebied dat hij voor enkele jaren regeerde in naam van een marionettensultan. Later vocht hij als legeraanvoerder voor het sultanaat Bijapur. "},{"question":"Aṣọ ṣọja lawọn eleyii ko sọrun, bẹẹ ogbologbo adigunjale ni wọn","answer":"Akolo awọn ọlọpaa lawọn ọkunrin meji yii wa lasiko yii, Ọgbẹni Yahaya Armayau, ẹni ọdun marundinlogoji, ati ekeji rẹ, Bashir Isiyaku, ẹni ọdun mejilelọgbọn, aṣọ ṣọja lawọn mejeeji wọ bii ẹni pe ṣọja ilẹ wa ni wọn loootọ, ṣugbọn afurasi adigunjale ni wọn, ọwọ si ti tẹ wọn.Alaye ti Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Katsina ṣe nipa wọn lọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, nigba ti wọn ṣafihan wọn fawọn oniroyin ni pe niṣe lawọn ayederu ṣọja yii n fi imura wọn jale, wọn n gba ọkada, wọn tun n gba owo lọwọ awọn araalu, bẹẹ ni wọn n fi ankọọfu sọwọ awọn ti wọn ba ha si wọn lọwọ, wọn si n fiya jẹ wọn.Bashir, ti inagijẹ rẹ n jẹ Ṣọja, ati Yahaya, tawọn eeyan mọ si Kofur, jẹ ọmọ bibi abule Yar-Kaware, nijọba ibilẹ Kafur, nipinlẹ Katsina.Ọga ọlọpaa naa ni ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, to kọja yii lọwọ palaba awọn mejeeji segi, lasiko ti wọn fipa gba ọkada Bajaj Ọgbẹni Yau Zaharadin, ti wọn si tun gba ẹgbẹrun lọna igba naira lọwọ ẹlomi-in ni abule Sheka, nipinlẹ naa.O ni iwadii fihan pe lati bii oṣu diẹ sẹyin lawọn ọdaju ẹda yii ti n han awọn araalu leemọ, wọn lawọn funra wọn jẹwọ pe ọkada mẹrin lawọn ti gba l’Abuja, kawọn too sa kuro nibẹ nigba tawọn eeyan fẹẹ maa fura pe awọn ki i ṣe ṣọja gidi, ati pe awọn n mura lati sa kuro ni Katsina lọwọ fi ba wọn yii.Nigba tawọn ọlọpaa lọọ tu ile wọn, wọn ba awọn nnkan eelo ṣọja, ati aṣọ ọlọpaa olokun meji, ankọọfun meji, ibọn, fila bẹntigọọ ọlọpaa, bata ati ṣokoto ṣọja, awọn afurasi naa ni rira lawọn ra wọn, wọn lọrẹẹ awọn kan lo ba awọn ra awọn ẹru ofin yii.Ṣa, iwadii ti bẹrẹ lori wọn, wọn lawọn mejeeji ati ẹnikẹni tọwọ ba tẹ pe o lọwọ ninu iṣẹẹbi wọn yoo kawọ pọnyin rojọ laipẹ."},{"question":"Waa Maxay Qurux?","answer":"Quruxdu waa mida bamiaadamka ka muuqata."},{"question":"Kawọn gomina lọọ yanju eto aabo ipinlẹ wọn, ki wọn yee di gbogbo ẹru le mi lori – Buhari","answer":"L’Ọjọbọ, ọjọ kẹwaa, oṣu kẹfa, ọdun 2021 yii, ni Aarẹ orilẹ-ede wa, Muhammadu Buhari, han lori tẹlifiṣan kan ti wọn n pe ni ‘Arise’. Nibẹ lo ti fi idaniloju sọ pe ẹnikẹni to ba fẹẹ di aarẹ Naijiria lọdun 2023 ni lati darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ APC, nitori ẹgbẹ naa ni yoo maa ṣejọba orilẹ-ede yii lọ lẹyin oun.Aarẹ Buhari ko deede sọrọ yii, nigba to n dahun awọn ibeere ti atọkun eto naa n ti si i nipa Naijiria ti ko toro lasiko yii ni Aarẹ sọ pe ẹgbẹ APC ni yoo maa tukọ Naijiria lọ lẹyin oun.Ṣaaju ni Buhari ti kọkọ fi ibinu rẹ han si eto aabo to mẹhẹ tawọn eeyan n pariwo rẹ lasiko yii. O ni awọn gomina ilẹ Yoruba lo wa nibẹ yẹn ti awọn araalu dibo fun wọn tan ti wọn ko le lo agbara to wa nikaapa wọn lati daabo bo awọn eeyan wọn.Aarẹ sọ pe awọn gomina ilẹ Yoruba meji waa ba oun l’Abuja, wọn waa fẹjọ awọn Fulani sun, pe awọn agbẹ sọ pe Fulani n ba oko awọn jẹ. Buhari loun bi awọn gomina naa leere pe ki lo ṣẹlẹ sawọn alaabo ibilẹ wọn, bẹrẹ latori awọn ọba, titi de ori awọn ijọba ibilẹ to jẹ wọn n ṣepade loorekoore lati mọ hulẹhulẹ iṣoro wọn ati ibi ti awọn oniṣẹ ibi n wọlẹ si ni agbegbe wọn, ki wọn si mu wọn. O loun beere pe ta lo ba eto gbogbo nilẹ yii jẹ, ki wọn pada sile, ki wọn lọọ tun un to.Nitori oun koriira keeyan fi ojuṣe rẹ silẹ, ko maa sunkun ẹlẹya kiri, ko maa wa ẹni ti yoo ba a ṣe e nigba to ni agbara lati ṣe nnkan rẹ funra rẹ.‘‘Mi o nifẹẹ si keeyan polongo ibo pe ki wọn dibo foun lati di gomina, ki wọn dibo naa fun un tan, ko ma le ṣe ojuṣe rẹ fun wọn. Niṣe ni wọn fẹẹ ti ohun to jẹ iṣẹ wọn sawọn eeyan mi-in.‘‘Ẹka iṣejọba mẹta la ni, ijọba apapọ, ipinlẹ ati ibilẹ. A ti pa ijọba ibilẹ ku patapata. Ijọba apapọ yoo fi ọọdunrun miliọnu ranṣẹ sijọba ibilẹ gẹgẹ bii owo to tọ si wọn, gomina kan yoo gba a, yoo ni ki alaga ijọba ibilẹ kọwọ bọwe pe oun ti gba gbogbo ọọdunrun miliọnu naa, ko si ni i fun un ju ọgọrun-un kan miliọnu lọ. Alaga naa yoo gba a, ko ni i wi nnkan kan. Ṣe ba a oo ṣe maa ba a lọ niyẹn.’’ Bẹẹ ni Buhari beere lai reti esi lọdọ ẹnikan.Aarẹ ko ti i dakẹ, o tun sọrọ nipa pinpin ipo olori lẹnu iṣẹ ologun, eyi tawọn eeyan n sọ pe o fi si apa ibi kan ju ibi kan lọ. Buhari ni ko si bi ko ṣe ni i ri bẹẹ, nitori ẹni to ti gba ẹkọ lẹnu iṣẹ ọlọpaa ati ti ologun, to mọ apade-alude iṣẹ naa loun yoo fi sibẹ, ki i ṣe ẹya ti ẹni naa jẹ lo ṣe koko.O fi kun un pe ẹya ko ni nnkan kan i ṣe pẹlu iṣẹ ati ipo ologun, nitori wọn ko fi ti ẹya ṣe ki wọn too gbaayan sibẹ. O lẹni to ba wu lati darapọ lo n di ṣọja tabi ọlọpaa, ẹni ti ko ba darapọ, ko sẹni ti yoo mu un pe ko ṣe bawọn kọṣẹ ologun. Ṣugbọn ti wọn ba n pin ipo olori, ki ẹni ti ko kẹkọọ debi ti yoo fi dọga ma sọrọ, ẹni ti ẹya rẹ ko si bawọn kẹkọọ to ko gbọdọ sọ pe wọn ko pin in daadaa.Nipa iṣẹ ti ko si ni Naijiria, ti awọn ọdọ to kawe ko ribi kan gba lọ. Aarẹ sọ pe awọn ọdọ naa lo fa a. O ni nigba to jẹ jagijagan ni wọn n ṣe. O ṣakawe rogbodiyan to waye nigba END SARS, ti wọn jo ọpọlọpọ mọto BRT nina l’Ekoo. Buhari sọ pe ta ni yoo gbọ iru iroyin bẹẹ ti yoo ti ilẹ okeere waa daṣẹ silẹ ni Naijiria, o lohun to n fa wahala sọrun awọn ọdọ niyẹn. Bi wọn ba fẹ kiṣẹ wa, ki ara si rọ wọn, Buhari ni kawọn ọdọ fọwọ sibi tọwọ n gbe ni.Ko ṣai dahun ibeere ti wọn bi i nipa awọn IPOB, iyẹn awọn ẹya Ibo ti wọn n beere fun Orilẹ-ede Biafra. Aarẹ ni oun ti sọ fawọn ṣọja atawọn ọlọpaa pe ki wọn fi ọwọ lile mu wọn. O loun ko kabaamọ ohun toun sọ tẹlẹ nipa wọn rara, awọn ọlọpaa ati ṣọja ni yoo kapa wọn ni tiwọn.Nipa pinpin Naijiria tawọn ẹya n beere fun bayii, Buhari sọ pe apẹẹrẹ buruku ni, ko si ni i jẹ kawọn olokoowo waa daṣẹ silẹ ni Naijiria.‘Ṣe orilẹ-ede kọọkan ta a ba da silẹ yoo di paradise ni? Bawo la ṣe fẹẹ pin awọn nnkan to da wa pọ? Awọn ohun ta a ti jọ ṣe nigba ta a ti wa papọ. O ya mi lẹnu pe awọn ọmọwe lorilẹ-ede yii tun n ba awọn eeyan yii sọ ọrọ arufin yii. Ta a ba wa papọ bii Naijiria lo daa ju fun wa’’ Bẹẹ ni Buhari wi, to si fi ifọkanbalẹ pari rẹ pe APC ni yoo maa ṣejọba Naijiria lọ lẹyin oun"},{"question":"Bakit nagbabago-bago ang petsa ng simula ng Ramadan kada taon?","answer":"Nagbabago-bago ang petsa ng simula ng Ramadan kada taon dahil nakabase ito sa yugto ng buwan o lunar phases. Nagsismula lamang ang Ramadan kapag nakita ng mga pinuno ng Islam ang gasuklay o cresent na buwan na nagsisimbolo ng simula ng Ramadan, ang ikasiyam na buwan sa kalendaryong Islam."},{"question":"Unsa ang book sa Bisaya?","answer":"Ang \\"book\\" sa Bisaya mao ang \\"libro.”"},{"question":"How to say I’m angry in Bisaya?","answer":"Nasuko ko"},{"question":"Ọlọkada ati ero rẹ riku ojiji he n’Ibadan, waya ina lo ja lu wọn lori","answer":"Ọlọkada kan, Ọgbẹni Kabiru, to n na agbegbe Iwo Road si Mọkọla, n’Ibadan,  pẹlu ero to gbe lẹyin, ti riku ojiji he. Waya ina to ja lu awọn mejeeji lo ṣeku pa wọn.Ni nnkan bii aago mẹfa aabọ irọlẹ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, to kọja, niṣẹlẹ ọhun waye nigba ti ọlọkada yii pẹlu ero to fẹẹ gbe jọ n dunaa-dura lọwọ.Ina ilẹtiriiki to wa lara waya ọhun lo gbe wọn, ti awọn mejeeji si gan pa loju ẹsẹ.Gẹgẹ b’ALAROYE ṣe gbọ, gbese ẹgbẹrun kan Naira (N1,000) ti awakọ kan jẹ obinrin to maa n kiri ounjẹ yii lo lọọ sin onimọto to ra ounjẹ àwìn lọwọ ẹ ni garaaji awọn awakọ naa laduugbo Iwo Road, to fi ba iku ojiji pade nibi to ti n gbiyanju lati gun ọkada pada si ṣọọbu to ti wa.Ẹgbẹrun kan Naira ọhun ti onibaara rẹ fun un lowo to tobi ju lọ ti wọn ba lọwọ obinrin olounjẹ naa nigba to ku tan.Ọkan ninu awọn tiṣẹlẹ ọhun ṣoju wọn ṣalaye fakọroyin wa pe awọn oṣiṣẹ Federal Road Safety Corps, FRSC, iyẹn, ẹṣọ alaabo oju popo ni wọn gbe oku awọn mejeeji kuro loju titi.Oludari ajọ FRSC ni ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Abilekọ Uche Chukwura, fidi ẹ mulẹ pe ileewosan Adeọyọ, n’Ibadan, ti i ṣe ileewosan ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ lawọn lọọ tọju awọn oku ọhun pamọ si."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన ప్రశ్నకి ఆలోచించి ఐదేసి వాక్యాల్లో సమాధానాలు రాయండి.“కష్టం ఒకళ్ళది ఫలితం మరొకళ్ళది” అని అనడంలో రచయిత ఉద్దేశం ఏమై ఉంటుంది?","answer":"పల్లెటూరి వాళ్ళు ఎంతో కష్టపడతారు. కూలిపని చేస్తారు. పస్తులు ఉంటారు. రెక్కలు ముక్కలు చేసుకొని వ్యవసాయం చేస్తారు. రాత్రనక, పగలనక అనేక కష్ట నష్టాల కోర్చి పంటను పండిస్తారు. కంటికి రెప్పలా కాపాడతారు. కాని, పండించిన దానిలో ఎక్కువ భాగం ఆ పొలం సొంతదారునకు ఇవ్వాలి. వాళ్ళు కష్టపడకుండా తీసుకొంటారు. హాయిగా అనుభవిస్తారు.ఈ విధానం మారాలని రచయిత ఉద్దేశం. దున్నేవానిదే భూమి కావాలనేది రచయిత ఉద్దేశం. పేదరికం పోవాలంటే, పేదలకు భూమిపై హక్కు ఉండాలనేది రచయిత ఉద్దేశం."},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Hôm nay (31/7), ghi nhận tại Trạm thu phí BOT cầu Bạch Đằng (TX Quảng Yên, Quảng Ninh) có hàng trăm phương tiện dừng tại lề đường gần trạm thu phí để đăng ký dán thẻ ETC. Theo nhân viên tại đây, đa số người dân có ý thức xếp hàng, chờ tới lượt dán thẻ. Một số khác dừng xe nhờ nhân viên hỗ trợ tải app ETC và nạp tiền vào tài khoản, trong đó nhiều người lớn tuổi. Phía trạm thu phí cầu Bạch Đằng treo biển thông báo nội dung \\"Từ 9h00 ngày 1/8, Trạm thu phí BOT cầu Bạch Đằng từ chối phục vụ phương tiện không đủ điều kiện thu phí ETC\\". \\"Do tính chất công việc phải đi lại nhiều trên cao tốc Hạ Long - Hải Phòng, tôi dán thẻ ETC từ lâu, nay do mã số bị bong tróc nên giờ ra dán lại với phí 120.000 đồng\\", anh Hoàng Lê Nguyên (trú TP Hải Phòng) cho biết. Hiện tại nhiều tài xế qua Trạm thu phí BOT cầu Bạch Đằng vẫn chọn đi làn hỗn hợp và trả tiền mặt, việc này khiến trạm thu phí xảy ra tình trạng ùn tắc.","answer":"Hàng trăm ô tô xếp hàng để dán thẻ ETC trên cao tốc ở Quảng Ninh"},{"question":"ટેક્સટાઇલ ટેક્નોલોજીના ભવિષ્ય વિશે અમને વધુ કહો.","answer":"ટેક્સટાઇલ ટેકનોલોજીનું ભવિષ્યટેક્ષટાઈલ ટેક્નોલોજીનું ભાવિ ઉજ્જવળ છે, જેમાં નવીનતા અને પ્રગતિની આકર્ષક શક્યતાઓ છે. ફોકસના ક્ષેત્રોમાં નીચેનાનો સમાવેશ થાય છે:ટકાઉ કાપડ: પર્યાવરણની અસર ઘટાડવા માટે ટકાઉ કાપડ ઉત્પાદન પદ્ધતિઓ વિકસાવવા પર ભાર મૂકવામાં આવી રહ્યો છે.વ્યક્તિગત કાપડ: ટેક્સટાઇલ ટેકનોલોજીનો ઉપયોગ વ્યક્તિગત જરૂરિયાતો અને પસંદગીઓને અનુરૂપ વ્યક્તિગત વસ્ત્રો અને ઉત્પાદનો બનાવવા માટે કરવામાં આવે છે.કાર્યાત્મક કાપડ: ટેક્સટાઇલ સંશોધન ઉર્જા ઉત્પન્ન કરતા કાપડ, સ્વ-હીલિંગ સામગ્રી અને આરોગ્ય પરિમાણોને મોનિટર કરી શકે તેવા કાપડ જેવા ઉન્નત કાર્યક્ષમતા સાથે કાપડના વિકાસની શોધ કરી રહ્યું છે.ટેક્સટાઇલ ટેક્નોલોજી આપણા વિશ્વને આકાર આપવામાં, આપણી ફેશન, ઉદ્યોગો અને રોજિંદા જીવનને પ્રભાવિત કરવામાં મહત્વપૂર્ણ ભૂમિકા ભજવવાનું ચાલુ રાખે છે. ચાલુ પ્રગતિ અને ટકાઉપણું અને નવીનતા પર ધ્યાન કેન્દ્રિત કરીને, ટેક્સટાઇલ ટેક્નોલોજી અમે ટેક્સટાઇલ સાથે ક્રિયાપ્રતિક્રિયા કરીએ છીએ અને અમારી સુખાકારીમાં વધારો કરીએ છીએ તે રીતે પરિવર્તન કરવાનું ચાલુ રાખશે."},{"question":"Fifi maaluu jẹko ni gbangba deewọ patapata nipinlẹ Ondo, Akeredolu buwọ luwe ofin rẹ","answer":"Afi ẹni to ba fẹẹ fọwọ pa ida ofin loju lo le daṣa fifi maaluu jẹkoo ni gbangba lati asiko yii lọ nipinlẹ Ondo ati igberiko rẹ, pẹlu bi Gomina Oluwarotimi Akeredolu ṣe buwọ lu abadofin to ka aṣa naa leewọ, to si ṣe bẹẹ sọ ọ di ofin nipinlẹ Ondo.Atẹjade kan ti kọmiṣanna feto iroyin ati ilanilọyẹ nipinlẹ Ondo fi lede lori ọrọ yii lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, sọ pe Akeredolu gbe igbesẹ yii ni ibamu pẹlu ipinnu tawọn gomina iha Guusu ilẹ wa fẹnuko le lori ninu ipade ti wọn ṣe kẹyin.Ninu ipade naa, eyi to waye nileejọba ipinlẹ Eko, l’Alausa, Ikẹja, ni wọn ti gbe gbedeke kalẹ pe gbogbo ipinlẹ mẹtadinlogun to ṣepade naa gbọdọ fidi ofin to ta ko fifi maaluu jẹko ni gbangba mulẹ ni ipinlẹ kaluku wọn ko too di ọjọ ki-in-ni, oṣu kẹsan-an, ọdun yii.“Igbesẹ yii ṣe pataki, o ṣe koko, lati fopin si iṣoro ati aawọ to n figba gbogbo waye lori ọrọ fifi ẹran jẹko ni gbangba, ki awọn eeyan ipinlẹ Ondo le fi ẹdọ wọn leri oronro.“A o ṣe ofin yii lati doju sọ ẹya tabi awujọ eeyan kankan, bẹẹ la o ṣe e lati finran, a ṣe e lati mu ki ajọṣepọ, anfaani tọtun-un tosi, laarin awọn olugbe ipinlẹ Ondo tubọ rẹsẹ walẹ ni, lai ka ẹya tabi ẹsin tabi ede ti ẹnikẹni n sọ si.“A reti pe kawọn olugbe ipinlẹ Ondo pa ofin yii mọ, tori ilu ti ko ba si ofin lẹṣẹ ko si, ijọba ko ni i fojuure wo ẹnikẹni to ba tasẹ agẹrẹ si ofin naa, onitọhun yoo kan dudu inu ẹkọ nile-ẹjọ.Latari eyi, ijọba yoo sapa lati jẹ kawọn eeyan mọ hulẹhulẹ ofin yii, ko si wa larọwọto wọn nibikibi ti wọn ba wa, tori ko si awawi kan to maa ṣetẹwọgba lori ofin ọhun.”Bẹẹ ni atẹjade naa sọ."},{"question":"絵や模様をつづれ織りなどにした壁掛けを英語で何というでしょう？","answer":"タペストリー"},{"question":"Apakah perbezaan Amanah Saham Bumiputera (ASB) dan Amanah Saham Nasional Berhad (ASNB) di Malaysia?","answer":"Amanah Saham Bumiputera (ASB) ialah satu tabung unit amanah yang diuruskan oleh ASNB manakala Amanah Saham Nasional Berhad (ASNB) ialah syarikat pengurusan unit amanah yang merupakan anak syarikat Permodalan Nasional Berhad (PNB)."},{"question":": Waxaad sheegtaan Malakul-Jibriil bishee buu u imaan jiray Nabiga (scw) oo uu quraanka u meerini jira isaga oo la dhameeynaayo quaanka oo dhan?","answer":": Bisha ramadaanka    "},{"question":"极端动物保护组织和其他动物权益组织有什么区别？","answer":"答：与其他主张和平、合法手段保护动物权益的组织不同，极端动物保护组织更倾向于采取激进或非法的行动。然而，所有这些组织都共享一个共同目标，那就是保护动物免受不必要的痛苦和剥削。"},{"question":"フランス語でイナヅマという意味がある、シュークリームにチョコレートをかけたお菓子は何？","answer":"エクレアです。"},{"question":"Dime cuál es el tema principal o categoría de esta pregunta: ¿Quién fue la primera mujer en ganar un Grammy?","answer":"La categoría de esta pregunta es música. "},{"question":"هل يمكنك مساعدتي في إنشاء قصيدة حزينه من بحر الطويل؟","answer":"بالطبع، تفضل هذه القصيدة: لِقَلبي بِغَورَيَّ البِلادِ لُبانَةٌوَإِن كُنتُ مَسدوداً عَلَيَّ المَطالِعُلَعَلِّيَ أُعطى وَالأَمانيُّ ضِلَّةٌوَإِنَّ اللَيالي مُعطَياتٌ مَوانِعُمَبيتِيَ في أَثوابِ ظَمياءَ لَيلَةًبِوادي الغَضا وَالعاذِلونَ هَواجِعُوَما نُطفَةٌ مَشمولَةٌ بِمَجَمَّةٍوَعاها صَفاً مِن طامِنِ الطَودِ فارِعُمِنَ البيضِ لَولا بُردُها قُلتُ دَمعَةٌمُرَنَّقَةٌ ما أَسلَمَتها المَدامِعُبِأَعذَبَ مِمّا نَوَّلَتنيهِ مَوهِناًوَقَد شيمَ بِالغَورِ النُجومُ الطَوالِعُأَرى بَعدَ وِردِ الماءِ في القَلبِ غُلَّةًإِلَيكَ عَلى أَنّي مِنَ الماءِ ناقِعُوَإِنّي لَأَقوى ما أَكونُ طَماعَةًإِذا كَذَّبَت فيكَ المُنى وَالمَطامِعُ."},{"question":"هل السؤال التالي يمكن الإجابة عليه بنعم أو لا؟: من هو رئيس الحكومة السودانية؟","answer":" لا، لا يمكن."},{"question":"Кандай тамактар ​​иммундук системаны көтөрөт?","answer":"1)жашыл жалбырактуу жашылчалар2)мөмөлөр3)балык 4)бал"},{"question":"uAya uyambandaza","answer":"Aya is speaking awkwardly "},{"question":"Ìbéèrè: Tani ló ń kọ orin fún akọni Amẹ́ríkà tó tóbi jùlọ?","answer":"Joey Scarbury ni"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'cincin emas takkan tampan bermata kaca'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud gadis yang elok dan hartawan takkan sejodoh dengan orang yang miskin dan hodoh."},{"question":"নিচের অনুচ্ছেদের বিষয় কি? বাংলাদেশের মাটিতে ২০১৩ খ্রিষ্টাব্দ থেকে একাধিক ধর্মনিরপেক্ষ নিরীশ্বরবাদী(নাস্তিক) লেখক, ব্লগার ও প্রকাশক সন্ত্রাসবাদীদের হাতে নিহত বা গুরুতর আহত হয়েছেন। এই আক্রমণের ঘটনাগুলির সম্ভাব্য কারণ হল সমসাময়িক বাংলাদেশে চলমান এক দ্বন্দ্ব। এর এক দিকে আছেন ধর্মনিরপেক্ষ জনসমাজ, যাঁরা বাংলাদেশের ধর্মনিরপেক্ষতার ঐতিহ্য বজায় রাখতে চান, ও অন্যদিকে আছেন ইসলামবাদী জনসমাজ যাঁরা বাংলাদেশকে ইসলামী রাষ্ট্র হিসেবে দেখতে চান। যুদ্ধাপরাধ ট্রাইবুনাল-এর বিচারকাজগুলি, যেগুলিতে সাম্প্রতিক অতীতের বিরোধী দল জামায়াতে ইসলামীর অনেক নেতাকে ১৯৭১ সালে বাংলাদেশের রক্তক্ষয়ী স্বাধীনতা যুদ্ধে সংঘটিত অপরাধের কারণে দোষী সাব্যস্ত করা হয়েছে, সেগুলিও এই দ্বন্দ্বের তীব্রতা বৃদ্ধি করেছে।","answer":"স্বাধীনতা যুদ্ধ |"},{"question":"Wacabanga ukuthi athole abantu ayengabathuma kodwa waxakwa ukuthi naloyomuntu kuyofana nokuthi uhambe ngesandla sakhe. Into eyayibangela ashikashikekekangaka omdala, yingoba lo muntu ayemelapha, odokotela base besikaze ukuthiunengculazi. Ngakho-ke wayemagange efuna ukuphakamisa igama lezinyanga ukuthiasikho isifo esehlula izinyanga ngisho sesibehlulile odokotela. UNonkamfela wayaziukuthi abantu sebancamela abamhlophe badela izinyanga zakubo ngenxa yobuwakaobukhona kwezinye izinyanga zigagamela into noma zingayazi zethembe ukuthi cisheucilo angethuka uzishaya endukwini.Ekubonaneni kwabo noSandanezwe wamlandisa ukuthi, 'Mfo kaMkhumane, indimayokuqala yalo msebenzi wethu sengiyigojele. Osekusele manje yikhona osekuthandaukuba umqansa, kodwa-ke izinyanya zakithi ngeke neze zingilahle. Ngiyethembaukuthi zizongikhanyisela ukuthi leso sitho esesisilele sizotholakala kanjani.''Akukho baba Mbeje okwehlula ukuhlala ethembeni.''Kunjalo fana, futhi-ke abaphansi abavamisile ukuthi umuntu bambonise into engelonaiqiniso. Kodwa-ke uma loyo muntu owelashwayo kwenzeka eba nedlozi elibi elivalayolingafuni elashwe kuyenzeka.''Hhayi-ke, mina nje angikholwa ukuthi ukhona kwabakithi ongavala izindlela zamingoba angikaze ngibone ngalutho nokudla ngihlale ngibenzela.''Cha-ke uma kunjalo, asethembe mfo kaMkhumane ukuthi izinto zizohambangononina. Khululeka, usuyozwa ngami futhi uma sengikudinga.'1. Yimiphi imiyalezo eyethulwa umbhali kule noveli? Bhala EMIBILI.","answer":"Imiyalezo EMIBILI kwelandelayo: Abantu kumele bakwamukele ukuthi kukhona izifo ezidanjiswa odokotelakuphela, njengoba uSandanezwe eqa esibhedlela waya enyangeniwangabanika ithuba elanele odokotela lokumsiza badambise isifoesasimphethe.√/ Abantu kumele bakubone ubumqoka bokuthi baziphathe kahlekwezothando ukuze baphephe ezifweni, uSandanezwe wayethandananezintombi eziningi ngesikhathi esisodwa esasebenza eThekwini./ Izinyanga kumele zithembeke zisho uma zingeke zikwazi ukwelapha izifoezithize, zinganikezi iziguli ithemba elingekho njengoNonkamfela okwathinoma esehlulekile ukwelapha uSandanezwe wathi akahambe ayohlabelaabakubo abangasekho./Sesifikile isikhathi sokuthi isenzo sobusoka singashayelwa ihlombekodwa sibukeke njengento eyingozi emphakathini njengobakwakuhlawumbiselwa ukuthi uSandanezwe uphethwe isifo sengculazi."},{"question":"Эгерде баланын оозу оюлуп эчнерсе жей албай калса, табигый шартта кандай дарылоо болот?","answer":"Жанжавырды (имбирдин талканы) оозу оюлган жерлерге кою."},{"question":"கேள்வி:       அயோடின் குறைபாட்டால் ஏற்படும் நோய் என்ன?","answer":"கேள்வி: மனித உடலில் அயோடின் குறைவினால் ஏற்படும் நோய்கள் பற்றி கூறுக ?பதில்:       அயோடின் என்பது தைராய்டு சுரப்பியின் இயல்பான செயல்பாடு மற்றும் சரியான வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் வளர்ச்சிக்கு தேவையான ஒரு அத்தியாவசிய நுண்ணூட்டச்சத்து ஆகும். இருப்பினும், அயோடின் குறைபாடு சீர்குலைவுகள் இன்றைய நிலவரப்படி உலகளாவிய பொது சுகாதார கவலைகளில் ஒன்றாகும். அயோடினின் உலகளாவிய நிலை பற்றிய சமீபத்திய அறிக்கையின்படி, சுமார் 1.88 பில்லியன் மக்கள் அயோடின் குறைபாட்டால் பாதிக்கப்படுகின்றனர் மற்றும் 241 மில்லியன் பள்ளி குழந்தைகள் போதிய அயோடின் உட்கொள்ளலைக் கொண்டுள்ளனர். எனவே இந்த உலக அயோடின் குறைபாடு தினத்தில், அயோடின் குறைபாட்டின் அறிகுறிகளைப் பற்றி கொஞ்சம் புரிந்துகொள்ள உங்களுக்கு உதவுவோம். அயோடின் குறைபாடு பற்றி நீங்கள் தெரிந்து கொள்ள வேண்டிய 9 விஷயங்கள்  இங்கே  .அயோடின் குறைபாட்டின் சில பொதுவான அறிகுறிகள் மற்றும் அறிகுறிகள் இங்கே:1. கழுத்து வீக்கம்: கோயிட்டர் என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறது, இது அயோடின் குறைபாட்டின் பொதுவான அறிகுறிகளில் ஒன்றாகும். உடலில் அயோடின் குறைவாக இருக்கும்போது, ​​தைராய்டு சுரப்பி (கழுத்து பகுதியில் அமைந்துள்ளது) தேவையை பூர்த்தி செய்ய போதுமான தைராய்டு ஹார்மோன்களை உருவாக்கத் தவறிவிடும். எனவே தேவையை பூர்த்தி செய்ய, சுரப்பி கடினமாக வேலை செய்கிறது, இது தைராய்டு செல்கள் வளர மற்றும் பெருக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்துகிறது, இதனால் சுரப்பியின் அளவு வளரும், இது கழுத்து வீக்கத்திற்கு வழிவகுக்கிறது.2. பலவீனம் மற்றும் சோர்வாக உணர்கிறேன்: இது அயோடின் குறைபாட்டால் ஏற்படும் ஹைப்போ தைராய்டிசத்தின் பொதுவான அறிகுறியாகும். ஹைப்போ தைராய்டிசம் பற்றிய 2017 இந்திய ஆய்வின்படி[2], குறைந்த தைராய்டு மற்றும் அயோடின் அளவுகளால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களில் சுமார் 95% பேர் பலவீனம் மற்றும் சோம்பலை அனுபவிப்பதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. தைராய்டு ஹார்மோன்கள் உடலில் ஆற்றல் அளவைப் பராமரிப்பதில் முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கின்றன என்பதே இதற்குக் காரணம். எனவே ஹார்மோனின் பற்றாக்குறை உங்கள் ஆற்றல் மட்டங்களில் வீழ்ச்சியை ஏற்படுத்தும் மற்றும் நீங்கள் சோம்பலாகவும் பலவீனமாகவும் உணரலாம்.3. விவரிக்க முடியாத எடை அதிகரிப்பு: தைராய்டு ஹார்மோன்கள் வளர்சிதை மாற்றத்தைக் கட்டுப்படுத்தவும் உதவுகின்றன. எனவே அயோடின் பற்றாக்குறை தைராய்டு ஹார்மோன்களின் குறைந்த அளவை ஏற்படுத்துகிறது, இது உடல் கலோரிகளை எரிக்கும் வேகத்தை பாதிக்கிறது. இதன் விளைவாக, உடல் குறைந்த கலோரிகளை எரிக்கிறது மற்றும் அதிகப்படியான கலோரிகளை கொழுப்பு வடிவில் சேமித்து, உங்கள் எடை அதிகரிக்கும்.4. முடி உதிர்தல்: தைராய்டு அளவு குறைவதால் முடி உதிர்வு ஏற்படும் என்பது நம்மில் பலருக்குத் தெரியும். ஏனென்றால், தைராய்டு ஹார்மோன்கள் மயிர்க்கால்களின் வளர்ச்சிக்கு உதவுகின்றன. எனவே, அயோடின் பற்றாக்குறை மற்றும் குறைந்த தைராய்டு அளவுகள் மயிர்க்கால்களின் வளர்ச்சியைத் தடுக்கலாம், இது காலப்போக்கில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க முடி உதிர்தலுக்கு வழிவகுக்கும்.5. வறண்ட மற்றும் கரடுமுரடான தோல்: குறைந்த தைராய்டு மற்றும் அயோடின் அளவைக் கொண்ட மக்கள் தொகையில் 85% க்கும் அதிகமானவர்கள் வறண்ட மற்றும் கடுமையான சருமத்தை அனுபவிக்கலாம் என்று இந்திய ஆராய்ச்சியாளர்கள் 2017 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஆய்வு[2] தெரிவித்தனர். தைராய்டு ஹார்மோன்கள் தோல் செல்களை மீளுருவாக்கம் செய்ய உதவுவது மட்டுமல்லாமல், வியர்வை பொறிமுறையை ஒழுங்குபடுத்துவதன் மூலம் சருமத்தை நீரேற்றமாக வைத்திருக்க உதவுகிறது. இதனால், தைராய்டு அளவு குறைவாக உள்ளவர்களுக்கு வியர்வை குறைவாக இருக்கும், இதனால் சருமம் வறண்டு போகும்.6. நினைவாற்றல் குறைபாடு: அயோடின் குறைபாடு குழந்தைகளின் மூளைப் பாதிப்பை ஏற்படுத்தலாம், இது கற்றல் குறைபாடு மற்றும் சைக்கோமோட்டர் குறைபாடு ஆகியவற்றிற்கு வழிவகுக்கும், இதில் நினைவாற்றல் (நினைவாற்றல்), பேசுதல், பேசுதல் மற்றும் சிந்தனை ஆகியவற்றில் சிரமம் அடங்கும். ஏனென்றால், தைராய்டு ஹார்மோன்கள் மூளையின் வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் வளர்ச்சிக்கு உதவுகின்றன மற்றும் போதுமான அயோடின் காரணமாக இந்த ஹார்மோன் இல்லாததால் அறிவாற்றல் குறைபாடு ஏற்படலாம்.மேலும், வளரும் மூளைக்கு தைராய்டு ஹார்மோன்கள் போதுமான அளவு வழங்கப்படாமல் இருப்பது மனநலம் குன்றிய நிலைக்கு வழிவகுக்கும். கர்ப்பிணிப் பெண்களில், மூளை பாதிப்பு மற்றும் வளரும் கருவின் மாற்ற முடியாத மனநல குறைபாடு ஆகியவை அயோடின் குறைபாட்டால் தூண்டப்படும் சில பொதுவான சிக்கல்களாகும்.7. சளிக்கு சகிப்புத்தன்மை: தைராய்டு ஹார்மோன்களின் L ow அளவுகள் வளர்சிதை மாற்றத்தை பாதிக்கலாம் மற்றும் குறைந்த வெப்ப உற்பத்திக்கு வழிவகுக்கும், இதனால் நீங்கள் குளிர்ச்சியை உணருவீர்கள். மேலும், குறைந்த வளர்சிதை மாற்ற விகிதம் மற்றும் குறைந்த உடல் வெப்பநிலை உங்களை குளிர்ச்சியாக உணர வைக்கும். தைராய்டு அளவு குறைவாக உள்ளவர்களில் கிட்டத்தட்ட 84% பேர் குளிர் சகிப்புத்தன்மையை அனுபவிக்கின்றனர்[2].எனவே, உங்கள் தினசரி பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்ட அயோடின் அளவை உங்கள் உணவின் மூலம் இயற்கை மூலங்கள் அல்லது செறிவூட்டப்பட்ட உணவுகள் (அல்லது உப்புகள்) மூலம் பூர்த்தி செய்வதை உறுதி செய்யவும். அயோடின் குறைபாட்டின் இந்த அறிகுறிகளில் ஏதேனும் ஒன்றை நீங்கள் சந்தித்தால் , நோய்க்கான சரியான காரணத்தை அறிந்து, விரைவில் சிகிச்சை பெற மருத்துவரை அணுகுவது புத்திசாலித்தனம் .காய்டர் ( தொண்டை வீக்கம் ).மண்ணில் அயோடின் குறைவாக இருக்கும் போது அயோடின் குறைபாடு ஏற்படுகிறது, இதனால் உணவுப் பொருட்களில் குறைந்த செறிவு மற்றும் மக்கள் தொகையில் போதுமான அயோடின் உட்கொள்ளல் ஏற்படுகிறது. அயோடின் தேவைகள் பூர்த்தி செய்யப்படாவிட்டால், தைராய்டு இனி போதுமான அளவு தைராய்டு ஹார்மோனை ஒருங்கிணைக்க முடியாது.அயோடின் குறைபாடு என்பது அருகிய தனிமமான அயோடின் இல்லாமையைக் குறிக்கும். இக்குறைபாடு கழுத்தில் முன்பும் பக்கவாட்டிலும் தைராயிடு வீக்கத்தையும் தைராயிடுச் சுரப்புக் குறைபாட்டையும் விளைவிக்கும். இதனால் வளர்ச்சிக் குறைபாடுகளும் நலவாழ்வுச் சிக்கல்களும் உருவாகும்.அயோடின் குறைபாடு அறிதிறன் குறைபாட்டையும் உருவாக்குவதால் இது ஒரு பொது நலவாழ்வு வினாவாகும்.நோய்க்காரணமும் நோய்நாடலும்:அயோடின் ஒரு முதன்மையான அருந்தனிமம் ஆகும்; தைராயிடு இசைமங்களாகிய தைராக்சின் மூவயடோத்ய்ரொனைன் இரண்டிலும் அயோடின் உள்ளது. அயோடின் குறைபாடு மண்ணின் குறைபாடு ஆகும். மண்ணின் மேற்பரப்பில் இருந்த அயோடின் தட்ப வெட்ப காரணமாக குறிப்பாக வெள்ளம் காரணமாக கடலில் சென்று கலந்து விட்டது. மண்ணின் மேற்பரப்பில் போதுமான அளவு அயோடின் இல்லாத காரணத்தால் மண்ணில் வளரும் தாவரங்களிலும் மனிதனுக்கு போதுமான அளவு அயோடின் இருப்பதில்லை. தாவரங்களில் போதுமான அளவு அயோடின் இல்லாத காரணத்தால் அதை உண்டு வாழும் விலங்குகளிலும் மற்றும் தாவரங்களையோ அல்லது இவை இரண்டையுமோ உண்டு வாழும் மனிதர்களுக்கு போதுமான அளவு அயோடின் கிடைப்பதில்லை."},{"question":"Ahitsio ny tsipelina amin'ity fanambarana manaraka ity:\\"Sationany sy apahany ihany io. Rah ny harena manitona ny firenena vahiny eto Madagaskara de betsak.\\"","answer":"Ity ny fanambarana miaraka amin'ny hadisoana voahitsy “Santionany sy ampahany ihany io. Raha ny harena manintona ny firenena vahiny eto Madagasikara dia betsaka.”"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਚਰਨ ਕਮਲ ਕੀ ਆਸ ਪਿਆਰੇ ॥ਜਮਕੰਕਰ ਨਸਿ ਗਏ ਵਿਚਾਰੇ ॥੧॥ਤੂ ਚਿਤਿ ਆਵਹਿ ਤੇਰੀ ਮਇਆ ॥ਸਿਮਰਤ ਨਾਮ ਸਗਲ ਰੋਗ ਖਇਆ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਅਨਿਕ ਦੂਖ ਦੇਵਹਿ ਅਵਰਾ ਕਉ ॥ਪਹੁਚਿ ਨ ਸਾਕਹਿ ਜਨ ਤੇਰੇ ਕਉ ॥੨॥ਦਰਸ ਤੇਰੇ ਕੀ ਪਿਆਸ ਮਨਿ ਲਾਗੀ ॥ਸਹਜ ਅਨੰਦ ਬਸੈ ਬੈਰਾਗੀ ॥੩॥ਨਾਨਕ ਕੀ ਅਰਦਾਸਿ ਸੁਣੀਜੈ ॥ਕੇਵਲ ਨਾਮੁ ਰਿਦੇ ਮਹਿ ਦੀਜੈ ॥੪॥੨੬॥੭੭॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 389 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਪਿਆਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਤੇਰੇ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜੇ ਰਹਿਣ ਦੀ ਆਸ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਜਮ-ਦੂਤ ਭੀ ਉਸ ਉੱਤੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਜ਼ੋਰ ਨਾਹ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਵੇਖ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਦੂਰ ਭੱਜ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉੱਤੇ ਤੇਰੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਚਿੱਤ ਵਿਚ ਤੂੰ ਆ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਤੇਰਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਿਆਂ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਰੋਗ ਨਾਸ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਹੋਰਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਤਾਂ (ਇਹ ਜਮ-ਦੂਤ) ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਕਿਸਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਦੁੱਖ ਦੇਂਦੇ ਹਨ,ਪਰ ਸੇਵਕ ਦੇ ਇਹ ਨੇੜੇ ਭੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਢੁੱਕ ਸਕਦੇ ।੨।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਤੇਰੇ ਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਦੀ ਤਾਂਘ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਮਾਇਆ ਵਲੋਂ ਵੈਰਾਗਵਾਨ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਦੇ ਆਨੰਦ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! (ਆਪਣੇ ਸੇਵਕ) ਨਾਨਕ ਦੀ ਭੀ ਅਰਜ਼ੋਈ ਸੁਣ, (ਨਾਨਕ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣਾ) ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਨਾਮ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ (ਵਸਾਣ ਲਈ) ਦੇਹ ।੪।੨੬।੭੭।\\""},{"question":"ما اسم أصغر محيطات العالم ؟","answer":"المحيط المتجمد الشمالي"},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Một nghiên cứu từ công ty tiếp thị kỹ thuật số Yard của Anh dựa trên việc phân tích các chuyến bay tư nhân cho thấy máy bay riêng của Taylor Swift thải gần 8.300 tấn CO2. Cô dẫn đầu danh sách những người nổi tiếng sở hữu máy bay riêng thải lượng CO2 cao nhất tính từ đầu năm đến nay. Máy bay riêng của Taylor Swift thực hiện 170 chuyến bay, với thời gian bay trung bình 80 phút, quãng đường bay trung bình hơn 139 dặm/chuyến bay. Các chuyến bay do máy bay riêng của Taylor Swift thực hiện đã thải ra gần 8.300 tấn CO2, nhiều hơn 1.184 lần tổng lượng khí thải CO2 hằng năm của một người bình thường. Trước","answer":"sự chỉ trích của công luận, nhất là khi bị gọi là \\"tội phạm khí hậu\\", đại diện của Taylor Swift lên tiếng phản pháo. \\"Taylor Swift thường xuyên cho người khác mượn máy bay riêng. Việc quy kết hầu hết tất cả các chuyến bay trên đều do cô ấy thực hiện là không chính xác\\" - người đại diện nói với Rolling Stone. Taylor Swift thường giữ im lặng với các vấn đề chính trị, xã hội trong phần lớn sự nghiệp của mình. Tuy nhiên, những năm gần đây, cô lên tiếng nhiều hơn với những vấn đề liên quan đến môi trường, khí hậu. Trong cuộc phỏng vấn năm 2020 với trang Variety, nữ ca sĩ cho biết biến đổi khí hậu là một trong những vấn đề cô quan tâm. Trong danh sách trên, bên cạnh Taylor Swift là ngôi sao quyền anh Floyd Mayweather với 177 chuyến bay và thải ra hơn 7.000 tấn CO2. Một số cái tên trong tốp 10 có: Jay-z, Blake Shelton, Steven Spielberg, Kim Kardashian, Mark Wahlberg, Oprah Winfrey…."},{"question":"অনুগ্রহ করে নিচের অনুচ্ছেদটি পড়ুন এবং প্রশ্নের উত্তর দিন |অনুচ্ছেদ :স্বামী বিবেকানন্দ উত্তর কলকাতার এক কায়স্থ দত্ত পরিবারে জন্মগ্রহণ করেছিলেন। এই দত্ত-পরিবারের আদি নিবাস ছিল অধুনা ভারতীয় প্রজাতন্ত্রের পশ্চিমবঙ্গ রাজ্যের বর্ধমান জেলার কালনা মহকুমার অন্তর্গত দত্ত-ডেরিয়াটোনা বা দত্ত-ডেরেটোনা গ্রাম। মুঘল শাসনকাল থেকেই দত্তরা উক্ত গ্রামের অধিবাসী ছিলেন। গবেষকরা অনুমান করেন যে তারাই ছিলেন ওই গ্রামের জমিদার। অষ্টাদশ শতাব্দীতে দত্ত-পরিবারের সদস্য রামনিধি দত্ত তার পুত্র রামজীবন দত্ত ও পৌত্র রামসুন্দর দত্তকে নিয়ে গড়-গোবিন্দপুর গ্রামে (অধুনা কলকাতার ফোর্ট উইলিয়াম ও ময়দান অঞ্চল) চলে আসেন। ফোর্ট উইলিয়াম দুর্গ নির্মাণের কাজ শুরু হলে উক্ত এলাকার অন্যান্য বাসিন্দাদের সঙ্গে দত্তরাও সুতানুটি গ্রামে (অধুনা উত্তর কলকাতা) চলে আসেন। এখানে প্রথমে তারা মধু রায়ের গলিতে একটি বাড়িতে বাস করতেন। ৩ নম্বর গৌরমোহন মুখোপাধ্যায় স্ট্রিটের যে বাড়িতে বিবেকানন্দ জন্মগ্রহণ করেছিলেন, সেই বাড়িটি নির্মাণ করেন রামসুন্দর দত্তের জ্যেষ্ঠ পুত্র রামমোহন দত্ত। রামমোহন দত্তের জ্যেষ্ঠ পুত্র দুর্গাপ্রসাদ দত্ত ছিলেন বিবেকানন্দের পিতামহ। তিনি সংস্কৃত ও ফারসি ভাষায় পণ্ডিত ছিলেন।২৫ বছর বয়সে একমাত্র পুত্র বিশ্বনাথ দত্তের জন্মের পর তিনি সন্ন্যাস গ্রহণ করে গৃহত্যাগ করেন।বিশ্বনাথ দত্ত দুর্গাপ্রসাদের কনিষ্ঠ ভ্রাতা কালীপ্রসাদ কর্তৃক প্রতিপালিত হয়েছিলেন। তিনি ছিলেন কলকাতা হাইকোর্টের অ্যাটর্নি। বিশ্বনাথ দত্ত বাংলা, ফারসি, আরবি, উর্দু, হিন্দি ও সংস্কৃত ভাষা শিখেছিলেন। সাহিত্য, ইতিহাস ও ধর্মগ্রন্থ পাঠে তার বিশেষ আগ্রহ ছিল। ধর্ম বিষয়ে তিনি উদার ছিলেন। বাইবেল ও দেওয়ান-ই-হাফিজ ছিল তার প্রিয় বই। তিনি সুলোচনা (১৮৮০) ও শিষ্টাচার-পদ্ধতি (বাংলা ও হিন্দি ভাষায়, ১৮৮২) নামে দুইটি বই রচনা করেছিলেন। ঈশ্বরচন্দ্র বিদ্যাসাগরের বিধবাবিবাহ প্রথা প্রবর্তনের সমর্থনে তিনি প্রকাশ্যে মতপ্রকাশ করেছিলেন। দুর্গাপ্রসাদের সংসারত্যাগের পর কালীপ্রসাদের অমিতব্যয়িতায় দত্ত-পরিবারের আর্থিক সাচ্ছল্য নষ্ট হয়েছিল। কিন্তু অ্যাটর্নিরূপে বিশ্বনাথ দত্তের সুদূর-প্রসারিত খ্যাতি সেই সাচ্ছল্য কিয়দংশে ফিরিয়ে আনতে সক্ষম হয়। তার স্ত্রী ভুবনেশ্বরী দেবী ছিলেন সিমলার নন্দলাল বসুর মেয়ে। তিনি বিশেষ ভক্তিমতী নারী ছিলেন।প্রশ্ন :স্বামী বিবেকানন্দের জন্ম কোথায় হয় ?","answer":"উত্তর কলকাতা |"},{"question":"Akon Eyakenyi","answer":"Akon Etim Eyakenyi (tí a bí ni 24 February 1960 ni Urue-Offong/Oruko, Nàìjíríà) je òtòkùlú olósèlú ní Naijiria. Òun ló ún se asoju Akwa ibom South senetorial District ti ìpinlè Akwa Ibom ní ilé igbimo asofin àgbàa. Wón diboyan sí ipo náà ní odun 2019. O jawe olúborí pẹlu ibo 122,412 lapapo. Kí o to di pe ayan sí ipò Senato, o jẹ minisita teleri fun eto ilé, ilè ati idagbasoke ilu labé ijọba Aare Goodluck Ebele Jonathan.A bi Eyakenyi ni 1960 si inú idile Oloye Uweh Isangedihi ni agbegbe ìjoba Urue-Offong/Oruko ti Akwa Ibom. Ni ọdun 1968 o lọ si Ile-iwe alakọbẹrẹ Ijọba, Uko Uyokim  nibiti o ti gba Iwe-ẹri akobere ní ọdun 1974. Ni ọdun kanáà, o forukọsilẹ wolé sí ilé-èkó Methodist Teachers College Olukọni Methodist ni Oron.Ni ọdun 1983 Akon wolé si Ile-ẹkọ giga ti Calabar o si fun ni Nigerian Cerrificate(NCE) ni ọdun 1986. Ni ọdun 1990, o gba oye Bachelor of Education (B.Ed) lati University of Calabar. O 4 tèsíwájú nínú ìwé rè. O fé oko, wón sì bi omo àti omo-omo.Akon Eyakenyi bere ise oluko ní odun 1986, o tún sísé ní State Ministry of Education laarin 1993 sí 1999. Ni odun 1991, nigba to n sise oluko, won fi i se Alabojuto fun eto eko, odo, ere idaraya ati Asa ni Oron.Ni ọdun 2000, a yan gegebi Komisona fun Ile-iṣẹ, oko-òwò ati Irin-ajo ni Ipinle Akwa Ibom lábé ijọba ti Victor Attah. Ni ọdun 2013, Godswill Akpabio yàn gẹgẹbi Alaga Igbimọ awon technical schools in ìpinlè Akwa Ibom. Ó ṣiṣẹ́ gẹ́gẹ́ bí Alaga ìgbìmọ̀ náà títí di ìgbà tí Ààrẹ Goodluck Jonathan fi yàn án gẹ́gẹ́ bí Minisita fún ilẹ̀, Ilé àti Ìdàgbàsókè Ìlú ní ọdún 2014.Ni ọdun 2018, Eyakenyi kede erongba rẹ lati dije fun ile igbimọ aṣofin agba ati aṣoju agbegbe senatorial Akwa Ibom South. Ni Oṣu Kẹwa ọdun 2018, o kopa ninu ìbò primary ẹgbẹ People's Democratic Party (Nigeria) lati ṣe aṣoju agbegbe senatorial Akwa Ibom South o si jawe olubori ninu awọn alakọbẹrẹ. Ni 25 February 2019, a kede rè gegebi olubori ninú idibo gbogbogbo 2019 lati ṣe aṣoju agbegbe senatorial Akwa Ibom South."},{"question":"Que lingua é falada em Andorra?","answer":"catalão"},{"question":"‘Korona ni ko ti jẹ ka ṣafikun si ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgbọn naira ataabọ ti oṣiṣẹ to kere ju lọ nipinlẹ Ọyọ n gba’","answer":"Lẹyin ipinlẹ Eko, ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ lo tun n sanwo daadaa ju lọ fawọn oṣiṣẹ, ifasẹyin ti ajakalẹ arun Korona mu ba eto ọrọ aje nilẹ yii ati kaakiri agbaye ni ko jẹ ki wọn ti fi kun owo naa. Eyi jẹ yọ ninu ọrọ ti Ọgbẹni Bayọ Titilọla Sodo ti i ṣe oludamọran fun Gomina Ṣeyi Makinde lori ọrọ awọn oṣiṣẹ ipinlẹ naa sọ fawọn oniroyin lasiko ti ẹgbẹ awọn aṣojukọroyin (Correspondents’ Chapel) ninu ẹgbẹ NUJ ipinlẹ Ọyọ gba a lalejo l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee.Ọgbẹni Sodo sọ pe lati ọpọlọpọ ọdun sẹyin lawọn oṣiṣẹ atawọn oṣiṣẹ-fẹyinti nipinlẹ Ọyọ ti n koju iṣoro airowogba lasiko, ati pe ọpọ igba ni wọn ki i rowo wọn gba pe, to jẹ aabọ owo ni wọn maa n ri gba, tabi ki awọn oṣiṣẹ-fẹyinti  gba owo lẹẹkan ṣoṣo laarin oṣu mẹta.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe sọ, “Awọn oṣiṣẹ ipinlẹ Ọyọ ko niṣoro rara lori ọrọ ilana owo-oṣu tuntun ti ijọba apapọ gbe kalẹ nitori a ti n sanwo yẹn fawọn oṣiṣẹ wa ni tiwa. Ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgbọn naira ataabọ (N30,500) lowo ti oṣiṣẹ to kere ju lọ nipinlẹ Ọyọ n gba. A ba ti ṣafikun ẹ gan-an bi ki i baa ṣe ọrọ Korona to ba eto ọrọ aje jẹ.“Bii ẹgbẹrun mọkanlelọgọrun-un (101,000) oṣiṣẹ la ni ni ipinlẹ Ọyọ. Ileewe girama ta a ni nipinlẹ yii le lẹgbẹta. Ẹ waa wo iye oṣiṣẹ to maa wa nileewe girama nikan.”Nigba to n sọrọ lori ọna ti ijọba n gba gbogun ti iwa ibajẹ laarin awọn oṣiṣẹ, oludamọran gomina yii sọ pe “Awọn kan n gbowo lati ba awọn oṣiṣẹ-fẹyinti fiili fọọmu, ẹni to ba wa ṣe e funra rẹ, wọn le fi faili rẹ ṣawati.“A le awọn kan danu lẹnu iṣẹ lọsẹ meji sẹyin lori ọrọ riba gbigba ki wọn too le fun awọn oṣiṣẹ-fẹyinti lowo-oṣu.Ko too di pe Gonina Ṣeyi Makinde gori aleefa, iṣoro to n koju awọn oṣiṣẹ ni pe wọn kì í rí owó-oṣu wọn gba pe, bẹẹ lawọn oṣiṣẹ-fẹyinti le ma ri owo gba ju ẹẹkan lọ laarin oṣu mẹta. Ṣugbọn nnkan ti yatọ lasiko iṣejọba Makinde, owo to ti fi sanwo oṣu ati owo ajẹmọnu awọn oṣiṣẹ-fẹyinti laarin ọdun meji to ṣẹṣẹ lo nipo yii ti to ilopọ marun-un iye owo ti ijọba mi-in to ti kọja na fun awọn beeyan yii laarin ọdun mẹrin ti won fi ṣejọba lọ.Ọgbẹni Sodo, ẹni to ti fi ọpọlọpọ ọdun wa lara awọn adari ẹgbẹ awọn oṣiṣẹ (NLC) nipinlẹ Ọyọ, ko ṣai bu ẹnu atẹ lu lile ti gomina ipinlẹ Kaduna, Mallam Nasir El-Rufai, le ọpọlọpọ oṣiṣẹ ijọba danu nipinlẹ rẹ, o ni igbesẹ to lodi sofin patapata gbaa ni gomina naa hu."},{"question":"Lu bees ?","answer":"Yaa bees ! wala dara bessoul!"},{"question":"Òwò Oògùn Olóró-gbígbé ní orìlé-èdè Nàìjíríà ","answer":"Òwò gbígbé oògùn-olóró lọ sí ilẹ̀ mìíràn láti tà á jẹ́ ẹ̀sẹ̀ tó lágbára ni Orílé èdè Nàìjíríà. Ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwọn ènìyàn ló rí iṣẹ́ yìí bí i òwò tó lérè lóri. Àwọn Ọ̀daràn ènìyàn ló máa ń ṣiṣẹ́ yìí. Èyí fi hàn wí pé kò kì í ṣe àwọn nìkan lọ máa ń mú lọ sókè òkun láti fi ṣìwò burúkú yìí. Èyí ti di ohun ìbàjẹ́ láwùjọ wa débi wí pé àwọn ènìyàn tí à ń fi ojú wò gan-an ti ń ṣe é. Àwọn ènìyàn bí àlùfáà, páṣítọ̀ àti àwọn ènìyàn ńláńlá mìíràn.Òwò yìí ti jẹ́ ọ̀nà kíkówójọ fún  àwọn ọ̀wọ́ Ọ̀daràn púpọ̀, tí ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwọn ọwọ́ yìí tì ń kópa nínú àwọn ìwà ìbàjẹ́ bí i Dídigunjalè, Sísọ àwọn ọmọ ènìyàn di Ẹrú àti ẹ̀ṣẹ̀ Onírìnàjò láti ìlú kan sí òmíràn."},{"question":"Awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun atọlọpaa kọju ija sira wọn n’Ikorodu","answer":"Kọṣẹkọṣẹ ni wọn ni iro ibọn n dun n’Ikorodu, nipinlẹ Eko, lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, to kọja yii, awọn ọlọpaa ati awọn ọmọ ẹlẹgbẹ okunkun ni wọn doju irin tutu kọra wọn, ọrọ ọhun si dogun gidi.Adugbo kan ti wọn n pe ni Igbelara, niṣẹlẹ ọhun ti waye, n’Ikorodu, ni nnkan bii aago mejila aabọ ọsan. Awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun ‘Aiye’ ni wọn gboju agan sawọn agbofinro laduugbo ọhun.Gẹgẹ ba a ṣe gbọ, awọn kan ni wọn tẹ ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa laago pe awọn ọmọ ẹlẹgbẹkẹgbẹ yii tun ti gbode, wọn tun ti n wa ara wọn kiri igboro, wọn fẹẹ tajẹ silẹ.Bii ọgan tawọn ọlọpaa ti gba ipe yii ni wọn ti dari ikọ awọn agbofinro lọ sibẹ, ṣugbọn, gẹgẹ bi Alakoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko ṣe ṣalaye f’ALAROYE ninu atẹjade to fi ṣọwọ lori atẹ ayelujara Wasaapu ẹ, o ni bi wọn ṣe foju kan awọn ọlọpaa naa ni wọn dana ibọn bolẹ, ibọn si lawọn ọlọpaa naa fi fesi pada, ni iro ibọn ba gba adugbo kan, bẹẹ ni jinnijinni bo awọn araadugbo naa.Adejọbi ni ọpọ lara awọn ẹlẹgbẹ okunkun naa ni wọn fara gbọgbẹ, tọgbẹ-tọgbẹ naa si ni wọn sa lọ.Ṣugbọn ọwọ tẹ meji lara wọn, Waliyu ati Timilẹyin Ọmọbọlaji, bo tilẹ jẹ pe wọn ti fara gbọgbẹ gidi, wọn si ti n gba itọju lọsibitu ti wọn ko wọn lọ.Wọn tun ri ibọn oyinbo meji, katiriiji ibọn ti wọn ti yin mẹwaa, eyi ti wọn o ti i yin mẹfa, ada ati aake pẹlu awọn oogun oloro ti wọn o ribi ko sa lọ.Awọn ọlọpaa ọtẹlẹyẹmu wa ni agbegbe naa lati fimu finlẹ awọn to sa lọ yii, atawọn ẹlẹgbẹ wọn to ku tọwọ ofin ko ti i to, gẹgẹ bi kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa Eko, Hakeem Odumosu, ti paṣẹ. Wọn lawọn ẹka ọtẹlẹmuyẹ to wa ni Panti, ni Yaba, ti n ṣiṣẹ lori ọrọ yii.."},{"question":"请给以下的文言文它的译文：（张）溥幼嗜学，所读书必手钞，钞已，朗读一过，即焚之；又钞，如是者六七始已。右手握管处，指掌成茧。冬日手皲，日沃汤数次。后名读书之斋曰“七录”……溥诗文敏捷，四方征索者，不起草，对客挥毫，俄顷立就，以故名高一时。","answer":"张溥小时侯喜欢学习，所读的书必定亲手抄，抄完了，朗诵一遍，就（把所抄的）烧掉；再抄，象这样六七次才停止。右手握笔的地方，手指和手掌都有了茧。冬天皮肤因受冻而开裂，每天用热水浸好几次。后来命名读书的书房叫“七录”…… 张溥作诗和写文章非常快。各方来索取的，（张溥）不用起草，在客人面前挥笔，马上就完成，因为这样所以（张溥）的名声在当时很高。"},{"question":"வினா: சரியான விடையைத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்து எழுதுக.இரத்தத்திலுள்ள ஹீமோகுளோபினைப் பாதிக்கக்கூடிய வாயு எது ? 1.கார்பன் மோனாக்சைடு2.நைட்ரஜன்3.புரோமின்4.நீர்ம ஹைட்ரஜன்","answer":"விடை: இரத்தத்திலுள்ள ஹீமோகுளோபினைப் பாதிக்கக்கூடிய வாயு1. கார்பன் மோனாக்சைடு.கார்பன் மோனாக்சைடு அல்லது கார்பன் ஓராக்சைடு (இலங்கை வழக்கு: காபனோரொட்சைட்டு, என்பது காற்றை விட இலேசானதும், நிறம், மணம், சுவை ஏதுமில்லாததும் ஆன ஒரு வளிமம் ஆகும். இது கொடிய நச்சுத்தன்மை காரணமாக மனிதர்களையும் விலங்குகளையும் கடுமையாகப் பாதிக்கக்கூடியது. இதில் ஒரு கரிம அணுவும் ஆக்சிசன் அணுவும் இருக்கும். அவ்விரண்டின் இடையே முப்பிணைப்பு அமைந்திருக்கும். கரிமம் கொண்ட பொருட்களை எரிக்கும் போது போதுமான அளவு ஆக்சிசன் இருந்தால் கார்பன் டை ஆக்சைடு உருவாகும். ஒரு கார்பன் அணுவுடன் ஓர் ஆக்சிசன் அணு முப்பிணைப்பால் இணைந்து கார்பன் மோனாக்சைடு உருவாகும். கார்பன் மோனாக்சைடு ஆக்சிசனோடு சேர்ந்தால் ஒரு நீல நிறப் பிழம்போடு எரிந்து கார்பன் டை ஆக்சைடை உருவாக்கும். இங்கு கார்பன் ஒக்சிசனோடு மும்மைப் பிணைப்பால் இணைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. இதில் இரண்டு பங்கீட்டுப் பிணைப்புகளும், ஒரு ஈதற் பங்கீட்டுப் பிணைப்பும் உள்ளன."},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚 Саякбай Москвада кайсы окуу жайда Манас айткан?а) Пушкин атындагы институттаб) Бауман атындагы училиүадав) Ломоносов атындагы университеттег) Щепкин атындагы театралдык училищада","answer":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚Туура жообу:в) Ломоносов атындагы университетте"},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക: \\"എൽഎസ്ഡിഃ ലവ്, സെക്സ് ഔർ ധോക\\" എന്ന ഇന്ത്യൻ സിനിമയെക്കുറിച്ച് ഒരു ചെറിയ വിവരണം നൽകുക. സംവിധായകൻ, സിനിമയുടെ തരം, സിനിമയുടെ റിലീസ് വർഷം തുടങ്ങിയ വിശദാംശങ്ങൾ ഉൾപ്പെടുത്തുക.","answer":"ചോദ്യത്തിനുള്ള ഉത്തരം ഇതാണ്: 2010ൽ ഇന്ത്യയിൽ പുറത്തിറങ്ങിയ ഡ്രാമ, ഇൻഡി ചിത്രമാണ് ദിബകർ ബാനർജി സംവിധാനം ചെയ്ത \\"എൽഎസ്ഡിഃ ലവ്, സെക്സ് ഔർ ധോക\\". നുസ്രത്ത് ബറൂച്ച, അൻഷുമാൻ ജാ, നേഹ ചൌഹാൻ എന്നിവരാണ് ചിത്രത്തിലെ പ്രധാന കഥാപാത്രങ്ങളെ അവതരിപ്പിച്ചത്. 112  മിനിറ്റായിരുന്നു സിനിമയുടെ ദൈർഘ്യം. ആഗസ്റ്റ് 27, 2021 മുതൽ നെറ്റ്ഫ്ലിക്സിൽ സ്ട്രീമിംഗിനായി ലഭ്യമാക്കിയ ഈ ചിത്രത്തിന് ടിവി-എംഎ റേറ്റിംഗ് ഉണ്ട്. സിനിമയുടെ കഥ ഇങ്ങനെ സംഗ്രഹിക്കാം \\"ആധുനിക സമൂഹത്തിന്റെ വായോറിസ്റ്റിക് സ്വഭാവം ഉത്തരേന്ത്യയിലെ മൂന്ന് അസാധാരണ ദമ്പതികളെ എങ്ങനെ ബാധിക്കുന്നുവെന്ന് ഈ നാടകം പരിശോധിക്കുന്നു.\\""},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"எங்கு அளவுக்கு மீறிய, தாங்க முடியாத கொடுமை நடைபெறுகிறோதோ அங்குதான் புரட்சி மலர்கள் வீறுகொண்டு பூக்கும்."},{"question":"Wanene jarumin Kannywood da ya fi kowa albashi a 2021?","answer":"Ali Nuhu. Ali Nuhu Mohammed shi ne ke kan gaba a jerin hamshakan attajiran Kannywood da dukiyar da ta kai dala miliyan daya. Ali Nuhu wanda ya fito daga birnin Maiduguri na jihar Borno a arewa maso gabashin Najeriya, ya shiga harkar fim ne a shekarar 1999, bayan da ya samu digiri na farko a fannin Geography daga Jami’ar Jos."},{"question":"ඇලන් ෂෙපර්ඩ් අභ්‍යවකාශයට ගියේ කෙසේද සහ ඔහුගේ මෙහෙයුම සඳහා ඔහු භාවිතා කළේ කුමන අභ්‍යවකාශ කැප්සියුලයද?","answer":"ඇලන් ෂෙපර්ඩ් ෆ්ලොරිඩාවේ Cape Canaveral සිට අභ්‍යවකාශයට දියත් කරනු ලැබුවේ එක් පුද්ගලයෙකුට පමණක් ඉඩ තිබූ Freedom 7 අභ්‍යවකාශ කැප්සියුලයෙනි."},{"question":"Nebi kasta miyaa Rasuul ahaa mise Rasuulkasta ayaa nibi 1ahaa?","answer":"waa Rasuulkata waa nebi laakiin nebi kasta Rasuul ma ahan."},{"question":"Maak de volgende passages af: Hooker, wiens vader Bill rond het begin van de jaren zeventig een goede 800 meter- (pr: 1.45,36) en 400 m hordeloper (pr: 50,6 s) was en wiens moeder Erica Nixon triomfen vierde als verspringster (tweede op de","answer":"Gemenebestspelen 1978 met 6,58 m), begon zelf zijn sportloopbaan als deelnemer aan het Australian Rules Football, voordat hij op atletiek overstapte."},{"question":"'அலைக்கழிக்கும் மனக்கோளாறு' என்ற தலைப்பில் ஒரு சிறுகுறிப்பு எழுதுக.","answer":"தர்க்க ரீதியான காரணங்கள் எதுவும் இல்லாத போதும் தங்கள் கைகளைச் சிலர் திரும்பத் திரும்பக் கழுவுவதையும், தேவையில்லாத போதும் திரும்பத் திரும்ப சுத்தப்படுத்துவதையும், குளிப்பதற்கு வழக்கத்துக்கு மாறாக பலமணி நேரங்கள் எடுத்துக் கொள்வதையும், புறப்படுவதற்கு அசாதாரணமாகப் பல மணி நேரங்களை செலவிடுவதையும், ஒன்றைச் செய்வதிலும் அதன் ஒழுங்கிலும் மிகவும் குறிப்பாக இருப்பதையும் அல்லது சிலர் சொல்லுவது போல் தாங்கள் நினைக்க விரும்பாத வன்முறை அல்லது பாலியல் எண்ணங்கள், படிமங்கள் போன்றவைத் திரும்பத்திரும்ப ஏற்படுவதையும் போன்ற அசாதாரணமான நடத்தைகளை நீங்கள் ஒருசிலரிடம் கண்டு வியந்திருக்கலாம். அப்படியானால் அந்த நபரை ஒரு உளவியல் நிபுணர் சோதித்தறிய வேண்டும். இவைகள் அலைக்கழிக்கும் மனக்கோளாறுகளின் அறிகுறிகளாக இருக்கலாம்.அலைக்கழிக்கும் மனக்கோளாறு போன்றே காணப்படும் வேறு சில கோளாறுகளும் இருக்கின்றன. குறிப்பிடத்தக்க அளவில் மனக்கலக்கம் மற்றும் அந்த மனக்கலக்கத்தை எப்படியாவது குறைக்க வேண்டும் என்று ஒரே மாதிரி நடத்தைகள் அல்லது மன வேலைகளில் ஈடுபடச் செய்யும் அலைக்கழிக்கும் கவலை ஒருசிலருக்குக் காணப்படும். எனவே சமீப காலமாக இவைகளும் அலைக்கழிக்கும் மனக்கோளாறுகள் நோய்த்தொகுதிகளோடு ஒருங்குவைத்து எண்ணப்படுகின்றன. எடுத்துக்காட்டுகள்:* மறைப்பெண்ணக் கோளாறு (உடைமைகளைப் பிரிவதில் மிகவும் சிரமம்)* உடல்வடிவ அதிருப்திக் கோளாறு (உடல் வடிவம்/உறுப்பு குறித்து மிகையாக  அதிருப்தி கொள்ளுதல்)*முடிபிடுங்கும் கோளாறு (முடிகளைப் பிடுங்குதலும் சில சமயம் உண்ணுதலும்)* தோல் உரிக்கும் கோளாறுபொது மக்கள் தொகையில் அலைக்கழிக்கும் மனக்கோளாறு 2-3 % பேருக்கு வாழ்நாள் கோளாறாக உள்ளது (நூறு பேரில் 2-3 பேருக்கு வாழ்நாள் முழுவதும் இக்கோளாறு உள்ளது என்று இதற்குப் பொருள்). ஆண் பெண் இருபாலாரையும் இது பாதிக்கிறது.பொதுவாக இது இருபது வயதில் தொடங்கும். இருந்தாலும் இது எந்த வயதிலும் ஆரம்பிக்கலாம். இரண்டு வயதுக் குழந்தைகளுக்கும் ஏற்படக் கூடும். மனச்சோர்வு, சமூக அச்சம், டூரெட்டின் சீர்கேடு போன்ற கோளாறுகளுடன் பெரும்பாலும் இது இணைந்து காணப்படுகிறது.அலக்கழிக்கும் மனக்கோளாறு சிகிச்சை அளிக்கக் கூடிய ஒரு நோய் என்பதை நினைவில் வைத்துக்கொள்ள வேண்டும். எனவே, சந்தேகம் ஏற்பட்டால் அல்லது இது போன்ற அறிகுறிகள் கொண்ட யாரையாவது அறிந்தால் உடனடியாக உதவியை நாடவும்."},{"question":"दिए गए प्रश्न का उत्तर दीजिए।संयुक्त राष्ट्र शासकीय रूप से 1945 में किस तिथि को अस्तित्व में आया ?","answer":"उत्तर :  24 अक्टूबर"},{"question":"Siapakah Nur Fathia? Jelaskan dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 90 patah perkataan. ","answer":"Nur Fathia Binti Abdul Latiff (lahir 1 September 1987) merupakan seorang pelakon, penyanyi dan model wanita di Malaysia. Beliau terkenal menerusi watak lakonannya sebagai Ummu Hani di dalam drama Hani bersama dengan Ryzal Jaafar, Siti Fathiyah Ibrahim, Nurul Elfira Loy dan Esma Daniel, sebagai Nabila di dalam drama Nur Kasih dan sebagai Dewi Yusra di dalam drama Dia... Isteri Luar Biasa bersama dengan Shukri Yahaya dan Keith Foo. Penampilan terkini beliau adalah dalam drama Menanti Februari bersama dengan Zul Ariffin."},{"question":"问题：三星在教育领域有哪些举措？","answer":"答案：三星通过教育技术和项目支持，促进数字化教育和学习机会的提供。"},{"question":"2022 අගෝස්තු 15 වන දින ඉන්දියාවේ නිදහසේ වසර කීයක් සමරනු ලැබුවේ ද?","answer":"ඉන්දියාව 2022 අගෝස්තු 15 වන දින 75 වන නිදහස් සංවත්සරය සමරනු ලැබීය. ඒ අනුව එදිනට ඉන්දියාව නිදහස් උත්සව 75 ක් සමරා ඇත."},{"question":" Sheeg magacii hore ee loo-Yaqaana Sacuudiga Boqortooyada Kahor?","answer":"Jawab , Waxaa Loo-Yaqaanay Xijaas."},{"question":"నిలువెల్లా మమతల వెలుగై నిలిచిందో అమ్మరూపు – అంటే మీకేమి అర్థమైంది?","answer":"సి. నారాయణరెడ్డిగారు తల్లిని చక్కగా అభివర్ణించారు. మాతృత్వ మధురిమలను సుమనోహరంగా ఆవిష్కరించారు. మానవునికి తొలి గురువు తల్లి. చేతులను పట్టుకొని నడిపిస్తుంది. అజ్ఞానాంధకారాన్ని తొలగిస్తుంది. మమతానురాగాలను అందిస్తుంది. మూర్తీభవించిన శాంతమూర్తి తల్లి. మమతను అందిస్తుంది. మనలో దుఃఖాన్ని తొలగిస్తుంది. సుఖాన్ని కల్గిస్తుంది. వెలుగులా దారి చూపిస్తుంది. అందుకే సి.నా.రె. గారు తల్లిని ఉద్దేశించి, నిలువెల్ల మమతల వెలుగై నిలిచిందో అమ్మరూపు – అని ప్రశంసాత్మకంగా అన్నాడు."},{"question":"شنو هي اللغة المستعملة بعد اللغات الرسمية في المغرب؟","answer":"بدرجة أولى الفرنسية من بعد الانجليزية والاسبانية"},{"question":"ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀ ਮਵਧਆਨ ਰੇਖਾ ਬਾਰੇਇੱ ਇੱਕ ਨੋਟ ਲਖੋ।","answer":"ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀ ਮੁੱਖ ਮਹਿਆਨ ਰੇਖਾ ਉੱਤਰ ਪਰਦੇਸ਼ ਹ ੱਚ ਇਲਾਹਾਬ੍ਾਦ ਕੋਲ ਹਮਰਜਾਪੁਰ ਨਾਮਕ ਿਥਾਨ ਤੋਂਲੰ ਘਦੀ ਹੈ। ਇਿਨੂੰ82.5° ਦੇਸ਼ਾਂਤਰ ੀ ਹਕਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਭਾਰਤ ਦਾ ਹਮਆਰੀ ਿਮਾਂ 0° ਦੇਸ਼ਾਂਤਰ ਜੋ ਹਕ ਇੰ ਗਲੈਂਡ ਦੇਗਰੀਨਹ ੱਚ ਨਾਮਕ ਿਥਾਨ ਤੋਂਲੰ ਘਦੀ ਹੈ ਤੋਂ5.30 ਘੰਟੇਅੱਗੇਹੈ।82°5’= 82°5×4=330 ਹਮੰਟ 330/60 = 5.5=5.30 ਘੰਟੇ।ਇਹ ਰੇਖਾ ਪੰਜ ਰਾਜਾਂ ਛੱਤੀਿਗੜ੍ਹ, ਓਡੀਸ਼ਾ, ਉੱਤਰ ਪਰਦੇਸ਼, ਮੱਿ ਪਰਦੇਸ਼ ਤੇਆਂਿਰਾ ਪਰਦੇਸ਼ ਹ ੱਚੋਂਗੁਜਰਦੀ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"لاندې پوښتنې ځواب کړئ. کله ریبا میسینټیر بیرته خدای ته ثبت کړ","answer":"د ۲۰۱۷ کال د فبرورۍ مه  ۳"},{"question":"پوښتنه: صنعتي انقلاب د ډله ایز تولید او معیاري تولید په پراختیا کې څه رول لوبولی؟","answer":"ځواب: صنعتي انقلاب د ډله ایز تولید او معیاري تولید په پراختیا کې مرکزي رول لوبولی دی. د اسمبلۍ لاین په څیر نوښتونه چې د شلمې پیړۍ په لومړیو کې د هنري فورډ لخوا معرفي شوي، او د تبادلې وړ برخو مفهوم، د ایلی ویټني لخوا پیل شوی، د تولید پروسې بدلې کړې. دې پرمختګونو په لویه پیمانه د توکو د اغیزمن او ارزانه تولید لپاره اجازه ورکړه. د هنري صنایعو څخه میخانیکي او معیاري تولید ته بدلون د توکو د تولید په طریقه کې یو بنسټیز بدلون په نښه کړ، چې د پام وړ تولید یې زیات کړ او لګښتونه یې کم کړل. دې کار د عصري صنعتي کړنو لپاره زمینه برابره کړه او د شلمې پیړۍ د مصرف کونکي اقتصاد لپاره یې مرحله جوړه کړه."},{"question":"கேள்வி: இஸ்ரோவின் குறிக்கோள் என்ன?","answer":"பதில்:இஸ்ரோ (இந்திய விண்வெளி ஆய்வு மையம்)  உலகின் மிகப்பெரும் விண்வெளி ஆய்வு நிறுவனங்களில் ஆறாவதாக உள்ளது. இஸ்ரோவின் குறிக்கோளானது விண்வெளி தொழில் நூட்பங்களையும் அதன் பயன்பாடுகளையும் உருவாக்குவதன் மூலம் நாட்டுக்கு தேவையான பணிகளை நிறைவேற்றுதலாகும்."},{"question":"ગુજરાતની મુખ્ય નદીઓ જણાવો.","answer":"સાબરમતીનર્મદાતાપીમચ્છુઆજીમહી"},{"question":"ആദ്യ വാചകം: സുരേഷ് ഒരു ശുദ്ധ സസ്യഭുക്കാണ്. രണ്ടാമൻ: സുരേഷിന്റെ ഇഷ്ടഭക്ഷണം മീൻകറിയാണ്. രണ്ട് വാക്യങ്ങളും പരസ്പരം യോജിക്കുന്നുണ്ടോ?","answer":"ഇല്ല, ഈ രണ്ട് വാക്യങ്ങളും പരസ്പര വിരുദ്ധമാണ്. ശുദ്ധ വെജിറ്റേറിയൻ ആയതിനാൽ മീൻകറി സുരേഷിന്റെ ഇഷ്ടഭക്ഷണമായിരിക്കില്ല."},{"question":"ප්‍රංශ විප්ලවයේදි බිඳ දමන ලද සිරගෙය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ප්‍රංශ විප්ලවයේදි බිඳ දමන ලද සිරගෙය වූයේ බැස්ටිල් (Bastille) සිරගෙදරයි."},{"question":"आग्रातील ताजमहालात एकूण किती खोल्या आहेत?","answer":"उत्तर: ताजमहालमध्ये १२० खोल्या आहेत. "},{"question":"ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ අගනගරය ?","answer":"කැන්බරා"},{"question":"ග්‍රීක මිථ්‍යා කථා වලට අනුව යුද්ධයට අධිපති දෙවඟන කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"මාර්ස්"},{"question":"س200- بما أهلك الله قوم نوح عليه السلام ؟","answer":"ج200- الطوفان"},{"question":"ጥያቄ፡- ቮልስዋገን በዓለም ላይ በጣም የሚታወቀው በየትኛው ተሽከርካሪ ነው? መልስ፡- ","answer":"ቢትል"},{"question":"Iza no filozofa grika fahiny noheverina ho rain’ny filozofia tandrefana ary mpanoro hevitra an’i Platon?","answer":"Socrate no anaran' ilay filozofa grika fahiny noheverina ho rain'ny filozofia tandrefana ary mpanoro hevitra an’i Platon."},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত সম্পূর্ণ করুন :১৯৮০-৮১ মৌসুমে অস্ট্রেলিয়া সফরে তার ওডিআই অভিষেক হয়। গাব্বায় নিউজিল্যান্ডের বিপক্ষে তার নিজস্ব সেরা বোলিং পরিসংখ্যান গড়েন ৪/৩০। ওভারপ্রতি ৩.৯৬ গড়ে ও ২৩.৮১ গড়ে উইকেট পেয়েছেন। তিনি মাত্র ১৫ ওডিআইয়ে অংশ নিয়েছেন। তার ব্যাটিং দূর্বলতার কারণে অল-রাউন্ডার রবি শাস্ত্রীকে ১৯৮৩ সালের","answer":"ক্রিকেট বিশ্বকাপে অন্তর্ভুক্ত করা হয়।"},{"question":"Cái mỏ xinh xinhHai chân tí xíuLông vàng mát dịu“”Chiếp! Chiếp!” suốt ngày","answer":"Đáp án: Con gà con"},{"question":"සිංහයාට සමාන පදයක් කියමු ද?","answer":"සිංහලයේ සිංහයාට නම් ගණනාවක් ඇති අතර සමහරක් මෙසේ ය.1.) කේසර2.) හරි3.) සිහ4.) සී5.) ගජසතුරු6.) සීරද7.) බාසුරු 8.) පස්වන්9.) මුවිදු"},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và trả lời câu hỏi:Một lần, khi được hỏi về thời gian sáng tác bài hát, ông cười trả lời: “Tôi viết trong hai tiếng cộng cả cuộc đời! Bởi nếu không sống những ngày gian khổ, không nuôi khát vọng giải phóng dân tộc, làm sao cảm xúc có thể vỡ òa cùng ngày chiến thắng. Để có được như ngày hôm nay, chúng ta đã phải đổi bằng máu và nước mắt.”. (Nguyệt Cát)a) Tìm trạng ngữ của câu mở đầu đoạn văn và cho biết: Vì sao tác giả không cần nêu đích xác ngày tháng như trong các văn bản Hồ Chí Minh và “Tuyên ngôn Độc lập”, Diễn biến Chiến dịch Điện Biên Phủ (sách Ngữ văn 6, tập một, trang 90, 94)?b) Tìm trạng ngữ của câu thứ hai trong đoạn văn và cho biết: Nội dung trạng ngữ đó được giải thích ở những câu tiếp theo như thế nào? Cách viết này phù hợp với yêu cầu thể hiện nghĩa của văn bản (trình bày sự kiện theo mối quan hệ nguyên nhân – kết quả) như thế nào? ","answer":"a) - Trạng ngữ của câu mở đầu đoạn văn: Một lần, khi được hỏi về thời gian sáng tác bài hát. - Tác giả không cần nêu đích xác ngày tháng như trong các văn bản Hồ Chí Minh và “Tuyên ngôn Độc lập”, Diễn biến Chiến dịch Điện Biên Phủ (sách Ngữ văn 6, tập một, trang 90, 94) vì ý nghĩa của bài viết là tập trung vào hoàn cảnh ra đời và phát hành của bài hát Như có Bác trong ngày đại thắng giúp người đọc nắm được cảm xúc vỡ òa của tác giả khi sáng tác bài hát, ý nghĩa bài hát đối với người dân Việt Nam.b) - Trạng ngữ của câu thứ hai trong đoạn văn: Bởi nếu không sống những ngày gian khổ, không nuôi khát vọng giải phóng dân tộc.- Nội dung trạng ngữ đó được giải thích ở những câu tiếp theo cho người thấy được sự vỡ òa trong cảm xúc, nhấn mạnh ý để có được độc lập ngày hôm nay đã phải hi sinh biết bao xương máu.- Cách viết này phù hợp với yêu cầu thể hiện nghĩa của văn bản (trình bày sự kiện theo mối quan hệ nguyên nhân – kết quả) ở chỗ trình bày rõ được mối quan hệ giữa nguyên nhân và kết quả của bài. "},{"question":"What is the role of the unstructured effect vi in the BYM model?","answer":"The unstructured effect \\"vi\\"  in the Besag-York-Mollié (BYM) model plays a crucial role in capturing spatial variation in disease mapping and other spatial statistical analyses. The BYM model is a popular choice for modeling spatially correlated data, particularly in the context of epidemiological studies. It is designed to analyze area-based spatial data, considering both structured (spatially correlated) and unstructured random effects."},{"question":"சங்ககாலத்திலேயே ஆண் மையச் சமூக முறை வலுவாக இருந்ததற்குச் சான்று தந்து விளக்குக.","answer":"சங்ககாலத்தில் ஆண் மையச் சமூக முறை வலுவாக வேர்ஊன்றி இருந்தது. பெண் திருமணத்திற்குப் பின் தன் கணவனுடைய தந்தையின் வீட்டிலே வாழ வேண்டும் என்பதே ஆண் மையச் சமூகத்தின் அமைப்பு முறையாகும். மணமான பின்பு தலைவியைத் 112 தலைவன் அவனுடைய இல்லத்திற்கு அழைத்துச் செல்வான்.“நும்மனைச் சிலம்பு கழீக அயரினும்எம்மனை வதுவை நல்மணம் கழிக”என்ற ஐங்குறுநூற்றுப் பாடல் (399:1-2) இதற்குச் சான்றாகும்.மணமகளின் வாழிடம் கணவன் அகம் என்பதை இச்சான்று உறுதிப்படுத்தும். தந்தை வழி குடும்ப முறை பரவலாக இருந்துள்ளது. பொருள் வயிற்பிரிவு, போர், வாழ்வியல் சடங்குகள், குடும்பம், திருமணம் போன்ற பல்வேறு சமூக களங்கள் மூலம் ஆண் மையச் சமூக முறை வலுவாக இருந்ததை அறியலாம்."},{"question":"नेपालको सर्वोच्च स्थानमा रहेको मन्दिर कुन हो ?","answer":"नेपालको सर्वोच्च स्थानमा रहेको मन्दिर मुक्तिनाथ हो। मुक्तिनाथ हिन्दू र बौद्ध दुवैका लागि पवित्र विष्णु मन्दिर हो। यो नेपालको मुस्ताङको थोरङ ला पहाडको फेदमा रहेको मुक्तिनाथ उपत्यकामा अवस्थित छ। यो विश्वको सबैभन्दा अग्लो मन्दिर (3,800 मिटर) मध्ये एक हो। हिन्दू धर्म भित्र, यो 108 दिव्य देशम मध्ये एक हो र भारत बाहिर स्थित एकमात्र दिव्य देशम हो। यसलाई मुक्ति क्षेत्र भनेर चिनिन्छ, जसको शाब्दिक अर्थ हो 'मुक्ति क्षेत्र' (मोक्ष) र नेपालको चार धामहरू मध्ये एक हो।"},{"question":"Mikä on suomalaisen yksinoikeusjärjestelmän tavoite? ","answer":"Suomalaisen yksinoikeusjärjestelmän virallinen tavoite ja tärkein oikeuttamisperusta on rahapelaamisesta aiheutuvien sosiaalisten, terveydellisten ja taloudellisten haittojen ehkäisy ja vähentäminen. Tämän linjauksen taustalla on EU:n oikeus, jonka mukaan EU:n perussopimuksissa taatusta tavaroiden ja palvelujen vapaan liikkuvuuden periaatteesta voidaan poiketa vain yleiseen etuun liittyvillä perusteilla.  Suomi on käyttänyt yleistä etua perusteena yksinoikeusjärjestelmälleen. Varsinaista rahapelialaa koskevaa lainsäädäntöä EU:ssa ei ole, vaan jokainen jäsenvaltio voi itse päättää sääntelystään EU-oikeudessa asettamissa puitteissa. Tämän vuoksi rahapelialan sääntely vaihtelee jäsenvaltiosta toiseen. Tyypillisin tapa säännellä rahapelaamista EU:ssa on myöntää eri toimijoille toimilupia rahapelitoiminnan harjoittamista varten. Perinteisillä valtiollisilla rahapeliyhtiöillä on useissa maissa edelleen keskeinen asema rahapelialalla.  "},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'jika beranak ikut kata bidan'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud ikutlah nasihat orang yang lebih mengetahui. Contoh ayat: Pepatah yang mengatakan jika beranak ikut kata bidan amat sesuai diikuti oleh anak muda sekarang."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: \\"Níu tay\\" cùng làm du lịch","answer":"6 tháng đầu năm, du lịch cụm này gồm Cần Thơ, Sóc Trăng, Bạc Liêu, An Giang, Cà Mau, Kiên Giang và Hậu Giang đón trên 16 triệu lượt khách (tăng 57,3% so với cùng kỳ), doanh thu đạt trên 12.500 tỉ đồng (tăng 54%). Tuy nhiên, khách lưu trú chỉ đạt 4,4 triệu lượt, trong đó Kiên Giang là 1,5 triệu lượt và Cần Thơ khoảng 1,2 triệu lượt; các tỉnh còn lại khoảng vài trăm ngàn lượt. Chia sẻ về cách làm du lịch tại địa phương để níu chân du khách, bà Quảng Xuân Lụa, Phó Giám đốc Sở Du lịch tỉnh Kiên Giang, nói: \\"Kiên Giang có lợi thế về du lịch biển đảo. Ngày trước, khách đến Phú Quốc ở lại 3 ngày 2 đêm đã hết chỗ chơi nhưng hiện nay là 4 ngày 3 đêm vẫn chưa trải nghiệm hết các dịch vụ tại địa điểm du lịch nổi tiếng của tỉnh\\". Bà Lụa tiết lộ để khách lưu trú dài ngày, Kiên Giang đã quy hoạch sản phẩm dịch vụ, vui chơi giải trí và vận động doanh nghiệp đầu tư phát triển các sản phẩm. Nhờ vậy, thời gian lưu trú của khách tại Kiên Giang lâu hơn các địa phương khác. Bà Trần Thị Lan Phương, Giám đốc Sở VH-TT-DL tỉnh Bạc Liêu, nhận định: \\"Du lịch nội địa phục hồi khi dịch Covid-19 được kiểm soát, việc liên kết của các địa phương trong cụm phát sinh một số hạn chế, tồn tại. Đặc biệt, xuất hiện việc mỗi địa phương, doanh nghiệp tự làm, dẫn đến cạnh tranh không lành mạnh. Rất mong các địa phương trong cụm thông qua Hiệp hội Du lịch ĐBSCL sớm tìm ra cơ chế điều phối liên kết phù hợp hiệu quả hơn\\". Lãnh đạo Sở VH-TT-DL tỉnh Cà Mau cho rằng hiện nay mỗi nơi đều tự làm lễ hội. Chẳng hạn như vừa qua Cần Thơ có Lễ hội Bánh dân gian Nam Bộ, Hậu Giang có lễ hội về cá thát lát và khóm, Cà Mau có ngày hội cua… Ông Nguyễn Chí Công, Phó Giám đốc Sở VH-TT-DL tỉnh Cà Mau, nêu: \\"Tôi cảm nhận là mạnh ai nấy làm, tự thân vận động là chính, sự liên kết chưa rõ. Cần có sản phẩm chung như làm lễ hội đặc sản của các địa phương rồi đem về một địa phương trong cụm và bán tour bán tuyến theo lễ hội này. Khách mua tour này phải rẻ hơn các tour khác từ 5%-10%. Năm sau, công ty đưa khách trở lại thì tiếp tục được ưu đãi từ 5%-10%... Làm như vậy sẽ giải quyết bước đầu lễ hội trùng lắp, sản phẩm trùng lắp. Qua đó cũng quảng bá giới thiệu, có hoạt động chung của cụm thì liên kết sẽ rõ hơn\\". Cái thiếu của du lịch ĐBSCL là thời gian lưu trú ngắn, chi tiêu tiền của du khách cho hoạt động cho du lịch địa phương thấp hơn so với các vùng khác, trong khi kinh phí để đi đến ĐBSCL không hề thấp. Vì vậy, để du lịch ĐBSCL cất cánh thì đã đến lúc các địa phương \\"níu tay\\" nhau lại. ĐƠN VỊ ĐỒNG HÀNH"},{"question":"¿Qué caracteriza al signo de Escorpio? ","answer":"Escorpio es un signo fijo y de agua; su potencia y energía emocional son únicas en todo el zodíaco. Tiene mucha imaginación e intuición, además de una gran capacidad para el análisis, fuerza de voluntad y firmeza, aunque también es muy sensible y emocional consigo mismo y con el entorno."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి భావం రాయండి:మ. కలలోనం దను మున్నెఱుంగని మహాకష్టాత్ముడై నట్టి దుర్బలుఁ దావత్సమయంబునన్ నిజపదాఙ్ఞాతంబు లుల్లంబులోదలఁప న్నంతన మెచ్చి యార్తిహరుఁడై తన్నెన నిచ్చున్, సునిశ్చలభక్తిని భజియించు వారి కిడఁడే సంపద్విశేషోన్నతుల్ (శ్రీకృష్ణుడు – కర్త)","answer":"ఆ శ్రీకృష్ణ పరమాత్ముడు కలలో కూడ తన్ను స్మరింపని నీచాత్ముడు కష్ట సమయంలో తన పాద పద్మములను మనస్సులో తలచినంత మాత్రముననే మెచ్చుకొని వాని ఆపదను బట్టి తన్ను తాను సమర్పించుకొనును. అట్టి కరుణామయుడు తనను నిశ్చలమైన భక్తితో సేవించు వారికి అపారమైన సంపదలను ఈయడా ? (ఇచ్చునని భావము) – అని కుచేలుని భార్య తన భర్తతో పలికెను."},{"question":"Allwell Adémọ́lá","answer":"Allwell Adémọ́lá tí wọ́n bí ní Ọjọ́ Ọjọ́ Kẹ̀sán-án oṣù kẹjọ ọdún 1983 jẹ́ gbajúmọ̀ òṣèrébìnrin, olùdarí, oǹkọ̀tàn, akọrin àti olóòtú sinimá àgbéléwò ọmọ bíbí ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn lórílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Ó jẹ́ ọmọ-ọmọbìnrin adájọ́-àgbà jùlọ àkọ́kọ́ ní Nàìjíríà, Adájọ́-Àgbà, Olóògbé Adétòkunbọ̀ Adémọ́láÓ kàwé gbàwé ẹ̀rí ní ifáfitì ìjọba àpapọ̀ tó gúnwà sí Ilé-Ifẹ̀, OAU. Allwell bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ sinimá àgbéléwò láti èwe ṣùgbọ́n ní ọdún 2008 ni ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní gbajúmọ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bí òṣèré sinimá àgbéléwò. Láti ìgbà náà, ó ti kópa nínú ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ sinimá àgbéléwò, lára àwọn sinimá-àgbéléwò tó gbé ìràwọ̀ rẹ̀ síta ni; Láródó Ọjọ́, Etí kẹta, Ọmọ Ẹ̀mí, You. Or I, Ayé Kejì."},{"question":"Rema","answer":"Divine Ikubor (ibí 1 May 2000),Orúkọ orí itage rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ REMA, akọrin ti orílẹ-èdè Nàìjíríà. Ayé mo Rema nígbà tí ó gbé orin tí àkọlé rẹ ń jẹ́ \\"Iron Kan\\", èyí tí ó jẹyọ nínú summer playlist ti Barack Obama ni ọdún 2019. Bákan náà ní 2019, Ó sí fọwọ́ sí láti bá Jonzing World ṣíṣe, èyí tí ó wa labẹ Mavin Records.Divine Ikubor jẹ́ ọmọ tí wón bí sí ilé bí ìgbàgbọ Kíìtẹ́nì ni ìpínlẹ̀ Benin ni orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Bí o ṣé ń dàgbà ní ọ má ń kọ Orin, béè sì ní ọ má ń Rap, nígbà tí ó wà ní ilé ìwé Sẹ́kọ́ńdírì. Ó ká ìwé alákọ̀bẹ́rẹ́ tí primary àti Sẹ́kọ́ndiri rẹ ni Ighile Group of School ni ipinlẹ Edo."},{"question":"س201 - ما الدولة الأوروبية التي استعمرت إندونيسيا ؟","answer":"ج201 - هولندا"},{"question":"Daj mi przykład zagadki w kategorii: gry wideo","answer":"Kandydat, który został 44-tym prezydentem Stanów Zjednoczonych wypuścił reklamy dla swojej pierwszej kampanii prezydenckiej w której grze Madden NFL? Madden NFL 09"},{"question":"निम्नलिखित लेखन का हिंदी में अनुवाद करें: ट्युब प्रवेशद्वारे बंद करण्यासाठी डंप ट्रक्सचा वापर करण्यात आला आणि वाहन चालकांना अन्य मार्गे वळवण्यासाठी 80 पोलिस सज्ज ठेवले होते. ","answer":"दिए गए लेखन का हिंदी में अनुवाद इस प्रकार किया जा सकता है: सुरंग के प्रवेश को बंद करने के लिए डंप ट्रकों का इस्तेमाल किया गया था और मोटर चालकों को दूसरे रास्ते से भेजने के लिए ८० पुलिस कर्मियों की सहायता ली गई।"},{"question":"கேள்வி: வல்லமை என்ற சொல்லின் பொருள் என்ன?கீழ் காணப்படும் நான்கு பதிலில் இருந்து சரியான பதிலை தேர்ந்து எடுக்கவும்:அ) வலிமைஆ) எளிமைஇ) இனிமைஈ) புதுமை","answer":" பதில்:அ) வலிமை"},{"question":"Kí ni a ń pe Monday ní èdè Yorùbá?","answer":"Ọjọ́ Ajé ni."},{"question":"கேள்வி :ரக்திகா என்பதுஅ. பண்டைய இந்தியாவின் கலைப் பிரிவுஆ. பண்டைய இந்தியாவின் ஓவியப் பிரிவுஇ. பண்டைய இந்தியாவின் எடை முறைஈ. இவை எதுவும் சரியல்ல","answer":"பதில் :இ. பண்டைய இந்தியாவின் எடை முறை"},{"question":"सफा ऊर्जा वाहकको रूपमा हाइड्रोजनको सम्भावना अन्वेषण गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"हाइड्रोजनसँग स्वच्छ ऊर्जा वाहकको रूपमा सेवा गर्ने क्षमता छ, विशेष गरी विद्युतीकरण गर्न चुनौतीपूर्ण क्षेत्रहरूमा। नवीकरणीय ऊर्जा स्रोतहरू प्रयोग गरेर हरियो हाइड्रोजन उत्पादन दिगो ऊर्जा भविष्यको लागि केन्द्रित छ।"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన సంక్లిష్ట వాక్యముని సామాన్య వ్యాఖ్యలుగా మార్చండి: శరత్ ఇంటికి వచ్చి అన్నం తిన్నాడు.","answer":"శరత్ ఇంటికి వచ్చాడు. శరత్ అన్నం తిన్నాడు."},{"question":"கேள்வி : மக்கள் தொகையில் ஆண்களை விட பெண்கள் அதிகமாக உள்ள மாநிலம் எது ?","answer":"பதில் : கேரளா."},{"question":"අජරාමර නිවන්සුව\\"අජරාමර\\" අර්ථය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"අජර- ජරාවට පත් නොවනඒ කියන්නෙ වයසට නොයනඅමර- මරණයකින් තොරඅජරාමර යනු එයයි .ඒ නිවනයි"},{"question":"సామాజిక న్యాయం గురించి వ్యాసాన్ని వ్రాయండి.","answer":"సామాజిక న్యాయం అనేది సాధారణంగా సమానత్వ భావనగా పరిగణించడమైంది. అలాగే సామాజిక న్యాయంలో సమానత్వం అనేది అంతర్లీనమైన, వివాదరహితమైన అంశం. సామాజిక న్యాయం (Social Justice) అనే పదానికి విస్తృతమైన అర్థం ఉంది. సమాజంలో నిష్పాక్షికత, పరస్పర కర్తవ్యం వంటి బాధ్యతలను ఇది సూచిస్తుంది. ప్రతి ఒక్కరూ ఇతరులకు బాధ్యత వహించాలని అది విశ్వసిస్తుంది. ప్రతి ఒక్కరికీ చాలినంత అవకాశాలు కల్పించాలని కోరుతుంది. క్లుప్తంగా చెప్పాలంటే అన్యాయాన్ని పారద్రోలి న్యాయబద్ధమైన సమాజ సాధనకు సామాజిక న్యాయం సంకల్పిస్తుంది. సమాజంలో లభించే వస్తుసేవలను పంచుకోవాలనే నమ్మకం ప్రజలలో ఉన్నప్పుడు సామాజిక న్యాయం నెలకొంటుంది. ప్రజలందరికీ సమానమైన ఆదరణ, మానవ హక్కులను కల్పించి ఉమ్మడి వనరులను నిష్పక్షపాతమైన రీతిలో ప్రతి ఒక్కరూ వ్యవహరించినప్పుడే సామాజిక న్యాయాన్ని సాధించడం సులభమవుతుంది.ఈ సందర్భంలో జాన్రాల్స్, డేవిడ్ మిల్లర్ వంటి ఆధునిక రాజనీతి శాస్త్రవేత్తలు రెండు ముఖ్యమైన ప్రకటనలు చేశారు. జాన్ రాల్స్ సామాజిక న్యాయం అనే సిద్ధాంతాన్ని ప్రతిపాదించాడు. అతడు ఈ సిద్ధాంతాన్ని న్యాయం లేదా ‘నిష్పాక్షికత’ అని సాధారణంగా వ్యవహరించడమైంది. అతడి ప్రకారం ‘సామాజిక న్యాయం’ అనేది ప్రతి ఒక్కరికీ స్వేచ్ఛ హక్కులు, ఇతర అవకాశాలు కల్పించడానికి సంబంధించినది. అలాగే సమాజంలో నిరాదరణకు గురైన వర్గాల ప్రయోజనాల గురించి శ్రద్ధ వహించడానికి ఉద్దేశించింది. వ్యక్తుల కార్యకలాపాల ప్రయోజనాన్ని బట్టి వ్యక్తుల మంచి చెడులను నిర్ణయించవచ్చనీ అతడు పేర్కొన్నాడు. సామాజిక న్యాయం ద్వారా వ్యక్తులు సుఖ సంతోషాలతో కూడిన జీవనాన్ని గడిపేందుకు అవకాశం ఉంటుందన్నాడు. సామాజిక న్యాయం భావన వ్యాప్తి ద్వారా నిరాదరణకు గురైన వ్యక్తుల గురించి పట్టించుకోవడం సాధ్యం అవుతుందని ఉద్ఘాటించాడు.పైన పేర్కొన్న జాన్రాల్స్ సిద్ధాంతం సామాజిక ఒడంబడిక భావన ఆధారంగా రూపొందింది. ఆ భావన ప్రకారం ప్రజలందరూ ఒకానొక ఒప్పందంపై సంతకం చేస్తారు. తద్వారా మెరుగైన సమాజ స్థాపనకై వారంతా కొన్ని నియమ నిబంధనలను అనుసరించి వాటికి విధేయత చూపించేందుకు సంసిద్ధంగా ఉంటారు. అటువంటి నియమ నిబంధనలు కొన్ని మౌలిక హక్కులు, కర్తవ్యాలను నిర్దేశిస్తాయి. సామాజిక, రాజకీయ సంస్థలలో ప్రజలే సభ్యులుగా అంతిమంగా కొనసాగుతారు. సామాజిక సహకారం ద్వారా ప్రజలకు ఎన్నో ప్రయోజనాలు లభిస్తాయి.డేవిడ్ మిల్లర్ సామాజిక న్యాయం అనేది సమాజంలో మంచి చెడుల పంపిణీకి సంబంధించినది. మంచి ఎన్నో ప్రయోజనాలు, చెడు ద్వారా ఎన్నో నష్టాలు ప్రజలకు ఒనగూరుతాయి. సామాజిక రాజకీయ సంస్థలు ఏ విధంగా ప్రజల మధ్య వనరుల పంపిణీకి చర్యలు తీసుకొంటాయనే విషయాన్ని సామాజిక న్యాయం సూచిస్తుందని మిల్లర్ పేర్కొన్నాడు. సామాజిక న్యాయం ద్వారా ప్రజలు విద్య, ఉపాధి, ఆరోగ్యం, సంపద, సంక్షేమం, రవాణా వంటి రంగాలలో అనేక ప్రయోజనాలను పొందుతారని ఉద్ఘాటించాడు. అయితే సామాజిక న్యాయం వల్ల కొన్ని దుష్ఫరిణామాలు ఎదురవుతాయని అతడు హెచ్చరించాడు. వ్యక్తుల స్వీయ వ్యవహారాలలో రాజ్యం జోక్యం, వ్యక్తులు నిర్బంధంగా సైనిక పరమైన సేవలను అందించడం వంటి దుష్ఫరిణామాలు ఉంటాయని పేర్కొన్నాడు.మిల్లర్ సిద్ధాంతం ప్రభుత్వ, ప్రైవేటురంగాలు రెండింటికీ వర్తిస్తుంది. అతడి సిద్ధాంతం ప్రకారం సామాజిక న్యాయం అనేది సామాజిక సుగుణంగా భావిస్తుంది. వ్యక్తులు సమాజంలో వేటిని కలిగిఉంటారో, సమాజానికి వారు అందించాల్సినవి ఏమిటో అనే విషయాన్ని ఇతడి సిద్ధాంతం ప్రస్తావించింది."},{"question":"N'akwụkwọ nsọ, onye Nwe Anyị kwuru sị","answer":"Ụnụ atụla egwu ndị n'egbu anụ arụ, ma ha apụghị ịla mkpụrụ Obi na anụ ahụ n'iyi n'ọkụ ala mmụọ. Ma agụọlarị́ agịrị isi unu niile ọnụ."},{"question":"Zer da fotosintesia?","answer":"Fotosintesia landareen, algaren eta zenbait bakterioen prozesu kimikoa da, argiaren energia erabiliz karbono dioxidoa eta ura glukosara eta oxigenora eraldatzen dutena."},{"question":"W oparciu o poniższy fragment, odpowiedz na poniższe pytanie. Według autora, Douglasa Hofstadtera, jaki jest temat przewodni książki \\"Gödel, Escher, Bach\\"? W odpowiedzi na zamieszanie związane z tematem książki, Hofstadter podkreślił, że \\"Gödel, Escher, Bach\\" nie dotyczy relacji matematyki, sztuki i muzyki, ale raczej tego, jak poznanie wyłania się z ukrytych mechanizmów neurologicznych. W pewnym fragmencie książki przedstawiono analogię tego, jak poszczególne neurony w mózgu koordynują się, tworząc jednolite poczucie spójnego rytmu, porównując go do organizacji społecznej charakterystycznej, na przykład w koloniach mrówek.","answer":"Oto odpowiedź: według Hofstadtera, głównym tematem Gödela, Eschera, Bacha jest to, jak zrozumienie świata wynika z ukrytych mechanizmów neurologicznych."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : భక్తి ఉద్యమం మరియు సూఫీ ఉద్యమం నుండి ప్రస్తుత సమాజం ఏమి నేర్చుకోవచ్చు?","answer":"భక్తి ఉద్యమం మరియు సూఫీ ఉద్యమం నుండి ప్రస్తుత సమాజం నేర్చుకోవలసినవి :కుల, మత అసమానతలను పారద్రోలాలని.శ్రామికులకు (శ్రమకు) గౌరవం ఇవ్వాలని.ప్రాంతీయ భాషలను అభివృద్ధి చేయాలని.నిరాడంబర పూజా విధానాన్ని, జీవన విధానాన్ని అనుసరించాలని.క్రమశిక్షణతో కూడిన జీవనం సాగించాలని.పరమత సహనం కలిగి ఉండాలని.తోటివారి పట్ల దయ, సోదరభావం కల్గి ఉండాలని."},{"question":"Жөнөкөй жана татаал сын атоочтор  деген эмне ?","answer":"Бир сөздөн турган сын атооч жөнөкөй сын атооч болот.М и с а л ы: мээримдүү, акылдуу, жарык.Эки же андан ашык сөздөрдүн тизмегинен туруп, бир маанинитүшүндүргөн сын атоочтор татаал сын атоочтор деп аталат. Аларкош сөз жана кошмок сөз түрүндө болот.М и с а л ы: бийик-бийик, абдан кооз, эң сонун ж. б."},{"question":"问题：三星耳机在语音通话质量方面有何创新？","answer":"答案：三星耳机采用降噪技术和双麦克风设计，提供清晰的语音通话质量。"},{"question":"Inona no oniversite tranainy indrindra eran-tany mbola miasa?","answer":"Ny Anjerimanontolon'i \\"Al-Qarawiyyin\\", naorina tamin'ny taona 859 tao Fez, Maroc , no heverina ho oniversite tranainy indrindra miasa tsy tapaka teto an-tany, nanome fampianarana nandritra ny 1100 taona mahery."},{"question":"问：在旅游行业中，什么是生态旅游？","answer":"答：生态旅游是一种注重环保和当地文化保护的旅游方式，旨在实现旅游业的可持续发展。"},{"question":"Kodi mbiri ya National Bank of Malawi ndi chiyani?","answer":"National Bank of Malawi plc idakhazikitsidwa mchaka cha 1971 kudzera mu mgwirizano wa Barclays Bank DCO (Dominion Colonial Overseas) ndi Standard Bank. Yotsirizirayi idachokera ku Republic of South Africa ndipo idapezeka ku Africa konse."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Lấy cảm hứng từ quá trình phủ xanh của Singapore, Bình Dương ưu tiên quỹ đất phát triển mảng xanh, tạo mô hình thành phố không rác, đáng sống.Thông tin được nêu tại buổi giới thiệu về hành trình phủ xanh của đất nước Singapore và định hướng mục tiêu phát triển cây xanh ","answer":"và bảo vệ môi trường tỉnh Bình Dương, hôm 14/8.Ông Chuah Hock Seong - Giám đốc Tổ hợp công viên tại Singapore, cho biết dự án phủ xanh Singapore do Thủ tướng Lý Quang Diệu phát động từ năm 1963 với tầm nhìn tạo ra một \\"thành phố trong vườn\\". Quốc gia này đã \\"xanh hóa\\" các con đường và cơ sở hạ tầng, biến các công viên và khu vườn thành không gian phục vụ cộng đồng."},{"question":"السؤال: شحال من مرة ربح النادي الإفريقي التونسي بطولة الدوري الممتاز (حتى لعام 2019) ؟","answer":"الإجابة: 13 لقب."},{"question":"ਜੀਵ ਵਿਭਿੰਨਤਾ (Biodiversity) ਦੀ ਸੁਹਜਾਤਮਕ ਮਹੱਤਤਾ (Aesthetic value) ਦਾ ਵਰਣਨ ਕਰੋ ।","answer":"ਕਈ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਪੰਛੀਆਂ, ਕਈ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਰੰਗਾਂ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਤਿੱਤਲੀਆਂ, ਥਣਧਾਰੀ ਜੀਵ ਅਤੇ ਹਰੇ-ਭਰੇ ਜੰਗਲਾਂ ਦੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਜਾਤੀ ਲਈ ਬੜੀ ਸੁਹਜਾਤਮਕ ਮਹੱਤਤਾ ਹੈ ।ਕਈ ਪੌਦਿਆਂ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਿ ਪਿੱਪਲ, ਤੁਲਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਖਿਜਰੀ ਆਦਿ ਨੂੰ ਪਵਿੱਤਰ ਮੰਨਦਿਆਂ ਹੋਇਆਂ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿਚ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਪੂਜਾ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Apakah lagu kebangsaan Malaysia?","answer":"Negaraku"},{"question":"வினா:”நல்ல மாணவன்” என்பது?","answer":"விடை: குறிப்புப் பெயரெச்சம்"},{"question":" МКБ - кыскартылган сөзүнүн түшүндүрмөсү кандай?","answer":"МКБ— маалымат консультациялык борбору."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي مقاسات الطوب المفرغ العادي في الأردن؟","answer":"الإجابة: 40×20×10 أو 40×20×15 أو 40×20×20"},{"question":"Kí ni orúkọ gómínà ìpínlẹ̀ Lagos?","answer":"Ọlọ́lájùlọ Babajide Sanwo-Olu ni."},{"question":"Em hãy viết bài văn ngắn khoảng 250 từ để miêu tả cây hoa lan nhà em","answer":"Ông ngoại em là một người rất yêu hoa. Trong căn nhà nhỏ nơi ông bà sống có trồng rất nhiều hoa. Và em thích nhất là những giỏ phong lan của ông trước hiên nhà.Trước hiên nhà, dưới mái hiên râm mát của ông có 3 giỏ phong lan rất đẹp. Mỗi giỏ không quá to, nhỏ thôi. Chậu màu nâu đất, chỉ to cỡ khoảng một chiếc bát tô. Trên chậu có những lỗ tròn như bị ai đó khoét ra vậy. Ông em nói những lỗ đó là để cho cây lan hô hấp, hấp thụ khí oxy. Trong giỏ của ông, mỗi giỏ chỉ trồng có 1 cây phong lan thôi, nhỏ lắm. Mỗi cây vươn ra làm 3 nhánh, thân cây màu xanh, mềm mại tạo thành một đường cong duyên dáng.Lá hoa màu xanh, lá dài, đầu lá hơi nhọn. Hồi còn bé nghịch ngợm, em còn bắc ghế đứng lên sờ thử lá phong lan ra sao. Một cảm giác mềm mịn thích tay vô cùng. Ba nhánh nhưng mỗi cây lại chỉ ra 2 nhánh hoa mà thôi. Bởi vậy nên hoa phong lan quý lắm. Hoa phong lan ông em trồng có màu trắng. Mỗi nhánh có khoảng từ 5 đến 7 bông hoa nho nhỏ, giống như chuỗi hoa chuông vậy. Cánh hoa thuôn dài, xếp cạnh nhau che chở ôm ấp nhụy hoa bên trong. Hương hoa dịu nhẹ thoang thoảng trong không gian khiến lòng người dễ chịu và mê mẩn.Thi thoảng em lại thấy có vài anh chị học sinh đi học ngang qua, hương phong lan như níu giữ đôi chân, đôi mắt tò mò ngẩn ngơ mà tìm kiếm nơi mang tới hương thơm kia rồi lại vội vã chạy đi về. Người ta nói, người trồng hoa phong lan là người có tâm hồn thanh cao và liêm khiết, giản dị, lại rất yêu hoa. Quả thật vậy. Hàng ngày, ông ngoại đều cầm một bình xịt nước nhỏ, tưới nước cho cây, nên hoa luôn rất đẹp và tươi lâu. Ai động đến giỏ hoa, ông đều lo lắm.Em rất yêu loài hoa này. Dường như em cũng được ông truyền cho tình yêu hoa, sắc trắng của phong lan luôn thấp thoáng trong tâm trí em mỗi lần thấy mái hiên nhà ngoại."},{"question":"ਫਰਵਰੀ ਮਹੀਨੇ ’ਚ ਵੈਲਨਟਾਈਨ ਡੇ  ਭਾਵ ਪਿਆਰ ਦਾ ਦਿਨ ਹੋਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਬਹੁਤੀਆਂ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ  ਇਸ ਵਿਸ਼ੇ ’ਤੇ ਆਧਾਰਤ ਹੁੰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ। ਇਨ੍ਹੀਂ ਦਿਨੀਂ ਇੱਕ ਵਾਰ ਫਿਰ ਰੁਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਕਾਮੇਡੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਦੌਰ ਚੱਲ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ, ਇਸ ਲਈ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਖੋ, ਉਹੀ ਰੁਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਕਾਮੇਡੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਬਣਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਸਭ ਦੇ ਚੱਲਦੇ 21 ਸਾਲ ਦੀ ਉਮਰ ’ਚ ‘ਆਸ਼ਿਕ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਆਪਨੇ’ ਜਿਹੀ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਫਿਲਮ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਆਦਿਤਿਯ ਦੱਤ ਕਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਰਹਿ ਸਕਦੇ ਸਨ। ਉਹ ਵੀ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਖਰੀ ਰੁਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਕਾਮੇਡੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਵਿਲ ਯੂ  ਮੈਰੀ ਮੀ’ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਆ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਦਾਅਵਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਅਖੀਰ ਤਕ  ਇਸ ਗੱਲ ਦਾ ਅੰਦਾਜ਼ਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲਗਾਇਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਕਿ ਕਿਹੜਾ ਪਾਤਰ ਕਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਾਏਗਾ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਵਿਲ ਯੂ ਮੈਰੀ ਮੀ’ ਤਿੰਨ ਦੋਸਤਾਂ ਆਰਵ (ਸ਼੍ਰੇਅਸ ਤਲਪੜੇ), ਰਾਜਵੀਰ (ਰਾਜੀਵ ਖੰਡੇਲਵਾਲ) ਤੇ ਨਿਖਿਲ (ਮੁਜਮਿਲ ਇਬਰਾਹਿਮ) ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਹੈ। ਤਿੰਨੇ ਬਚਪਨ ਦੇ ਦੋਸਤ ਹਨ ਜੋ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਖੇਡਦੇ-ਕੁੱਦਦੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਹੋਏ ਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਸਾਥ ਹੀ ਅੱਗੇ ਵਧੇ। ਤਿੰਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਸ਼ਰਤ ਰੱਖੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ’ਚੋਂ ਜਿਹੜਾ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਾਏਗਾ, ਉਹ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਡੀ ਰਕਮ ਆਪਣੇ ਦੂਜੇ ਦੋਸਤਾਂ ਲਈ ਖਰਚ ਕਰੇਗਾ। ਕੁਝ ਸਮੇਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਨਿਖਿਲ ਆਪਣੀ ਪ੍ਰੇਮਿਕਾ ਅੰਜਲੀ (ਤ੍ਰਿਪਤਾ ਪਰਾਸ਼ਰ) ਨਾਲ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਰਾਜਵੀਰ ਤੇ ਆਰਵ ਨੂੰ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਤਾਂ ਯਕੀਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਦੋਸਤ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਜਦੋਂ ਵਿਆਹ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਡ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਦੋਨੋਂ ਦੋਸਤ ‘ਬੀਚ ਵੈਡਿੰਗ’ ਲਈ ਦੁਬਈ ਪਹੁੰਚ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ। ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਸਮਾਗਮ ’ਚ ਰਾਜਵੀਰ ਅਤੇ ਆਰਵ ਨੂੰ ਅੰਜਲੀ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਸ ਦੋਸਤ ਸਨੇਹਾ (ਮੁਗਧਾ ਗੋਡਸੇ) ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰ ਬੈਠਦੇ ਹਨ। ਇਸ ਤਿਕੋਣੀ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਦਾ ਦੁਖ਼ਦ ਪੱਖ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇੱਕ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਉਦਯੋਗਪਤੀ (ਪਰੇਸ਼ ਰਾਵਲ), ਨਿਖਿਲ ਨੂੰ ਅਗਵਾ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਨਤੀਜਾ ਨਿਖਿਲ ਤੇ ਅੰਜਲੀ ਦੇ ਵਿਆਹ ਸਮਾਗਮ ’ਚ ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਉਲਟਾ-ਪੁਲਟਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਕੀ ਨਿਖਿਲ, ਅੰਜਲੀ ਨਾਲ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰ ਸਕੇਗਾ? ਦੂਜੇ ਪਾਸੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡਾ ਸਵਾਲ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸਨੇਹਾ, ਰਾਜਵੀਰ ਅਤੇ ਆਰਵ ’ਚੋਂ ਕਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰੇਗੀ?ਸੁਪਰਹਿੱਟ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਆਸ਼ਿਕ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਆਪਨੇ’ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ‘ਦਿਲ ਦੀਆ ਹੈ’ ਜਿਹੀ ਅਸਫ਼ਲ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਤ ਕਰ ਚੁੱਕੇ ਆਦਿਤਿਯ ਆਪਣੀ ਇਸ ਤੀਜੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਪੂਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਆਸਵੰਦ ਹਨ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਮਨੋਰੰਜਨ ਭਰਪੂਰ ਰੁਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਤਿਕੋਣੀ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਵੀ ਹੈ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਪੂਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਵਰਗ ਲਈ ਬਣਾਈ ਗਈ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਲਈ ਚਾਰ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਸੰਗੀਤਕਾਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਜੋੜਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਕਹਾਣੀ ’ਚ ਮਨੋਰੰਜਨ ਹੀ ਮਨੋਰੰਜਨ ਹੈ। ਕਿਤੇ ਕੋਈ ਸੰਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇਣ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਹੈ। ਹਸਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਬੇਵਕੂਫ਼ੀ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਹਰਕਤਾਂ ਵੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹਨ। ਇਹ ਮੌਜੂਦਾ ਸਮੇਂ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਅੰਤ ਤਕ ਇਹੀ ਪਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਕਿ ਕਿਸ ਦਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ। ਐਨਾ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਮੱਧ ਤਕ ਤਾਂ ਇਹ ਵੀ ਪਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਚੱਲਦਾ ਕਿ ਰਾਜਵੀਰ, ਆਰਵ ਤੇ ਸਨੇਹਾ ’ਚੋਂ ਕੌਣ, ਕਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਪਟਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ।ਰੁਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਕਾਮੇਡੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਵਿਲ ਯੂ ਮੈਰੀ ਮੀ’ ਦੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੀ ਖਾਸੀਅਤ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨੂੰ ਦੁਬਈ ਅਤੇ ਬੈਂਕਾਕ ਦੇ ਸਮੁੰਦਰੀ ਬੀਚ ਦੀਆਂ ਸ਼ਾਨਦਾਰ ਲੋਕੇਸ਼ਨਾਂ ’ਤੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਦਸ ਦਿਨ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੂਟਿੰਗ ਮੁੰਬਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ।ਮਜ਼ੇਦਾਰ ਗੱਲ ਜੋ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਆਦਿਤਿਯ ਦੱਸਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਇਸ ਲਈ ਵੀ ਅਨੂਠੀ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਮਸਲਾ ਮੇਰੀ ਨਿੱਜੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਹੋ ਚੁੱਕਿਆ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਤੋਂ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਿਤ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਮੈਂ ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਲਿਖੀ, ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨ ਚੌਧਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਸੁਣਾਇਆ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਪਸੰਦ ਆਈ ਅਤੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਬਣ ਗਈ।ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਚੌਧਰੀ ਤੇ ਵਿਪਿਨ ਜੈਨ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਸਚਿਨ ਗੁਪਤਾ ਤੇ ਸ਼ਰੀਬ ਤੋਸ਼ੀ ਨੇ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ‘ਦਿਲ ਦੀਆ ਹੈ’ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਕੌਣ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ ‘ਦਿਲ ਦੀਆ ਹੈ’ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਆਦਿਤਿਯ ਦੱਤ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"யானை தன் வாய்நிறை கொண்ட வலிதேம்பு தடக்கை குன்றுபுகு பாம்பின் தோன்றும் – இப்பாடலில் பயின்று வரும் படிமத்தை விளக்குக.","answer":"இப்பாடலில் மெய்ப்படிமம் பயின்று வந்துள்ளது. மதங்கொண்ட யானையானது தன் வாய்க்குள் துதிக்கையின் மூலம் உணவை வைக்கிறது. யானையின் வாய் மலைக்குகை வாயினைப் போல் உள்ளதாகவும். துதிக்கை மலைக்குகையில் நுழையும் பாம்பினைப் போல் உள்ளதாகவும் வடிவத்தைக் காட்சிப்படுத்தியுள்ளார்."},{"question":"Исхак Раззаковдун атында кайсы университет аталган?","answer":"Исхак Раззаковдун атында \\"Кыргыз Мамлекеттик Техникалык Университет\\" аталган."},{"question":"Wala nabay pulos ang mga universities karon?","answer":"A kumbinasyo sa mga nitaas nga mga pambayaran na tuition ug sa pag transition sa remote learning kay basin maoy mahimong ningtungdan sa pagkawala sa mga universities puhon. Nakasayod tanan sa expectation sa kada tao nga naka graduate sa university pero ang mga goals sa mga estudyante kay ga usab na. Ang abilidad sa pag network or sa pagsikat aron mulambo sa imong career or pag ila nimo kay dili na lisod gawas sa mga institutes. Bisan sa pag access sa mga venture capital ug sa mga negosyo, athletic ug sa ubang mga dagko sa industrya kay dali nalang mabuhat sa uban na pamaagi."},{"question":"世界三大美女の1人と言われ、酢に真珠を溶かして飲んだと伝えられるエジプトの女王は誰？","answer":"クレオパトラです。"},{"question":"මොළයේ ඇති සෛල මොනවාද?","answer":"නියුරෝන"},{"question":"السؤال: كيف نزل القرآن الكريم على رسول الله صلّى الله عليه وسلّم؟","answer":"الجواب: نزل مفرّقًا بواسطة الوحي جبريل عليه السلام."},{"question":"கேள்வி : தாய்லாந்தின் பழைய பெயர் என்ன ?","answer":" தாய்லாந்து வரலாற்றில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க நிகழ்வுகள் மற்றும் மக்கள் பற்றிய ஆய்வு . தென்கிழக்கு ஆசியாவின் பிரதான நிலப்பகுதியின் மையத்தில் அமைந்துள்ள தாய்லாந்து இரண்டு பரந்த புவியியல் பகுதிகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளது: வடக்கில் ஒரு பெரிய, முக்கிய பகுதி மற்றும் தெற்கில் ஒரு சிறிய, தீபகற்ப விரிவாக்கம் . 1939 வரை தாய்லாந்து அதிகாரப்பூர்வமாக அழைக்கப்பட்ட சியாம், ஐரோப்பிய காலனி ஆதிக்கத்தின் கீழ் கொண்டு வரப்படவில்லை . சுதந்திர சியாம் 1932 இல் ஒரு புரட்சி வரை ஒரு முழுமையான முடியாட்சியால் ஆளப்பட்டது . அந்த நேரத்தில் இருந்து, தாய்லாந்து ஒரு அரசியலமைப்பு முடியாட்சியாக இருந்து வருகிறது , மேலும் அனைத்து அடுத்தடுத்த அரசியலமைப்புகளும் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட பாராளுமன்றத்தை வழங்கியுள்ளன. எவ்வாறாயினும், அரசியல் அதிகாரம் பெரும்பாலும் இராணுவத்தால் நடத்தப்பட்டது, இது சதிப்புரட்சி மூலம் அதிகாரத்தை கைப்பற்றியது . 20 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டின் கடைசி இரண்டு தசாப்தங்களிலும் 21 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டின் முதல் தசாப்தத்திலும், நாடாளுமன்ற ஜனநாயகம் சீராக பரந்த மக்கள் ஆதரவைப் பெற்றது. 2006 இல் ஒரு நெருக்கடி தோன்றினாலும், முடியாட்சியுடன் இணைந்த இராணுவம் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட அரசாங்கத்தை கவிழ்த்தபோது, ​​​​புதிய பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தல்கள் நடத்தப்பட்டன - இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தால் வாக்குறுதியளிக்கப்பட்டபடி - 2007 இல்.தாய்லாந்துதாய்லாந்துதாய் மொழி பேசும் மக்களின் மிகப் பெரிய குழுவிலிருந்து வந்தவர்கள் . பிந்தையவை மேற்கில் தீவிர வடகிழக்கு இந்தியாவிலிருந்து கிழக்கில் வடக்கு வியட்நாம் வரையிலும், வடக்கில் தெற்கு சீனாவிலிருந்து மத்திய மலாய் தீபகற்பம் வரை தெற்கிலும் காணப்படுகின்றன . கடந்த காலத்தில், புரோட்டோ-தாய் என்று அழைக்கப்படும் ஒரு பெற்றோர் குழு தெற்கு சீனாவில் தோன்றியதாகவும், சீனாவின் நிலப்பரப்பில் இருந்து தெற்கு மற்றும் மேற்கு நோக்கி வடக்கு பிரதான நிலப்பகுதியான தென்கிழக்கு ஆசியாவிற்குள் தள்ளப்பட்டதாகவும் அறிஞர்கள் கருதுகின்றனர் . பெரும்பாலான அறிஞர்கள் இப்போது தை வட வியட்நாமில் இருந்து Dien Bien Phu பகுதியைச் சுற்றி வந்ததாகவும், சுமார் 1,000 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு அங்கிருந்து வடக்கே தெற்கு சீனாவிற்குப் பரவியதாகவும் நம்புகிறார்கள் ; மேற்கு நோக்கி தென்மேற்கு சீனா, வடக்கு மியான்மர் (பர்மா) மற்றும் வடகிழக்கு இந்தியா; மற்றும் தெற்கு நோக்கி இப்போது லாவோஸ் மற்றும் தாய்லாந்து."},{"question":"বরিশাল জিলা স্কুলের দশম শ্রেণির শিক্ষার্থীরা বাংলাদেশের দক্ষিণ-পূর্বাঞ্চলে শিক্ষাসফরে যায়। তারা সেখানে একটি নদী দেখতে পায়। ৩২০ কি.মি. দৈর্ঘ্যের এ নদীটি চট্টগ্রামের কাছ দিয়ে বঙ্গোপসাগরে পড়েছে। এ নদীটির অনেকগুলো উপনদীও রয়েছে। এই নদীর তীরে গড়ে উঠেছে অনেক শিল্প ও কল-কারখানা। তুমি কি মনে কর উক্ত নদী শুধু ব্যবসা-বাণিজ্যের জন্য গুরুত্বপূর্ণ? তোমার মতামত দাও।","answer":"উদ্দীপকে কর্ণফুলী নদীর কথা বলা হয়েছে। আমি মনে করি কর্ণফুলী নদী শুধু ব্যবসা-বাণিজ্যের জন্য গুরুত্বপূর্ণ নয়; বরং অন্যান্য ক্ষেত্রেও এর অনেক গুরত্ব আছে।কর্ণফুলী নদীর উৎপত্তি হয়েছে ভারতের মিজোরাম অঙ্গরাজ্যের লুসাই পাহাড়ে। বাংলাদেশের দক্ষিণ-পূর্বাঞ্চলের মধ্য দিয়ে প্রায় ৩২০ কি.মি. পথ অতিক্রম করে নদীটি বঙ্গোপসাগরে পড়েছে। আমাদের প্রধান সমুদ্র বন্দর চট্টগ্রাম এই নদীর তীরেই অবস্থিত। তাই দেশের আমদানি এবং রপ্তানি বাণিজ্যে কর্ণফুলী অত্যন্ত গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ভূমিকা পালন করছে। তবে ব্যবসা-বাণিজ্য ছাড়াও নদীটির আরও অনেক গুরুত্ব আছে।কর্ণফুলী বহুমুখী পরিকল্পনার ফলে ৬৪৪ কি.মি. পথে নৌ চলাচল করছে, ১০ লাখ একর জমিতে চাষাবাদ হচ্ছে। কর্ণফুলী একটি পাহাড়ি খরস্রোতা নদী বলে পার্বত্য চট্টগ্রামের কাপ্তাইয়ে এ নদীতে বাঁধ দিয়ে জলবিদ্যুৎ উৎপাদন করা হচ্ছে। পাকিস্তান আমলে এ বাঁধ নির্মাণের ফলে পাহাড়ের বিশাল আকারের নিচু এলাকা স্থায়ীভাবে প্লাবিত হয়। তবে বৃহত্তর চট্টগ্রাম অঞ্চলকে বড় বন্যা থেকে মুক্ত রাখা সম্ভব হয়েছে। এ ছাড়া চট্টগ্রাম অঞ্চলের লোকজ সংস্কৃতিতে কর্ণফুলী নদীর গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ভূমিকা রয়েছে। অনেক আঞ্চলিক গান, লোককথায় রয়েছে এ নদীর উজ্জ্বল উপস্থিতি।উপরের আলোচনায় প্রমাণিত হয়, ব্যবসা-বাণিজ্য ছাড়াও কৃষি, সংস্কৃতি ইত্যাদি ক্ষেত্রে কর্ণফুলী নদীর গুরুত্বপূর্ণ অবদান রয়েছে।"},{"question":"አፈወርቅ ተክሌ የምህንድስና ትምህርታቸውን ትተው ኪነጥበብ ለማጥናት ለመጀመሪያ ጊዜ የገቡበት ትምህርት ቤት ምን ይባላል?","answer":"በሎንዶን የኪነ ጥበብ ማእከላዊ ትምሕርት ቤት"},{"question":"පහත තේරවිල්ල විසඳන්න.ගියොත් ආයෙත් නොයෙයි       ","answer":"වයස"},{"question":"Kuaförde keratin kaç saat sürer?","answer":"Kuaförde keratin bakımı işlemi genellikle 2 ila 3 saat arasında sürebilir. İşlemden sonra saçlarınız daha sağlıklı, daha parlak, daha düzgün ve daha kolay şekillendirilebilir olacaktır."},{"question":"அங்காடியில் வாங்கிய உணவுப் பொருளின் உருவாக்க நாள், முடிவு நாள், உறையில்அச்சடிக்கப்பட்ட உணவுப்பொருளின் ஆற்றல், குறியீட்டுப் பட்டை ஆகியவற்றின் விவரங்களைக் கொண்டு உணவுப் பொருளின் உண்மைத்தன்மையை எப்படி அறிவது?","answer":"நாம் அங்காடிக்குச் சென்று, உணவுப்பொருள், குளிர்பானங்கள், அழகுசாதனப் பொருள்கள் போன்றவற்றை வாங்கும்போது, அதன் உறைகளிலோ அல்லது மேல் அட்டைப் பெட்டியிலோ குறியீட்டு பட்டை அமைந்திருக்கும், அதன் உண்மைத் தன்மையை ஆராயும் முறை. குறியீட்டுப் பட்டை இடம் பெற்றிருக்கும் பகுதியை கணினியுடன் கூடிய ஒளிக் கதிர் மூலம் வருடும் போது அப்பொருளின் எடை, விலை, உற்பத்தி செய்த இடம், உற்பத்தி செய்த நாள், எந்த நாள் வரை பயன்படுத்தலாம் (முடிவு நாள்); அப்பொருளில் அடங்கியிருக்கும் பிறபொருள்களின் அளவு, தன்மை, உற்பத்தி உரிமம் போன்ற அனைத்து விபரங்களும் திரையில் தெரியவரும்.  இம்முறையில் தான் ஒரு பொருளை வாங்கும்பொழுது ஆராய்ந்து வாங்குதல் வேண்டும்."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Mới đây tại Hà Nội, một triển lãm thú vị về nghề kiến trúc lại thu hút sự chú ý của nhiều người khi chọn trưng bày những dự án, ý tưởng thiết kế bị khách hàng, chủ đầu tư từ chối. Triển lãm mang tên Kẻ Lữ Hành Kỳ Dị Hay Là Câu Chuyện Của Những Dự Án Bị Từ Chối là một trưng bày kiến trúc của KTS. Nguyễn Hà và các cộng sự. Triển lãm bao gồm 24 mô hình là những đồ án đã dựng lên hoàn chỉnh nhưng bị bỏ ngỏ, những ý tưởng vừa mới thành hình đã bị dập tắt. Tuy nhiên nếu nhìn ở góc độ tích cực, nghệ thuật, đây là triển lãm của những thử nghiệm thuần túy, không bị tác động bởi vấn đề \\"cơm áo gạo tiền\\" mà mang đậm sự sáng tạo, gu thẩm mỹ đặc biệt của kiến trúc sư. Điều thú vị của buổi triển lãm này có lẽ phải kể đến 24 lý do bị khách hàng, chủ đầu tư từ chối khác nhau như: \\"Giám đốc điều hành tập đoàn từ chức\\", \\"Không chịu thiết kế đường đủ to cho ô tô vào tận cửa\\", \\"Chủ đầu tư im lặng\\", \\"Có người hỏi mua đất, được giá, khách bán luôn đất\\",... Với nhiều người đến xem, những lý do này vừa hài hước, \\"lãng xẹt\\" nhưng đôi khi lại rất sâu cay khiến họ suy nghĩ về những vấn đề thực tế. Gần 20 năm hoạt động trong lĩnh vực kiến trúc, KTS. Nguyễn Hà là một người cực giản dị, chỉ muốn được làm nghề thuần túy. Chia sẻ về dự án độc lạ này, nữ kiến trúc sư cho hay đây chỉ là một trong số ít những mô hình dang dở trong suốt hành trình làm nghề của mình. Đã có rất nhiều bản vẽ, mô hình và ý tưởng sau khi đưa ra thuyết trình lại thỏa hiệp bất thành. Tuy nhiên, KTS. Nguyễn Hà cho rằng đây là điều rất đỗi bình thường trong nghề nghiệp, chị chỉ khác những kiến trúc sư khác ở việc lưu lại toàn bộ mô hình và dám mang chúng ra trưng bày. \\"Mỗi sự việc đều có 2 mặt vấn đề, muốn thành công thì phải có thất bại, muốn có cái đẹp phải có cái xấu để đem ra so sánh. Tôi không nghĩ đây là một sự \\"cà khịa\\" đến chủ đầu tư hay bất cứ khách hàng nào. Tôi chỉ muốn truyền tải một thông điệp rằng tất cả những thứ mọi người làm, mọi người sáng tạo bằng cả tâm huyết đều đáng được trân trọng, không có gì đáng để bỏ đi. Chẳng ai dám trưng bày sự thất bại của mình, tôi nghĩ đây là một sự dũng cảm và có thể sẽ nhận về hiệu ứng ngược. Ví dụ chủ đầu tư của những dự án mà tôi đang thực hiện nhìn vào sẽ thấy sao kiến trúc sư toàn thất bại thế này thì mình thành con chuột bạch để thử nghiệm à? Nhưng tôi cũng không ngại điều đó bởi thực tế, họ phải tìm hiểu rất kĩ về tôi và làm việc đủ lâu mới quyết định hợp tác. Tôi cho rằng những khách hàng của tôi cũng là những người rất hay\\", KTS chia sẻ. Bên cạnh đó, KTS. Nguyễn Hà còn bật mí nhiều khách hàng, nhà đầu tư là chủ nhân của những lý do \\"lãng xẹt\\" kia cũng đã đến tham dự triển lãm và đều cảm thấy vui vẻ, thú vị. Trong số đó phải kể đến chị Huyền Bùi đang làm trong ngành bất động sản, là khách hàng thân quen của nữ kiến trúc sư sinh năm 1980. Chị Huyền Bùi chia sẻ: \\"Mình biết đến KTS. Nguyễn Hà trong một lần đi ngang qua công trình và rất ấn tượng với thiết kế đó. Mình đã tìm mọi cách vào hỏi, xin chủ đầu tư xem người thiết kế ra dự án này là ai và từ đó biết đến chị Hà. Cũng thông qua lần đó, mình trở thành chủ đầu tư và làm việc với chị Hà. Trong suốt khoảng thời gian làm việc, cũng có những ý tưởng, quan điểm trái ngược nhau nhưng cuối cùng vẫn có sự thống nhất cao để có thể hiện thực hóa tất cả bản vẽ vào thực tế từ chi phí đầu tư đến ý tưởng. Bởi độc đáo mà không có tính khả thi thì cũng rất khó trở thành công trình hoàn thiện. Trong các tác phẩm ngày hôm nay, có một dự án của mình và chị Hà, là ngôi nhà ven sông với lý do tạm ngừng \\"kiến trúc sư tự thấy quá phức tạp\\". Tuy nhiên đề án được làm ra 3 mô hình, tuy nhiên mô hình trưng bày tại đây thì không được lựa chọn mà đã chọn một mô hình khác\\". Có mặt trong buổi triển lãm, KTS. Hồ Mộng Long - người cũng từng thử sức với nhiều dự án táo bạo dành lời khen ngợi cho đồng nghiệp của mình. Anh cũng cho rằng, triển lãm mang đến nhiều sự sáng tạo, thú vị và có thể nhìn nhận được cách làm việc nghiêm túc, tỉ mỉ đến từ người làm nghề tâm huyết. \\"Mình cũng gặp nhiều trường hợp bị từ chối trong gần 20 năm làm nghề. Điều này cũng hết sức bình thường. Nhưng qua triển lãm, mình nghĩ đây cũng là dịp để các kiến trúc sư nhìn lại và có thêm động lực để mình theo đuổi công việc này. Có thể nhiều người cho rằng, kiến trúc sư không hiểu khách hàng, làm sai hướng của chủ đầu tư nên mới thất bại. Tuy nhiên thực chất, công việc này không dừng lại ở tư duy đáp ứng. Thông thường, cách làm việc của mình là xem đề bài khách đưa có phù hợp không, sau đó, mình đưa rõ quan điểm là chúng ta làm cùng nhau, chứ không phải ai làm việc cho ai. Như vậy sẽ hạn chế được rủi ro và cũng khiến nhà đầu tư hiểu rõ hơn về sản phẩm thiết kế của mình\\", KTS. Hồ Mộng Long chia sẻ. Bên cạnh những kiến trúc sư nổi tiếng, có rất nhiều bạn trẻ chỉ là \\"ma mới\\" trong nghề, có cả những người không làm trong lĩnh vực này cũng đến tham quan và bày tỏ sự thích với triển lãm \\"có 1-0-2\\" này. Đang làm việc trong nghề truyền thông, cũng thường xuyên phải làm việc với khách hàng, Châu Anh cho biết: \\"Mình cực kì ấn tượng với triển lãm bởi những lý do vô cùng hài hước, mình cảm thấy sự đồng cảm trong đó. Mình hiểu cảm giác khi một dự án bị hủy hay từ chối đều rất là buồn. Thế nhưng ở đây, các kiến trúc sư đã biến nỗi buồn đó thành một điều gây cười, mình nghĩ đó là điều khiến các bạn trẻ thích thú và dù mới khai mạc đã có rất đông người đến xem\\". Cùng ý kiến với Châu Anh, Phương Dung cho hay bình thường đi triển lãm, cô luôn mong muốn có thể mang về những bức ảnh \\"sống ảo\\" nhưng khi đến đây, cô còn có được nhiều hơn thế. \\"Mình biết đến triển lãm vì sáng nay mọi người chia sẻ rầm rộ trên MXH. Đến đây, mình không chỉ thưởng lãm nghệ thuật, chụp ảnh mà còn đọng lại nhiều cảm xúc. Bởi ngoài sự hài hước, mình hiểu được tâm huyết của kiến trúc sư để vào trong tác phẩm của mình. Dù bị từ chối nhưng đây lại là những ý tưởng nguyên bản và mình thích điều này\\", Phương Dung nói. Chỉ mới bắt đầu làm việc trong ngành kiến trúc 2 năm nay nhưng Đậu Được cũng ngậm ngùi cho hay anh đã nhiều lần trải qua cảm giác buồn bã khi bị khách hàng \\"chê\\" sản phẩm của mình. \\"Điều đầu tiên mình phải dành lời khen là ý tưởng của triển lãm thực sự rất hay và mới mẻ. Cách mọi người quảng bá đơn giản nhưng lại thu hút rất đông bạn trẻ kể cả những người không trong ngành bởi câu chuyện với khách hàng, ai mà chẳng có. Còn về góc độ chuyên môn, triển lãm như trở thành một động lực để cho những bạn trẻ đang làm nghề như mình thêm yêu và kiên nhẫn hơn trên con đường này. Bởi tại đây, những mô hình quá hoành tráng, những dự án quá lớn còn đổ bể thì mình hiểu bản thân phải cố gắng hơn thế nào\\", Đậu Được nói. Còn Nguyệt Minh, cô nàng đến triển lãm với tâm thế \\"dạo chơi\\" nhưng lại bị hút hồn ngay từ những mô hình đầu tiên. Cô chia sẻ, dù bản thân không quá hiểu về kiến trúc nhưng cũng rất ấn tượng bởi những dự án được tạo dựng tỉ mỉ, chi tiết, thấy rõ cái tâm của người sáng tạo. Đặc biệt, Nguyệt Minh rất thích cách mà KTS. Nguyễn Hà kể câu chuyện \\"thất bại\\" của mình một cách dửng dưng, thực tế, có sao nói vậy nhưng lại \\"trúng tim đen\\" của phần đông người xem. Một số hình ảnh khác tại triển lãm:","answer":"Triển lãm những dự án kiến trúc bị từ chối đang gây sốt ở Hà Nội: Người tổ chức nói gì về ý tưởng độc đáo này?"},{"question":"本が沢山売れることを､ 中国の都市の名を取って｢どこの紙価を高める｣というでしょう？","answer":"洛陽です。"},{"question":"No português do Brasil, a palavra \\"amigo\\" tem quantas sílabas?","answer":"A palavra \\"amigo\\" tem 3 sílabas: a-mi-go."},{"question":"सगरमाथा कति मिटर उचाई भएको छ?","answer":"सगरमाथा 8,848.86 मिटर उचाई भएको छ।"},{"question":"Iza no renivohitr'i \\"Allemagne\\" ?","answer":"Ny renivohitr'i \\"Allemagne\\"dia \\"Berlin\\". \\"Berlin\\" koa no tanàna lehibe indrindra any \\"Allemagne\\" ary manana tantara manankarena sy sarotra."},{"question":"भारतातील सगळ्यात उंच धरण ‘भाक्रा धरण’ कोणत्या नदीवर बांधले गेले आहे?(A) झेलम नदीवर(B) गोदावरी नदीवर(C) सतलज नदीवर(D) व्यास नदीवर=>","answer":" (C) सतलज नदीवर"},{"question":"இந்தியாவின் ஏவுகணைப் பெண் என்று அழைக்கப்படுபவர் யார்?","answer":"டெஸ்ஸி தாமஸ் இந்தியாவின் ஏவுகணை பெண் என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறார். 'அக்னி புத்ரி' என்றும் அழைக்கப்படும் இவர் ஒரு சிறந்த இந்திய விஞ்ஞானி மற்றும் இந்தியாவில் ஏவுகணைத் திட்டத்தை வழிநடத்திய முதல் பெண் விஞ்ஞானி ஆவார்."},{"question":"Кыргыз накыл кептери англис тилинде жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Never put off till tomorrow what you can do today – Бүгүн бүтчү ишти эртеңкиге калтырба."},{"question":"Категориялар деген эмне ?","answer":"Категориялар (байыркы грек. κατηγορία (kategoria) – аныктама, пикир) – курчап турган дүйнө менен таанымдын өтө маанилүү, универсалдуу касиеттери менен алакаларын чагылдырган өтө жалпы жана фундаменталдуу түшүнүктөр.Категориялар тааным менен тажрыйбанын тарыхый өнүгүшүн жалпылоонун натыйжасында пайда болушкан (мисалы: [[заттек жана аң-сезим, мейкиндик жана убакыт, себеп жана натыйжа, зарылдык жана кокустук, мүмкүндүк жана чындык).Категориялар:а) дүйнөнүн сүрөтүн;б) ар кандай объекттерди адам тарабынан өздөштүрүүнүн ыкмаларын;в) жалпы эле болмушту.Анын ичинен адам болмушун түшүнүүнүн нормаларын иштеп чыгуунун каражаты болуп саналган философиялык түшүнүктөр жана ар кандай объекттерди түшүнүүнүн белгилүү бир тибин аныктагандыктан, категориялар адамдын ой жүгүртүүсү жана ишмердиги үчүн маанилүү методологиялык ролду ойношот.Мисалы: «процесс» түшүнүгү категориалдык мааниде каралса, анда бардык кубулуштар, окуялар процесс түрүндө, башкача айтканда дайым өнүгүп, өсүп, калыптанып, динамикалуу алакада болуп турган процесстин калыпында түшүнүлөт.Байыркы мезгилде категориялар нерселердин, кубулуштардын, энергиялардын белгилүү бир типтерин белгилөө үчүн колдонулган. Акырындык менен категориялардын логикалык иштеми ачык байкалып, алардын нерселердин ортосундагы алакалардын өзөктүү типтерин мүнөздөгөн түшүнүк катары ролу анык боло баштаган. Адамдын ишмердүүлүгүн калыптары өнүккөн сайын категориялар жалпылоочу түшүнүккө айланган. түшүнүктөр ар кандай категориялар чиеленген торду элестетет.Категориялардын өз ара алакасы тууралуу маселе философтор арасындагы кызуу талаш-тартыштарды пайда кылат: ал тургай категориялардын эң мыкты системасын түзүүгө карата аракеттер да болгон. Бирок, мындай аракеттерден эч майнап чыккан эмес. Ал тургай Гегелдин категориялар системесынын калыпындагы «гармониялуу» деп эсептелген системанын кризиси көптөгөн философтор тарабынан классикалык философиянын күнүнүн бүтүшү катары кабыл алынган. Табигый жана коомдук процесстердин үстүнөн түзүлгөн категориялардын иерархиялуу системасын курууга болгон философиялык «долбоор» келечексиз гана эмес, негизсиз да экендиги анык болгондо метафизиканын күнү бүттү деп жарыяланылган.Метафизиканы сындоо менен философиянын дарегине айтылган дооматтар төмөнкүдөй мотивтерден турган:1) категориялардын конкреттүү кубулуштардан, окуялардан, алакалардан обочолонгон мүнөз күтүшү,2) турмуш динамикасына, айкын изилдөөлөргө, адамдардын жеке өнүгүшүнө кайдыгер мүнөздөгү категориялар системасынын иерархиясы жана бекемдиги.Мындай мотивдердин аралашуусу философиянын, теориялык жана кадыресе ойломдун категориялык маданияты тууларуу маселени 20-кыымдын философиясында узак мезгилдер бою философиялык изилдөөлөр чөйрөсүнөн сүрүп салган. Бирок, онтологиялык, социалдык-философиялык, экзистенциялдык жана маданият таануу көйгөйлөрүн иштеп чыгуунун жүрүшүндө категориялар тууралуу маселе учурдагы философиянын изилдөө талаасынан чыкпагандыгы анык болгон.Мисалы: жалпы менен жеке, коомдук жана жеке, маданий жана табигый нерселердин иерархиялуулугун сынга алуу аркылуу аталган категориялардын өз ара табигый жана маданий байланышынын негиздерин четке кагуу мүмкүн эмес.Категориялык структураларды сынга алуу категориялык динамиканы четке какпайт. Экзистенциализм тарабынан философияга киргизилген болмуштун экзистенциалдуу көйгөйлөрү адамдын жеке турмуштун тажрыйбасын категориялар аркылуу чагылдырууга болгон аракет болуп саналат. Салтуу рационализмде философиялык маанайда болбосо да, илимий өңүттө категориялардын үстүнөн бир кыйла иш-аракеттер жүргүзүлгөн. Ошого карабастан, система, уюмдашуу, Түзүлүш түшүнүктөрү категориялык статуска ээ болушкан."},{"question":"Siyabonana mndeni wakwaDuma.Yebo ndoda. Sengathi ngiyakwazi nje ndoda.(ngenhlonipho) Yebo baba, uyangazi. Mina ngingunogada wenkosi.(ahlahle amehlo futhi inkulumo igcwale indelelo) Yebo siyakwazi.Manje ufunani lapha?(Uthukuthele futhi ubuka uMbandlwa ngeso lengulube.) Kahle boMbandlwa! Lo muntu akezile kuwe. (Aqondise kuNogada)Usivakashele ngani muntu wenkosi?Ngithunywe nguNdabezitha kubaba uDuma.(abuyise izinhlozi maqede akhulume ngolaka) Hheyi wena, angidingemyalezo wenkosi mina lapha! Angithi yona ingisasazela ngale ndunayayo uDlamini! Angithi mina angikwazi ukwenza umsebenzi wamingenxa yayo?(asukume akhulume ngolaka ekhomba unogada) Habe! Habe! Habe!Ubaba yini? Hheyi wena ndoda! Bona oze ngayo khona manje.(asukume maqede akhombe uMbandlwa ngenkomba yesokunenebese ekhuluma ngolaka) We Mbandlwa! Kukwami lapha! Ngithi,Kukwami lapha! Nawe unekini! UDuma ngeke ahlothoziswa nguwe.Hlala phansi uthule noma uphume uphele lapha kwami. (ahlale phansibese eqondisa kunogada) Shono muntu wenkosi. Uthini uNdabezitha?(ethukuthela) We MaShezi! Ubani umnumzane kuleli khaya? Ungalingiukhulume ngaleyo ndlela kuMbandlwa. UMbandlwa ngunobhala wamifuthi sisuka kude naye. Wawukuphi seqa izinkalo naye sizamaukukhulula abantu? (aqondise kunogada ngoshova) ithini le nkosiyakho?(Bathule bonke balalele ngesikhathi unogada edlulisa umyalezowenkosi.)(ngolaka) Angiyingeni leyo! 1. Kwaba namthelela muni ukushona kukaDlamini empilweni yenkosi uShandu?","answer":"Inkosi yavukwa yisifo senhliziyo yaphathwa yisinxe, yaphuthunyiswaesibhedlela. "},{"question":"Sheeg magaca Safiirkii ugu dambeeyey ee Xukuumaddii Kacaanka u fadhiyey dalka Jarmalka Galbeed?","answer":"Waxaa u fadhiyey Xasan Abshir Faarax."},{"question":"أريد إنشاء قصيدة قصيره من بحر الرجز. هل يمكنك مساعدتي؟","answer":"لَبّاكَ مَشزوزُ القُوى ذَيّالُأَغلَبُ قَوّالُ النَدي فَعّالُمِن قَبلِ أَن تَدعو بِهِ الآمالُإِن قالَ لَم تَقعُد بِهِ الفِعالُيُنيلُ جوداً فَوقَ مايَنالُخُلقٌ رَقيقٌ ماؤُهُ زُلالُكَالخَمرِ إِلّا أَنَّهُ حَلالُالمالُ يَفنى وَالثَناءُ المالُتَبقى العُلى وَتَذهَبُ الرِجالُ"},{"question":"كنت أقرأ في مراجعة ووجدت الجملة التالية 'جيد. نظافة الفندق وتصميمه العصري الحديث وتوفر المواقف للسيارات كان تعامل الطاقم جيدا. موظفة الأستقبال السورية تنقصها الابتسامه وحسن التعامل مع الزبائن ازعاج من خارج الفندق باعمال أنشائيه بجانب الفندق .' ماهي مشاعر الجملة السابقة؟","answer":"المراجعة السابقة تعبرعن مشاعر جيدة جدا."},{"question":"Ndàx man ngaa jubbanti mbind mii?Wax nañu ne: \\"Safara dunu laal lu dul ay bis yu ñuy waññi! \\". Neeleen: \\"Moo ndax dangeen cee déggook Yàlla - te Yàlla du wuute ab digam; - walla dangeen di wax ci Yàlla lu ngeen xamul\\".","answer":"Waaw! Mi ngii:Wàx na ñu ne: \\"Safara du nu laal lu dul ay bis yu ñu'y wàññi!\\". Neeléen: \\"Moo ndàx da ngéen cee déggoo'k Yàlla - te Yàlla du wùute ab digam; - walla da ngéen di wàx ci Yàlla lu ngéen xàmul\\"."},{"question":"Afaka ny ho faly foana ve isika?","answer":"Ara-dalàna ny miaina fisondrotana ara-pihetseham-po. Ny fiezahana hahazo fahasambarana lalandava dia mety tsy ho tanteraka, fa ny fambolena izay hahasoa dia fomba azo tanterahina."},{"question":"Kể tên các tác phẩm chính của Huy Cận","answer":"Tác phẩm chính của Huy Cận: Lửa thiêng (thơ, 1939); Vũ trụ ca (thơ, 1942); Tính chất dân tộc trong văn nghệ (nghiên cứu, 1958); Trời mỗi ngày lại sáng (thơ, 1958); Đất nở hoa (thơ, 1960); Hai bàn tay em (thơ, 1967); Phù Đổng Thiên Vương (thơ, 1968); Những năm sáu mươi (thơ, 1968); Cô gái Mèo (thơ, 1972); Thiếu niên anh hùng họp mặt (thơ, 1973); Chiến trường gần đến chiến trường xa (thơ, 1973); Những người mẹ, những người vợ (thơ, 1974); Ngày hằng sống, ngày hằng thơ (thơ, 1975); Sơn Tinh - Thủy Tinh (thơ, 1976); Ngôi nhà giữa nắng (thơ, 1978); Hạt lại gieo (thơ, 1984); Lời tâm nguyện cùng hai thế kỷ (thơ, 1997); Ta về với biển (tập thơ, 1997)..."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao :  \\"  Aleo Manao Zavatra Vokatra Ny Fo Misy Tanjona Atao, ................................... \\"","answer":"\\"  Aleo Manao Zavatra Vokatra Ny Fo Misy Tanjona Atao,toy Izay Manaonao Fotsiny Tsisy Dikany \\""},{"question":"オリンピックの女子バレーボールで日本は２度金メダルを獲得していますが、それは東京と、どこの都市で開催された大会でしょう？","answer":"モントリオールです。"},{"question":"ငရုတ်သီးစိမ်းငံပြာရည်ချက် လုပ်နည်းပြောပြပါ။","answer":"ကြက်သွန်နီ ၅ လုံးနဲ့ ကြက်သွန်ဖြူ ၃ မွှာလောက်ကို ညှက်နေအောင်ထောင်းထားပါ။ ပုဇွန်ခြောက် လက်တဆုပ်စာလောက်ကို ရေဆေးပြီး မညှက်တညှက်ထောင်းပါ။ ငရုတ်သီးစိမ်း ၁၀ တောင့်လောက်ကို သက်သက်ထောင်းထားပါ။အိုးထဲကို ဆီ လိုသလောက်ထည့်ပါ။ ဆီဆူလာလျှင် နနွင်းမှုန့်အနည်းငယ် ထည့်ပါ။ ကြက်သွန်ဖြူ/နီ ထည့်ပြီး ဆီသပ်ပါ။ အနံ့လေးမွှေးပြီး ကြက်သွန်နီလေး နွမ်းလာပြီဆိုရင်  ထောင်းထားတဲ့ပုဇွန်ခြောက်ကို ထည့်ပါ။ အရသာအတွက် ငံပြာရည်၊ အချိုမှုန့်၊ ကြက်သားမှုန့်ထည့်ပါ။ ငရုတ်(ငြုပ်)သီးခွဲခြမ်း ထမင်းစားဇွန်းနဲ့ ၂ ဇွန်းလောက် ထည့်ပြီး မွှေပေးပါ။ ပြီးလျှင် ရေအနည်းငယ်ထည့်ပါ။ ရေဆူလာပြီဆို၊ ထောင်းထားတဲ့ ငြုပ်(ငရုတ်)သီးစိမ်းကို ထည့်ပြီး ခနအုပ်ထားပါ။ ဆီပြန်လာပြီဆိုလျှင် အရသာလေးမြည်းပြီး ချလို့ရပါပြီ။ အသားဟင်းတောင်မလိုပဲ၊ တစ်မျိုးထဲစားရင်တောင် ထမင်းမြိန်တဲ့ဟင်းလေးဖြစ်ပါတယ်။"},{"question":"Dijital reklam modelleri nelerdir?","answer":"Dijital reklam modelleri, çevrimiçi platformlarda ürün veya hizmet tanıtımı için kullanılan farklı stratejileri ifade eder. İşte bazı temel dijital reklam modelleri:1. CPC (Cost Per Click - Tıklama Başına Maliyet): Reklamveren, reklamının bir kullanıcı tarafından tıklanması durumunda ödeme yapar. Bu modelde, reklamveren tıklama başına belirli bir ücret öder.2. CPM (Cost Per Mille - Bin Gösterime Maliyet): Reklamveren, reklamının 1000 defa görüntülenmesi için belirli bir ücret öder. Bu modelde, reklamverenin ödemesi, bin gösterim üzerinden hesaplanır.3. CPA (Cost Per Acquisition - Edinim Başına Maliyet): Reklamveren, reklamının belirli bir eylem gerçekleştiren bir kullanıcı tarafından görüntülenmesi durumunda ödeme yapar. Bu eylem genellikle bir satın alma, kayıt veya başka bir belirli hedef olabilir.4. CPV (Cost Per View - Gösterim Başına Maliyet): Video reklamları için kullanılan bir modeldir. Reklamveren, reklamın belirli bir süre boyunca izlenmesi için ödeme yapar.5. Affiliate Marketing (Bağlı Pazarlama): Reklamveren, kendi ürün veya hizmetini tanıtan diğer sitelere veya yayıncılara ödeme yapar. Bu ödeme genellikle bir satış, lead veya belirli bir eylem üzerinden gerçekleşir.6. Sponsorluklar ve İş Ortaklıkları: Bir marka, belirli bir platformda, içerik üreticisi veya etkinlikle işbirliği yaparak kendi ürün veya hizmetini tanıtabilir. Bu işbirlikleri genellikle belirli bir süre veya proje tabanlıdır.7. Retargeting (Yeniden Hedefleme): Bir kullanıcı bir web sitesini ziyaret ettiğinde, daha sonra başka sitelerde karşılaştığı reklamlar aracılığıyla tekrar hedeflenir. Bu, kullanıcıları geri çekme ve potansiyel müşteri dönüşümlerini artırma amacını taşır.Bu modeller, reklamverenlere çevrimiçi pazarlama stratejilerini uygulama ve başarılarını ölçme imkanı sağlar. Reklamverenler genellikle hedef kitlelerine ulaşmak, etkileşimi artırmak ve dönüşümleri teşvik etmek için bu modelleri bir arada veya tek başına kullanabilirler."},{"question":"Kupihwa rekufuga nerekuwarira kuita sei?","answer":"Kutukwa zvinorwadza"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'Download' ketika menyemak kelajuan internet? ","answer":"-Menunjukkan kelajuan internet anda untuk memuat turun sesuatu. -Sebagai contoh kelajuan untuk menstrim video. -Kelajuan ini biasanya diukur dalam nilai (megabyte per second) mbps. Ianya bergantung kepada pembekal perkhidmatan internet anda serta pakej yang anda langgan."},{"question":"සාර්ක් විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය පිහිටා ඇත්තේ කොහේද?","answer":"සාර්ක් විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය පිහිටා ඇත්තේ ඉන්දියාවේය."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：在17世纪的英国，哪位君主被推翻并导致共和国的建立？","answer":"答案：在17世纪的英国，查理一世被推翻，并导致了英国共和国（清教徒共和国）的建立。"},{"question":"Сөздүк бул…","answer":"Сөздүк – бир элдин тилиндеги сөздөрдүн жалпы жыйындысы. Аны учурдагы турмуштук зарылдыкка, муктаждыкка жараша китеп (сөздүк) түрүндө бастырып чыгаруу кезектеги илимий-маданий талап болуп саналат."},{"question":"Ileyska imisa nooc ayuu u kala baxaa?","answer":"Ileyska wuxuu u kala baxaa: 1. Mid dabiica ah.2. Mid aan dabiici aheen."},{"question":"கேள்வி: இஸ்ரோவின் குறிக்கோள் என்ன?","answer":"பதில்: இஸ்ரோவின் (இந்திய விண்வெளி ஆய்வு மையத்தின்) குறிக்கோளானது விண்வெளி தொழில் நூட்பங்களையும் அதன் பயன்பாடுகளையும் உருவாக்குவதன் மூலம் நாட்டுக்கு தேவையான பணிகளை நிறைவேற்றுதலாகும்."},{"question":"खालील श्लोकाचा सोप्या मराठीत अर्थ सांगा श्लोक:स्थिरता नाहीं येक क्षण । चपळविशईं अग्रगण ।साअजिरी मूर्ति सुलक्षण । लावण्यखाणी ॥ २२॥अर्थ:","answer":"इतका विशाल व थुलथुलीत देह असूनही चपलतेमध्ये गणेश अग्रगण्य असून क्षणभरही स्वस्थ राहात नाही. त्याची साजिरी मूर्ती सुलक्षण व लवण्याची जणू खाणच आहे. (२२)"},{"question":"拍电影时常用的“杀青”来表示拍摄完成，“杀青”原指什么？","answer":"“杀青”一词源于先秦时代。那时，书大都用竹简（称“简”)、木简(称“牍”)制成。先在简和牍上刻字，接着在它们一边打孔，然后用丝绳或牛皮带编联起来，形成了形状像“册”字的书，又因为竹竿的表面有一层竹青，含有油水成分，不易刻字，而且竹容易被虫蛀，所以古人就想出了火烤的办法，把竹简放到火上炙烤。经过火烤处理的竹简刻字方便且防虫蛀所以火烤是竹简制作的重要工序。当时人们把这个工序叫做“杀青”，也叫“汗青”“汗简”。“杀青”一词就是这样来的。 到了秦朝，有了笔，于是，简牍上的字可以不用刀刻而用笔写了。那时候，人们写文章常常用毛笔把初稿写在竹青上因为竹青光滑，要修改只须揩去就行了，初稿改定后，就削去竹青，把定稿写在竹白上。这一道手续也叫“杀青”。"},{"question":". Title: Indian GDP: ఆరేళ్ళలో అధమంగా 4.5 శాతానికి ఎలా పడిపోయింది... దీని ప్రభావం ఎలా ఉంటుంది? - అభిప్రాయంnSummary: గత త్రైమాసికానికి సంబంధించిన జీడీపీ గ్రోత్ గణాంకాలు విడుదలయ్యాయి.nArticle (Max 500 characters):","answer":"అనకున్నంతా అయింది. అంచనా నిజమేనని తేలింది. జీడీపీ గ్రోత్ రేటు పతనమై నాలుగున్నర శాతానికి చేరింది. కొంతకాలం ముందు రాయిటర్స్ వార్తా సంస్థ ఆర్థికవేత్తలతో ఒక సర్వే చేసింది. అందులో ఈ రేటు ఐదు శాతం కంటే తక్కువకు పడిపోతుందని అంచనా వేశారు. కానీ వారు కూడా ఈ గణాంకాలు 4.7 శాతం వరకే ఉంటాయని భావించారు.ఇప్పుడు వచ్చిన గణాంకాలు, శాస్త్రవేత్తల అంచనాల కంటే మరింత ఘోరంగా ఉన్నాయి. గత ఆరేళ్లలో అత్యంత ఘోరమైన గణాంకాలు ఇవే. ఇంతకు ముందు 2013లో జనవరి నుంచి మార్చి మధ్య ఈ రేటు 4.3 శాతం దగ్గర ఉంది."},{"question":"Astaamaha qofka hanka sare leh  Sheekadii Takeo Awsahira.","answer":"Sheekadii Takeo Awsahira ee u dhashay wadanka japaan ahaana midkii japaan u horseeday horumarka ay maanta haysato :- Wuxuu yiri takeo dawladayda ayaa waxay ii dirtay in aan wax ka soo barto wadanka jarrmalka, gaar ahaan jaamacada layiraahdo (University of Hamburg), waxaana laydiray in aan soo barto makaaniknimada iyo sida matoorada loo sameeyo, jarmalka ayaan aaday anigoo xanbaarsan himmiladaydii ii gaarka ahayd,  ee ku milantay jirkayga dhuuxana iga gashay ee aan har iyo habeen ku hamminaayay saan ku gaarilahaa, himmiladaas oo ahayd in aan sameeyo matoor !! . Waxaan aqaanay inay farsama kasta ay leedahay shay sir ah oo farsamadaas u ah udub dhexaad (Model Motors), haddii aad barato sida moodeelkaas loosameeyo gacanta waxaad ku dhigtay sirta farsamadaas ay ku dhisan tahay. Macallimiintii wax i baraysay meeshay iga barilahaayeen sida loo sameeyo matoorada, ayay waxay isiiyeen kutub badan oo igu dhaheen xifdi ilaa aan xifdiyay wixii ku qornaa walina aanan lahayn aqoon aan ku samayn karo matoor, waayo farsamo hadal laxifdiyo uma baahnee waxay u baahan tahay in gacanta wax lagaa baro oo lagu tababaro laguna tuso sida wax lays kugu rakibaayo oo lays kugu xiraayo. Markii aan arko matoor shaqaynayaa wuxuu ilayahay sidii hal xiraale aan la furi karin, layma barin sida loo fur furo, sida loo cabbiro bir kasta oo ku jirta matoorka, hadal uun ayaa lay baraa farsamo gacan layma baro. Waxaan u hilawsanahay sidii aan ku gaarilahaa in aan matoorkaas gacantayda ku furfuro  kuna xirxiro  bir kastana aan u aqoon lahaa qaabka loo sameeyo looguna rakibo meesha ay ku jirto, saan ku baran lahaa bir kasta, bool kasta, silig kasta iyo shaqada ay  qabanayaan, waxaan u hilawsanahay in aan  matoorka habsiiyo sidii waalid ilmihiisii muda ka maqnaa oo kale, in aan is arko anigoo qaba dhar ay ka buuxdo olyo iyo  naafto, gacmahaygana aan ku daliigo olyada matoorka, in aan gacmahayga iyo dharkaygaba ay kasoo carafto urka olyada. Maalin maalmaha ka mid ah ayaan waxaan arkay shirkad xayaysiinaysa oo rabta inay soo bandhigto matooro lagu sameeyay wadanka talyaaniga, markaas waxay ahayd bisha awalkeeda waxaana soo qaatay biilkii laysoo diray, shirkadii ayaan u tagay waxaana ku arkay matoor awoodiisu le'egtahay laba faras oo kale qiimihiisuna uu dhan yahay lacagta bisha laysoo diray ee aan haysto, waxaan is iri haddaad lacagta kugadato matoorka bishan waxaad cunto ma helaysid, hadadaan gadanina matoorka waligaa magaaraysid in aad ka salgaarto himmadada ah in aad matoor samayso, muda hadaan fikriray waxaa ila xoog badatay in aan gaajoodo oo matoorka iibsado, matoorkii ayaan iibsaday guriga ayaan u soo qaatay, markaan guriga u soo socday lugihii ayaa i cuslaaday farxad darteed waxaan aaminay in aan maanta garabka kuwato wixii adduunka ugu qaalisanaa, saan u soo socday markaan soogaaray guriga ayaan matoorkii dhigay miis halkan yaala, markaas  ayaan fariistay anigoo aaminsan in aan guriga soogashaday shaygii adduunka ugu qaalisanaa, marna matoorkaan fiiriyaa marna farxadaa  igabadata oo aad ayaan u farxaa, naftayda ayaan ugu sheekaynayaa oo ku dhahayaa '' matoorkan waa sirta ay ku hormareen reer yurub'', '' haddii aan sameeyo matoor waxaa hubaal ah in aan taariikhda iyo nolosha japaan wax weyn ka badali doono. Waxaan naftayda ku iri matoorkan wuxu ka kooban yahay boolal, biro yaryar ah iyo kuwa waaweyn, sida loo rakibay waxay ku dhisan tahay aqoon iyo isku dheelitir, haddii marka aan ku guulaysto in aan fufuro isla markaasna aan markale rakibo oo uu shaqeeyo waa talaabo weyn oo aan horey u qaaday saan uga salgaaro sirta ay yurub ku hormartay. Waxaan soo diyaarsaday waraaqo iyo qalimaan waxan bilaabay in aan guud ahaan sawiro matoorka, waxaan ku xejiyay in aan bir kasta iyo bool kastaba aan sawiro meesha uu ku jiro, sida ugu jiro iyo in aan tiro siiyo bir kasta iyo meesha ay ku jirto, dadaal dheer oo ay waheliso daal, rafaad, hurdo la'aan, waxaan ku guulaystay in aan furfuro matoorkii, waxaan guda galay in aan xirxiro oo rakibo matoorka, markaan dhameeyay rakibaadii iyo xirxiridii ayaan istaaray oo daaray, markaan maqlay codkii matoorka oo shidmay jirkayga dhan waxaa buuxiyay farxad, farxadii aan maalintaas farxay waxaan ku qiyaaso magaranaayo, furfurida iyo  xirxirada matoorka waxay igu qaadatay sadex maalmood oo aan hal mar wax cunaayay hurda aad u yar aan seexanaayay. Gudoomiyihii ardayda japaanka ee wax ka barta wadanka jarmalka ayaan u tagay oo u sheegay in aan ku guulaystay in aan furfuro oo xirxiro matoor, markaas ayuu yiri, waa talaabo fiican, waxaan hayaa matoor kharaabsan waxaan rabaa inaad hagaajiso oo soosaarto cilada keentay inuu kharaabo oo aad ka dhigto matoorkan mid shaqaynaaya. Toban maalmood oo aan nasniin lahayn ayay iga qaadatay in aan ogaado cilada matoorkan haysata, waxaan ogaaday inay jirto sadex birood oo gubtay isla markaasna dhamaaday, waxaan isku dayay in aan sadexdaas birood aan gacantayda ku sameeyo oo aanan kasoo gadan tukaanka, dadaal dheer kadib waxaa ii suurtagashay in aan sameeyo sadexdaas birood oo aan ku rakibo matoorka, markii aan  ku xiray birihii matoorka oo aan daaray codkii matoorkana aan maqlay  waxaan dareemay raaxo iyo farxad aad u weyn iyadoo waliba isagoo uu ihayo daal farabadan, gaajo, hurdo la'aan, waxaas oo dhan in aan u dulqaato waxaa ii sahlay shaqadaan hayo ayaa wax kasta igala weyn. Markii uu ogaaday gudoomiyihii in aan ku guulaystay inaan hagaajiyay matoorkii kharaabsanaa, wuxuu igu yiri maanta waxaa lagaarabaa inaad adigu matoor gacantaada ku samayso. Haddaba si ay iigu suurtagasho in aan sameeyo matoor, waxaan qaatay go'aan ah in aan ka shaqeeyo meelaha geyrashyada eelagu hagajiyo matoorada, waxaan xirtay dhargii olyada badnaa ee ay xirtaan dadka ka sheqeeya gayrashyada, waxaan ku talagalay in aan noqdo shaqaale dhega nugul, karti badan, aan noogin, daal aqoon, shaqadiisa u heelan, iyado ay jirto in aan ka dhashay reer ahaan qoyska  kataliya wadanka japaan, reer boqor ayaad tahay iima diidin in aan ka shaqeeyo garaash, reer boqor ayaad tahay iima diidin in aan meel kasta u maro sidii aan japaan u hormarin lahaa. Shaqadaan waxay igu qaadatay sideed sano oo aan shaqaynaayo shan iyo toban saac, markii shaqadu dhamaatana waxaan ku dhihi jirey  ninka meesha haysta waardiyaha igu qor mushaharna kaama rabo, waxaas oo dhan waxaan uga goleeyahay in aan habeenkii ku soo jeedo in aan u dhabagalo bir kasta sida ay u shaqayso iyo sida loosameeyo. Boqorkii japaan katalinaayay ayaa maqlay sheekadayda, markaas ayuu lacag ii soo diray aan ku iibsado dhamaan qalabka lagasameeyo matoorada, qalabkii ayaan soo dhoofsaday  waxaana  la imi wadanka japaan, boqorkii ayaa codsaday in aan u imaado si uu ii arko qadasharafna iisiiyo,  markaas ayaan ku iri  ilaa aan toban matoor oo ay ku qorantahay japaan ayaa lagu sameeyay aan sameeyo, ma istaahilo in aan boqorka qaabilo ama qado sharaf laysameeyo.  Sagaal sano kadib waxaan ku guulaystay in aan sameeyo warshad lagu sameeyo matoorada, maalintii aan sameeyay toban matoor oo aan dusha kaga qoray '' waxaa lagu sameeyay japaan'' ( made in japan),  waxaan u qaaday oo geeyay matooradii guriga madaxtooyada , markii ladaaray matooradii ayaa waxaa soo galay boqorkii isagoo dhoolacadaynaaya markaas ayuu yiri '' codkii ugu macaanaa ayaan maanta maqlayaa, matooro japaan lagu sameeyay ayaan codkooda maqlayaa'' . Markii aan indhahayga ku arkay in aan sirtii ay ku horumareen reer yurub aan japaan usoo raray, ayaan seexday 10 saac oo xiriir ah, mana seexan 10 saac oo xiriir ah 15 sano gudahood. Walaalaha qiimah badanoow aynu is waydiino, maxaa sababay inuu ninkaan dadaalka intaas le'eg ku bixiyo horumarka wadankiisa? Maxaa keenay inuu noqdo mid rafaad kasta u mara sidii uu wadankiisa u hormarin lahaa ?  Walaalaha qiimaha badanoow, ninkan wuxuu ahaa wiil loo diray inuu jarmalka  wax ku soo barto, waxaa is weydiin leh intee soomaali loo diray inay jarmalka wax ku soo bartaan, malaga helay wiil ninkan oo kale ah ? intee wiil soomaaliyeed wax barasho loogu diray wadamada reer yurub malaga helay wiil lamid ah ninkan oo kale ? intee wiil soomaaliyeed wax barasho loogu diray wadanka maraykanka ma'aragnay wiil noqday sida wiilkan oo kale?Intee wiilal deeq waxbarasho loogu diray adduunka daafihiisa ma'aragnay hal wiil oo hankii takeo kujiro?. Intee wiil soomaaliyeed naftiisa ku haligay isagoo u tahriibaaya wadamada reer galbeedka? Mays waydiinay wiilashaasi maxay naftooda u haligaayeen ? maxay badda u dhaxaysa liibiya iyo talyaaniga iskugu biimaynaayeen ? maxay barafka u dhaxeeya ruushka iyo yurub iskugu biimaynaayeen ? maxaa ka maqnaa oo ay raadinaayeen ? ma lacag raadis ayay ahaayeen ? ma sharaf raadis ayay ahaayeen ? ma aqoon raadis ayay ahaayeen ? maxay tahay sababta ugu weyn ee ay naftooda ugu biimaynayaan dhibaatooyinkaas oo dhan ? hankoodu magarsiisanaa inay soo min guuriyaan horumarka iyo ilbaxnimada ka jirta wadamadaas ay u qaxeen oo ay keenaan wadankooda ?  haddii aad weydiiso dhallin yaro tahriibaysa oo aad ku dhahdo maxaa yurub ugu socotaan ? jawaabta ugu badan ay ku siinayaan waxaa weeye, shaqo raadis ayaan nahay, basaboor raadis ayaan nahay, caruurta ayaan u soo xamaalanaynaa iwm, waxaa is weydiin leh dhallin yaradii soomaaliyeed hankoodii ma'intaas ayuu noqday shaqo, basaboor , xamaali !!! . Waxaa layaableh, inaad aragto wiilashii, odoyaashii, gabdhihii, hooyooyinkii, u qaxay wadamada reer galbeedka  iyagoo lacag lagarab taagan  nin dagaal ooga ah oo sabab u ahaa inay wadankooda kasoo qaxaan,  warmaynu garan weynay xattaa inaynaan taageerin dagaal oogihii shalay wadanka inaka soo qixiyay ? warmaynu garan waynay inay ceebtahay in aan fadhi ku diriryada ku taageerno dagaal oogayaashii wadankeena hoos u dhigay ee maanta inaan qaxooti noqono sababta u ahaa ? Nacaybka aan wadankeena hooyo u qabnaa waynaa !! inaynu ka qaxno isla markaasna kii sababta u ahaa in qarankeenii dumo, adduunka daafihiisa ku firxano, qaxooti noqono aynu lagarab istaagno hiil iyo hoo, hadal iyo lacag, soo cajiib maahan ? dhamaan dadka soomaliya buburka kawada waxaa taageera qurba joogta soomaaliyeed, taasna waa shay laga naxo, meeshaad ka shaqayn lahayd horumarka wadankaaga inaad ka shaqayso burburka wadankaaga, meeshaa horumarka galbeedka yaala soo rari lahayd inaad ku mashquusho qabyaalad iyo dhammaan wixii wadankeena hoosu dhac ku keenaya soo shay laga naxo maahan ? "},{"question":"වං ඇපල යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ආඩතෝඩා හෙවත් වං ඇපල ලෙස හඳුන්වන්නේ ඉන්දියානු උප මහාද්වීපයේ බොහෝ ප්‍රදේශවල වැවෙන ඖෂධීය ශාකයකි."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga: \\"Ny _ dia ireo mpianatra roa ambin'ny folo voalohany nofidin'i Jesosy mba hampiely ny fampianarany.\\"","answer":"Valiny: Ny apostoly no mpianatra roa ambin'ny folo notendren'i Jesosy hampiely ny fampianarany."},{"question":": Waxaad sheegtaan Digaalkii Uxud Saxaabigii u hor bilaabay Mubaarazada?","answer":": al-Zubayr ibnul-Cawwaam (Xawaarigii Rasuulka (scw) ahaana ina Safiya bintu Cabdil-Mudhalib Suubbanaha Rasuulka eeddadiis.    "},{"question":"Ẹgbẹ awọn oṣere ni: Baba Ijẹṣa ba wa loju jẹ, o gbọdọ jiya ẹṣẹ ẹ","answer":"Asiko yii ti kọja awada ṣiṣe fun Baba Ijẹṣa, boya si l’Ọgbẹni Ọlanrewaju James le dẹrin-in pa ara rẹ lọwọ yii pẹlu bi ọpọ awọn ololufẹ rẹ ṣe kọyin si i lori ẹsun ifipa bọmọde lo pọ ti wọn fi kan an, bakan naa si ni ẹgbẹ awọn oṣere tiata ilẹ wa, TAMPAN, ti lawọn o ni i ṣatilẹyin kan fun afurasi ọdaran yii, bo ba jẹ loootọ lo huwa ọhun, ko lọọ maa da iya rẹ jẹ loju paali ni.Ẹgbẹ TAMPAN (Theatre Arts and Motion Pictures Practitioners Association of Nigeria) sọ iduro wọn lori iṣẹlẹ yii lọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, ninu atẹjade kan ti ọga to wa lẹka iwadii ati akọsilẹ ẹgbẹ naa, Ọgbẹni Yẹmi Amodu, fi lede. O ni ẹgbẹ awọn o ni i ṣatilẹyin fun ọmọ ẹgbẹ to yọ kẹlẹ huwa ainitiju ati iwa ọdaran eyikeyii, wọn lawọn o laṣọ aṣiri tawọn fẹẹ da bo iru ẹni bẹẹ, kaka bẹẹ, awọn ṣetan lati ṣatilẹyin fun ijọba ipinlẹ Eko ninu igbesẹ rẹ lati fidi idajọ ododo mulẹ lori ọrọ yii.Atẹjade naa to tẹ ALAROYE lọwọ, ka lapa kan pe:“A ri i gẹgẹ bii ojuṣe wa lati kede pe awa o fara mọ ẹsun ti wọn fi kan ọmọ ẹgbẹ wa yii, a si bẹnu atẹ lu iwa ailojuti ati iṣekuṣe ti wọn ni Ọgbẹni Olanrewaju James, ti inagijẹ rẹ n jẹ Baba Ijẹṣa jẹwọ pe oun hu. O ka ẹgbẹ wa, TAMPAN, lara, o si dun wa gan-an pe ọkan lara awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ wa ni wọn fi iru ẹsun iwa abani-loju-jẹ bayii kan, a da iwa ibajẹ buruku yii lẹbi gidi.“Nitori ọrọ to gbẹgẹ gan-an lọrọ yii, ti ọrọ ọhun ṣi wa labẹ iwadii, a o ni i sọ ohunkohun lati ṣegbe tabi ta ko ẹni tọrọ yii kan, ju pe ka fi ero wa han lodi si iwakiwa ọhun lọ.“Gẹgẹ bii ẹgbẹ kan, a loye pe apẹẹrẹ to daa lawọn eeyan n reti latọdọ wa lawujọ, tori naa, a o ni i kẹrẹ lati ṣatilẹyin fun ijọba ki idajọ ododo le fidi mulẹ lori ọrọ yii.“A ba awọn obi ati mọlẹbi ọmọde tọrọ yii kan kẹdun, a si rọ gbogbo awọn obi lati tubọ wa lojufo si ojuṣe wọn lati maa daabo bo awọn majeṣin wọn lọwọ ewu ati iwa ibajẹ to gbode kan lasiko yii.”"},{"question":"दुःख का कारण क्या है?","answer":"दुःख का सबसे बड़ा कारण है अपने आज में न जीना| जो उपलब्ध है हम उसका सुख नहीं लेते और भविष्य या भूतकाल की चिंता में डूब जाते है| अपने बीते हुए कल से सबक लेकर अपने आज को अच्छा बनाने की कोशिश करे आपका आने वाला कल अपने आप अच्छा हो जायेगा और इसके लिए जरुरी है खुश रहते हुए उस काम को करना नहीं तो आपका आज आपके सामने कई चुनोतियाँ खड़ा कर देगा जो आपको दुःख की और धकेलेंगी|"},{"question":"Dictatus Papae – dokument sporządzony przez papieża Grzegorza VII (fragment):\\"Kościół rzymski przez samego Boga został założony.Tylko sam biskup rzymski może być prawnie nazwany biskupem powszechnym.On sam tylko może używać insygniów cesarskich.Jemu wolno władcami rozporządzać, a więc i cesarzy z tronu składać.\\"Jakie jest głównie przesłanie w powyższym tekście? ","answer":"Powyższy teskt tłumaczy o wyższości władzy papieskiej nad cesarską. "},{"question":"සම්ප්‍රදායික ගවේෂණාත්මක දත්ත විශ්ලේෂණය (සංඛ්‍යාලේඛනවල) යන්ත්‍ර ඉගෙනීමට වඩා වෙනස් වන්නේ කෙසේදැයි වචන කිහිපයකින් පැහැදිලි කරන්න?","answer":"යන්ත්‍ර ඉගෙනීම සහ සම්ප්‍රදායික ගවේෂණ දත්ත විශ්ලේෂණය (EDA) අතර අවධානය සහ අරමුණෙහි වැදගත් පොදු වෙනසක් නම් යටින් පවතින සංසිද්ධිවල මූලික ස්වභාවය පැහැදිලි කිරීමට වඩා යන්ත්‍ර ඉගෙනීම යෙදුම් දෙසට නැඹුරු වීමයි. යන්ත්‍ර ඉගෙනීම සම්බන්ධ විචල්‍යයන් අතර නිශ්චිත සම්බන්ධතා හඳුනා ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සාපේක්ෂව අඩු සැලකිල්ලක් දක්වයි. උදාහරණයක් ලෙස, යටින් පවතින ශ්‍රිතවල ස්වභාවය හෝ විචල්‍ය අතර අන්තර්ක්‍රියාකාරී, බහුවිචල්‍ය පරායත්තතා වල ස්වභාවය අනාවරණය කිරීම යන්ත්‍ර ඉගෙනීමේ ප්‍රධාන ඉලක්කය නොවේ. ඒ වෙනුවට, ප්‍රයෝජනවත් අනාවැකි ජනනය කළ හැකි විසඳුමක් නිෂ්පාදනය කිරීම කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කෙරේ. Machine Learning දත්ත ගවේෂණ හෝ දැනුම සොයා ගැනීම සඳහා \\"කළු පෙට්ටි\\" ආකාරයේ ප්‍රවේශයක් පිළිගන්නා අතර සාම්ප්‍රදායික ගවේෂණ දත්ත විශ්ලේෂණ (EDA) ශිල්පීය ක්‍රම පමණක් නොව, වලංගු අනාවැකි ජනනය කළ හැකි නමුත් හඳුනා ගැනීමට හැකියාවක් නැති ස්නායුක ජාල වැනි ශිල්පීය ක්‍රම ද භාවිතා කරයි. අනාවැකි පදනම් වී ඇති විචල්‍යයන් අතර අන්තර් සම්බන්ධතා වල නිශ්චිත ස්වභාවය."},{"question":"Fason estrawòdinè po bèt yo rele konkonm lanmè a fèt","answer":"Konkonm lanmè a se yon bèt k ap viv nan fon lanmè ak sou resif koray yo. Po yo kapab vin tankou yon bagay ki gen yon seri grenn, douk oswa menm pikan. Kò l tèlman fleksib, li kapab vin mou tankou pat moun fè pen oswa li kapab vin di tankou yon bout bwa nan kèk minit sèlman oubyen menm nan kèk segonn. Kapasite sa a konkonm lanmè a genyen an pèmèt li glise kò l nan ti espas li jwenn nan resif yo epi li fè kò l vin di yon fason pou bèt ki bezwen manje l pa ka rale l soti. Kapasite sa a konkonm lanmè a genyen an soti nan fason estrawòdinè po l fèt.Fè yon ti reflechi: Po konkonm lanmè a kapab vin twa fason. Li ka vin di, li ka vin plizoumwen di e l ka vin mou. Pou konkonm lanmè a ka chanje de yon etap ak yon lòt etap konsa, se swa li konekte oswa dekonekte yon seri ti eleman nan po l ki rele fib. Konsa, pou l ka fè po l vin di oswa mou, li sèvi ak diferan pwoteyin nan kò l.Diferan pwoteyin ki fè po l vin di a fòme plizyè ti pon oswa plizyè ti chenn ant fib yo ak tisi li gen nan kò l yo, sa ki pèmèt po a vin pi di. E diferan lòt pwoteyin ki fè po l vin mou an dekonekte fib ki nan po l yo, sa ki pèmèt po a vin pi mou. Po konkonm lanmè a kapab vin tèlman mou, yon moun ka panse se fonn l ap fonn tankou glas.Syantifik yo ap eseye fè yon seri materyo ki kapab gen menm kapasite ak po konkonm lanmè a. Youn nan objektif yo genyen se rive fabrike plizyè sikui elektrik byen solid, yon fason pou yo ka enstale sikui yo nan sèvo moun y ap opere, men ki kapab vin mou nan tèt la apre operasyon an fin fèt. Si sikui elektrik yo gen kapasite sa, ap gen plis posibilite pou yo rive reyisi operasyon an."},{"question":"Bir evin ruhsatı ne kadar 2023?","answer":"S.S KAMUKENT ARSA VE KONUT YAPI KOOPERATİFİBuna göre, Bodrumsuz konutlarda Belediye'ye, Teknik Uygulama sorumlularına ve Şantiye şefliği için toplam 18.745,00TL, Bodrumlu konutlarda ise Belediye'ye, Teknik Uygulama sorumlularına ve Şantiye şefliği için toplam 20.770,00 TL kdv dahil ödenecektir."},{"question":"கோடிட்ட இடங்களை நிரப்புக:ஆடத்தெரியுமா என்ற வினாவிற்குப் பாடத்தெரியும் என்று கூறுவது ……………………………..அ) வினாஎதிர் வினாதல்ஆ) உற்றது உரைத்தல்இ) உறுவது கூறல்ஈ) இனமொழி விடை","answer":"ஆடத்தெரியுமா என்ற வினாவிற்குப் பாடத்தெரியும் என்று கூறுவது இனமொழி விடை"},{"question":"लुम्बिनी को अशोक पिल्लर (स्तम्भ) कहिले र कस्ले बनेका थिए ?","answer":"लुम्बिनी को अशोक स्तम्भ सम्राट अशोकले ईसा पूर्व २४९ मा निर्माण गरेका थिए।"},{"question":"文章から主要な単語を特定し、それを定義しなさい。 国によると、去年自殺した子どもは514人いました。今まででいちばん多くなりました。高校生が354人、中学生が143人、小学生が17人でした。SNSなどで相談を聞くNPOの人は次のように話しています。家庭や学校で楽しくないと思う子どもは、ショッピングモールなどを歩いて、気分を変えたり安心したりすることがありました。しかし新型コロナウイルスの問題で、できなくなりました。子どもは、自分の力だけで自分に合う場所をさがすことが難しくて、死ぬことを選んでしまうのかもしれません。そして「大人に相談しても、よく聞いてくれないと思っている子どもがたくさんいます。周りの大人は子どもがどんな気持ちでいるか気をつけて見て、大丈夫かどうか聞くようにしてほしいと思います」と話していました。子どもが電話で相談できるところです。▽NPO法人「チャイルドライン支援センター」が行う「チャイルドライン」（0120－99－7777）▽文部科学省が行う「24時間子供SOSダイヤル」（0120－0－78310）▽法務省が行う「子どもの人権110番」（0120－007－110）","answer":"この文章の中での主要な単語とその定義は以下のようになっています。- 自殺: 1）自分で自分の命を絶つこと。自害。- 小学生: 1）小学校に通っている子ども。- NPO: 1）営利を目的とせずに社会的な活動を行う組織。"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਗੁਆਰੇਰੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਜਿਨਾ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਧਿਆਇਆ ਤਿਨ ਪੂਛਉ ਜਾਇ ॥ਗੁਰ ਸੇਵਾ ਤੇ ਮਨੁ ਪਤੀਆਇ ॥ਸੇ ਧਨਵੰਤ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਕਮਾਇ ॥ਪੂਰੇ ਗੁਰ ਤੇ ਸੋਝੀ ਪਾਇ ॥੧॥ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਜਪਹੁ ਮੇਰੇ ਭਾਈ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸੇਵਾ ਹਰਿ ਘਾਲ ਥਾਇ ਪਾਈ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਆਪੁ ਪਛਾਣੈ ਮਨੁ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਹੋਇ ॥ਜੀਵਨ ਮੁਕਤਿ ਹਰਿ ਪਾਵੈ ਸੋਇ ॥ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਵੈ ਮਤਿ ਊਤਮ ਹੋਇ ॥ਸਹਜੇ ਸਹਜਿ ਸਮਾਵੈ ਸੋਇ ॥੨॥ਦੂਜੈ ਭਾਇ ਨ ਸੇਵਿਆ ਜਾਇ ॥ਹਉਮੈ ਮਾਇਆ ਮਹਾ ਬਿਖੁ ਖਾਇ ॥ਪੁਤਿ ਕੁਟੰਬਿ ਗ੍ਰਿਹਿ ਮੋਹਿਆ ਮਾਇ ॥ਮਨਮੁਖਿ ਅੰਧਾ ਆਵੈ ਜਾਇ ॥੩॥ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਦੇਵੈ ਜਨੁ ਸੋਇ ॥ ਅਨਦਿਨੁ ਭਗਤਿ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦੀ ਹੋਇ ॥ਗੁਰਮਤਿ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਬੂਝੈ ਕੋਇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮਿ ਸਮਾਵੈ ਸੋਇ ॥੪॥੧੨॥੩੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 161 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਨੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਰਾਹ ਉਤੇ ਤੁਰ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਿਆ ਹੈ (ਜਦੋਂ) ਮੈਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਪਾਸੋਂ (ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੀ ਜਾਚ) ਪੁੱਛਦਾ ਹਾਂ (ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਦੱਸਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਦੱਸੀ ਹੋਈ ਸੇਵਾ ਨਾਲ (ਹੀ) ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦਾ ਮਨ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਸਿਮਰਨ ਵਿਚ) ਪਤੀਜਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਣ ਵਾਲੇ) ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਧਨ ਖੱਟ ਕੇ ਧਨਾਢ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਇਹ ਅਕਲ ਪੂਰੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਹੀ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ ।੧।ਮੇਰੇ ਭਾਈ ! (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ) ਸਦਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਦੇ ਰਹੋ ।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੋਈ ਸੇਵਾ-ਭਗਤੀ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਕਬੂਲ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਆਪਣੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਨੂੰ ਪੜਤਾਲਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮਨ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ,ਉਹ ਇਸ ਜਨਮ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਬੰਧਨਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਖ਼ਲਾਸੀ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੀ ਬੁੱਧੀ ਸ੍ਰੇਸ਼ਟ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਫਸੇ ਰਿਹਾਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ-ਭਗਤੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ ।ਹਉਮੈ ਇਕ ਵੱਡਾ ਜ਼ਹਰ ਹੈ ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਵੱਡਾ ਜ਼ਹਰ ਹੈ (ਇਹ ਜ਼ਹਰ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਨੂੰ) ਮਾਰ ਮੁਕਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਮਾਇਆ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ) ਪੁੱਤਰ (ਦੇ ਮੋਹ) ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ, ਪਰਵਾਰ (ਦੇ ਮੋਹ) ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ, ਘਰ (ਦੇ ਮੋਹ) ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਠੱਗਦੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ,(ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ) ਅੰਨ੍ਹਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰ ਕੇ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਦੇ ਗੇੜ ਵਿਚ ਪਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ) ਆਪਣੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਦਾਤਿ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਉਸ ਦਾ) ਸੇਵਕ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ ਹਰ ਰੋਜ਼ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ ।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਹੀ ਕੋਈ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਜੀਵਨ-ਮਨੋਰਥ ਨੂੰ) ਸਮਝਦਾ ਹੈ,ਤੇ, ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੧੨।੩੨।\\""},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--खोट्याच्या कपाळी गोटा\\t","answer":"खोटेपणा वाईट काम करणाऱ्यांचे नुकसान होते."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Nebsenre (nghĩa là \\"Chúa tể của họ là Ra\\") là một pharaon của Ai Cập thuộc vương triều thứ 14 trong thời kỳ Chuyển tiếp thứ Hai","answer":". Nebsenre đã trị vì trong ít nhất năm tháng trên toàn bộ khu vực phía Đông và có thể cả phía Tây châu thổ sông Nile, vào giai đoạn nửa đầu thế kỷ 17 TCN. Do đó Nebsenre là một vị vua cùng thời với Vương triều thứ 13 có căn cứ tại Memphis."},{"question":"السؤال: شنو هو أطول نهر فالعالم ؟","answer":"الإجابة: نهر النيل هو أطول نهر فالعالم وكيمر على 11 ديال البلدان اللي هما بوروندي و تنزانيا و رواندا و جمهورية الكونغو الديمقراطية و كينيا و أوغندا و السودان و إثيوبيا و جنوب السودان و مصر"},{"question":"¿Cuál es le deporte nacional de Colombia?","answer":"El tejo esté es un deporte que consiste en lanzar un disco metálico de aproximadamente 680 gramos a unas canchas de embocinada​ (ubicadas una en cada extremo), en una cancha​ de juego de 19.5 metros de largo y 2.5 metros de ancho, para hacer estallar una mecha​ que se encuentra ubicada dentro de la caja (de greda) en el borde superior interno del bocín6​ y así ir sumando puntos. "},{"question":"जनसंख्याको हिसाबले सबैभन्दा ठूलो देश कुन हो ?","answer":"सबैभन्दा धेरै जनसंख्या भएको देश चीन हो।"},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાની \\"આ તે શી માથાફોડ !\\" પુસ્તકના એક લેખનના શરૂઆતના ફકરા નીચે મુજબ આપેલ છે.\\"એક ઘરમાં ગયો. બાળકોને કપડાં પહેરવાં હતાં. કપડાં પહેરવાની ઉતાવળ હતી પણ કપડાં વળગણી ઉપર હતાં. બા કે મોટી બેન આવે ત્યારે તે મળે તેમ હતાં. કોઈ મોટું આવ્યું, કપડાં ઉતારી દીધાં ને પછી બાળકોએ પહેર્યાં. હું કપડાં ઉતારી આપી શકત પણ હું જોતો હતો કે આ શું ચાલે છે.⁠મને થયું: “આમ શા માટે ? એક વળગણી નીચી ને બીજી ઊંચી ન રાખી શકાય ? અને તેમ જો બની શકે તો બાળકો પોતાનાં કપડાં પોતાની મેળે લઈ શકે ને પહેરી લે. કાઢીને પાછાં પોતાની મેળે ત્યાં જ મૂકી દે.”⁠મને થયું : “આ બાળકોનાં માબાપને વાત કહું.” મેં તેમને કહ્યું ને મારું કહેવું તેમને ગળે ઊતર્યું. એક નીચે વળગણી નખાઈ ને છોકરાંને ત્યાં કપડાં મૂકવા મળ્યું.\\"આ માથાફોડના આગળના ફકરા લખો.","answer":"⁠બીજી વાર હું આવી ચડ્યો ને મેં છોકરાંને પોતાની મેળે કપડાં ઉતારતાં અને પહેરી લેતાં જોયાં. તેઓને કોઈની ​રાહ જોવાની ન હતી. તેઓની પરાધીનતા દૂર થઈ હતી; તેઓ એટલા પૂરતા સ્વતંત્ર થયાં હતાં. તેઓને એટલું પોતાનું રાજ મળ્યું હતું.⁠મેં એમનાં માબાપનું બાળકોની સ્વાધીનતા તરફ લક્ષ ખેંચ્યું. માબાપોએ મારા વિચારને ઘરમાં ચારે કોર અમલમાં ઉતાર્યો, ને બાળકોને ઝીણી ઝીણી સગવડ કરી આપી.⁠થોડા દિવસ પછી મેં બાળકોને માટે નીચે મૂકેલો નાનો એવો ગોળો જોયો. તેઓ પોતાની મેળે પાણી પીતાં હતાં. કોઈની પાસે માગવું પડતું ન હતું. જમતી વખતે નાના એવ ઘોડા ઉપરથી પોતાનાં વાસણો પોતે જ લઈ આવતાં હતાં. અગાઉ જે કામોને માટે તેઓને મોટાંની મદદ લેવી પડતી હતી તે તેઓ જાતે કરી લેતાંહતાં.⁠મને થયું કે “મારે મારો અનુભવ સર્વ માબાપોને જણાવવો જોઈએ.”"},{"question":"ゴルフのクラブやテニスのラケットなどで、ボールを最も効果的に打つことができる場所のことを何というでしょう？","answer":"スイートスポット"},{"question":"తరుగుదల గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"యంత్రాలు నిరంతరం ఉపయోగించినప్పుడు అవి అరిగిపోయే అవకాశం ఉంది. వాటికయ్యే మరమ్మత్తు ఖర్చును తరుగుదల అంటారు."},{"question":"Ага — тууган кимде жок, сыйлашпаса жатча жок.","answer":"Кыргызда бир туугандар, туугандар менен жакшы мамиледе болуу өтө маанилүү, эгер туугандар бири-бири менен сый мамиледе болуп, бири-бирине каралашып турбаса, жат адамдан кандай пайдасы бар."},{"question":"'ඔටවනවා' මෙහි අර්ථය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ඔටවනවා  යන්න කටවහරේ ඇති වචනයක්. නිශ්චිත අර්ථයක් නැහැ. නුරුස්නා ලෙස සිටිනවාට කියන පදයක්.එස්. අයි. ගමගේ, එස්. වී. පී. සිරිසේන, සහ නයන තිලක් රත්නායක 2017 “ප්‍රාදේශීය ජනවහර වචන කෝෂය” අනුවඔටන්නා -නාම- (වැදි) නැට්ටුවා යන තේරුම සහිත යෙදුමකි.ඔටා දමනවා - ක්‍රියා- (වැදි) නටනවා යන අර්ථය දෙන්නකි.ඔටෝනවා -ක්‍රියා- (දකුණු පළාත) මාළුවාගේ කටින් බිළී කටුව ගලවනවා.ඔටෝනවා -ක්‍රියා- (හත් කෝරළය) ඔරවා බලනවා.ඔට්ටම් බිලිකතා - නාම - (හත් කෝරළය) අහංකාර කථාජේ, බී. දිසානායක 1976/1996 “සිංහල ජනවහර” පිට 87 අනුව “මාළුන් අවුත් 'මොදරෙ ඔටවන්ට' පුළුවන. 'ඔටනවා' හෝ 'ඔටෝනවා' යනු බිලී කටුව මාළු කටින් ඇදීමයි.”ප්‍රායෝගික සිංහල ශබ්දකෝෂය - හරිස්චන්ද්‍ර විජයතුංග අනුවඔටවනවා ඔටෝනවා (ක්‍රි.)1. මානනවා, අවිනම් ලෙස හෝ අඩමානෙට කියනවා.2. වැයමින් ගමන කරනවා, වැනි වැනී යනවා.3. නටනවා, ඇඟ නටවනවා.4. කට මැත හෙවත් පුරසාරම් කියනවා; ආඩම්බර පෙන්වනවා.5. කනස්සලු ලෙස මානා ගෙන ඉන්නවා, බුම්මා ගෙන ඉන්නවා.6. මාළුවා බිලි කටුව කටින් අදිනවා."},{"question":"Parí gbólóhùn tó wà nísàlẹ̀ yìí: Nígbà tí Pétérù wà lórí ìjókòó ní ọ̀run, ó dá a lábàá pé kí Ọlọ́run tún ronú nípa àwọn míì tó ṣeé ṣe kí wọ́n di onígbàgbọ́: àwọn tí kò gbà pé Ọlọ́run wà, àmọ́ tí wọ́n ṣì lè jẹ́ olódodo. Lẹ́yìn tí Marge Simpson padà sí kíláàsì Sunday school, ó sọ ìtàn nípa ìyá rẹ̀ àgbà tí kò gbà pé Ọlọ́run wà, Genevieve Bouvier, tí ó sọ pé ó gbé ní ilẹ̀ Faransé tí ìjọba Násì gbà ní 1944 nígbà Ogun Àgbáyé Kejì; ṣùgbọ́n, àkọlé ìwé náà fi hàn pé ìyá rẹ̀ àgbà ń gbé ní Vichy, Faransé tí ìjọba Násì gbà ní 1944. O ṣe alakoso Cafe Meaux pẹlu orukọ orukọ kafe naa, ọkọ rẹ Meaux, alabaṣiṣẹpọ Nazi kan. Nígbà tí Meaux tó jẹ́ òpùrọ́, tí òun fúnra rẹ̀ gbà pé ó jẹ́ òpùrọ́, ń fi ẹsẹ̀ lé ọ̀gágun Násì àti àwọn òṣìṣẹ́ tó wà pẹ̀lú rẹ̀, Genevieve lọ síbi ìsàlẹ̀ tó fẹ̀ lọ́nà láti lọ se oúnjẹ alẹ́ fún àwọn òṣìṣẹ́ náà. Ibẹ̀ ló ti rí àwọn nkankan...","answer":"Àwọn ọmọ ogun tí wọ́n ń fi parachute wọlé, tí wọ́n sì fi ara wọn hàn bí àwọn òṣìṣẹ́ ilé oúnjẹ. Nígbà tí wọ́n ń jẹun, ọ̀kan lára àwọn ọmọ ogun ilẹ̀ Amẹ́ríkà sọ fún wọn nípa bí wọ́n ṣe fẹ́ kó àwọn ọmọ ogun wọn dé ilẹ̀ Normandy. Láti dá àwọn Násì dúró láti kìlọ̀ fún àwọn ẹlòmíràn, àwọn ọmọ ogun Amẹ́ríkà kọrin La Marseillaise, orin orílẹ̀-èdè Faransé, èyí tí ó mú kí àwọn oníbàárà ilé ìjẹun náà dìde dúró kí wọ́n sì dara pọ̀ mọ́ wọn láti dí àwọn Násì lọ́wọ́. Genevieve àti Meaux ló mú kí wọ́n pa àwọn òṣìṣẹ́ ìjọba Násì, èyí sì fi hàn pé òótọ́ ni ohun tí Marge ń sọ pé àwọn aláìgbà-pọ́lọ́run náà lè ṣe àwọn nǹkan ńláńlá. Ní ọ̀run, Ọlọ́run gbà láti ṣí ọ̀run fún àwọn aláìgbọlọ́rungbọ́."},{"question":"Inty misy fehezanteny:\\"Hilalao baolina izahay rahapmpitso.\\"Omeo ny anjara asan'ny teny tsirairay mandrafitra io fehezanteny io.","answer":"Indro ny anjara asan'ny teny tsirairay mandrafitra io fehezanteny io:Hilalao: Enti-milazaizahay: Lazainarahampitso: Famenon'ny enti-milaza"},{"question":"Ang mga sumusunod nga sentensya kay Ingles, e-translate sa Bisaya\\"I come from Manila. My name is Michael and I'm 23 years old. I go to University of the Philippines.\\"","answer":"\\"Taga Manila ko. Ako si Michael, 23 anyos nako. Ga skwela ko sa University of the Philippines.\\""},{"question":"Ity fanambarana manaraka ity dia amin'ny teny anglisy, adika amin'ny teny Malagasy\\"Madagascar is an island nation located in the Indian Ocean, off the southeastern coast of Africa.\\"","answer":"I Madagasikara dia nosy iray izay mipetraka eny amin'ny faritra ranomasina indianina , atsimo antsinanan'i Afirka"},{"question":"उत्सव मनाउनमा बालबालिकाहरू कसरी सहभागी हुन्छन्?","answer":"बालबालिकाहरू उत्सवमा सजावट बनाउने, परम्परागत नृत्य सिक्ने, कथाकलाप गर्ने, र प्रत्येक उत्सवको खासै खेलमा सहभागी हुने क्रियाहरूद्वारा  सहभागी हुन्छन्।"},{"question":"Сен да меникисиң, өлүгүңдү Эсенканга белекке берем деген ким, аны кимге айтты?а) Эсенкан Коңурбайга б) Коңурбай Алмамбеткев) Бакай Нукерге г) Чубак Сыргакка","answer":"Сен да меникисиң, өлүгүңдү Эсенканга белекке берем деген Коңурбай, аны Алмамбетке айтты. Туура жообу б) варианты болот."},{"question":"Карадалы деген сөздү кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Карадалы деп турмушка чыкпай калган кыздарды айтышкан."},{"question":"اكمل الفقرة التالية:كيف تحصل على المساعدة؟وعن كيفية الحصول على المساعدة إذا كنت تعاني من شعورك بالهلاك الوشيك؟  نشر","answer":"بعض النصائح المساعدة من موقع \\"فري ول مايند\\"، وأولها، التحدث مع طبيبك لتشخيص حالتك، واستبعاد الأسباب الطبية المحتملة، والتوصية بعلاجات فعالة يمكن أن تساعدك."},{"question":"Yedi Güzel Adam dizisinin konusu nedir?","answer":"Konusu. Türk edebiyatında önemli yerleri bulunan edebî kişiler olan Cahit Zarifoğlu, Mehmet Akif İnan, Erdem Bayazıt, Rasim Özdenören, Ali Kutlay, Nuri Pakdil ve Alâeddin Özdenören'in hayatları konu alınmaktadır."},{"question":"'Ngiyajabula ukukwazi,' kungundaza uNdumiso engayibuki nokuyibuka,eyizamulisa kakhulu imoto sekuthi akaqhume ukucasuka ngenxa yalomuntu olokhu embangela ukushisa ekubeni engafune kuxoxa ngobakuningi okumxake engqondweni.Hhayi, yabona intokazi yabantu ukuthi kayingangayo, yazithungelaumlomo wayo. Yashosholoza njalo imoto kuthule kuthe cwakalapha emotweni. Kwakudlange zona nje izithukuthuku kuNdumisoowayelokhu eqalaza ubala, ikakhulukazi uma kuqhamuka imoto ethikayifane neyamaphoyisa. Okwase kumjulukisa nakakhulu ngukuthiwayengasakwazi nokuvula umsakazo ezwe ukuthi kayikaphumi yiniindaba yakhe ezindabeni emsakazweni. Wayengenakuwuvula-ke ngobauZakithi wayezoba nezinsolo, konakale yonke le nto.1. Uyazwelana nabazali bakaNkululeko mayelana nokungaphumeleli komshadowakhe? Yikuphi owawungakwenza ukuba wawulitholile ithuba lokukhulumanoNkululeko?","answer":"Ngiyazwelana nabo ngoba ukwaliwa nokuzibulala kukaNkululeko kwabathelangehlazo futhi bachithakalelwa yizimali ngokulungiselela umshadoongekho.Ngangingamduduza ngimbonise ngokubaluleka kokuqhubekanempilo bese ngimfunela usizo kodokotela abaluleka ngokwezengqondo."},{"question":"Welke elementen zijn er in het spel Genshin Impact?","answer":"Er zijn 7 elementen in Genshin Impact. Deze zijn Pyro (Vuur), Anemo (Wind), Hydro (Water), Geo (Steen), Electro (Elektriciteit), Dendro (Planten), en Cryo (Ijs)."},{"question":"I will like to throw","answer":"I will like to throw light on this understanding. Several have always lived their lives with the perception of cultivating earthly possessions, fame, and earthly power, amongst others, whom the preacher identifies as vanity. This indicates that if we walk through the path of life with a fixated mindset of acquiring what we could see with our physical eyes, which is heard now and thereafter, it is not feasible as the owner of the breath of life will one day withdraw it from the container (body). Many have fallen into the trap of deceit; they have delved into despicable acts at the expense of acquiring things that would attract the flesh. This statement was extracted from the scripture in Matthew 4. Jesus was tempted by the devil, and his first temptation was that of the lust of the flesh. It is a pity that it is an ancient antics orchestrated by man's archenemy, and it is still very much in play today. This is for someone who is about to make a decision that could alter the course of their destiny. The scripture went on to say, 'WHAT CAN A MAN EXCHANGE FOR HIS SOUL'. Many are hourly or daily doing so, and several are at the junction of making such a decision. Remember, the life you live in this world is infinitesimally small compared to that which is to come in eternity. However, your decision in this limited timeline will determine where your destination lies (eternal life or eternal damnation). Choose life (JESUS CHRIST) today and start living."},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Trong hình ảnh của NASA, Moonikin Campus đã mặc xong bộ quần áo phi hành gia màu cam, là trang phục mới được thiết kế riêng cho sứ mệnh Mặt Trăng mới. Theo tờ Space, Moonikin Campus sẽ là phi hành gia ngồi ghế chỉ huy của tàu vũ trụ Orion, thứ sẽ được đặt lên đỉnh Hệ thống phóng Không gian (SLS) - một siêu tên lửa mới của NASA - để thực hiện sứ mệnh Artemis 1 quanh Mặt Trăng. Điều bất thường duy nhất, đó là Moonikin Campus... không phải con người. Anh ta là một hình nộm có kích thước y hệt con người và mang rất nhiều cảm biến trên cơ thể, với nhiệm vụ chính là thu thập những dữ liệu quan trọng","answer":"về tác động của chuyến đi đối với cơ thể người. Đây là lần đầu tiên NASA thử nghiệm phóng tàu vũ trụ bằng tên lửa SLS với một nhiệm vụ nhiều khác biệt so với các nhiệm vụ Mặt Trăng trước đó, nên họ cần thử nghiệm để đảm bảo cho Artemis 2 vào năm 2024 và Artemis 3 sau đó. Hai sứ mệnh 2 và 3 sẽ có người thật, trong đó một cái sẽ là chuyến bay vòng quanh Mặt Trăng, cái thứ 2 là nhiệm vụ đổ bộ. \\"Moonikin Campus sẽ đo các rung động và gia tốc mà các phi hành gia NASA Artemis trong tương lai sẽ trải qua\\" - NASA cho biết trên Twitter. Các phép đo quan trọng sẽ được thu thập bởi 2 cảm biến đặt sau ghế chỉ huy và dưới cái tựa đầu. Vị chỉ huy này cũng sẽ mang 2 cảm biến bức xạ để đo độ phơi nhiễm bức xạ. Bộ đồ màu cam Moonikin Campus mặc cũng là một thử nghiệm khác của NASA, nhằm tạo nên trang phục tối ưu nhất cho các sứ mệnh vũ trụ. Campos sẽ không đơn độc vì anh ta sẽ bay cùng 2 \\"thuộc cấp\\" khác là Helga và Zohar, tất nhiên cũng là hình nộm. Hai hình nộm này không có tay chân như vị chỉ huy, là thiết kế đơn giản hơn, như một phần của Thí nghiệm bức xạ Matroshka AstroRad (MARE). Hiện Moonikin Campus đã yên vị trên ghế chỉ huy. Sứ mệnh Artemis 1 dự kiến sẽ khởi động vào ngày 29-8 sắp tới."},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ કહે છે: \\"આશ્રમવૃક્ષો પછી આ વનવૃક્ષો છે. મનુષ્યજીવન અને વનસ્પતિજીવન એકબીજાનાં કેવી રીતે સહાયક છે અને કુદરતનું ડહાપણ કેવું અદ્‌ભૂત છે એની ખબર કુદરતના અભ્યાસમાંથી પડે છે. વનવૃક્ષો માત્ર વૃક્ષોની યાદી નથી કે તેનાં વર્ણનો નથી. પક્ષીઓ પેઠે વૃક્ષો પણ અભ્યાસ કરવા યોગ્ય છે, અને એ રસિક અભ્યાસની દિશા ઉઘાડવા માટે આવાં પુસ્તકોની યોજના છે.\\"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાએ \\"નેતર\\" વિષે શું વર્ણન કર્યું છે?","answer":"કોઈ વાર તમે નેતરની સોટી વાંસામાં ખાધી હશે. નાની નાની, હલાવીએ ત્યારે આમતેમ વળે તેવી, નેતરની સોટીઓ તમે વાપરી હશે. નેતરથી ભરેલી ખુરશી ઉપર તમે કદાચ બેઠા પણ હશો.તમને ખબર છે આ નેતર શું છે ?નેતરની સોટીઓ નેતરના ઝાડની ડાળો છે. નેતરની ટોપલીઓ, નેતરની સોટીઓની ચીપોમાંથી બનાવે છે.આ નેતરનું ઝાડ મેં તો હજી ભાળ્યું નથી અને કદાચ તમે પણ નહિ જોયું હોય. આપણે ત્યાં નેતર મલબાર ને મહાબળેશ્વર, મેંગલોર અને રામેશ્વરમાં થાય છે. પણ નેતરનાં વનનાં વન તો ચીનમાં થાય છે.ચીનમાંથી આપણા દેશમાં ચીની વાસણ આવે છે, ચીની ફટકડા આવે છે, એ તો તમે જાણતા હશો; પણ એટલું બધું નેતર પણ ચીનમાંથી આવે છે એ હવે જાણજો.બધા દેશો આપણા દેશમાં મોકલે અને આપણે વાપરીએ ! આપણે ત્યાં તો ઘણું છે પણ આપણને હજી ઉગાડતાં, વધારતાં ને વાપરતાં ક્યાં આવડે છે ? એનું કારણ તો એમ કે આપણે આળસુ છીએ. આપણે ચીનમાંથી નેતર ન મગાવીએ તો મોટો એક લાભ એ થાય કે માસ્તરો ને સિપાઈઓના હાથમાંથી નેતરની સોટીઓ ચાલી જાય. જે નિશાળિયા હશે તેમને તો આ વાત ખૂબ ગમશે.નેતર વાળીએ તેમ વળે તેવું છે. ચોપડીઓમાં તેને માટે અઘરું વિશેષણ લખેલું છે; વાળીએ તેવું વળે ને પાછું હતું તેમ થઈ જાય એટલે સ્થિતિસ્થાપક.વાંસની સોટી જેમ નેતર ભાંગી જતું નથી. તે ઘણું ચીકણું છે એટલે જ માસ્તરો નેતરની સોટી પસંદ કરે છે. છોકરાનો બરડો ભાંગે પણ નેતરની સોટી ન તૂટે ! પણ મને લાગે છે કે નિશાળના બધા છોકરા ભેગા મળીને માસ્તરના વાંસા ઉપર એને ભાંગી શકે ખરા. પણ આવું કોઈ કરશો નહિ, હો ભાઈ !કોઈ કહેશો કે નેતરનું ઝાડ કેટલા હાથ ઊંચું થતું હશે ?તમે નથી કહેતા ત્યારે લ્યો હું કહું. તે ત્રીશથી ચાળીશ હાથ ઊંચું થાય છે. ઊંચું થાય છે છતાં તે ભલા માણસ પેઠે ખૂબ નમે છે. ભલાઈથી નમવું બહુ સારું છે, પણ નેતરની સોટીથી નમવું એ કાંઈ સારું નથી !"},{"question":"Inona no volana faharoa anatin'ny taona?","answer":"Ny volana faharoa anatin'ny taona dia volana febroary."},{"question":"Напиши продовження - В ході розвідувального польоту під час боїв на Курській дузі","answer":"Володимир Ніколаєнко виявив в районі сіл Рогівка і Куракіне 490 танків і до 950 автомашин противника. Цінні розвідувальні відомості були використані командуванням фронту при розробці плану наступальної операції. "},{"question":"પ્રાણીશાસ્ત્ર વિષે વર્ણન કરો.","answer":"પ્રાણીશાસ્ત્ર એ પ્રાણીઓનો વૈજ્ .ાનિક અભ્યાસ છે.તેના અધ્યયનોમાં રચના, ગર્ભ, વર્ગીકરણ, ટેવ અને તમામ પ્રાણીઓનું વિતરણ, જીવંત અને લુપ્ત બંને અને તેઓ તેમના ઇકોસિસ્ટમ્સ સાથે કેવી રીતે સંપર્ક કરે છે તે શામેલ છે.પ્રાણીશાસ્ત્ર એ જીવવિજ્ .ાનની પ્રાથમિક શાખાઓમાંની એક છે.આ શબ્દ પ્રાચીન ગ્રીક પરથી આવ્યો છે.તેમ છતાં, માણસો હંમેશાં તેમની આસપાસના પ્રાણીઓના કુદરતી ઇતિહાસમાં રસ લેતા હોય છે, અને આ જ્ knowledge ાનનો ઉપયોગ અમુક પ્રજાતિઓનું પાલન કરવા માટે કરે છે, ઝૂલોજીનો study પચારિક અભ્યાસ એરિસ્ટોટલથી થયો હોવાનું કહી શકાય.તેમણે પ્રાણીઓને જીવંત સજીવ તરીકે જોયા, તેમની રચના અને વિકાસનો અભ્યાસ કર્યો, અને તેમના આસપાસના અને તેમના ભાગોના કાર્યમાં તેમના અનુકૂલનને ધ્યાનમાં લીધું.આધુનિક પ્રાણીશાસ્ત્રની ઉત્પત્તિ પુનરુજ્જીવન અને પ્રારંભિક આધુનિક સમયગાળા દરમિયાન છે, જેમાં કાર્લ લિનાયસ, એન્ટોની વેન લીઉવેનહોક, રોબર્ટ હૂક, ચાર્લ્સ ડાર્વિન, ગ્રેગોર મેન્ડેલ અને અન્ય ઘણા લોકો છે.\\""},{"question":"Inona no anjara asan'ny kolontsaina eo amin'ny fanehoana ny fihetseham-po?","answer":"Ny kolontsaina dia mety hisy fiantraikany amin'ny fomba fanehoana, fandikana ary fitantanana ny fihetseham-po ao anatin'ny fiarahamonina iray."},{"question":"Joko: … Konférénsi Asia Afrika lumangsung?Sri: Konférénsi Asia Afrika lumangsung antara 18 April-24 April 1955.A. Di manaB. IrahaC. SahaKontéks: Lengkepan kalimah di luhur ku kecap nu paling bener.","answer":"Eusi: B. Iraha"},{"question":"« Efa tsy fisian-drano no manahirana ny sain’ny vahoaka maro ankehitriny. May ny tranon’ny olona iray anefa ka tsy maintsy natao izay hamonoana ny afo ; indrindra raha tsy ahena ny firedaredan’ny afo dia tsy maintsy hihitatra izany. Ela ihany koa ireo mpamonjy voina vao tonga hamono izany. Tsy maintsy nitady vahaolana maika anefa. » Inona  amin’ireto manaraka ireto no mety fiafaran’ny tantara :A. Niandry mpamonjy voina ho tonga vao namono ny afo kanefa efa mihitatra ilay izy.B. Nanondraka ny afo tamin’ny rano sisa izay mbola nisy.","answer":"B no mety fiafaran’ny tantara."},{"question":"ماهو الجواب الصحيح للسؤال التالي: من هي الشخصية الرئيسية في جراند ثفت أوتو 5؟","answer":"الشخصية الرئيسية هي تريفور فيليبس."},{"question":"வினா: மயொங்கொலி எழுத்துக்களின் எண்ணிக்கை?","answer":"விடை: 8"},{"question":"ما هي عاصمة الجزائر؟","answer":"الجزائر"},{"question":"Vẽ ba đường thẳng phân biệt bất kì, số giao điểm của ba đường thẳng đó không thể là:A. 0B. 1 hoặc 2C. 4D. 3","answer":"Trả lời:Với 3 đường thẳng phân biệt ta có các trường hợp sau:+ Không có đường thẳng nào cắt nhau nên không có điểm chung.+ Hai đường thẳng cắt nhau, đường thẳng còn lại không cắt hai đường thẳng đó, khi đó có 1 điểm chung.+ Ba đường thẳng đó có đôi một cắt nhau thì có ba điểm chung.Vậy không thể có trường hợp ba đường thẳng phân biệt bất kì mà có 4 điểm chung.Đáp án cần chọn là: C"},{"question":"Rispondi alla domanda. Dove è la Francia?","answer":"Risposta: la Francia è uno Stato situato nell'Europa occidentale[10] e nell'Europa meridionale, ma che possiede ugualmente territori disseminati su più oceani e altri continenti."},{"question":"Fan la universite Asan Sekk nekk ?","answer":"Ziguinchor "},{"question":" Qual é o único mamífero que voa?","answer":"A folha."},{"question":"வினா : திருவள்ளுவரின் மனைவி பெயர் என்ன ?","answer":"விடை : வாசுகி,"},{"question":"1 tercihlerde yerleşen 2 Tercih Yapabilir mi?","answer":"Bir bölüme yerleşen öğrenciler ek tercih döneminden yararlanamayacak. Tercihinden memnun olmayanlar seneye tekrar sınava girmek zorunda kalacak. Yerleştirme sonuçları açıklandı, sıra kazanılan üniversitelere kayıt yaptırmaya geldi."},{"question":"昔からの言い伝えで地震を起こすといわれる淡水魚といえば何？","answer":"なまずです。"},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Marshall?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Marshall mu ngi tudu Majuro."},{"question":"बर्दिया राष्ट्रिय निकुञ्ज","answer":"गतिविधिहरू: जंगल सफारी, जंगल पैदल, डुङ्गा सवारी, जीप ड्राइभआवास: जंगल लजहरूपहुँच: नेपालगन्जबाट तीन घण्टाको ड्राइभ (९५ किमी), जुन हवाई मार्गबाट १ घण्टा वा काठमाडौंबाट सडकबाट ५१६ किमी।वन्यजन्तु: रोयल बेङ्गाल टाइगर, एकसिङ्गे गैंडा, हात्ती, दलदल मृग, कालो हरिण सहित ३० भन्दा बढी स्तनपायी प्राणीहरू; सरीसृपहरूमा घरियाल गोही, मार्स मगर गोही समावेश छ; कर्णाली नदीमा ताजा पानीको गंगाको डल्फिन प्रायः देखिन्छचराहरू: २३० प्रजातिका चराहरूमा बंगाल फ्लोरिकन, लेसर फ्लोरिकन, सिल्भर इयरेड मेसिया र सरस क्रेन समावेश छन्।वनस्पति: साल, सवाना जंगल र घाँसे मैदानउत्तम सिजन: अक्टोबर-मार्च, अप्रिल-जून (तातो/सुक्खा, ४२ डिग्री सेल्सियससम्म), जुलाई-सेप्टेम्बर (वर्षा)पार्क मुख्यालय: ठाकुरद्वाराप्रवेश शुल्क: नेपाली - प्रतिदिन रु ५० प्रति प्रवेश, सार्क नागरिक - प्रतिव्यक्ति रु ५०० प्रति दिन, विदेशी - प्रतिव्यक्ति रु १,०००"},{"question":"Ẹ̀yà àrà wo ni ó wà fún ìríran?","answer":"Ojú "},{"question":"මධ්‍යධරණි මුහුදත් රතු මුහුදත් යා කරමින් මිනිසා විසින් තැනූ ඇළ කුමක්ද?","answer":"මධ්‍යධරණි මුහුදත් රතු මුහුදත් යා කරමින් මිනිසා විසින් තැනූ ඇළ සූවස් ඇළ වේ. එය ඊජිප්තියානු කෘත්‍රිම මුහුදු-මට්ටම් දිය මගකි. වසර 10 ක ගොඩනැගීම් කටයුතු වලින් පසුව 1869 නොවැම්බර් මසදී විවෘත කෙරුණු එය, අප්‍රිකාව වටා යාත්‍රණයෙන් වැලැකෙමින් යුරෝපය සහ ආසියාව අතර යාත්‍රා ප්‍රවාහණය සලසයි."},{"question":"தமிழ் எழுத்து பற்றிய வரலாற்றை எழுதுங்கள்","answer":"மற்ற பிராமிக் எழுத்துக்களைப் போலவே தமிழ் எழுத்துக்களும் அசல் பிராமி எழுத்துக்களில் இருந்து உருவானதாகக் கருதப்படுகிறது . தமிழ் எழுத்துக்கான எடுத்துக்காட்டுகளாக ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட ஆரம்பகால கல்வெட்டுகள் அசோகன் காலத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவை. இத்தகைய கல்வெட்டுகளால் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் கையெழுத்துப்படிவம் பொதுவாக தமிழ்-பிராமி அல்லது \\"தமிழி எழுத்து\\" என்றும் நிலையான அசோகன் பிராமியிலிருந்து பல வழிகளில் வேறுபடுகிறது. எடுத்துக்காட்டாக, ஆரம்பகால தமிழ்-பிராமி, அசோகன் பிராமியைப் போலல்லாமல், தூய மெய்யெழுத்துக்கள் ( மீ , இந்த எடுத்துக்காட்டில்) மற்றும் மெய்யெழுத்துக்களை உள்ளார்ந்த உயிரெழுத்துக்களுடன் ( மா , இந்த எடுத்துக்காட்டில்) வேறுபடுத்துவதற்கான அமைப்பு இருந்தது . கூடுதலாக, ஐராவதம் மகாதேவன் கருத்துப்படி, ஆரம்பகால தமிழ் பிராமி, சற்றே வித்தியாசமான உயிரெழுத்து குறிப்பான்களைப் பயன்படுத்தியது, சமஸ்கிருதத்தில் காணப்படாத எழுத்துக்களைக் குறிக்கும் கூடுதல் எழுத்துக்களைக் கொண்டிருந்தது மற்றும் தமிழில் இல்லாத குரல் மெய்யெழுத்துக்கள் மற்றும் ஆஸ்பிரேட்டுகள் போன்ற ஒலிகளுக்கான எழுத்துக்களை விடுவித்தது. இரண்டாம் நூற்றாண்டைச் சேர்ந்த கல்வெட்டுகள் தமிழ்-பிராமியின் பிற்கால வடிவத்தைப் பயன்படுத்துகின்றன, இது தொல்காப்பியத்தில் விவரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள எழுத்து முறையைப் போன்றது, இது பண்டைய தமிழ் இலக்கணமாகும். மிகவும் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க வகையில், அவர்கள் உள்ளார்ந்த உயிரெழுத்தை அடக்குவதற்கு புள்ளியைப் பயன்படுத்தினர். அதன்பிறகு தமிழ் எழுத்துக்கள் மிகவும் உருண்டையான வடிவத்தை நோக்கி பரிணமித்தன, மேலும் ஐந்தாம் அல்லது ஆறாம் நூற்றாண்டில், அவை ஆரம்பகால வட்டெழுத்து என வடிவத்தை அடைந்தன.இருப்பினும், தற்காலத் தமிழ் எழுத்துமுறை அந்த எழுத்தில் இருந்து தோன்றவில்லை. நான்காம் நூற்றாண்டில், பல்லவ வம்சத்தினர் தமிழுக்குப் பல்லவ எழுத்துக்கள் என்று ஒரு புதிய எழுத்தை உருவாக்கினர் மற்றும் கிரந்த எழுத்துக்களில் இருந்து உருவாகி, சமஸ்கிருதத்தை எழுதக் காணப்படாத ஒலிகளுக்கு வட்டெழுத்து எழுத்துகளைச் சேர்த்தனர். கிரந்த எழுத்துக்களுக்கு இணையாக ஒரு புதிய கையெழுத்துப்படிவம் (சோழ-பல்லவ கையெழுத்துப்படிவம், இது நவீன தமிழ் எழுத்துக்களாக உருவானது) மீண்டும் பல்லவ மற்றும் சோழ பிரதேசங்களில் கிரந்த போன்ற கிரந்த வளர்ச்சியை ஒத்திருக்கிறது, இருப்பினும், அதன் வடிவங்களில் பெரிதும் குறைக்கப்பட்டது மற்றும் முந்தவில்லை. தாய்மொழி தமிழ் உரத்த ஒலிகள். எட்டாம் நூற்றாண்டில் பல்லவ மற்றும் சோழர்களில் புதிய எழுத்துக்கள் வாட்டெழுத்துக்குப் பதிலாக மாற்றப்பட்டன.தமிழ் பேசும் பிராந்தியத்தின் வடக்குப் பகுதியில் அமைந்திருந்த ராஜ்யங்கள். இருப்பினும் , தமிழ் பேசும் பகுதியின் தென்பகுதியில், சேர மற்றும் பாண்டிய ராஜ்ஜியங்களில், பதினோராம் நூற்றாண்டு வரை, பாண்டிய ராஜ்ஜியம் சோழர்களால் குறுகிய காலத்திற்குப் பல்லவர்களின் நிலப்பிரபுத்துவத்தில் இருந்தபோது பாண்டிய இராச்சியத்தை கைப்பற்றும் வரை வட்டெழுத்து தொடர்ந்து பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டது.பல்லவ சாம்ராஜ்ஜியத்தின் வீழ்ச்சியுடன், சோழ வம்சம் சோழ-பல்லவ எழுத்துக்களை நடைமுறை எழுத்துகளாக மாற்றியது. அடுத்த சில நூற்றாண்டுகளில், சோழ-பல்லவ எழுத்துகள் நவீன தமிழ் எழுத்துகளாக பரிணமித்தன. கிரந்தமும் அதன் மூல எழுத்தும் தமிழ் எழுத்துக்களில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தியது. பனை ஓலைகளை முதன்மையான ஊடகமாகப் பயன்படுத்தியதால் எழுத்துமுறையில் மாற்றங்கள் ஏற்பட்டன. எழுத்தாளர் எழுதும் போது எழுத்தாணியால் இலைகளைத் துளைக்காமல் கவனமாக இருக்க வேண்டும், எனவே துளையுடன் கூடிய இலைகளை வேகமாக கிழித்து அழுகும் வாய்ப்பு அதிகம். இதன் விளைவாக, தூய மெய்யெழுத்துகளை வேறுபடுத்திப் பார்ப்பதற்குப் புள்ளியைப் பயன்படுத்துவது அரிதாகிவிட்டது, தூய மெய் எழுத்துக்கள் பொதுவாக உள்ளார்ந்த உயிரெழுத்து இருப்பது போல் எழுதப்படும். இதேபோல், உயிரெழுத்து குறிப்பான் ( ஃ ) என்றால்: தமிழ்: குற்றியலுகரம் , ஒரு அரை வட்டமான , சில சொற்களின் முடிவிலும், சில கூட்டுச் சொற்களின் இடைநிலை நிலையிலும், சுருக்கப்பட்ட ஒலியைக் குறிக்கும், மேலும் பயன்பாட்டில் இருந்து வெளியேறி, குறிப்பானால் மாற்றப்பட்டது. எளிய 'உ' அச்சிடும் அறிமுகம் வரை புள்ளி முழுமையாக மீண்டும் தோன்றவில்லை , ஆனால் குறிப்பான 'ஃ' அதன் பயன்பாடு சில இலக்கண கருத்தியல் சொற்களில் தக்கவைக்கப்பட்டாலும், இந்த நோக்கத்திற்காக மீண்டும் ஒருபோதும் பயன்பாட்டிற்கு வரவில்லை, அதேசமயம் ஒலியே இன்னும் தமிழ் உரைநடையில் முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கிறது .கையெழுத்துப்படிவம் எளிதாக தட்டச்சு செய்ய சில எழுத்துக்களின் வடிவங்கள் பத்தொன்பதாம் நூற்றாண்டில் நவீனப்படுத்தப்பட்டன. இருபதாம் நூற்றாண்டில் தமிழில், கையெழுத்துப்படிவம் சீர்திருத்தங்களின் தொடரில் மேலும் எளிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்டது , இது சிறப்பு குறிப்பான்கள் மற்றும் மிகவும் ஒழுங்கற்ற வடிவங்களை நீக்குவதன் மூலம் மெய்யெழுத்துக்களுடன் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் உயிரெழுத்து குறிப்பான்களை முறைப்படுத்தியது."},{"question":"Qual o papel dos sinais e da intuição no livro \\"O Alquimiasta\\".","answer":"Sinais e intuição desempenham um papel crucial em \\"O Alquimista\\". Santiago aprende a interpretar os sinais do universo, confiando na sua intuição para guiar as suas escolhas, simbolizando a conexão entre o indivíduo e o cosmos."},{"question":"Анапсиддер деген эмне ?","answer":"Анапсиддер (лат. Anapsida) — сойлоктордун бир классчасы."},{"question":"De qual categoria é essa pergunta: Quantos países na Ásia possuem uma área total menor que 1000 milhas quadradas?.","answer":"Geografia"},{"question":"সৈন্যদের একটি দল নদীর তীরে দাঁড়িয়ে আছে। নদী পার হতে হবে। কিন্তু ব্রিজটি ভাঙা। আবার নদীটি বেশ গভীর আর বড়। সাঁতার কেটে পার হওয়া প্রায় অসম্ভব। হঠাৎ এক সৈন্যের চোখ পড়ল নদীর তীরে। একটি ছোট নৌকায় দুটি ছোট ছেলে খেলছে। সৈন্য নৌকা নিয়ে কাছে আসতে বললেন তাদের। তারা এল। কিন্তু তাদের নৌকা অনেক ছোট। ওই দুই ছেলের পাশাপাশি আর কোনো সৈন্য নৌকায় উঠলে নৌকা ডুবে যাবে। হয় ছেলে দুটি নৌকায় থাকতে পারবে অথবা একজন সৈন্য। কিন্তু তারপরও সব সৈন্য সুন্দরভাবে নৌকার সাহায্য নিয়ে নদী পার হলো। বলো তো, সৈন্যরা কীভাবে পার হলো নদীটি?","answer":"প্রথমে ছোট ছেলে দুটি নদী পার হলো। এরপর ছেলেদের একজন নৌকা নিয়ে আবার ফিরে আসে সৈন্যদের কাছে। এরপর একজন সৈন্য নৌকাটি নিয়ে নদী পার হবে। নদীর ওপারে দাঁড়িয়ে থাকা ছেলেটি আবার নৌকা নিয়ে ফিরে আসবে সৈন্যদের কাছে। এভাবে সব সৈন্য নদী পার হবে।"},{"question":"No trato digestório humano, a digestão química de proteínas depende basicamente de enzimas produzidas em que órgãos?","answer":"A digestão de proteínas no corpo humano depende de enzimas produzidas no estômago, no pâncreas e no duodeno."},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"சாமி குழந்தைகளைக் கொடுக்கிறது என்று சொல்லுகிறார்களே, அந்தச் சாமி கஞ்சியையும் ஊற்றுமா?."},{"question":"اذكر الحدث الأهم في النص التالي: بعد تفكك الاتحاد السوفيتي ، قادت الولايات المتحدة أو دعمت الحروب لتحديد حكم عدد من البلدان. تضمنت أهداف الولايات المتحدة المعلنة في هذه النزاعات خوض الحرب على الإرهاب كما في حرب أفغانستان عام 2001 ، أو إزالة الأنظمة الديكتاتورية والعدائية في حرب العراق عام 2003 والتدخل العسكري في ليبيا عام 2011 .","answer":"التدخل العسكري في ليبيا عام 2011"},{"question":"Okay, so I'll lead the team.is it grammatically correct?","answer":"Yes, the sentence \\"Okay, so I'll lead the team\\" is grammatically correct. It's a clear and concise way to confirm your decision to take on the leadership role."},{"question":"Inona no vahaolana ?","answer":"Ny vahaolana dia ny  fizarana ny olana"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਬਹੁਤਾ ਕਹੀਐ ਬਹੁਤਾ ਹੋਇ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 5 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਿਉਂ ਜਿਉਂ ਇਹ ਗੱਲ ਆਖੀ ਜਾਵੀਏ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਵੱਡਾ ਹੈ, ਤਿਉਂ ਤਿਉਂ ਉਹ ਹੋਰ ਵੱਡਾ, ਹੋਰ ਵੱਡਾ ਪਰਤੀਤ ਹੋਣ ਲੱਗ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ।\\""},{"question":"Fenoy ity ohabolana ity: \\"Tahaka ny kitoza ny fiainana, ___\\"","answer":"\\"Tahaka ny kitoza ny fiainana, ka izay mahadinidinika azy ihany no mandre ny tsirony.\\""},{"question":"次のパラグラフを続ける： 千葉県香取市の佐原地区には江戸時代のようなまちがあります。12日、まちを流れる小野川で、ひな祭りのイベントがありました。","answer":"60人ぐらいがきれいな着物を着て、ひな人形と同じ格好をしました。そして5つの舟に乗って、川を進んでいきました。舟の上では、古い歴史がある音楽の演奏がありました。舟に乗った女の子は「お姫様になって楽しかったです。とてもすてきだと思いました」と話していました。 川の周りでは、たくさんの人が楽しんでいました。神奈川県から来た女性は「ゆっくり見ることができてよかったです。美しくて春のような気分になりました」と話していました。"},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന വാചകം പൂർത്തിയാക്കുക: ഒന്നാം ഗൾഫ് യുദ്ധത്തിനിടെ അമേരിക്കൻ വ്യോമസേന ഇറാഖിലെ ബാഗ്ദാദിൽ നടത്തിയ ഒരു സിവിലിയൻ കൂട്ടക്കൊലയാണ് അമീറിയ ഷെൽട്ടർ കൂട്ടക്കൊല അല്ലെങ്കിൽ അമീറിയ ഷെൽട്ടർ ബോംബിംഗ് എന്ന് അറിയപ്പെടുന്നത്. 13 February 1991 ഫെബ്രുവരി 13നായിരുന്നു പ്രസ്തുത സംഭവം. അമേരിക്കൻ വ്യോമസേനയുടെ ബോംബിങ്ങിൽ നിന്ന് രക്ഷപ്പെടാൻ അൽ അമീറിയ സിവിലിയൻ ബോംബ്‌ ഷെൽട്ടറിൽ (\\"Public Shelter No. 25\\") പുലർച്ചെ നാലുമണിക്ക് അഭയം തേടിയ ജനങ്ങൾക്കുമേൽ അമേരിക്കൻ വിമാനം ബങ്കർ ബസ്റ്റർ ബോംബ്‌ വർഷിക്കുകയായിരുന്നു. ഇറാൻ ഇറാഖ് യുദ്ധസമയത്ത് നിർമിച്ചതായിരിയുന്നു ഈ ഷെൽട്ടർ.","answer":" രക്ഷ തേടിയിറങ്ങിയ സ്ത്രീകളും കുഞ്ഞുങ്ങളും അടക്കം 408 സാധാരണക്കാർ കൊല്ലപ്പെട്ടു. ബോംബു സ്ഫോടനത്തിൽ ഉയർന്ന ചൂടിൽ കൊല്ലപ്പെട്ടവരിൽ ചിലരുടെ ശരീരം ഉരുകി ഷെൽട്ടറിന്റെ ഭിത്തികളിൽ ചിത്രം പോലെ പതിക്കപ്പെട്ട സംഭവങ്ങളും ഉണ്ടായി. ഈ ഷെൽട്ടർ ഏറെ കാലം ഒരു യുദ്ധ വിരുദ്ധ സ്മാരകം ആയിരുന്നു."},{"question":"Акча деген эмне ?","answer":"Акча — бул товар же кызматка төлөм катары кабыл алынуучу кагаз же эсептеги жазуу. Акча — жалпы товарлардын жана кызматтардын баалоо эквивалентинин өзгөчө товары."},{"question":"Indil péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Paaka ba nag daa lemu; duggut.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Paaka ba nag daa lemu; duggut.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Paaka: NOUNba: DETnag: ADVda: AUXa: PARTlemu: VERB;: PUNCTduggut: VERB.: PUNCT"},{"question":"రెండు పాచికలను ఒకేసారి దొర్లించినపుడు వాటిపై సంఖ్యలను కలిపిన 13. వచ్చు సంభావ్యత ఎంత?","answer":"0 [∵ రెండు పాచికలను దొర్లించినపుడు వాటిపై సంఖ్యలను కలిపిన 13 రావడం అసంభవ ఘటన]"},{"question":"Кызматчы сөздөр деген эмне? ","answer":" Өз алдынча турганда эч кандай маани бербеген жана сөз менен сөздү, сүйлөм менен сүйлөмдү байланыштыруу үчүн же кошумча маани берүү үчүн  колдонулган сөздөр кызматчы сөздөр деп аталат. Алардын төмөнкүдөй түрлөрү бар: жандоочтор, байламталар, бөлүкчөлөр.М и с а л ы: жана, менен, көздөй, жөнүндө, эч, го, абдан ж. б."},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: Thời sự 12h VTV1 - 31/7/2022Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Cơ quan Cảnh sát điều tra Công an huyện Trấn Yên, tỉnh Yên Bái, đang tạm giữ Vũ Văn Hoàn (34 tuổi, ở xã Hồng Ca, huyện Trấn Yên) để điều tra về hành vi cố ý gây thương tích. Theo cơ quan chức năng, Hoàn kết hôn với chị H.T.T.T. (32 tuổi) từ năm 2016. Quá trình chung sống, 2 vợ chồng thường xảy ra mâu thuẫn. Hoàn ghen tuông khi thấy vợ hay nhắn tin với người khác giới. Đến tối 28/7, Hoàn và chị T. tiếp tục cãi vã sau bữa cơm. Nguyên nhân vẫn là nghi phạm ghen với vợ. Lúc này, chị T. viết đơn ly dị khiến Hoàn nóng giận, mất bình tĩnh. Hoàn đã dùng hung khí chém vợ nhiều nhát khiến nạn nhân trọng thương. Cơ quan chức năng bắt giữ Hoàn ngay sau đó. Hiện, chị T. đã qua cơn nguy kịch và đang được điều trị tại bệnh viện.","answer":"Lời khai kẻ chém vợ trọng thương"},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Ngày 30/7, một nhóm 6 học sinh từ lớp 2 đến lớp 12 ra biển Cửa Lò để tắm. Trong lúc tắm, vì mải chơi nên các cháu bị sóng đánh ra xa bờ hàng chục mét. Lúc này, anh Nguyễn Văn Trung - Bí thư Đảng ủy phường Nghi Hải cùng anh Trần Quốc Tuấn - Bí thư Đảng ủy phường Nghi Hòa và một số người dân nghe tiếng kêu cứu của nhóm trẻ nên lao ra biển để ứng cứu. Không ngần ngại và suy nghĩ nhiều, các anh đã","answer":"nhanh chóng bơi ra chỗ các cháu nhỏ đang đuối nước để cứu. Lần bơi ra đầu tiên, anh Trung tiếp cận và kéo được một nữ sinh lớp 12 vào bờ. Lần thứ 2 bơi ra, anh Trung kéo được 2 cháu nhỏ vào bờ. Cùng thời điểm này, anh Tuấn và người dân tiếp cận cứu được 3 cháu nhỏ khác. Hiện nay, sức khỏe 5 cháu bé đã ổn định, còn một cháu do uống nhiều nước nên được đưa vào bệnh viện theo dõi."},{"question":"生活中辨別方向的方法有哪些","answer":"1.利用樹木辨別方向根據樹木的茂盛程度來分辯南北方向俗話說「萬物生長靠太陽」。掌握植物這項特徵後，即使在陰天，也可以觀察植物的生長情況來判別方向。樹木若能吸收足夠充足的陽光則枝繁葉茂，及植物茂盛的一方為南方。2.由樹木的年輪來辨別在我國北方許多樹木的樹幹斷面可見清晰的年輪。向南一側的年輪較為稀疏，向北一側的年輪一般是較緊密。樹幹斷面的年輪紋一般南面間隔大，北面間隔小。3.由石頭或樹根的青苔辨別青苔喜歡生長在潮濕的地方，利用這項特質可以找出背陽處，進而分辨出向陽的南方。4.太陽辨別方向。太陽升起的一方是東，面對太陽，前面是東，後面是西，左面是北，右面是南。"},{"question":"Tôi hay bị táo bón, ăn nhiều rau xanh để cung cấp chất xơ nhưng vì sao vẫn không cải thiện? ","answer":"Táo bón là triệu chứng rối loạn đường tiêu hóa dẫn đến đại tiện khó khăn, gây cảm giác đau rát. Nguyên nhân phổ biến do mất cân bằng hệ vi sinh vật đường ruột, ít vận động, tác dụng phụ của một số loại thuốc, thói quen thường xuyên nhịn đại tiện, ăn uống chưa hợp lý. Trong đó, dung nạp ít chất xơ là nguyên nhân gây táo bón thường gặp nhất. Ăn nhiều dưỡng chất này (có nhiều trong rau) là cách được nhiều người áp dụng. Tuy nhiên, nếu ăn quá nhiều chất xơ không hòa tan, ít chất xơ hòa tan có thể khiến phân đặc, cứng, táo bón nặng thêm.Chất xơ không hòa tan (không tan trong nước, không bị vi khuẩn đường ruột phá hủy) có nhiều trong các thực phẩm như bông cải xanh, măng, cà rốt, atiso, ngũ cốc, các loại hạt, đậu. Chất xơ không hòa tan giúp thức ăn dễ dàng đi qua dạ dày, hỗ trợ cân bằng độ pH, ngăn ngừa viêm nhiễm đường ruột. Chất xơ hòa tan có nhiều trong rau mồng tơi, rau đay, rau lang, đậu bắp, khoai lang, cam, bưởi, đu đủ, thanh long. Chất xơ này tan trong nước, giống gel giúp phân dễ dàng di chuyển theo đường tiêu hóa.Lượng chất xơ được khuyến nghị mỗi ngày là khoảng 30-38 g với nam và 25 g với nữ. Cứ 1.000 calo ăn vào nên có khoảng 14 g chất xơ. Mỗi người nên được bác sĩ tư vấn để có chế độ hấp thu dưỡng chất phù hợp. Để cải thiện táo bón hiệu quả, bạn cần cung cấp đủ nước, ăn đủ bữa, đi vệ sinh đều đặn hàng ngày. Thường xuyên vận động và bổ sung thêm lợi khuẩn góp phần cân bằng hệ vi sinh đường ruột.Táo bón cũng có thể do nguyên nhân bệnh lý như tổn thương, khiếm khuyết cấu trúc đại trực tràng, có vấn đề về nhu động ruột hay một số rối loạn chuyển hóa như suy giáp... Đây là những nguyên nhân gây táo bón ít gặp, chiếm khoảng 5-10%. Nếu bị táo bón bất thường, kéo dài, bạn nên đi khám để điều trị."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau:  Vị trí của quảng trường Bastille trước đây là pháo đài Bastille, được xây dựng trong khoảng 1370 tới 1383, dưới thời vua Charles V. Tới thế kỷ 17, hồng y Richelieu cải tạo nó thành nhà tù. Trong Cách mạng Pháp, ngày 14 tháng 7 năm 1789, nơi đây diễn ra sự kiện","answer":"Chiếm ngục Bastille, một biểu tượng cho Cách mạng, trở thành ngày quốc khánh của Pháp. Sau đó, vào ngày 15 tháng 7 năm 1789, nhà từ Bastille bị phá bỏ.Nơi nhảy múaNgày 14 tháng 7 năm 1790, một chiếc lều được dựng giữa đóng đổ nát của Bastille với tấm biển « Ở đây chúng ta nhảy múa ». Đó là buổi khiêu vũ 14 tháng 7 đầu tiên và thành truyền thống cho tới ngày nay. Căn lều này được vẽ lại trong một bức tranh bột màu trên bìa của Henri-Joseph Van Blarenberghe, một họa sĩ quân đội. Hiện nay tác phẩm được bày ở bảo tàng Carnavalet về lịch sử Paris. Henri-Joseph Van Blarenberghe cũng là người vẽ các bức tranh khác về sự kiện Chiếm ngục Bastille.Ngày 16 tháng 7 năm 1792, vị trí Bastille được quyết định sẽ mở một quảng trường mang tên Liberté - Tự do - cùng việc dựng một cây cột. Pierre-François Palloy - nhà thầu từng chịu trách nhiệm phá hủy nhà tù Bastille sau sự kiện 14 tháng 7 - đã bắt đầu viên đá đầu tiên, nhưng công viên không được tiến hành. Tới năm 1793, một đài phun nước được xây dựng ở đây."},{"question":"Em năm nay học lớp 10, thấy kiến thức Lý, Hóa quá nặng nên nghĩ đến việc bỏ khối A00.Em đang học sâu tổ hợp A00 (Toán, Lý, Hóa) nhưng cảm thấy những kiến thức Lý, Hóa ở cấp THPT không hợp với mình. Hơn nữa, nó quá nặng, xen lẫn áp lực về những con số dù chỉ mới đầu năm học.Em đang băn khoăn liệu lớp 11 em có thể chuyển sang học theo tổ hợp D01 (Toán, Văn, Anh) hay không? Kiến thức Văn, Anh có dễ để học lại từ đầu không?Em mong nhận được lời khuyên từ mọi người ạ. Em cảm ơn.","answer":"Nếu không phù hợp em có thể chuyển ngay từ bây giờ, chứ không cần chờ đến lớp 11."},{"question":"أريد إنشاء قصيدة قصيره من بحر الوافر. هل يمكنك مساعدتي؟","answer":"وَقَد تَرَكَت صَوارِمُهُم بِحِجرٍوَقائِعَ مِن دِماءِ بَني عِقالِوَما ضَلَّت ضَلالَهُمُ بِحِجرٍسَقيطَةُ جَندَلٍ بَينَ الرِجالِ"},{"question":"Aste honetan, hizkuntzaren eta teknologiaren arteko interakzioaren gaineko mintegia egin nuen. Zein teknologia moderno pentsatzen duzu hizkuntzalaritzan erabili daitezkeenik, eta zergatik?","answer":"Machine Learning teknikak erabil daitezke hizkuntza egituren azterketan, edo hizkuntzen arteko itzulpen automatikoetan. Hizkuntza naturalaren prozesamendua teknologia hauen bidez hobetu daiteke."},{"question":"ለዚህ ጥያቄ መልስ ስጥ: በሮማ ግዛት ንጉሠ ነገሥቶች ስም የተሰየሙት ሁለት ወራት የትኞቹ ናቸው?  ሀ. ጥር እና የካቲት ለ. መጋቢት እና ሚያዝያ ሐ. ግንቦት እና ሰኔ መ. ሐምሌ እና ነሐሴ","answer":"መ. ሐምሌ እና ነሐሴ"},{"question":"Kuşkonmaz hangi hastalığa iyi gelir?","answer":"Kuşkonmaz iyi bir idrar söktürücü olarak da fazla suyun dışarı atılmasına yardımcı olarak şişkinliğin inmesinde faydalı olabilir. Kemik Sağlığı İyileştirir: Güçsüz kemikler K vitamini eksikliğine bağlanır. Bir bardak kuşkonmaz ise günlük K vitamini ihtiyacınızın yarısından fazlasını karşılamanızı sağlar."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'genggam bara api, biar sampai jadi arang'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud semasa membuat sesuatu pekerjaan yang susah, hendaklah sabar dan tabah sehingga mencapai kejayaannya."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga amin'ity ohabolana ity: \\"Velona iray trano, ___. \\"","answer":"\\"Velona iray trano, maty iray fasana.\\""},{"question":"‘கலை முழுமை’ பற்றித் தொல்காப்பியம் குறிப்பிடுவது யாது?","answer":"‘கலை முழுமை’, என்பது இலக்கியத்திற்கான நோக்கம் அல்லது அறிவியல் சார்ந்த கருத்துநிலைகள், கலை உருவாக்கத்தின் போதே சரிவர இணைந்திருக்க வேண்டும் என்று தொல்காப்பியம் குறிப்பிடுகின்றது."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'berpaut sehasta tali'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud tidak dapat berbuat sesuatu dengan sesuka hati"},{"question":"(Ngokumangala) Sanibonani Sonto, kwenzenjani? Wafika nabantuboMthetho?Ungethuki Nkosikazi. Mina ngingumseshi uNhleko. Kasizile ngobubi.Sidinga usizo lwakho nje, esethemba ukuthi sizoluthola.(Esathukile) Mina nginguMaNsibande. Kwenzenjani?Siyadabuka ukukwazisa ukuthi uMfundisi uZondo uhlaselwe,utholakale edutshuliwe, njengamanje ulimele kakhulu esibhedlela.(Ethwala izandla ekhanda) Hawu! Hawu! Ngomfundisi Nkosi yamiwoneni nje, kubani?(Ngezwi elinozwela) Nathi sizwe ubuhlungu nkosikazi. Impelasiyadabuka, sizwelana nani.(Esula izinyembezi emehlweni.) Kodwa ngoMfundisi pho!Nami ivele nje yangethusa le ndaba ntombi.Hawu! Kodwa ubangiswani uMfundisi? Kanti banjani abantuemhlabeni bakithi? Bambulala ebe enzeni nje uMfundisi?Kusolakala sengathi kumayelana nemali ngoba kukhona etholakeleendlini lapho edutshulelwe khona uMfundisi.Washo ngabona, kade befuna imali yomnikelo. Kodwa beyazelaphingoba indaba yemali ibiphakathi kwethu sobathathu?E, ngizodinga usizo lwakho-ke dadewethu. (Ekhipha ibhukwana.)Ngingakubuza imibuzo embalwa?Yebo, ayikho inkinga.Umgcine nini uMfundisi?Izolo ntambama.Bekungaba ngubani isikhathi?(Elokhu esula izinyembezi.) Bese ligamanxile ihora lesikhombisa.Ingabe ukhona yini umuntu enimgibelisile endleleni?Cha, impela akekho.Kuyiqiniso ukuthi ngenkathi nigcinana nobathathu benikade nibalaimali yomnikelo negcine ihambe noMfundisi?Yebo kuyiqiniso.1. Ngokusho kukaNhleko, uMfundisi bambulalelani? ","answer":"Bambulalela imali yomnikelo."},{"question":"Quem foi o primeiro presidente negro dos Estados Unidos?","answer":"O primeiro presidente negro dos Estados Unidos foi Barack Obama."},{"question":"வினா:சரியான பழமொழியைக் கண்டறிக.  அ) மண் குதிரையை நம்பி ஆற்றில் இறங்கலாமா?ஆ ) மண் குதிரை நம்பி ஆற்றில் இறங்கலாமா?","answer":"விடை:சரியான பழமொழிமண் குதிரை நம்பி ஆற்றில் இறங்கலாமா?குதிர்  - மண் திட்டு ஆற்றின் மத்தியில் மண் திட்டுக்கள் தீவு போலத்தெரியும் , அடடே இதுவும் தரை தானே என்று நம்பி ஆற்றில் இறங்கினால் அது புதை மணல் போல உள்ளே இழுத்துவிடும் . "},{"question":"سورة صغيرة، إن قراءتها تعدل قراءة ربع القرآن الكريم كله؟.","answer":"سورة الكافرون."},{"question":" الذي نعرفه عن لقاحي الملاريا المتاحين حالياً اللذين توصي بهما المنظمة؟","answer":"لقد تبيّن أن كلا اللقاحين R21 وRTS,S يتسمان بالمأمونية والفعالية في الوقاية من الملاريا لدى الأطفال، ومن المتوقع أن يكون لهما تأثير كبير على الصحة العامة عند تنفيذهما على نطاق واسع.ونظراً إلى أن اللقاحين متشابهان، وأن اللقاح RTS,S كان له تأثير كبير في المناطق ذات الانتقال المرتفع والمعتدل والمنخفض، فمن المرجح أن يكون اللقاح R21 فعالاً أيضاً في جميع الأماكن التي تتوطنها الملاريا. ويمكن إنقاذ عشرات الآلاف من أرواح الأطفال كل عام من خلال التنفيذ الواسع النطاق للقاحي الملاريا هذين.ولم يُختبر لقاحا الملاريا R21 وRTS,S في إطار تجربة مقارنة مباشرة. ويوفر كلاهما وقاية من حوالي 75% من نوبات الملاريا عند إعطائهما بشكل موسمي في المناطق ذات الانتقال الموسمي الشديد، حيث يتم توفير المعالجة الكيميائية الوقائية للملاريا الموسمية. ولا يوجد دليل حتى الآن على أن أحد اللقاحين يعمل بشكل أفضل من الآخر. وينبغي أن يستند اختيار المنتج الذي سيُستخدم في بلد ما إلى الخصائص البرنامجية، وإمدادات اللقاح، والقدرة على تحمل تكاليف اللقاح.وقد خضع اللقاح RTS,S لاختبار المنظمة المسبق للصلاحية في تموز/يوليو 2022.وتشمل الخطوة المهمة التالية بالنسبة إلى اللقاح R21 في استكمال عملية المنظمة للاختبار المسبق للصلاحية، التي تتم حالياً. وتُعد عملية المنظمة للاختبار المسبق للصلاحية شرطاً مسبقاً لشراء اللقاح على الصعيد الدولي من قبل وكالات الأمم المتحدة، مثل اليونيسيف وتحالف غافي للقاحات وغيرهما."},{"question":"‘Idi ti a fi ti ileewe aladaani bii ẹgbẹta pa nipinlẹ Ọṣun ree’","answer":"Kọmiṣanaa fun eto ẹkọ nipinlẹ Ọṣun, Ọnarebu Fọlọrunṣọ Bamiṣayemi, ti sọ pe, o kere tan, ileewe aladaani to to ẹgbẹta ti wọn ko wa nibaamu pẹlu ilana ijọba lawọn ti ti pa bayii.Lasiko to n jabọ iṣẹ iriju rẹ fawọn oniroyin l’Ọjọbọ, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii, lo ṣalaye pe igbesẹ naa pọn dandan lati le ri i pe ayika to dara lawọn akẹkọọ ti n kẹkọọ, to si jẹ pe awọn olukọ ti wọn kunju oṣuwọn ni wọn n kọ wọn nibẹ.O ni ọrọ eto-ẹkọ to peye jẹ ijọba logun pupọ, idi si niyi tijọba ko fi ni i faaye gba ẹnikẹni lati sọ awọn akẹkọọ di alaabọ-ẹkọ.Bamiṣayemi sọ siwaju pe awọn ko ni i fojuure wo ileewe ti ko ba ni ayika to dun un kẹkọọ, bẹẹ ni olukọ ti ko ba kunju oṣuwọn ko le kọ awọn ọmọ ni ẹkọ to dara.O ni, “A mọ bo ṣe ṣe pataki to ki ipilẹ ẹkọ awọn ọmọ duroore, ti ipilẹ ba ti wọ, yoo ṣoro lati mọ nnkan to lagbara le e lori. Idi niyi ti a ko ṣe fi ọwọ yẹpẹrẹ mu awọn oludasilẹ ileewe aladaani.“Oniruuru ẹka la ti ṣedasilẹ rẹ nileeṣẹ eto ẹkọ, awọn kan ti wa lati maa lọ kaakiri fun amojuto awọn ileewe aladaani ati tijọba.“Ẹnikẹni to ba fẹẹ da ileewe silẹ nipinlẹ Ọṣun gbọdọ ni iwe-ẹri TRCN atawọn nnkan amuyẹ yooku, ko saaye dida ileewe silẹ tori pe o ri owo lojiji.“Oniruuru igbekalẹ la ti ni, iru ẹni bẹẹ si gbọdọ yege ki a too fọwọ si i pe ko da ileewe silẹ’Kọmiṣanna yii fi kun ọrọ rẹ pe mimu atunṣe ba oriṣiiriṣii ilana iṣejọba to kọja lori eto ẹkọ ti n so eso rere pupọ, o si ṣeleri pe gbogbo awọn araalu ni wọn yoo yin Gomina Oyetọla lawo lẹyin iṣejọba rẹ nipasẹ awọn aṣeyọri ti yoo ṣe lẹka eto ẹkọ."},{"question":"星巴克如何选择咖啡豆？","answer":"答：星巴克通过严格的质量控制和评估程序，从全球各地的咖啡种植园中选择最优质的咖啡豆。"},{"question":"I've always wondered: భద్రంపల్లె గ్రామ ప్రజలు ప్రధానంగా పండించే పంట ఏది?","answer":"వేరుశనగ, పొద్దుతిరుగుడు, కంది"},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : భారతదేశం ఏ అర్ధగోళంలో ఉంది?","answer":"భారతదేశం ఉత్తరార్ధగోళంలో ఉంది."},{"question":"Inona no hevitry ny hoe \\"nanao ny ainy tsy ho zavatra\\"?","answer":"Ny hevitry ny teny hoe \\"nanao ny ainy tsy ho zavatra\\" dia hoe nanao tsinontsinona ny ainy, tsy nitsitsy aina, nahafoy tena tanteraka"},{"question":"Apa tips supaya menang judi slot?","answer":"Mohon maaf, saya tidak dapat membantu Anda dalam aktivitas perjudian. Jika Anda memiliki pertanyaan lain, saya senang membantu."},{"question":" Tohizo izao ohabolana izao amin'ny alalan'ny famenoana ny banga: \\"   Fohy fa enjana _ \\" ","answer":"\\"  Fohy fa enjana tahaka ny rambon'omby tapaka \\" "},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'hendak belajar berenang dapatkan itik, hendak belajar memanjat dapatkan tupai'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud sekiranya hendak mengetahui ataupun menguasai sesuatu perkara belajarlah daripada orang-orang yang ahli ataupun akar dalam perkara itu."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\" Basy _ ka tsy afenina fa arangaranga\\"","answer":" Basy atifi-kavana ka tsy afenina fa arangaranga"},{"question":"Qual a resposta da piada a seguir: O que a namorada do Einstein disse quando o viu nadando na piscina?","answer":"Nossa, que físico!"},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: Nóng tuần qua: Hà Nội sắp đấu giá hàng trăm thửa đất, giá khởi điểm 18 triệu đồng/m2","answer":"Hà Nội sắp đấu giá hàng trăm thửa đất tại Mê Linh và Đông Anh Cụ thể, tại huyện Mê Linh đang tập trung hoàn thiện thủ tục để đưa ra đấu giá 106 thửa đất tại 4 dự án trong tháng 7 và tháng 8, trong khi huyện Đông Anh ngày 30/7 sẽ tổ chức đấu giá 20 thửa đất. Theo Trung tâm Phát triển quỹ đất huyện Mê Linh, cả 4 điểm đưa vào đấu giá trong đợt này đều có tiềm năng bởi đã được giải phóng mặt bằng, hoàn thành xây dựng hạ tầng kỹ thuật, gần Khu Công nghiệp Quang Minh, trung tâm hành chính của huyện, trường học và nằm trên trục giao thông huyết mạch. Các thửa đất có tổng diện tích 3.412,7 m2 (từ 67,4 m2 đến 193 m2). Giá khởi điểm 32,1 triệu đồng đến 44,2 triệu đồng/m2, tổng giá khởi điểm hơn 129 tỷ đồng.  Tại Đông Anh, Công ty Đấu giá Hợp danh Lạc Việt thông báo tổ chức đấu giá 20 thửa đất trên địa bàn huyện Còn tại huyện Đông Anh, Hà Nội, Công ty Đấu giá Hợp danh Lạc Việt thông báo tổ chức đấu giá 20 thửa đất trên địa bàn huyện cũng vào ngày 30/7. Tổng cộng có 13 thửa đất tại khu đất X4 thôn Đoài, xã Kim Nỗ và 7 thửa tại khu đất X7 thôn Đào Thục, xã Thụy Lâm, huyện Đông Anh. Các thửa đất này có diện tích từ 70 m2 đến 108 m2, giá khởi điểm từ 18 triệu đồng đến 55,1 triệu đồng/m2. Tiền mua hồ sơ 500 nghìn đồng/bộ. Theo quy định, mỗi hồ sơ tham gia đấu giá phải đặt cọc số tiền từ 252 triệu đồng đến hơn 1,1 tỷ đồng. Trợ giá xe buýt từ ngân sách: Doanh nghiệp vẫn than lỗ Nhiều doanh nghiệp xe buýt lớn tại TPHCM, Hà Nội dù được trợ giá mỗi năm hàng nghìn tỷ đồng nhưng có xu hướng than lỗ, thậm chí xin bỏ tuyến. Ở Hà Nội và TPHCM, mỗi năm ngân sách chi ra hơn một nghìn tỷ đồng để trợ giá cho xe buýt (tại Hà Nội là 114 tuyến, TPHCM có 101 tuyến trợ giá). Số tiền trợ giá liên tục tăng qua các năm. Toàn quốc hiện có 56/63 tỉnh thành đã tổ chức khai thác trên 700 tuyến buýt, trên 11.000 phương tiện buýt các loại với tổng chiều dài các tuyến vận tải hành khách công cộng lên đến trên 23.000km. Tại TPHCM, 3 năm qua, trợ giá xe buýt tăng dần (từ 1.123 tỷ đồng năm 2018, lên 1.247 tỷ đồng năm 2019 và 1.311 tỷ đồng năm 2020). Đầu tháng 7 này, Cty TNHH Bắc Hà có văn bản xin ngừng vận hành 5 tuyến xe buýt có trợ giá (mang số hiệu: 41, 42, 43, 44, 45), dù chưa hết thời hạn hợp đồng giao thầu. Đại diện phía Cty TNHH Bắc Hà chia sẻ, do thua lỗ đến 200 triệu đồng mỗi ngày, nguồn lực của đơn vị cạn kiệt, không đủ sức duy trì vận hành các tuyến buýt nữa nên buộc phải xin ngừng. Nhà xây sẵn ở Hà Nội và TP HCM đồng loạt tăng giá Báo cáo Quý II/2022 của Công ty Tư vấn Bất động sản hàng đầu tại khu vực Châu Á Thái Bình Dương (JLL) chỉ ra, giá bán sơ cấp loại hình nhà liền thổ (nhà xây sẵn) ở khu vực Hà Nội, TP HCM và các tỉnh lân cận tăng mạnh. Tại thị trường Hà Nội và các tỉnh lân cận như Hưng Yên, Vĩnh Phúc, Bắc Ninh hay xa hơn như Hải Phòng, giá bán tăng trung bình khoảng 12% so với cùng kỳ năm ngoái, đạt mức 5.083 USD/m2, tương đương gần 120 triệu đồng/m2 Đáng chú ý, giá bán trung bình của thị trường Hà Nội ghi nhận mức tăng 15,8% theo quý do chênh lệch lớn giữa cung - cầu, quỹ đất khan hiếm và chi phí đầu vào tăng. Tại thị trường phía Nam, giá nhà liền thổ tại TP HCM và các tỉnh lân cận Bình Dương, Đồng Nai, Long An, Bà Rịa - Vũng Tàu tăng 12,4% so với cùng kỳ năm trước, đạt mức 3.202 USD/m2, tương ứng 75 triệu đồng/m2. Trong đó, giá bán sơ cấp trung bình ở TP HCM tăng 21,2% so với cùng kỳ do các dự án mở bán mới có mức giá cao hơn nhờ lợi thế vị trí. Còn các tỉnh lân cận, giá bán tăng mạnh nhất ở dòng sản phẩm nhà phố với mức giá 5 - 6 tỷ đồng/căn, ghi nhận mức tăng theo năm khoảng 11-13%. Theo chuyên gia của JLL, thời gian tới, giá bán sơ cấp tại thị trường miền Bắc được dự đoán sẽ tiếp tục tăng mạnh nhưng với tốc độ chậm hơn so với giai đoạn nửa đầu năm. Còn tại TP HCM, thị trường nhà liền thổ sẽ đối diện với thách thức hạn chế nguồn cung mới Tiền tiết kiệm dân mang đi gửi ngân hàng tăng mạnh Trước việc các ngân hàng liên tục tăng lãi suất huy động, lượng tiền nhàn rỗi được người dân mang gửi tiết kiệm tại các ngân hàng đã lập kỷ lục mới. Hàng loạt ngân hàng liên tục tăng lãi suất huy động từ đầu năm khiến mặt bằng lãi suất đã tăng từ 1-1,5% ở một số kỳ hạn. Thậm chí, nhiều ngân hàng đã nâng lãi suất huy động lên trên dưới 2% chỉ sau nửa đầu năm nay. Hiện mức lãi suất trên 7% đang được hơn chục nhà băng áp dụng ở những kỳ hạn dài nhằm hút tiền nhàn rỗi của người dân.  Lãi suất tăng, kênh tiết kiệm trở nên hấp dẫn Theo số liệu mới nhất từ Ngân hàng Nhà nước, tính đến cuối tháng 5, số dư tiền gửi của nhóm khách hàng dân cư tại các tổ chức tín dụng đã đạt gần 5,569 triệu tỷ đồng. Chỉ tính riêng trong tháng 5, người dân cũng mang thêm gần 36.900 tỷ đồng gửi vào ngân hàng, tương đương mỗi ngày có thêm 1.230 tỷ đồng được người dân mang gửi tiết kiệm. So với đầu năm, người dân đã gửi ròng vào hệ thống hơn 268.480 tỷ đồng - gấp đôi mức tăng 134.000 tỷ đồng của cùng kỳ năm ngoái, thậm chí cao hơn nhiều mức tăng 159.000 tỷ đồng của cả năm 2021. Còn nếu so với 5 tháng đầu năm 2020, mức tăng năm nay cũng cao hơn tới 40%. Tính bình quân trong 5 tháng đầu năm 2022, cứ mỗi ngày trôi qua, người dân lại mang thêm gần 1.790 tỷ đi gửi ngân hàng lấy lãi. Trong khi đó, số dư tiền gửi của các tổ chức kinh tế đạt khoảng 5,806 triệu tỷ, tăng 2,86% so với cuối năm 2021, tương đương mức tăng ròng 161.615 tỷ đồng sau 5 tháng. Như vậy, trong giai đoạn đầu năm nay, tốc độ tăng trưởng tiền gửi của nhóm khách hàng dân cư đã cao vượt trội so với tiền gửi của các doanh nghiệp, tổ chức kinh tế, trái ngược so với xu hướng trong 2 năm liền trước. Mặc dù lãi suất huy động đã ghi nhận mức tăng mạnh trong thời gian qua nhưng theo đánh giá của các chuyên gia từ nay đến cuối năm, lãi suất huy động được dự báo tiếp tục gia tăng. Công ty Chứng khoán SSI cho rằng lãi suất huy động có thể tăng nhanh hơn vào nửa cuối năm, kéo theo lãi suất cho vay bắt đầu tăng từ cuối quý 2. Các chuyên gia tại đây dự báo lãi suất huy động sẽ tăng thêm 0,5-0,7 điểm % sau khi Ngân hàng Nhà nước nới hạn mức tăng trưởng tín dụng cho các ngân hàng. Thu phí ETC trên tất cả các tuyến cao tốc Kể từ ngày 1/8, Bộ Giao thông Vận tải và các địa phương sẽ phải triển khai thu phí hoàn toàn tự động (ETC) đối với tất cả tuyến cao tốc. Trong trường hợp tài xế không dán thẻ tham gia dịch vụ ETC hoặc có dán thẻ nhưng trong tài khoản không đủ tiền thanh toán phí sẽ không được đi vào các tuyến cao tốc. Trong trường hợp tài xế không dán thẻ tham gia dịch vụ ETC mà đi vào cao tốc sẽ bị xử phạt từ 2 - 3 triệu đồng, đồng thời bị tước quyền sử dụng giấy phép lái xe từ 1 - 3 tháng. Chính phủ cũng đã chỉ đạo, sau ngày 31/7, nếu trạm thu phí nào chưa lắp đặt và vận hành thu phí tự động sẽ buộc phải xả trạm, dừng thu phí tới khi lắp đặt xong thu phí tự động (trừ một số trạm không triển khai thu phí tự động do sắp hết hạn thu phí). Trước đó, tuyến cao tốc Hà Nội - Hải Phòng đã tổ chức thu phí toàn bộ theo hình thức tự động không dừng từ ngày 1/6/2022. Nguồn: https://arttimes.vn/kinh-te/nong-tuan-qua-ha-noi-sap-dau-gia-hang-tram-thua-dat-gia-khoi-diem-18...Nguồn: https://arttimes.vn/kinh-te/nong-tuan-qua-ha-noi-sap-dau-gia-hang-tram-thua-dat-gia-khoi-diem-18-trieu-dong/m2-c6a8441.html "},{"question":"භද්‍ර යව්වනයභද්‍ර වූ දේශයමෙහි 'භද්‍ර' යන්නෙන් අදහස් වෙන්නේ කුමක්ද?","answer":"යෞවනය හැමටම හා හැමවිටම භද්‍ර වන්නේ නෑ. එය දුක්ඛිත, කාලකණ්නි, රෝගී, අසහනකාරී වුවද විය හැකියි.ඒවායින් තොර සුන්දර , සෞභාග්‍යවත් යෞවනය භද්‍ර යෞවනයයි."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي الدولة العربية التي تأهلت لكأس العالم 4 مرات ؟","answer":"الإجابة: الجزائر"},{"question":"ضرب المزارع طبق البيض في الجدار ولم ينكسر لماذا ؟","answer":"الجدار الذي لم ينكسر وليس طبق البيض ."},{"question":"kyiv no renivohitr'i Rosia. Marina sa diso?","answer":"Diso. Kyiv no renivohitr'i Okraina. Moskoa no renivohitr'i Rosia."},{"question":"Ci gan kembaar la réewum Chili nékk?","answer":"Réewum Chili mu ngi nékk ci kembaaru Amerique."},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. Kto otrzymał Nagrodę Nobla z Literatury w 1997 roku?","answer":"Oto odpowiedź na to pytanie. W 1997. roku Nagrodę Nobla z dziedziny literatury otrzymał: Dario Fo ( Włochy) otrzymał ją jako ten, który rywalizuje z błaznami średniowiecznymi w krytykowaniu władzy oraz popieraniu godności uciskanych."},{"question":"අවපාතයක් ඇතිවීමට හේතුව කුමක්ද?","answer":"අවපාතයක් ඇති වන්නේ ඩොමිනෝ රේඛාවක් වැනි සිදුවීම් දාමයක් වේගවත් වන අතර ආර්ථිකය හැකිලෙන තෙක් නොනැවතී. සෑම සිදුවීමක්ම කලින් සිදු වූ දෙයක් හා අනාගතයේ සිදු වන දෙයක් සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වේ. හැම්බර්ගර් මිල ඉහළ ගියහොත්, ඔබ හැම්බර්ගර් මිලදී ගැනීම නතර කළ හැකිය. මෙය අවන්හලකට බලපාන අතර, එය සේවාදායකයකට බලපානු ඇත. ආර්ථිකය පුරාවටම මෙවැනි අන්තර් සම්බන්ධිත දාම රාශියක් ඇත."},{"question":"Inona no foko tena manjaka ao Madagasikara?","answer":"Ny Merina no foko manjaka indrindra ao Madagasikara."},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH de Mali? ","answer":"0,428."},{"question":"Wat voor belangrijke gebeurtenis beschrijft de tekst: De Decembristenopstand in 1825 en Novemberopstand in 1830, die werden gehouden om de tsaristische aristocraten neer te halen, verdeelden het panslavisme in Rusland in pro-Russische en anti-Russische groepen.","answer":"Het gaat over de Decembristenopstand in 1825."},{"question":"May diarrhea yata ako. Ano ang maaring dahilan nito?","answer":"Ang mga sumusunod ay maaaring dahilan ng diarrhea at sakit ng tiyan:1. Isang bacterial infection.2. Isang virus.3. Nagkakaproblema sa pagtunaw ng pagkain o food intolerance.4. Allergy sa pagkain (tulad ng celiac disease, gluten allergy).5. Mga parasite na pumapasok sa katawan sa pamamagitan ng pagkain o tubig.6. Reaksyon sa mga gamot."},{"question":"لدينا الجملة التالية: خدمات مميزه موقع ممتاز وقريب خصوصا لمن معهم نساء وذلك لقربه من بوابة مصلى النساء نظافة المكان. ماهي مشاعر الجملة السابقة؟","answer":"الجملة السابقة تحتوي على مشاعر إيجابية."},{"question":"اكمل الجملة التالية:وحوالي 42.2% من النشطين الذين حققوا الحد الموصى به، ولكن خلال يوم أو يومين، على طريقة \\"محاربي عطلة نهاية الأسبوع\\". أما الربع المتبقي","answer":"من المشاركين (24%) فكانوا نشطين بانتظام، ويوزعون المدة الموصى بها على أيام الأسبوع."},{"question":"من هم الضالون الذي يقصدهم الله.","answer":"؟ الجواب النصارى"},{"question":"السؤال: بعض فرض الصلوات الخمس، ما هي أول صلاة أداها سيدنا محمد؟","answer":"الإجابة: هي صلاة الظهر."},{"question":"Apakah sejarah origami? Huraikan dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 300 patah perkataan.","answer":"Seni origami telah lama wujud dan berkembang sehingga kini. Buku The World Of Origami (1965) oleh Isao Honda menyatakan bahawa sejarah origami dianggap bermula apabila manusia mula menghasilkan kertas. Pengeluaran kertas berlaku pada abad pertama sekitar 105 Masihi di China (China) oleh Ts’ai Lun. Pada abad ke-6, kaedah membuat kertas telah dibawa ke Sepanyol oleh orang Arab dan juga ke Jepun pada tahun 610 Masihi oleh seorang sami Buddha bernama Doncho (Dokyo) dari Goguryeo (semenanjung Korea). Beliau memperkenalkan kertas dan dakwat kepada masyarakat Jepun semasa pemerintahan Maharani Suiko.Origami telah menjadi popular di kalangan orang Jepun sejak itu dan telah diturunkan dari generasi ke generasi. Origami ialah salah satu budaya yang diakui oleh orang Jepun dalam agama kepercayaan Shinto. Pada zaman Heian (741-1191 M) lipatan origami dipercayai telah digunakan sebagai penutup botol sake semasa upacara penyembahan di kalangan sami Shinto, wanita dan kanak-kanak. Pada masa itu, origami dikenali sebagai orikata atau origata, orisui, atau orimino. Ketika zaman Kamakura (1185-1333 M), bentuk origami dikenali dipanggil noshi. Noshi berasal daripada singkatan perkataan noshi-awabi, yang bermaksud daging tiram nipis yang dijemur di bawah sinar matahari yang dianggap sebagai hidangan istimewa bagi orang Jepun. Noshi dianggap membawa tuah kepada sesiapa yang menerimanya. Pada masa itu memotong kertas menggunakan pisau masih dibenarkan. Apabila tiba zaman Muromachi (1338-1573 M), undang-undang yang membenarkan pisau untuk digunakan memotong kertas telah dihentikan. Sebab tu lah Origami dilipat tanpa memotong kertas.Origami berkembang dan menjadi alat untuk memisahkan golongan atas dan bawahan masyarakat. Samurai mengikut ajaran Ise, manakala rakyat biasa mengikuti ajaran Ogasawara. Origami dari semasa ke semasa telah menjadi sinonim dengan budaya Jepun dan telah diturunkan dari generasi ke generasi. Origami menggunakan kertas Jepun asli yang dipanggil washi dan merupakan bahagian penting dalam upacara keagamaan tradisional Shinto yang masih dikekalkan sehingga hari ini."},{"question":"Quem administrou o West Ham United entre 2008 e 2010?","answer":"Gianfranco Zola"},{"question":"Ата-энеге насаат...","answer":"Бөлөк бирөөнүн баласын сүйө бил. Эгерде башкалардын сенин балаңа жакшы мамиле жасашын кааласаң, сен да бөлөк бирөөнүн баласына жылуу мамиле жаса."},{"question":"Giải thích ý nghĩa từ “tràm chim”?","answer":"“Tràm chim” đơn giản là những cây tràm kết thành rừng và chim thì dày đặc thành vườn."},{"question":"ඇතුල අරුත කුමක්ද? (ඇතුළ අරුත දනිමි)","answer":"ඔබ ඒ වචනය දුටු වාක්‍යය ලියා එවූවොත් පැහැදිලි පිළිතුරක් දිය හැකියි.ඇතුල යන්නෙන් මා දන්නා විදියට වදනක් නෑ. නමුත් ඇතුළ යන්න විශෙෂණයක් විදියට යොදනකොට ඇතුල් කියා නම් යෙදෙනව.ඇතුල් පැත්ත, ඇතුල් පත,"},{"question":"Animation-தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்","answer":"அசைவூட்டம். இயங்குபடம் என்பது சிறுசிறு வேறுபாடுகள் கொண்ட பல படங்களை வேகமாக இயக்கப்படுவதன் மூலமாக உருவாக்கப்படுவதாகும். இயக்கமூட்டல் என்பது நிலையான படிமங்களை அடுத்தடுத்துக் காட்சியளிக்க வைப்பதன் மூலம் படத்திலுள்ள பொருள் இயங்குவது போன்ற மாயத் தோற்றத்தை உருவாக்குவதாகும்."},{"question":"මිනිසාගේ බෙල්ලේ අස්ථි කොටස් ගණන කීයද?","answer":"හතකි."},{"question":"Soạn bài Người đàn ông cô độc giữa rừng Ngữ văn lớp 7","answer":"- Khi đọc truyện, các em cần chú ý: + Tóm tắt được nội dung văn bản (Truyện kể lại sự kiện gì? Xảy ra trong bối cảnh nào?) + Nhân vật chính là ai? Nhân vật ấy được nhà văn thể hiện qua những phương diện nào? + Truyện kể theo ngôi kể nào? Nếu có sự thay đổi ngôi kể thì tác dụng của việc thay đổi ấy là gì? + Truyện giúp em hiểu biết thêm những gì và tác động đến tình cảm của em như thế nào? - Đọc trước đoạn trích “Người đàn ông cô độc giữa rừng”, tìm hiểu những thông tin về tác phẩm Đất rừng phương Nam và nhà văn Đoàn Giỏi. - Đọc tóm tắt sau để hiểu bối cảnh của đoạn trích:Đất rừng phương Nam là tiểu thuyết của nhà van Đoàn Giỏi, viết về cuộc đời phiêu bạt của cậu bé An. An theo cha mẹ chạy giặc Pháp hết vùng này tới vùng khác của miền Tây Nam Bộ rồi lạc mất gia đình, trở thành cậu bé lang thang. Trong lúc lưu lực em đã được gặp và trở thành con nuôi gia đình ông Hai bán rắn, làm anh em với thằng Cò và làm bạn với chú Võ Tòng. Đoạn trích Người đàn ông cô độc giữa rùng kể lại việc tía nuôi dắt An đi thăm chú Võ Tòng.Trả lời: - Khi đọc truyện:+ Truyện kể lại sự kiện: ông Hai và bé An ghé thăm Võ Tòng; Võ Tòng kể cho 2 cha con ông Hai nghe về vụ giết hổ và giết tên địa chủ; sự việc Võ Tòng làm mũi tên thuốc độc và trao cho ông Hai.+ Nhân vật chính trong truyện là Võ Tòng được nhà văn thể hiện qua các phương diện: ngoại hình, ngôn ngữ, hành động, suy nghĩ của nhân vật.+ Truyện được kể theo ngôi thứ nhất là lời của cậu bé An ở phần đầu truyện và ngôi thứ ba khi nói về cuộc đời của nhân vật Võ Tòng. Việc thay đổi ngôi kể như vậy giúp cho việc kể được linh hoạt hơn và nhân vật hiện lên rõ nét hơn, khách quan hơn.- Tác giả Đoàn Giỏi: Đoàn Giỏi (17/ 5 / 1925 - 2 /4 / 1989), là một nhà văn hiện đại Việt Nam, hội viên Hội Nhà văn Việt Nam từ năm 1957.Đoàn Giỏi sinh ở quê tại thị xã Mỹ Tho, tỉnh Mỹ Tho (nay thuộc xã Tân Hiệp, huyện Châu Thành, tỉnh Tiền Giang). Ông xuất thân trong một gia đình địa chủ lớn. Trong những năm Việt Nam chống Pháp, Đoàn Giỏi công tác trong ngành an ninh, rồi làm công tác thông tin, văn nghệ, từng giữ chức Phó trưởng Ty thông tin Rạch Giá (1949). Từ năm 1949 đến năm 1954, ông công tác tại Chi hội Văn nghệ Nam Bộ, viết bài cho tạp chí Lá Lúa, rồi tạp chí Văn nghệ Miên Nam.Sau 1954, ông tập kết ra Bắc, đến năm 1955 ông chuyển sang sáng tác và biên tập sách báo, công tác tại Đài tiếng nói Việt Nam, rồi Hội Văn nghệ Việt Nam. Ông là viên Ban chấp hành Hội Nhà văn Việt Nam các khóa I, II, III. Ông là Đảng viên Đảng Cộng sản Việt Nam. Đoàn Giỏi còn có các bút danh khác: Nguyễn Hoài, Nguyễn Phú Lễ, Huyền Tư. Ngoài truyện, truyện ngắn, ký, Đoàn Giỏi còn sáng tác thơ. - Tác phẩm Đất rừng phương Nam:Đất rừng phương Nam là truyện viết cho lứa tuổi thiếu nhi rất thành công và nổi tiếng của ông. Truyện đã được dịch ra nhiều tiếng nước ngoài, tái bản nhiều lần, được dựng thành phim và in trong Tủ Sách Vàng của Nhà xuất bản Kim Đồng.Đất rừng phương Nam viết về cuộc đời phiêu bạt của cậu bé An. Em theo cha mẹ chạy giặc Pháp hết từ vùng này tới vùng khác của miền Tây Nam Bộ rồi lạc mất gia đình, trở thành cậu bé lang thang. Trong lúc lưu lạc, An đã gặp và trở thành con nuôi gia đình ông Hai bán rắn, làm an hem với thằng Cò và làm bạn với chú Võ TòngVõ Tòng sau này đòi đi giết Việt gian vì định mua chuộc ông Ba Ngù. Trong lần phục kích giặc trên cây Da, Võ Tòng đã giết chết tên Việt gian và một tên lính ngụy. Nhưng cuối cùng, Võ Tòng đã bị mụ Tư Mắm chỉ điểm rồi bị tên tướng bắn chết. Ba Ngù kêu An chỉ mụ Tư Mắm và biết được thói quen là thường đi tắm vào buổi chiều. Nên ông đã núp dưới đám bèo và dùng nỏ bắn chết mụ. Thời gian sau, bọn giặc phải lao đao nhiều lần vì ông. U Minh Thượng đã bị giặc đóng chiếm, gia đình tía nuôi và An rời đi U Minh Hạ sinh sống, gia nhập phường săn cá sấu, sau đó tới Soc Miên, chợ Mặt Trời, Năm Căn. Tại đây An gặp lại dì Tư Béo và rồi An theo các anh du kích.- Văn bản “Người đàn ông cô độc giữa rừng” thuộc chương 10 của tiểu thuyết Đất rừng phương Nam."},{"question":"කෝපි පිළියෙල කිරීම යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කෝපි පිළියෙල කිරීම (Coffee preparation) යනු කෝපි ඇට, කෝපි නමින් හැඳින්වෙන පානය බවට හැරවීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියයි."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini: Pelumba diminta menghidupkan benda ini sebelum bermula.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah enjin. "},{"question":" Sheeg Qofka Aan Hooyo Mooyee Aabo Laheyn","answer":" Waa Nebi Ciise Cs."},{"question":"Awọn ọmọ iya meji ti wọn fẹẹ ṣ’oogun owo n’Ijẹbu ti pa iya arugbo o","answer":"Ni Ijẹbu Muṣin lo ti ṣẹlẹ. Awọn ọmọ iya kan naa, Akinọla Akeem ati Muyiwa Akeem fẹẹ lowo ni gbogbo ọna, ni wọn ba lọọ ba oniṣegun kan, Moses Ọduntan ti wọn tun n pe ni Koba, pe ko ṣoogun owo fawọn. Niyẹn ba ni ki wọn mu ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgọrun-un Naira wa, oogun owo yoo jẹ ṣiṣe. Owo ti oniṣegun fẹẹ gba ti wọn n wa ni wọn ṣe lọọ digunjale, nibẹ ni wọn ti pa iya agbalagba, Christiana, ẹni ọdun mejilelaaadọrin (72).Baba arugbo kan ti wọn n pe ni Ọlatokunbọ lo n fọnnu lọdọ awọn ọrẹ rẹ nile ẹmu pe oun ni owo to to ẹgbẹrun lọna ẹẹdẹgbẹta ataabọ Naira (N550,000) nile oun, oun ko si mọ pe ni  gbogbo igba ti oun n tu aṣiri ara oun yii, Muyiwa Akeem to fẹẹ ṣe oogun owo pẹlu ẹgbọn rẹ wa nibẹ to n gbọ. Kia lo lọọ sọ fun ẹgbọn rẹ, ni wọn ba pada sọdọ Koba, oniṣegun wọn. NI iyẹn ba ṣe oogun fun wọn pe ki wọn lọọ fi ji owo naa wa. Lawọn ọmọ baba kan naa yii ba gba ile Baba Ọlatokunbọ lọ. Bi iyawo rẹ ti ri wọn to si ri i pe ole ni wọn lo fẹẹ pariwo, ni Akinọla ba gba a ̀orun mu, t ofọọ di i lẹnu, lo ba wọ ọ wọ inu yara kan, o si yi i lọrun pa. Niya ba ku.Baba yii ti kọkọ fun wọn ni ẹgbẹrun mẹẹdogun, to ni gbogbo owo to wa lọwo oun niyẹn, ṣugbọn igba to ri i pe wọn fẹẹ pa oun loootọ, o lọọ gbe owo naa jade fun wọn, ẹgbẹrun lọna ẹẹdẹgbẹta ataabọ. Bi wọn ti gba owo naa ni wọn pada wa lati pa baba, oun naa yaa ṣe bi ẹni to ti ku. Wọn ro pe o ti ku ni wọn ṣe fi i silẹ ti wọn lọ. Ni wọn ba gbe owo ti wọn ja gba, o dile Koba. Ni Koba ba fun Akinọla ni ọgọta ẹgbẹrun (N60,000), o fun Muyiwa ni aadọta (N50,000) O ni oun yoo fi eyi to ku ṣe oogun owo fun wọn ni. O ṣe oogun ka fun wọn loootọ, ṣugbọn oogun naa ko ti i di owo lati inu oṣu kẹta ọdun yii ti wọn ti ṣe e, titi ti ọwọ awọn ọlọpaa fi tẹ wọn yii o. Wọn kan pa iya arugbo naa danu lasan ni."},{"question":"Jan Janszoon","answer":"Janszoon van Haarlem, ti a mọ si Reis Mourad the Younger (c. 1570 – c. 1641), jẹ apaniyan Dutch ti tẹlẹ ti o di corsair Barbary ni Ottoman Algeria ati Republic of Salé. Lẹhin ti o ti gba nipasẹ awọn ẹlẹṣin Algerian kuro ni Lanzarote ni ọdun 1618, o yipada si Islam o si yi orukọ rẹ pada si Mourad. O di ọkan ninu olokiki julọ ti awọn corsairs Barbary orundun 17th. Paapọ pẹlu awọn corsairs miiran, o ṣe iranlọwọ lati fi idi Republic of Salé olominira mulẹ ni ilu orukọ yẹn, o ṣiṣẹ bi Alakoso akọkọ ati Alakoso. O tun ṣiṣẹ bi Gomina Oualidia.Janszoon van Haerlem ni a bi ni Haarlem ni ọdun 1570, eyiti o wa ni Holland, lẹhinna agbegbe kan ti ijọba ijọba Habsburg ṣe ijọba. Ogun Ọdun Mẹjọ laarin awọn ọlọtẹ Dutch ati Ijọba Ara ilu Spanish labẹ King Philip II ti bẹrẹ ni ọdun meje ṣaaju ibimọ rẹ; o pẹ ni gbogbo igbesi aye rẹ. A mọ diẹ nipa igbesi aye akọkọ rẹ. O fẹ Southgen Cave ni ọdun 1595 ati pe o ni awọn ọmọ meji pẹlu rẹ, Edward ati Lysbeth. [ijuwe ti nilo]Ni ọdun 1600, Jan Janszoon bẹrẹ bi ọkọ oju-omi aladani Dutch ti o wa lati ibudo ọkọ oju-ile rẹ ti Haarlem, ti n ṣiṣẹ fun ipinle pẹlu awọn lẹta ti marque lati ṣe ifilọlẹ gbigbe ọkọ oju omi Spanish ni Ogun Ọdun Mẹjọ. Janszoon bò awọn aala ti awọn lẹta rẹ o si wa ọna rẹ si awọn ilu ibudo igbẹkẹle ti Barbary Coast of North Africa, nibiti o le kọlu awọn ọkọ oju omi ti gbogbo ilu ajeji: nigbati o kọlu ọkọ oju omi Spanish kan, o fo asia Dutch; nigbati o kọlu eyikeyi miiran, o di Captain Ottoman o si fo oṣupa oṣupa ati asia irawọ ti awọn Tooki tabi asia eyikeyi ninu ọpọlọpọ awọn ijọba Mẹditarenia miiran. Lakoko yii, o ti kọ idile Dutch rẹ silẹ.A gba Janszoon ni ọdun 1618 ni Lanzarote ( ọkan ninu awọn erekusu Canary ) nipasẹ awọn ẹlẹṣin Algerian ati pe o mu lọ si Algiers bi igbekun. Nibẹ ni o \\"tan Turk\\", tabi Musulumi. Diẹ ninu awọn akoitan ṣalaye pe iyipada naa fi agbara mu. Janszoon funrararẹ, sibẹsibẹ, gbiyanju gidigidi lati yi awọn ara ilu Yuroopu ẹlẹgbẹ rẹ ti o jẹ Kristiẹni lati di Musulumi ati pe o jẹ ihinrere Musulumi ti o ni itara. Awọn Tooki Ilu Ottoman ṣetọju iwọn ipa ti ipa lori dípò ti Sultan wọn nipa iwuri fun awọn Moors ni gbangba lati ṣe ilosiwaju ara wọn nipasẹ ajalelokun lodi si awọn agbara Yuroopu, eyiti o binu si Ottoman Ottoman. Lẹhin iyipada Janszoon si Islam ati awọn ọna ti awọn ti o mu, o wọ ọkọ pẹlu olokiki olokiki Sulayman Rais, ti a tun mọ ni Slemen Reis, ẹniti o jẹ Dutchman kan ti a npè ni De Veenboer, ẹniti Janszoon ti mọ ṣaaju gbigba rẹ ati ẹniti o tun yipada si Islam. Wọn wa pẹlu Simon de Danser. [ijuwe ti nilo] Ṣugbọn, nitori Algiers ti pari alafia pẹlu ọpọlọpọ awọn orilẹ-ede Yuroopu, kii ṣe ibudo ti o yẹ lati eyiti lati ta awọn ọkọ oju omi ti o gba tabi ẹru wọn. Nitorinaa, lẹhin ti o pa Sulayman Rais nipasẹ ibọn kekere kan ni ọdun 1619, Janszoon gbe lọ si ibudo atijọ ti Salé o bẹrẹ iṣẹ lati ọdọ rẹ bi corsair Barbary kan.Ni ọdun 1619, Salé Rovers ṣalaye ibudo naa lati jẹ olominira olominira lati ọdọ Sultan. Wọn ṣeto ijọba kan ti o ni awọn oludari apaniyan 14 ati dibo Janszoon gẹgẹbi Alakoso wọn. Oun yoo tun ṣiṣẹ bi Admiral Grand, ti a mọ ni Murat Reis, ti ọgagun wọn. Awọn ọkọ oju-omi Salé jẹ to awọn ọkọ oju omi mejidilogun, gbogbo wọn kere nitori ẹnu-ọna abo aijinile pupọ.Lẹhin idoti ti ko ni aṣeyọri ti ilu naa, Sultan ti Ilu Morocco jẹwọ iṣẹ-ṣiṣe rẹ. Ni ilodisi igbagbọ olokiki pe Sultan Zidan Abu Maali ti gba ijọba ọba pada lori Salé o si yan Janszoon Gomina ni ọdun 1624, Sultan gba idibo Janszoon gẹgẹbi alaga nipasẹ yiyan ni yiyan bi gomina ayẹyẹ rẹ.Labẹ itọsọna Janszoon, iṣowo ni Salé ṣe rere. Awọn orisun akọkọ ti owo oya ti ijọba olominira yii jẹ apaniyan ati awọn oniwe-nipasẹ-trades, sowo ati awọn olugbagbọ ni ohun-ini ji. Awọn akoitan ti ṣe akiyesi oye ati igboya ti Janszoon, eyiti a fihan ninu agbara olori rẹ. O fi agbara mu lati wa oluranlọwọ lati tọju, eyiti o yorisi igbanisise ti arakunrin ẹlẹgbẹ kan lati Netherlands, Mathys van Bostel Oosterlinck, ẹniti yoo ṣiṣẹ bi Igbakeji-Admiral rẹ.Janszoon ti di ọlọrọ pupọ lati owo oya rẹ bi ẹwa apaniyan, awọn sisanwo fun ìdákọró ati awọn owo abo miiran, ati fifọ awọn ẹru ji. Oju-ọjọ iṣelu ni Salé buru si opin ọdun 1627, nitorinaa Janszoon dakẹ gbe ẹbi rẹ ati gbogbo iṣẹ rẹ pada si Algiers olominira.Àwọn ará Netherlands tí wọ́n kó nígbèkùnLakoko ti o wa ni Ilu Morocco, Janszoon ṣiṣẹ lati ni aabo itusilẹ ti awọn igbekun Dutch lati awọn ajalelokun miiran ati ṣe idiwọ wọn lati ta sinu ifi.Àgbékalẹ̀ Àárín Àwọn Ọmọ ilẹ̀ Faransé àti Morocco ti ọdún 1631Imọ ti awọn ede pupọ, lakoko ti o wa ni Algiers o ṣe alabapin si idasile adehun adehun Franco-Moroccan ti 1631 laarin Faranse King Louis XIII ati Sultan Abu Marwan Abd al-Malik II.LundyNi ọdun 1627, Janszoon gba erekusu Lundy ni ikanni Bristol o si mu u fun ọdun marun, ni lilo rẹ bi ipilẹ fun awọn irin-ajo gigun.Ilẹ̀ IcelandNi ọdun 1627, Janszoon lo Danish kan “ẹrú” ( o ṣee ṣe ki o jẹ ọmọ ẹgbẹ atukọ kan ti o gba ọkọ oju-omi Danish kan ti o gba bi ẹbun apaniyan kan ) lati ṣe awakọ oun ati awọn ọkunrin rẹ si Iceland. Nibẹ ni wọn ja abule ipeja ti Grindavík. Awọn ohun mimu wọn jẹ kekere, diẹ ninu awọn ẹja iyọ ati awọn ibi aabo diẹ, ṣugbọn wọn tun gba Icelanders mejila ati awọn Danes mẹta ti o ṣẹlẹ lati wa ni abule naa. Nigbati wọn nlọ Grindavík, wọn ṣakoso lati tan ati mu ọkọ oju-omi oniṣowo Danish kan ti o kọja nipasẹ ọna fifo asia eke. [ijuwe ti nilo]Awọn ọkọ oju omi wọ ọkọ oju omi lọ si Bessastaðir, ijoko ti gomina Danish ti Iceland, lati ja ṣugbọn ko lagbara lati ṣe ibalẹ – o sọ pe wọn ti kuna nipasẹ ina Kanonu lati awọn odi agbegbe ( Bessastaðaskans ) ati ẹgbẹ ti o ni kiakia ti awọn anfani lati Gusu Peninsula. Wọn pinnu lati ta ọkọ si ile Salé, nibiti wọn ti ta awọn igbekun wọn bi ẹrú.Awọn ọkọ oju omi corsair meji lati Algiers, o ṣee ṣe sopọ si igbogun ti Janszoon, wa si Iceland ni ọjọ 4 Keje ati pe o wa nibẹ. Lẹhinna wọn wọ ọkọ oju omi lọ si Vestmannaeyjar kuro ni etikun gusu ati ja si ibẹ fun ọjọ mẹta. Awọn iṣẹlẹ wọnyẹn ni a mọ ni Iceland gẹgẹ bi Tyrkjaránið ( awọn ifipa ti Ilu Turki ), bi awọn ipinlẹ Barbary ṣe jẹ apakan ti Ottoman Ottoman.Awọn iroyin nipasẹ awọn Icelanders ti o jẹ ẹrú ti o lo akoko lori awọn ọkọ oju omi corsair sọ pe awọn ipo fun awọn obinrin ati awọn ọmọde jẹ deede, ni pe wọn yọọda lati gbe jakejado ọkọ oju omi, ayafi si dekini mẹẹdogun. Awọn ajalelokun naa ni a rii fifun ni afikun ounjẹ si awọn ọmọde lati awọn ikọlu ikọkọ ti ara wọn. Obinrin ti o bi ọkọ oju-omi ni a tọju pẹlu iyi, ni agbara ikọkọ ati aṣọ nipasẹ awọn ajalelokun. Wọn fi awọn ọkunrin naa si idaduro awọn ọkọ oju omi ati pe wọn ti yọ ẹwọn wọn kuro ni kete ti awọn ọkọ oju omi ba to lati ilẹ. Laibikita awọn iṣeduro ti o gbajumọ nipa itọju ti awọn igbekun, awọn iroyin Icelander ko mẹnuba pe awọn ẹrú ni ifipabanilopo lori irin-ajo funrararẹ, sibẹsibẹ, Guðríður Símonardóttir, ọkan ninu awọn igbekun diẹ lati pada si Iceland nigbamii, ni a ta sinu ifi ẹrú ibalopo bi apejọ kan.Àpótí Ìlú Baltimore, ní Ilẹ̀ IrelandLehin ti o wọ ọkọ oju omi fun oṣu meji ati pẹlu diẹ lati ṣafihan fun irin-ajo naa, Janszoon yipada si igbekun ti o ya lori irin-ajo, Roman Katoliki kan ti a npè ni John Hackett, fun alaye lori ibiti igbogun ti ere le ṣee ṣe. Awọn olugbe Alatẹnumọ ti Baltimore, ilu kekere kan ni West Cork, Ireland, ni ilu abinibi ara ilu Roman Katoliki ti ara ilu Irish nitori wọn gbe wọn si awọn ilẹ ti o gba lati idile O'Driscoll. Hackett ṣe itọsọna Janszoon si ilu yii ati kuro lọdọ tirẹ. Janszoon ti gba Baltimore silẹ ni 20 June 1631, ti o gba ohun-ini kekere ṣugbọn mu awọn igbekun 108, ẹniti o ta bi ẹrú ni Ariwa Afirika. A sọ pe Janszoon ti tu Irish silẹ ati pe o mu awọn igbekun Gẹẹsi nikan. Laipẹ lẹhin apo naa, wọn mu Hackett ati gbe mọ fun ilufin rẹ. \\"Eyi kii ṣe Kristiẹni kan ti ko sọkun ati ẹniti ko kun fun ibanujẹ ni oju ọpọlọpọ awọn iranṣẹbinrin oloootitọ ati ọpọlọpọ awọn obinrin ti o dara ti a kọ silẹ si iwa ika ti awọn alaigbede wọnyi ”\\". Meji ninu awọn abule naa nikan pada si ilu wọn.Àwọn Ìjà Ìjà Ní Òkun MẹditaréníàÀtúnṣeMurat Reis pinnu láti rí owó tó pọ̀ gbà nípa lílo àwọn erékùṣù Mẹditaréníà bí àwọn erékún Balearic, Corsica, Sardinia, àti etíkun gúúsù Sicily. Ó sábà máa ń ta ọ̀pọ̀ lára àwọn nǹkan rẹ̀ ní ìlú Tunis, níbi tó ti di ọ̀rẹ́ àwọn Dey. Ó ti ń rìnrìn àjò ní Òkun Jóńsíkò. Ó bá àwọn ará Venice jà nítòsí etíkun Kírétè àti Sípírọ́sì pẹ̀lú ẹgbẹ́ àwọn ọmọ ogun olúgbìn tó ní àwọn ọmọ ilẹ̀ Dutch, Moriscos, Arab, Turkish, àti àwọn ọmọ ogun Janissaries tó jẹ́ olóye.Ni ọdun 1635, nitosi eti okun Tunisia, Murat Reis ti kun ati iyalẹnu nipasẹ ikọlu lojiji. Oun ati ọpọlọpọ awọn ọkunrin rẹ ni o gba nipasẹ awọn Knights ti Malta. O ti wa ni ewon ninu awọn ile nla dudu ti erekusu naa. O ṣe ibi ati ni ijiya, o si jiya ilera aisan nitori akoko rẹ ninu ile-ẹwọn. Ni ọdun 1640, o ko sa asala lẹhin ikọlu Corsair nla kan, eyiti Dey ti Tunis gbero ni pẹkipẹki lati le gba awọn atukọ ẹlẹgbẹ wọn ati Corsairs. O bu ọla fun pupọ o si yìn fun ipadabọ rẹ si Ilu Morocco ati awọn Ipinle Barbary nitosi.Lẹhin Janszoon pada si Ilu Morocco ni 1640, o ti yan gẹgẹ bi Gomina ti odi nla ti Oualidia, nitosi Safi. O ngbe ni Castle ti Maladia. Ni Oṣu Keji ọdun 1640, ọkọ oju omi de pẹlu consul Dutch tuntun kan, ẹniti o mu Lysbeth Janszoon van Haarlem, ọmọbinrin Janszoon nipasẹ iyawo Dutch rẹ, lati ṣabẹwo si baba rẹ. Nigbati Lysbeth de, Janszoon \\"joko ni pomp nla lori capeti, pẹlu awọn aga timutimu, awọn iranṣẹ ni ayika rẹ\\". O rii pe Murat Reis ti di alailagbara, arugbo. Lysbeth duro pẹlu baba rẹ titi di Oṣu Kẹjọ ọdun 1641, nigbati o pada si Holland. Little ni a mọ ti Janszoon lẹhinna; o ṣee ṣe ti fẹyìntì nikẹhin lati igbesi aye gbangba ati ajalelokun. Ọjọ iku rẹ ko jẹ aimọ.Ni ọdun 1596, nipasẹ obinrin Dutch ti a ko mọ, ọmọ akọkọ ti Janszoon ni a bi, Lysbeth Janszoon van Haarlem. [ mimọ ti nilo ]Lẹhin ti o di apaniyan kan, Janszoon pade obinrin ti a ko mọ ni Cartagena, Spain, ẹniti yoo fẹ. Idanimọ ti obinrin yii jẹ ohun ti ko ni itan-akọọlẹ, ṣugbọn ipohunpo ni pe o jẹ ti ipilẹṣẹ ti ọpọlọpọ-ẹya, ti a ka si “Morisco” ni Ilu Sipeeni. Awọn akoitan ti sọ pe ko jẹ nkankan diẹ sii ju apejọ kan, awọn miiran sọ pe o jẹ Musulumi Mudéjar kan ti o ṣiṣẹ fun idile ọlọla Kristiẹni kan, ati awọn iṣeduro miiran ni a ti ṣe pe o jẹ “Ọmọ-binrin ọba.”.\\" Nipasẹ igbeyawo yii, Janszoon ni awọn ọmọ mẹrin: Abraham Janszoon van Salee ( b.1602 ), Philip Janszoon van Salee ( b. 1604 ), Anthony Janszoon van Salee ( b.1607 ), ati Cornelis Janszoon van Salee ( b. 1608 ).O jẹ akiyesi pe Janszoon ṣe igbeyawo fun igba kẹta si ọmọbirin Sultan Moulay Ziden ni ọdun 1624.Ni ọdun 2009, ere kan ti o da lori igbesi aye Janszoon bi apaniyan kan, “Jan Janszoon, de bilondi Arabier”, ti Karim El Guennouni kọ irin-ajo Netherlands. \\"Ọmọ-baba agba: Ballad ti Murad the Captain\\" jẹ ewi awọn ọmọde nipa Janszoon ti a tẹjade ni ọdun 2007.[7]Ni ọdun 2015, Janszoon jẹ alatako bọtini ninu itan aramada Slave si Fortune nipasẹ D.J. Munro.A tun mọ Janszoon bi Murat Reis the Younger. Awọn orukọ Dutch rẹ ni a tun fun ni Jan Jansen ati Jan Jansz; orukọ rẹ ti a gba bi Morat Rais, Murat Rais, Morat; Little John Ward, John Barber, Captain John, ati Caid Morato jẹ diẹ ninu awọn orukọ Pirate rẹ. \\"“Irun irun” jẹ oruko apeso ti Janszoon."},{"question":"Doğumdan sonra üşüme titreme neden olur?","answer":"- Vücüt ısısında da değişiklikler görülür.Doğumdan hemen sonra vücuttan ani ısı kaybedilmesine bağlı olarak annede fizyolojik titreme ortaya çıkar, ve beraberinde üşüme hissi olur.Tüm bu şikayetler çok kısa sürede geçer."},{"question":"Volgens de tekst van het lied 'Piraten-potpourri' zijn Samson en Gert op weg naar Timbuktu. In welk land ligt Timbuktu?","answer":"Mali "},{"question":"Kedu ihe ụfọdụ a na-ejikarị eme ihe n'abụ Igbo?","answer":"Ngwongwo eji agụ agụ dị n'abụ Igbo nwere ike ịgụnye ihe atụ, ntule, agụgharị, nkwugharị, na akara ngosi."},{"question":"વાક્ય 1: 2010 માં, અન્ય એક મહિલા પ્રિત્ઝકર પુરસ્કાર વિજેતા બની, જાપાનથી ર્યુએ નિશીઝાવા, કાઝુયો સેજીમા સાથે ભાગીદારીમાં. વાક્ય 2: 2010 માં, અન્ય સ્ત્રી પ્રિત્ઝકર પુરસ્કાર વિજેતા, જાપાનના ર્યુએ નિશીઝાવા, કાઝુયો સેજીમા સાથે ભાગીદારીમાં હતા. પ્રશ્ન: શું વાક્ય 1 અને વાક્ય 2 એ જ અર્થ વ્યક્ત કરે છે? હા કે ના?","answer":"ના"},{"question":"तारापूर हे भारतातील कितवे अणुशक्ती केंद्र आहे?","answer":"पहिले"},{"question":"السؤال: عدد زوجات الرسول صلى الله عليه؟","answer":"الإجابة: 11"},{"question":"請回答這個問題：在物理學中，什麼是相對論？","answer":"答案：相對論是一個物理學理論，描述了物體在高速運動和強引力場中的行為，包括著名的相對論效應，如時間膨脹和空間收縮。"},{"question":"Terjemahkanlah penggalan teks Bahasa Inggris yang disadur dari kumpulan cerita anak dunia berikut ke teks dalam Bahasa Indonesia.I see a grey and black cat wearing an orange hat.","answer":"Aku melihat seekor kucing abu-abu hitam mengenakan topi jingga."},{"question":"Terjemahkanlah penggalan teks Bahasa Inggris yang disadur dari kumpulan cerita anak dunia berikut ke teks dalam Bahasa Indonesia.I see a black and orange tiger standing in the water.Terjemahan:","answer":"Aku melihat seekor harimau hitam jingga sedang berdiri di air."},{"question":"Yintoni eyenza ikhaya lifudumale?","answer":"Xa kukho uthando novuyo ikhaya liye lifudumale."},{"question":"Sheeg Warshada Sonkor Isnaay Oo Ku Taalo Magaalada Jowhar Sanadkii La-Aas-Aasay?","answer":"Waxaa La-Aas-Aasay Sanadkii 1925-Tii."},{"question":"يضرب به المثل في الاعياء فيقال أعيى من…؟","answer":"-باقل"},{"question":"Inona no tendrombohitra avo indrindra any Costa Rica?","answer":"Ny tendrombohitra Chirripó no tendrombohitra avo indrindra any Costa Rica, ahitana fijery mahafinaritra ny tontolo manodidina."},{"question":"Ao amin'ny zoo dia misy liona, elefanta ary zirafy. Ny liona rehetra mierona, ny elefanta rehetra dia manana trompetra, ary ny zirafy rehetra dia manana hatoka lava.Inona no azontsika tsoahina avy amin’ireo fanambarana etsy ambony ireo?A. Ny biby rehetra manana tenda lava dia zirafy.B. Lava tenda ny liona.D. Ny biby rehetra mitsoka trompetra dia elefanta.E. Ny biby rehetra mierona dia lava hatoka.","answer":"Ny valiny marina dia A. Ny biby rehetra manana tenda lava dia zirafy."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Nhiều vùng trên cả nước đón mưa dông kéo dài","answer":"Do ảnh hưởng của rãnh áp thấp kết hợp với vùng hội tụ gió trên cao nên ngày và đêm nay (31/7), khu vực Việt Bắc (Cao Bằng, Bắc Kạn, Hà Giang, Tuyên Quang, Lạng Sơn, Thái Nguyên), khu vực đồng bằng Bắc Bộ, Thanh Hóa và Nghệ An có mưa vừa và dông, có nơi mưa to với lượng mưa phổ biến từ 30-50mm, có nơi trên 70mm. Các nơi khác ở Bắc Bộ có mưa rào và dông, cục bộ có mưa to với lượng mưa từ 20-40mm, có nơi trên 60mm. Trong mưa dông có khả năng xảy ra lốc, sét, mưa đá và gió giật mạnh. Nguy cơ cao xảy ra lũ quét, sạt lở đất tại các tỉnh vùng núi Bắc Bộ và ngập úng tại các khu vực trũng, thấp. Hà Nội hôm nay nhiều mây, nắng gián đoạn, có lúc có mưa rào và dông, cục bộ có mưa to. Gió nam đến đông nam cấp 2-3. Trong mưa dông có khả năng xảy ra lốc, sét và gió giật mạnh. Nhiệt độ thấp nhất 24-26 độ. Nhiệt độ cao nhất 31-34 độ. Dự báo mưa dông ở miền Bắc và các tỉnh Thanh Hóa - Nghệ An kéo dài đến hết ngày mai (1/8). Từ 2/8, khu vực này trời nắng, có nắng nóng cục bộ. Các tỉnh Hà Tĩnh - Thừa Thiên Huế hôm nay trời nắng, có nơi nắng nóng, chiều tối có mưa rào và dông rải rác, đêm không mưa. Gió nhẹ. Trong mưa dông có khả năng xảy ra lốc, sét và gió giật mạnh. Nhiệt độ thấp nhất 24-27 độ. Nhiệt độ cao nhất 31-34 độ, phía Nam có nơi trên 35 độ. Các tỉnh Đà Nẵng đến Bình Thuận ngày mưa rào và dông vài nơi, nắng gián đoạn, riêng chiều tối có mưa rào và dông rải rác, cục bộ có mưa to. Gió tây nam cấp 2-3. Trong mưa dông có khả năng xảy ra lốc, sét và gió giật mạnh. Nhiệt độ thấp nhất 25-28 độ. Nhiệt độ cao nhất 31-34 độ, có nơi trên 34 độ. Dự báo từ chiều tối và đêm 1-2/8, miền Trung có mưa rào và dông rải rác, cục bộ có mưa to. Tây Nguyên ngày có mưa rào và dông vài nơi, nắng gián đoạn, riêng chiều tối và tối có mưa rào và rải rác có dông, cục bộ có mưa to. Gió tây nam cấp 2-3. Trong mưa dông có khả năng xảy ra lốc, sét, mưa đá và gió giật mạnh. Nhiệt độ thấp nhất 20-23 độ. Nhiệt độ cao nhất 29-32 độ, có nơi trên 32 độ. Nam Bộ ngày có mưa rào và dông vài nơi, nắng gián đoạn, riêng chiều tối và tối có mưa rào và rải rác có dông, cục bộ có mưa to. Gió tây nam cấp 2-3. Trong mưa dông có khả năng xảy ra lốc, sét, mưa đá và gió giật mạnh. Nhiệt độ thấp nhất 24-27 độ. Nhiệt độ cao nhất 31-34 độ, có nơi trên 34 độ. Dự báo trong nhiều ngày tới, Tây Nguyên và Nam Bộ tiếp tục có mưa rào và dông rải rác vào chiều tối và tối, cục bộ có mưa to, ngày nắng gián đoạn. Trong mưa dông có khả năng xảy ra lốc, sét, mưa đá và gió giật mạnh. "},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe \\"trano zozoro\\"?","answer":"ny \\"trano zozoro\\" dia trano vita tamin'ny takelaka zozoro ka, raha tiana ho mafy, dia nasiana ireny volotsangana novakiana teo ivelany ary nofetaina ho azo lalorina ny tao anatiny; zozoro koa ny lela varavarana."},{"question":"Waze wasiyala uHulumeni ngale mithetho yakhe esikhwezaabafokazana emakhanda amakhosi.Uqinisile baba, oDuma abasazikhohliwe bengamakhosi. NgempelauDuma ungekhohlwe sekunguye inkosi kule ndawo. Kukhona nabantuasebemkhulekela. Eqinisweni nje, lo Hulumeni wayecabangeni nje azeashaye umthetho onje?(ubuso buhwaqabala) Kwakunani nje ukuthi bavotiseabasemadolobheni kuphela? Thina makhosi basivikele ngokushayaumthetho othi masifundiswe ngokusebenzisana nabantu ekuletheniintuthuko. Buka nje manje, abantu sebenezimpawana zokuhlukanaphakathi. Kukhona asebengibuka njengento engathi shu. Abanyebazonda uDuma egameni lokuthi usethathe isikhundla samiengasinikwa uMvelingqangi kanye nobabamkhulu.(ahebeze ngezandla sakuphika) Cha! Cha! Noma ngabe lo mthethoushaywe ePitoli noma eKapa inkosi iyohlale iyinkosi. Angifundileokuyaphi kepha ngiyazi ukuthi ngaphambi kokushaya umthetho,kudingeka kube nocwaningo. Phela kumele bacwaninge ngosikompilolwama-Afrika kuqala ze bakwazi ukushaya umthetho ongachithiokukhona ngoba bakwethu, kuse-Afrika lapha.(aneke izandla sakuzivula, okukaMfundisi eshumayela)Ngivumelana nawe MaNgema. Uyazi kuyasho ukuthi walunguzaesikoleni. Futhi-ke nje akukhona ukulunguza ukufunda uze ubenguthisha. Phela uhleli nje ungafundisi ngoba yimi kanye nobabaesanquma ukuba ube yinkosikazi yenkosi egcwele. Wawungeke ubeyiyo egcwele ube ufundisa. Cabanga nje inkosikazi yenkosi idelelwayizingane zabafokazana. Okubi kakhulu-ke nawe utholakale ulawulwanguthishanhloko ongumfokazana.1. Umbhali walo mdlalo ukwazile ukufeza imigomo yokubhala isingeniso.Fakazela lokhu ngamaphuzu AMABILI.","answer":"Amaphuzu AMABILI kwalandelayo:Ukwazile ukufeza imigomo ngoba... Siyamthola umlingiswa oqavile esingenisweni, okunguDuma. √/Siyayithola nenkinga ayebhekene nayo yokungezwani nenkosi ngobaengafuni ukuthathisa enkosini. √/ Siyasithola nesizinda ekuqaleni kwendaba ngokwendawo ukuthi le ndabayenzeka endaweni yasemakhaya. √/ Siyathola nesizinda sesikhathi esikhombisa ukuthi isikhathi samanjenjengoba sekukhona intando yeningi. √/Isimo senhlalo asisihle, sikhombisa ukushayisana kusukela ekuqaleni.√"},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en está categoría : política. ","answer":"¿Quién se postuló a vicepresidente en 2020 y fue reelecto como Fiscal General de California en 2014? Kamala Harris. "},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් කණ්ඩායමේ පළමු ටෙස්ට් නායකයා  කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකා  ක්‍රිකට් කණ්ඩායමේ පළමු ටෙස්ට් නායකයා  වූයේ බන්දුල වර්ණපුරයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ටෙස්ට් ක්‍රිකට් පිටියට පිවිසීම සනිටුහන් කළ ඔවුන්ගේ මංගල ටෙස්ට් තරගයේදී ඔහු කණ්ඩායම මෙහෙයවීය. මෙම ඓතිහාසික තරගය 1982 පෙබරවාරි මාසයේදී එංගලන්තයට එරෙහිව කොළඹදී පැවැත්විණි. "},{"question":"Awọn eeyan binu si ọmọ Wasiu Ayinde to n bu Sunday Igboho","answer":"Pelu ibinu lawọn eeyan fi n ṣepe le ọmọ Alaaji Wasiu Ayinde, Arabinrin Damilọla Marshal, lórí bo ṣe bu ẹnu atẹ lu awọn eeyan to n ṣatilẹyin fun Sunday Igboho.Arabinrin to pe ara ẹ ni akẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ìmọ ofin yii sọ pe ki í ṣe ohun to ba ojú mu b’awọn eeyan ṣe sọ Igboho di olokiki lojiji, ti awọn oniroyin kan n pè é ni ajijagbara iran Yoruba, ti awọn kan lati ilẹ okeere si tun n da owo bayii, ti wọn láwọn fẹẹ fi ra awọn bọọsi ti yoo maa lo fun iṣẹ ijijagbara to n ṣe.Damilọla fi kun un pe gbogbo ọmọ Yorùbá ni wọn ṣì gbọdọ rántí ogun Ifẹ ati Mọdakẹkẹ daadaa, ohun toju awọn eeyan ri, ati pe Sunday Igboho yii kan naa kopa ninu ogun ọ̀hún, kò sí yẹ ki ọmọ Yorùbá to fẹẹ alaafia, to lodi si wahala, fara mọ ohun ti Sunday Igboho n ṣe kiri yii.Ọmọbinrin yii ni niṣẹ lo yẹ kí ìjọba fọwọ ṣikun mu ẹnikẹni tó bá ti lọwọ sí ariwo ogun ti ọkunrin yii n pa. O ni ọmọ Yorùbá gidi loun, bẹẹ loun yóò máa rí iran Hausa ati Ibo gẹgẹ bii mọlẹbi oun.Ọrọ ti Dami Marshal, ọmọ gbajumọ olorin fuji nní Alaaji Wasiu Ayinde, sọ niyẹn ti awọn eeyan fi kọ lu u, ti wọn fi n ṣepe fún un.Wọn ni ko si ọmọ Yorùbá gidi kan tó yẹ kó sọ ohun ti obinrin yii sọ sí Oloye Sunday Adeyẹmọ, ẹni tawọn eeyan tun mọ si Sunday Igboho, nitori ija gbogbo Yorùbá lo n ja.Bakan naa láwọn eeyan n sọ pé ẹnikẹni tó bá lòdì sí Sunday Igboho, ọta Yoruba ni, bẹẹ epe lo yẹ iru wọn.Awọn mi-in ni epe lo maa pa  apẹlu ọrọ buruku to n sọ jade lẹnu naa. Epe oriṣiiriṣii lawọn eeyan si n gbe e ṣẹ fun ọrọ ti wọn ka si ọrọ agọ to sọ ọhun.Bẹ o ba gbagbe, Damilọla yii kan na lo sọrọ si aọn ti wọn n ṣe iwọde lodi si awọn SARS ninu oṣu kẹwaa ọdun to kọja. Oriṣiiriṣii orukọ lo pe awọn eeyan naa to ni wọn di oun lọwọ lati lọ si ibi iṣẹ oun pelu iwọde ti wọn n ṣe.Ọrọ naa ko dun mọ awọn eeyan ninu nigba naa, niṣe ni wọn si n bu u lori ikanni rẹ lasiko naa."},{"question":"Sheeg magaca Abwaankii allifay Riwaayaddii “Dab jacayl kari waa”?","answer":"Waxaa allifay Xasan C/llaahi Ganey."},{"question":"Apakah maksud Gatal mulut?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah \\tSuka cakap keburukan orang."},{"question":"Кумурскалар жөнүндө жазып бере адасыңбы?","answer":"Кумурсканын «атта» деген түрү «жалбырак кескич» деп да аталат. Себеби, алар жашыл жалбыракты тыкан кылып кесип алып, уясына ташыйт. Бирок, алар аны жешпейт, болгону майдалап чайнап «каша» кылышат да, ага козукарын өстүрүшөт. Анан, ошол козукарын менен уюктагы бардык кумурскалар азыктанышат. Ошондон улам, булар чарбачыл кумур-скалар катары да белгилүү. Бул кумурскалардын иштөө ыкмасы да таң каларлык план менен ишке ашат. Ми-салы, алар алгач жолун таптаза кылып тазалап алышат. Кумурскалардын колониясы жумушчулардан, андан бир топ чоң аскер кумурскаларынан жана орто бойлуу «марафончулардан» турат. Мында жалбырак ташыганы марафончулар жана алар жалбырак ташып баратканда, көлөмү боюнча андан кичинекей дагы бир кумурска жалбыракта жабышып жүрөт. Кокус душмандар чыга турган болсо, кичинекей кумурска табылгасын жана чоңун коргоого дароо киришет. Эгер марафончулар-ды адамдарга салыштыра турган болсок, алардын жүгү менен 4 мүнөт жүгүрүүсү адамдардын желкесине 227 кг жүктү көтөрүп, 48 километр жол жүргөнү менен барабар болот экен.Кумурскалардын негизги милдети кышка жана кийинки тукуму үчүн кам көрүү максатында азык чогултуу болуп эсеп-телет. Ошондуктан, тапкан-ташыганынан «ооз тийбестен» ую-гуна алып келишет. Ал жерден ханышанын катуу көзөмөлүнүн астында уюкка тегиз бөлүнөт. Чогулткан дан азыктарын зарыл учурда күн ачык мезгилде сыртка алып чыгып кургатат. Иш учурунда жараат алган туугандарына өтө камкор келип, алар-ды бакканы менен жалкоо болуп, уюкка азык алып келбеген-дерин катуу чара колдонушат. Башкача айтканда, өлтүрүп ко-юшат. Эгер кумурсканын уюгуна коркунуч келген болсо, алар дароо курсагын көтөрүп, «кумурска кислотасын» душманын көздөй чача баштайт. Муну айрым канаттуулар денесиндеги паразиттерден кутулуу үчүн пайдаланышат. Башкача айтканда, уюкка барып, кумурскаларды атайын денесине кое беришет. Бул кумурскаларга өз ишине мынчалык берилүүнү, азык затын кургатып алуу керектигин, эсептөөлөрдү так жүргүзүүнү жана «жансакчы» алып жүрүүнү ким үйрөттү болду экен? Ал-бетте, Улуу Жаратуучу бардык нерсени өз орду менен улуу акылмандык менен жаратканынын дагы бир далили"},{"question":"هي حائل هي عاصمة السعودية؟","answer":"لا، عاصمة المملكة العربية السعودية هي الرياض."},{"question":"वि ।सं २०७१ सालमा प्रदान गरिएको भूपि स्मृति पुरस्कारबाट सम्मानित हुने स्रष्टा को हुन् ?","answer":"मोमिला"},{"question":"Isikan tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang sesuai. \\"Plot bermaksud …\\"","answer":"Jawapannya ialah jalinan peristiwa."},{"question":"Chọn câu trả lời đúng cho câu hỏi sau: Nữ Bộ trưởng Giáo dục đầu tiên của Việt Nam là ai?A. Bà Võ Thị Ánh XuânB. Bà Nguyễn Thị Kim TiếnC. Bà Nguyễn Thị Bình","answer":"Câu trả lời đúng là C. Bà Nguyễn Thị BìnhBà Nguyễn Thị Bình, tên khai sinh là Nguyễn Thị Châu Sa, sinh năm 1927 ở làng Tân Hiệp, quận Châu Thành, tỉnh Sa Đéc (nay là An Hiệp, Châu Thành, Đồng Tháp). Theo Bảo tàng phụ nữ, bà là cháu ngoại nhà yêu nước Phan Châu Trinh, đã tốt nghiệp tú tài, ngoại ngữ giỏi, có thời gian dài làm chính trị và hoạt động ở Sài Gòn.Nhà văn Nguyên Ngọc nhận định: \\"Có lẽ bà là người Việt Nam có nhiều bạn bè nhất trên thế giới, từ những người dân thường cho đến các nguyên thủ quốc gia nổi tiếng và thuộc nhiều chế độ chính trị khác nhau\\". Bà được đánh giá là \\"một phụ nữ nhỏ nhắn, khiêm nhường mà uyên bác, gần gũi mà sang trọng\\".Sau ngày 30/4/1975, bà được cử giữ chức Bộ trưởng Giáo dục và là nữ bộ trưởng đầu tiên và duy nhất của ngành giáo dục từ năm 1945 đến nay. Bà cũng từng giữ chức vụ Phó Chủ tịch nước đến khi nghỉ hưu năm 2002."},{"question":" பாரதியாரின் இயற்பெயர் என்ன?","answer":" பாரதியாரின் இயற்பெயர் சின்னசாமி சுப்ரமணிய பாரதி"},{"question":"కింది పరిచిత గద్యాలను చదవండి. ఇచ్చిన ప్రశ్నలకు సమాధానాలు రాయండి.సీసా భళ్ళుమంది. సీసా పెంకులు ఘళ్ళున చెదిరిపడ్డాయి. రాజసఖుల హృదయాలు రువ్వుమన్నాయి. ఆ ప్రదేశం అంతా అత్తరు సౌరభంతో గుమ్మంది. అందరూ ఆ పరిమళానికి మత్తెక్కుతున్నట్టయ్యారు.ఒక క్షణానికి తెలివివచ్చి అందరూ కళ్ళెత్తి చూసేటప్పటికి, హఠాత్తుగానూ అప్రయత్నంగానూ వెనక్కి తిరిగి చూసి ఖాను కొయ్యయిపోయాడు.అదేమిటో అని అందరూ వెనక్కి తిరిగి చూడగా, పంచకళ్యాణి మీద శ్రీ శ్రీ శ్రీ శ్రీవత్సవాయి చతుర్భుజ తిమ్మజగపతి మహాద్భుతమైన గులాబి అత్తరు సౌరభాన్ని ఆఘ్రాణిస్తూ. ఎక్కడివీ సమనోహర సుగంధ పరిమళాలు అని అరకంట చూస్తూ నిలిచి ఉన్నాడు.మోర పైకెత్తుకుని, పంచకళ్యాణి గుర్రం సైతం అద్భుతాన్ని ఆస్వాదిస్తూ ఉండుండి సప్రయత్నంగా ఊపిరి తీసుకుంటోంది.ప్రశ్నలు :1. రాజ సభ్యుల హృదయాలు ఏమైనాయి?2. మహారాజు దేని మీద వెళ్తున్నాడు?3. కొయ్యబారిపోయింది ఎవరు?4. ఏ పరిమళానికి అందరు మత్తెక్కిపోయారు?","answer":"1. రాజ సభ్యుల హృదయాలు ఏమైనాయి?జవాబు:రాజసఖుల హృదయాలు ఠువ్వుమన్నాయి.2. మహారాజు దేని మీద వెళ్తున్నాడు?జవాబు:మహారాజు పంచకళ్యాణి మీద వెళ్తున్నాడు.3. కొయ్యబారిపోయింది ఎవరు?జవాబు:కొయ్యబారిపోయింది ఖాను.4. ఏ పరిమళానికి అందరు మత్తెక్కిపోయారు?జవాబు:గులాబీ అత్తరు పరిమళానికి అందరు మత్తెక్కి పోయారు."},{"question":"ਬਹੁ-ਪਤੀ ਵਿਆਹ ।","answer":"ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਵਿਆਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਔਰਤ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਆਦਮੀਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਵਾਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਹੀ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਹ ਸਾਰਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਪਤਨੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਦੇ ਦੋ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਹਨ । ਭਰਾਤਰੀ ਬਹੁ-ਪਤੀ ਵਿਆਹ ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਔਰਤ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਤੀ ਆਪਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਭਰਾ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਗੈਰ-ਭਰਾਤਰੀ ਬਹੁ-ਪਤੀ ਵਿਆਹ ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਔਰਤ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਤੀ ਆਪਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਭਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੇ । ਗ਼ਰੀਬੀ, ਔਰਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਘੱਟ ਗਿਣਤੀ, ਅਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਦੀ ਭਾਵਨਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਹ ਪ੍ਰਥਾ ਵਧੀ ।"},{"question":"Tí có quả bóng màu đỏ và Tèo có quả bóng màu tím. Thầy giáo lấy quả bóng của hai bạn và xếp cùng với quả bóng màu trắng lên một vòng tròn theo một thứ tự nào đó nhưng không để cho quả bóng của Tí và quả bóng của Tèo cạnh nhau.Sau đó, Tí và Tèo cùng chơi một trò chơi như sau: Ở lượt chơi của mình, người chơi sẽ chọn một quả bóng nào đó nằm kề với quả bóng của mình và lấy quả bóng đó ra khỏi vòng tròn. Ai lấy được quả bóng của người kia ra khỏi vòng tròn sẽ là người thắng cuộc. Tí chơi trước, hỏi ai trong hai người chơi có cách chơi chắc chắn thắng cuộc bất kể người chơi còn lại có chơi thế nào chăng nữa, nếu:a. n = 2023?Giáo dụcTrắc nghiệmChủ nhật, 9/4/2023, 10:03 (GMT+7)Đáp án bài toán lớp 5 về trò chơi với các quả bóngLời giải của tác giả dưới đây sẽ giải đáp thắc mắc về bài toán trò chơi với các quả bóng của lớp 5.Đề bài:Tí có quả bóng màu đỏ và Tèo có quả bóng màu tím. Thầy giáo lấy quả bóng của hai bạn và xếp cùng với quả bóng màu trắng lên một vòng tròn theo một thứ tự nào đó nhưng không để cho quả bóng của Tí và quả bóng của Tèo cạnh nhau.Sau đó, Tí và Tèo cùng chơi một trò chơi như sau: Ở lượt chơi của mình, người chơi sẽ chọn một quả bóng nào đó nằm kề với quả bóng của mình và lấy quả bóng đó ra khỏi vòng tròn. Ai lấy được quả bóng của người kia ra khỏi vòng tròn sẽ là người thắng cuộc. Tí chơi trước, hỏi ai trong hai người chơi có cách chơi chắc chắn thắng cuộc bất kể người chơi còn lại có chơi thế nào chăng nữa, nếu:a. n = 2023?b. n = 2022?","answer":"a) Tí là người có cách chơi chắc chắn thắng. Vì có (một số lẻ) quả bóng trắng nên trong hai dãy quả bóng trắng ngăn cách quả bóng của Tí và của Tèo, có một dãy có chứa chẵn quả bóng, dãy còn lại có chứa lẻ quả bóng. Ở lượt đầu tiên của mình, Tí chỉ cần còn chọn lấy quả bóng bên dãy có chứa chẵn quả bóng.Khi đó, hai dãy quả bóng ngăn cách quả bóng của Tí và của Tèo đều có lẻ quả bóng (tức là có ít nhất một quả bóng ngăn cách), vì vậy ở lượt chơi của mình, chắc chắn Tèo không thể lấy được quả bóng của Tí. Sau khi Tèo chơi xong lượt, đến lượt của Tí, trạng thái một dãy có lẻ quả bóng, một dãy có chẵn quả bóng được lặp lại. Lúc này, Tí chỉ cần lặp lại cách chơi như lúc đầu là chắc chắn Tèo không thể lấy được quả bóng của mình.Cách chơi như vậy là cách chơi \\"an toàn\\". Vì số lượng quả bóng ngăn cách quả bóng của Tí và của Tèo cứ giảm dần nên đến một lúc nào đó, Tí sẽ lấy được quả bóng của Tèo nên Tí sẽ là người thắng cuộc.b) Tèo là người có cách chơi chắc chắn thắng. Sau khi Tí chơi lượt chơi đầu tiên của mình, hai dãy quả bóng ngăn cách quả bóng của Tí và của Tèo, có một dãy có chứa chẵn quả bóng và một dãy có chứa lẻ quả bóng. Lúc này, Tèo chỉ cần thực hiện chiến thuật chơi như Tèo ở câu a."},{"question":"س114 - ما إسم النبي الذي صام ثلاثة أيام حتى رزقه اللهولدا ؟","answer":"ج114 - سيدنا زكريا"},{"question":"Wace jam'iya ce ke mulki a jahar Ondo Nijeriya a 2023?","answer":"APC"},{"question":"Mipetraka an-tanety ny biby mampinono rehetra.","answer":"Tsia. Ny feso dia biby mampinono saingy miaina ambanin'ny ranomasina."},{"question":"ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ, 3 ਮਾਰਚਵਿੱਤ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਅਰੁਣ ਜੇਤਲੀ ਨੇ ਅੱਜ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਨੇ ਮਾੜੀ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਚਲਾਈ ਤੇ ਹੁਣ ਕਾਂਰਗਸ ਮਾੜੀ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਧਿਰ ਦੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਅ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਦੇ ਬਿਆਨ ਨਾਲ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਭਾਵਨਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਠੇਸ ਪਹੁੰਚੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀ ਬੇਇੱਜ਼ਤੀ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਮੌਕਾ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਹੈ। ਜ਼ਿਕਰਯੋਗ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਦੀ ਅਗਵਾਈ ਹੇਠ 21 ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਪਾਰਟੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਮਤਾ ਪਾਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਦੋਸ਼ ਲਗਾਇਆ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਨਰਿੰਦਰ ਮੋਦੀ ਪੁਲਵਾਮਾ ਤੇ ਬਾਲਾਕੋਟ ਘਟਨਾਵਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਿਆਸੀਕਰਨ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ।ਸ੍ਰੀ ਜੇਤਲੀ ਨੇ ਸੋਸ਼ਲ ਮੀਡੀਆ ’ਤੇ ਲਿਖਿਆ, ‘ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਧਿਰਾਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਗਏ ਬਿਆਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਦੇਸ਼ ਕੌਮੀ ਹਿੱਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਨੁਕਸਾਨ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ। ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਧਿਰਾਂ ਨੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਖੁਸ਼ੀ ਜ਼ਾਹਿਰ ਕੀਤੀ ਤੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਮੌਕਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਅਤਿਵਾਦ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀ ਲੜਾਈ ਦੀ ਅਹਿਮੀਅਤ ਘਟਾ ਸਕੇ।’ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਮਨਮੋਹਨ ਸਿੰਘ ਦੇ ਬਿਆਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਹੁਤ ਨਮੋਸ਼ੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਬਿਆਨ ’ਚ ਅਤਿਵਾਦ ਦੀ ਸਮੱਸਿਆ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਜ਼ਿਕਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ।ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ 'ਚ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਦੀ ਕੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ 'ਚ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਧਿਰ ਦੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਅ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"නාසා (NASA) ආයතනයේ \\"රසායන පරිණාම\\" (laboratory of chemical evolution) අංශයේ ප්‍රධානී තනතුරට පත්වූ ප්‍රථම ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයා කවුද?","answer":"නාසා (NASA) ආයතනයේ \\"රසායන පරිණාම\\" (laboratory of chemical evolution) අංශයේ ප්‍රධානී තනතුරට පත්වූ ප්‍රථම ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයා  මහාචාර්‍ය සිරිල් පොන්නම්පෙරුම මහතා වේ."},{"question":"રાજસ્થાન ના પહેરવેશ વિશે જણાવો.","answer":"રાજસ્થાનના લોકો મોટાભાગે ગ્રામીણ વિસ્તારોમાં રહે છે. તેથી જ સ્ત્રીઓ ઘાગરા અને કુર્તી પહેરે છે અને પુરુષો ધોતી અને કુર્તા અને પેન્ટ પહેરે છે. અહીં દરેક જગ્યાના પોતપોતાના અલગ-અલગ પહેરવેશ હોય છે, ડ્રેસ પણ ધર્મ અને જાતિ પ્રમાણે બદલાય છે. મનુષ્યના માથા પર પહેરવામાં આવતા પાલા કપડાની જેમ તેને સાફા, પાગ, મોથરા, પગડી, ટોપી, ફાંટા વગેરે જેવા અનેક નામોથી ઓળખવામાં આવે છે."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Bangladesh självständighetsdag är en nationell helgdag i Bangladesh, som firas den 26 mars till minne av dagen då Bangladesh 1971 utropade sig som självständigt från Pakistan. Den dagen minns man de stupade i","answer":"Bangladeshs befrielsekrig, som varade fram till december samma år."},{"question":"وش طبخة الثريد المعروفة في القطيف؟","answer":"الثريد طبق شعبي من المطبخ القطيفي، ويُعرف باسم المحموص. يُصنع المحموص من الخبز المقطع إلى قطع صغيرة، ويُضاف إليه مرق اللحم أو الدجاج، واللحم المفروم أو اللحم المقطع إلى قطع صغيرة، والبهارات. يُقدم المحموص عادةً مع صلصة الطماطم أو الدقوس و معروف بالصالونة"},{"question":"అయితే, వీళ్లు పాడుతున్న ప్రార్థనా గీతాలు వారి మాతృభాష అయిన కశ్మీరీలో లేవు. వీళ్లంతా జమ్మూలోని స్థానిక భాషైన డోగ్రీలో ప్రార్థనలు చేస్తున్నారు.మూడు దశాబ్దాల క్రితం కశ్మీర్ లోయలో తలెత్తిన హింస వాళ్లను జమ్మూకు వలస వచ్చేలా చేసింది.తమ ఊళ్లను, నివాసాలను, పొలాలను, చివరకు తమ సంస్కృతిని కూడా వదులుకొని ఇక్కడికి వచ్చారు. చివరకు, నేటి తరానికి వారి మాతృభాష కూడా రాకుండా పోయింది.కశ్మీరీ పండిట్లు: \\"అత్యంత దారుణ పరిస్థితుల నడుమ బతుకుతున్నాం’’జమ్మూలో నివసిస్తున్న సుమారు 20 వేల మంది పండిట్లకు ఆర్టికల్ 370ని రద్దు చేసిన తర్వాత కూడా తిరిగి తమ స్వస్థలానికి ఎలా వెళ్లాలో తెలియడం లేదు.\\"ఆర్టికల్ 370 రద్దు వల్ల కశ్మీరీ పండిట్లకు ఏం మేలు జరుగుతుందో మాకు తెలియదు. ఇప్పటి వరకు కశ్మీరీ పండితులు తిరిగి వారి స్వస్థలాలకు వెళ్లే విషయంలో ఎలాంటి విధి విధానాలూ లేవు. ఆ విషయంలో ప్రభుత్వం మౌనంగా ఉంటోంది. మా వరకు చెప్పాలంటే ఆర్టికల్ 370 పెద్ద విషయమేం కాదు\\" అని ఆల్ కశ్మీరీ పండిట్ అసోసియేషన్ అధ్యక్షుడు రవీందర్ రానా అన్నారు.అత్యంత దారుణమైన పరిస్థితులు ఉన్న ఈ పుర్ఖూ క్యాంపులోనే కశ్మీరీ పండితులు గడపాల్సి వస్తోంది. మహిళలు ... Continue the article for another 4000 characters max:","answer":"మరింత క్లిష్టమైన పరిస్థితులు ఎదుర్కొంటున్నారు.పుర్ఖూ శిబిరంలో కనీస సదుపాయాలు లేక కశ్మీరీ పండిట్లు తీవ్ర ఇబ్బందులు ఎదుర్కొంటున్నారు\\"ఎలాంటి పరిస్థితుల్లో మేం ఉంటున్నామో మీరే చూడండి. ఇక్కడ పాములు, తేళ్లు తిరుగుతుంటాయి. మాకు చిన్న పిల్లలున్నారు. ఇక్కడ మరుగుదొడ్డి సదుపాయం లేదు. మాకు సాయం  చేయమని కనిపించిన ప్రతి మంత్రినీ అడిగాం. అయినా, ఎలాంటి ప్రయోజనం లేదు\\" అని పుర్ఖూ శిబిరంలో తలదాచుకుంటున్న నీరూ చెప్పారు. \\"20 ఏళ్లుగా జమ్మూలోనే ఉంటున్నాను. మొదట్లో ఓ కశ్మీరీ పండిట్ ఇంట్లో అద్దెకు ఉండేవాళ్లం. కానీ, నేను గర్భవతిగా ఉన్న సమయంలో ఆ ఇంటి యజమాని భార్య నన్ను బయటకు గెంటేసింది. దాంతో ఇక్కడికి వచ్చాం. అప్పుడు మా పరిస్థితి  ఎలా ఉంటుందో మీరు ఊహించలేరు\\" అని శారదా దేవి ఆవేదన వ్యక్తం చేశారు.సరైన పారిశుద్ధ్య ఏర్పాట్లు లేవునాటి హింస తర్వాత మొత్తం 40 వేల మంది కశ్మీరీ పండితులు లోయ నుంచి జమ్మూకి వచ్చారు. అయితే, వారిలో 20 వేల మంది ప్రభుత్వ ఉద్యోగులు. వారి కుటుంబాలకు ప్రభుత్వం తగిన వసతి కల్పించింది. మిగిలిన 20 వేల మందిని పునరావాస శిబిరాలకు తరలించారు. అయితే, వారిలో కేవలం 5,428 కుటుంబాలకు మాత్రమే పక్కా ఇళ్లు నిర్మించి ఇచ్చింది ప్రభుత్వం. మిగిలిన వారిలో కొంతమంది ఇప్పటికీ తాత్కాలిక శిబిరాల్లోనే ఉంటుండగా, మరికొంత మంది అద్దె ఇళ్లలో నివసిస్తున్నారు. గడచిన మూడు దశాబ్దాల్లో ఎంతో మంది కశ్మీరీ పండితులు తిరిగి లోయ ప్రాంతంలోని తమ స్వస్థలాలకు వెళ్లేందుకు ప్రయత్నించారు. చాలా మంది కశ్మీర్ లోయలోని ప్రజలతో మళ్లీ సంబంధాలు నెలకొల్పుకునేందుకు ప్రయత్నించారు.\\"మేము ఈ 30 ఏళ్లలో కశ్మీర్‌లోని ముస్లిం సోదరులతో తెగిపోయిన సంబంధాలను మెరుగుపర్చుకునే ప్రయత్నం చేశాం. ఎప్పటికైనా అక్కడికి తిరిగివెళ్లాలని ఆశించాం. 370 అధికరణాన్ని రద్దు చేయడంతో ఈ 30 ఏళ్ల ప్రయత్నాలపై నీళ్లు కుమ్మరించినట్టయ్యింది. వాళ్లతో సంబంధాలు తెగిపోయాయి. మరోసారి వాళ్లూ, మేం శత్రువులమయ్యాం\\" అని కశ్మీరీ పండిట్ కొలిన్ చంద్రపురి అన్నారు. ఆలయంలో ప్రార్థన చేస్తున్న మహిళశిథిలావస్థకు చేరిన పుర్ఖూ క్యాంప్‌లో ఎవరిని పలకరించినా విషాద గాథలే వినిపిస్తున్నాయి.    \\"మాకంటూ ఏమీ లేదు. ఇల్లు కూడా లేదు. రేపు ఎవరికైనా మా గురించి చెప్పాలంటే ఏం చెప్పగలం? ఇలాంటి పరిస్థితుల్లో మాకు ఎవరు పిల్లనిస్తారు? బయట 40 డిగ్రీల సెంటీగ్రేడ్ ఉష్ణోగ్రతలుంటే... ఈ షెడ్డు లోపల 50 డిగ్రీలుంటోంది. "},{"question":"குற்றாலக் குறிஞ்சி (வரலாற்று நாவல்) எனும் நூலை இயற்றியவர்?        \\t","answer":"குற்றாலக் குறிஞ்சி (வரலாற்று நாவல்) எனும் நூலை இயற்றியவர் கோவி. மணிசேகரன்.1992 ஆம் ஆண்டின் சாதித்ய அகாதமி விருது பெற்ற ஓர் அபூர்வ இசையிலக்கியப் புதினம். அபூர்வமாகக் காணப்படும் குறிஞ்சியைப்போல, இந்நாவலும் தமிழுக்குக் கிடைத்த அரிய பொக்கிஷம் என்றே சொல்லலாம்.குறிஞ்சி என்ற ராகத்தின் பெயரையே தன் பெயராகக்கொண்டு, தாழ்ந்த குலத்தில் பிறந்துவிட்ட பெண். அவளின் சீலம், ஞானம், ‘தமிழ்ப் பாட்டையே பாடுவேன்’ என்கிற வீரம், ‘மக்களுக்காக மக்கள் மத்தியில் மட்டுமே பாடுவேன்; சமஸ்தானங்களை, ஜமீன்களை, கலெக்டர்களை, வெள்ளைக்காரத் துரைகளை மதியேன்; அவர்களுக்காகப் பாடேன்’ என்ற தியாகம்; இவையே குறிஞ்சியின் ஆரோகணம், அவரோகணம், ஆலாபனை எல்லாம். இதில் வரும் ஞானசுந்தரம், ராஜகாந்தி, முத்துசாமி தீட்சிதர், ஆனைய்யா, நெல்சன் துரை, அபிராமபட்டர், தியாகய்யர், கோபாலகிருஷ்ண பாரதியார், சரபோஜி மன்னர் எல்லாம் பிசிரில்லாத பக்க வாத்திய பாத்திரங்கள்.நாவலின் ஒவ்வோர் அத்தியாயமும் ஓர் ராகத்தின் பெயரால் அமைந்திருக்கிறது. தாள – லயம் – பிறழாத – சுருதி பிசகாத சுத்தமான சங்கீத நாவலாக படைத்து முத்திரை பதித்திருக்கிறார், இலக்கிய சாம்ராட் கோவி.மணிசேகரன்."},{"question":"روش کاشت درخت گردو به چه شکل است؟","answer":"درختان گردو در نهالستان به صورت ریشه برهنه در زمان خواب در خرداد و تیر کاشته می‌شوند. یک سیستم ریشه فیبری خوب برای رشد خوب مطلوب است. مشخص شده‌است که استفاده از کود حاوی فسفر قبل از کاشت مفید است. برای هر درخت یک چاله بزرگ و سخاوتمندانه حفر می‌شود و ریشه درختان قبل از کاشت به خوبی پوشانده می‌شود تا از خشک شدن جلوگیری شود. در مواردی که احتمال بیماری گال تاج وجود دارد، درختان باید قبل از کاشت با تلقیح ضد گال آماده‌سازی شوند. درخت را در چاله قرار می‌دهند، ریشه‌ها را کوتاه می‌کنند، در حین کاشت، خاک را در اطراف ریشه محکم می‌کنند و درخت را آبیاری می‌کنند."},{"question":"س281- كم يستغرق زمن مباراة كرة القدم ؟","answer":"ج281- ساعة ونصف"},{"question":"Adikao ho amin'ny teny malagasy ny fanambarana amin'ny teny anglisy manaraka: \\"Have a nice journey.\\"","answer":"Toy izao ny fanambarana amin'ny teny malagasy: \\"Mirary tontolo andro mafinaritra.\\""},{"question":"What are the seasons in isiXhosa?","answer":"Autumn - eKwindlaWinter - uBusikaSpring - iNtlako hlaza/iNtwasahloboSummer - iHlobo"},{"question":"SQL म्हणजे काय? SQL समजावून सांगा.","answer":"SQL म्हणजे स्ट्रक्चर्ड क्वेरी लँग्वेज, आणि ही एक डोमेन-विशिष्ट प्रोग्रामिंग भाषा आहे जी रिलेशनल डेटाबेसेस व्यवस्थापित करण्यासाठी आणि हाताळण्यासाठी वापरली जाते. रिलेशनल डेटाबेस हे माहितीच्या विविध भागांचे प्रतिनिधित्व करण्यासाठी पंक्ती आणि स्तंभांसह सारण्यांचा वापर करून, संरचित पद्धतीने डेटा संग्रहित आणि व्यवस्थापित करण्याचा एक मार्ग आहे.एसक्यूएल हे वापरकर्ता आणि डेटाबेसमधील पूल म्हणून काम करते, वापरकर्त्यांना डेटाबेससह विविध मार्गांनी संवाद साधण्याची परवानगी देते, यासह:डेटा पुनर्प्राप्ती: SQL वापरकर्त्यांना क्वेरी लिहून डेटाबेसमधून विशिष्ट डेटा पुनर्प्राप्त करण्यास सक्षम करते. क्वेरी ही विधाने आहेत जी तुम्हाला कोणता डेटा पुनर्प्राप्त करायचा आहे याचे वर्णन करतात.डेटा मॅनिप्युलेशन: डेटाबेसमधील डेटा सुधारण्यासाठी SQL चा वापर केला जाऊ शकतो. तुम्ही खालीलप्रमाणे विधाने वापरून रेकॉर्ड जोडू, अपडेट करू किंवा हटवू शकता:INSERT INTO: टेबलमध्ये नवीन रेकॉर्ड जोडते.अद्यतन: विद्यमान रेकॉर्ड सुधारित करते.DELETE FROM: टेबलमधून रेकॉर्ड काढून टाकते.डेटा व्याख्या: SQL वापरकर्त्यांना टेबल तयार करणे आणि बदलणे, टेबलांमधील संबंध परिभाषित करणे आणि डेटावरील मर्यादा सेट करणे यासह डेटाबेसची रचना परिभाषित करण्यास अनुमती देते.डेटा व्यवस्थापन: SQL डेटाबेस ऑब्जेक्ट्स व्यवस्थापित करण्यासाठी वैशिष्ट्ये प्रदान करते, जसे की क्वेरी कार्यप्रदर्शन सुधारण्यासाठी अनुक्रमणिका तयार करणे, प्रवेश नियंत्रित करण्यासाठी परवानग्या सेट करणे आणि अंतर्निहित डेटामध्ये बदल न करता डेटाचे आभासी प्रतिनिधित्व प्रदान करणारे दृश्ये तयार करणे.SQL विविध डेटाबेस व्यवस्थापन प्रणाली (DBMS) द्वारे वापरले जाते, जसे की MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle डेटाबेस, Microsoft SQL Server, आणि SQLite. या प्रणालींमधील वाक्यरचना आणि वैशिष्ट्यांमध्ये काही फरक असताना, SQL ची मुख्य तत्त्वे सर्व प्लॅटफॉर्मवर सुसंगत राहतात."},{"question":" Em que ano os navegadores portugueses chegaram ao Brasil pela primeira vez?","answer":"Abril de 1500."},{"question":"س270- متى استقلت الكويت ؟","answer":"ج270- عام 1961"},{"question":"Quốc kỳ Brunei có một dòng chữ Arab, đúng hay sai?","answer":"Quốc kỳ Brunei có một dòng chữ Arab màu vàng, có thể dịch là \\"Luôn phục vụ dưới sự dẫn đường của Thượng đế\\".Quốc kỳ Brunei được thông qua vào ngày 29/9/1959 khi quốc gia này trở thành một nước được Anh bảo hộ, sau đó được giữ lại khi Brunei giành độc lập vào 1/1/1984.Quốc kỳ có nền màu vàng - màu của hoàng gia và tượng trưng cho vương quốc Hồi giáo, cùng hai dài màu trắng, đen, tượng trưng cho hai bộ trưởng của Brunei. Quốc huy màu đỏ được đặt chính giữa, dòng chữ Arab nằm trên quốc huy."},{"question":"iPhone 11 kac senesinde çıktı?","answer":"Şimdi gelelim 2023 yılında iPhone 11 alınır mı sorusunun yanıtına. Apple'ın bu modeli 2019 yılının Eylül ayında tanıtıldı ve o yılın sonlarına doğru piyasaya sürüldü. Halen ülkemizde sıfır olarak bu telefon modellerini bulmak mümkün olduğu gibi ikinci elini de bulabiliyorsunuz."},{"question":"「♪夏がくーれば思い出すー」さてこの曲の１番の歌詞の中で咲いている花は何？","answer":"水芭蕉の花です。"},{"question":"Üniversite için online kayıt yeterli mi?","answer":"Elektronik sınavla veya özel yetenek sınavlarıyla alım yapan bölümler ve ikinci öğretim, uzaktan öğretim gibi programlarda e-kayıt tek başına kabul edilmemektedir. Bunlar için okula giderek bizzat kayıt yapmanız gerekmektedir."},{"question":"\\"Fomban-drazana manan-danja any Etazonia ny basikety any amin'ny oniversite, miaraka amin'ny fifaninanana mampientam-po toa ny March Madness. Mifaninana hahazo ny fiadiana ny ho tompondaka nasionaly ny ekipan’ny kolejy, ka niteraka fientanentanana teo amin’ireo mpianatra sy mpankafy. Mpilalao basikety manana talenta maro no mandeha amin'ny asa matihanina ao amin'ny NBA.\\". Inona ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io?","answer":"Ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io dia ny basikety."},{"question":"فيمن أنزلت الهمزة ؟","answer":"أمية بن خلف ."},{"question":"Ndàx mbind mii jub na?Ñooña ñoo di ña jaay njub jënde ci réer, seen njaay mooma amul tono. Te it gindikuwuñu.","answer":"Déedet; jubul cocc ba coset. Mbeqi ma a ngii:Ñooña ñoo di ña jaay njub jënde ci réer, séen njaay mooma àmul tono. Te ìt gindikuwu ñu."},{"question":"Tamin'ny andron'ny Ntaolo Malagasy, iza no nanapaka sy nandidy teo amin'ny tanàna?","answer":"Ny zokiolona no nanapaka sy nandidy teo amin'ny tanàna tamin'ny andron'ny Ntaolo Malagasy."},{"question":"Apa yang dimaksud dengan \\"komplikasi\\" dalam struktur teks drama?Jawaban:","answer":"Komplikasi, juga disebut bagian tengah cerita, adalah bagian struktur teks drama di mana konflik mulai tercipta. Pada bagian ini, tokoh utama akan menemukan berbagai kendala antara dirinya dengan tujuan atau keinginannya. Berbagai kesalahpahaman yang sering dialami oleh para tokoh, dalam perjuangan melawan rintangan tersebut, terjadi pada bagian ini. "},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"beralih akal\\"? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud berubah fikiran. Contoh ayat: Dia beralih akal dan tidak jadi berpindah ke Sarawak."},{"question":"Completa la siguiente frase: Edward Balliol es claramente una figura importante; pero es difícil decidir si perseguía sus ambiciones o fue utilizado por otros. No había luchado en la primera guerra, y es dudoso que tuviera alguna experiencia militar antes de su llegada a Escocia en 1332. El impulsor de estas acciones fue Henry Beaumont, el principal conspirador de los desheredados. Fue él el que formó el partido de los desheredados tras el periodo de paz tras Northampton: animó a Balliol, con la autorización de Eduardo III, viajar a Inglaterra. Era un guerrero experimentado, que había estado presente en Bannockburn y la Batalla de Boroughbridge y casi seguro que fue el arquitecto de la victoria de Balliol en Dupplin Moor, donde luchó; y que hubiera asesorado a Eduardo III en la Batalla de Halidon Hill, anticipo del posterior triunfo... ","answer":"En Crécy Beaumont, además, proporcionó apoyo financiero para que Balliol pudiera entrar en Escocia a la cabeza de un ejército. Pero era leal sobre todo a sí mismo y luego a Eduardo III, y Balliol era para él un medio para conseguir un fin."},{"question":" Sheeg Wadama Ey Ku Yaalaan Harta Ugu Weyn Ee Loo-Yaqaano Like Victoria ?","answer":" Waxay Kala Yihiin1- Kenya,2- Uganda,3- Tanzania."},{"question":"السؤال: شكون هو النبي اللي بغاو القوم د ياولو يعذبوه بالعافيه فكانت عليه بردا وسلامه ؟","answer":"الإجابة: إبراهيم عليه السلام"},{"question":"Wọn ji ọlọpaa gbe ni Aba Tuntun, n’Ijẹbu-Igbo, wọn tun ba mọto wọn jẹ","answer":"Titi di asiko ti a n ko iroyin yii jọ ni ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ṣi n wa ọlọpaa kan, Emmanuel Gene, ti awọn janduku kan ji gbe niluu Aba Tuntun, n’Ijẹbu-Igbo, ipinlẹ Ogun.Ṣaaju asiko yii ni baalẹ ilu naa ti kọwe ẹsun si ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa pe awọn kan ninu ilu naa ni awọn nnkan ija oloro lọwọ, eyi ti wọn fi n ṣiṣẹ ibi lagbegbe naa.ALAROYE gbọ pe ọlọpaa mẹẹẹdogun atawọn ẹṣọ fijilante bii marundinlogoji lawọn ọlọpaa ko lọ sinu ilu naa l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, to kọja yii.Ọkan lara awọn eeyan ilu naa to ba awọn oniroyin sọrọ sọ pe ọpọlọpọ ibọn ni wọn ba lọwọ awọn janduku tọwọ ọlọpaa tẹ ọhun. Ibọn oyinbo mẹfa, ibọn ibilẹ mẹrindinlogun ati ọta ibọn bii mẹẹdogun.Wọn ni lojiji ni wahala bẹ silẹ niluu Aba Tuntun, lasiko ti awọn ọlọpaa n mura lati kuro ninu ilu naa lẹyin tọwọ ti tẹ awọn eeyan kan pẹlu ohun ija oloro lọwọ. Awọn kan ninu ilu naa ni wọn sọ pe wọn kọ lu wọn, ti wọn bẹrẹ si i yinbọn, ninu eyi ti DPO, iyẹn ọga ọlọpaa to ko wọn wa atawọn ọlọpaa mi-in ti fara pa.Ninu iṣẹlẹ ọhun ni wọn ti ji ọlọpaa marun-un atawọn fijilante mẹta gbe, tawọn yooku si fẹsẹ fẹ ẹ.Ibọn AK-47, atawọn ohun ija mi-in bii afẹfẹ tajutaju ni wọn ri gba lọwọ awọn ọlọpaa ti wọn ji gbe yii.Ninu iwadii wa ni agbẹnusọ fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi, ti sọ pe lojuẹsẹ naa ni ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ti gbe ikọ ẹ dide lati lọọ gba awọn ọlọpaa ti wọn ji gbe ọhun silẹ, ninu eyi ti wọn ti ri mẹrin ninu wọn gba pada atawọn fijilante mẹta.  O ni awọn ṣi n wa Kọnsitebu Emmanuel Gene, to wa laahamọ awọn ajinigbe ọhun.Siwaju si i, a gbọ pe ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ti tu awọn eeyan ti ọwọ tẹ lasiko laaṣigbo ọhun silẹ, bo tilẹ jẹ meji ninu mọto ọlọpaa ni awọn araalu ọhun bajẹ lasiko rogbodiyan ọhun.Abimbola Oyeyemi  sọ pe afuarsi mẹta lo ti wa lọdọ awọn ọlọpaa bayii, nibi ti wọn ti n ran wọn lọwọ lori agbofinro ti awọn ṣi n wa."},{"question":"Berikan jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Burung yang tak boleh terbang, suka sejuk, boleh berenang.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah penguin. "},{"question":"Wybierz prawidłową odpowiedź.Jaki zespół zdobył Puchar Świata w Rugby Union w 2019. roku?A) WaliaB) Nowa ZelandiaC) Południowa AfrykaD) Anglia","answer":"Poprawna odpowiedź to C) Południowa Afryka."},{"question":"வினா:தீமையான செயல் புரிபவர்கள் மரண தருவாயில் பாவ மன்னிப்பு கோருவது குறித்து இறைவன் கூறுவது என்ன?","answer":" விடை:      ‘இன்னும் எவர்கள் தீவினைகளைத் (தொடர்ந்து) செய்து கொண்டேயிருந்து, முடிவில் அவர்களை மரணம் நெருங்கிய போது நிச்சயமாக இப்பொழுது நான்  மன்னிப்புத் தேடுகிறேன் என்று கூறுகின்றார்களோ அவர்களுக்கும் எவர் காஃபிர்களாகவே  மரிக்கிறார்களோ அவர்களுக்கும் பாவமன்னிப்பு இல்லை இத்தகையோருக்குத் துன்பம்  கொடுக்கும் வேதனையையே நாம் சித்தப்படுத்தி வைத்துள்ளோம்.                                                 (உலகப் பொதுமறை அல்-குர்ஆன் 4:18 )"},{"question":"Atsakykite į šį klausimą: Kai kurios įmonės siūlo klientams pirkti prekes, naudodamos jų pirštų atspaudus kaip identifikacinį dokumentą. Kuris iš toliau nurodytų veiksnių labiausiai naudingas vartotojams, kurie naudojasi šia nauja technologija? Galimi pasirinkimai: A). sumažėja produkto kaina. B) privataus asmens informacijos apsauga. C) gebėjimas stebėti klientų pageidavimus. D) lėšos būtų įskaitytos nedelsiant. Atsakymas:","answer":" B) privataus asmens informacijos apsauga"},{"question":"Bada Tatsuniyar Gizo da Ƙoƙi da Kantu.","answer":"Gata nan gata nanaku. Ta zo mu ji ta.Wata rana ce dai, wata rana ce dai, da Gizo da Ƙoƙi da Kantu, suka shirya suka tafi daji farauta. A kan hanyar su ta tafiya, sai suka ci karo da ruwa. Da suka shiga ruwan nan don su tsallake shi, sai Kantu ya fara marmashewa, sai Gizo ya ce da shi, kai Kantu, idan ka ci gaba da marmashewa zan cinye ka. Shi ke nan, sai Kantu ya daure, suka ci gaba da tafiya. Can sun shiga tsakiyar ruwa, sai Kantu ya sake marmashewa, sai Gizo ya juyo ya cinye shi.Bayan Gizo da Ƙoƙi sun tsallake ruwa, sai Gizo ya ɗaura lilo a gindin wata bishiya yana ta fillawa/hillawa. Can yana cikin lilo yana jin daɗi, sai ya hango wani damo, sai ya bi shi da gudu ya kama damon nan, ya yanka, ya gasa, ya hana ƙoƙi ko hanji.Da Gizo ya koma ya hau lilonsa yana ta hillo, can sai ya ji cikinsa ya fara ƙugi, sai ya ce da Ƙoƙi cikinsa yana ciwo. Saboda haka sai Ƙoƙi ta goya shi dan ta kai shi gurin mai magani.Ƙoƙi tana cikin tafiya sai ta zo gindin wata babbar bishiya, tana zuwa gindin wannan bishiya sai ta ji wata tsuntsuwa tana cewa:Tsuntsuwa:          Ke Ƙoƙi ina za ki?Ƙoƙi:                   Za ni gurin maganar nan.Tsuntsuwa:          In kin je ki ce Gizo ya ci damo ba zai yi rai ba.Shike nan sai Ƙoƙi ta ci gaba da tafiyarta. Tana nan tana ta tafiya, sai ta sake isowa gidin wata bishiyar, sai ta sake jin muryar tsuntsuwar nan tana cewa: Tsuntsuwa:          Ke Ƙoƙi ina za ki?Ƙoƙi:                   Za ni gurin maganar nan.Tsuntsuwa:          In kin je ki ce Gizo ya ci damo ba zai yi rai ba.Da Ƙoƙi ta ji haka sai ta ce da Gizo, kana dai ji an ce ba za ka rayu ba ko? Gizo ya yi shiru ya kasa cewa komai. Ƙoƙi kuma ta ci gaba da tafiya. Tana cikin tafiya ta sake isa gindin wata bishiyar, sai ta sake jin muryar tsuntsuwar nan tana cewa:Tsuntsuwa:          Ke Ƙoƙi ina za ki?Ƙoƙi:                   Za ni gurin maganar nan.Tsuntsuwa:          In kin je ki ce Gizo ya ci damo ba zai yi rai ba.Ai kuwa kafin tsuntsuwar nan ta gama rufe bakinta Gizo ya tsuge da zawo. Da Ƙoƙi ta ga haka, sai ta sauke shi daga bayanta, ta zuba masa ido tana kallon abin mamaki. Ba jimawa sai damo ya ce da Gizo, “ta ina zan fito?” Sai gizo ya ce da shi, “fito ta hammata”. Sai damo ya ce, “in fito ta hammata warin hammata ya dame ni. Ta ina zan fito?” Sai Gizo ya ce, “fito ta ciki”. Sai damo ya ce, “in fito ta ciki hanji ya tare ni. Ta in azan fito?” Sai Gizo ya ce, “fito ta, taka shi”. Sai damo ya ce, “in je kashi ya taɓa ni. Ta in azan fito?” Sai Gizo ya ce fito ta hammata. Shike nan sai damo ya fito ta hammatar Gizo. Yana fitowa sai Gizo ya mutu.Tunƙurunƙus, badan Gizo ba da na yi ƙarya."},{"question":"ਕੰਮ ਦੇ ਆਧਾਰ ‘ਤੇ ਜਨਸੰਖਿਆ ਦਾ ਕਾਮਿਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਅਕਾਮਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਵਰਗਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਵੰਡਣ ਦਾ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਲੋਕ ਗਿਣਤੀ ਵਿਚ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਵਾਰ ਕਿਸ ਸਾਲ ਵਿਚ ਆਇਆ ?","answer":"ਕੰਮ ਦੇ ਆਧਾਰ ‘ਤੇ ਜਨਸੰਖਿਆ ਦਾ ਕਾਮਿਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਅਕਾਮਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਵੰਡਣ ਦਾ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਵਾਰ 1961 ਦੀ ਗਣਨਾ ਦੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਆਇਆ।"},{"question":"Please give me the Chapter 1 of MOTHER'S CURSE!","answer":"MOTHER'S CURSEChapter 1Izunna looked bewildered and disappointed as he trekked home. His slippers, which he had been managing for months, were cut. He picked them up and mumbled to himself.He cleaned the balls of sweat on his forehead with his palm and continued walking under the hot sun.How did it go, Izu? His wife askedGet me water first. I'm thirsty,he instructed, resting his back on the floor.His wife, Cassandra, ran inside and got a cup of water for him. She sat beside him, rubbing his legs with her palm.How did it go? Tell me... Cassandra insistedIt didn't go well at all. I'm just exhausted, like I don't even know if I am a curse. Izu said, almost crying.I've told you to come so as to go see my spiritual father, but you won't listen until I leave this house for you. I've been suffering with you for the past eight years, thinking that things will get better, not knowing that things are getting worse each blessed day. Can't you listen to me for once? Cassandra shouted, clapping her hands.Izu stared at her like someone who had seen a ghost. He sighed and drank the remaining water left in the cup.Why are you staring at me like that? Asked CassandraI never knew you'd be this shameless; why are you shouting? So that everybody will know that you want to take me to your so-called spiritual father, Inukwa, Izu replied, standing to his feet.Hei chimooo,Izu I've been keeping quiet all these while nah, oya, give me money for dinner because your children will soon be back from school, not even a good school...Cassandra cut my two hands and took them to Ogbefi. You can use the money to prepare dinner. Izu saidI'm just regretting it, Izu. Had I known? Cassandra burst out crying.I can't stop laughing. Why do you want to paint me black, Cassy? Let's go inside, please.He moved closer to her,pecked her pretty face, and took her inside.When will all this end? She asked himSoon, Cassy,what do you intend to cook this evening?"},{"question":"Qual é o livro mais editado e traduzido da história, perdendo apenas para a Bíblia?","answer":"Dom Quixote."},{"question":"நியூட்டனின் இயக்க விதிகளுக்கு பொதுவாக கேட்கப்படும் கேள்விகளை பட்டியலிடுங்கள்.","answer":"நியூட்டனின் இயக்க விதிகள் தொடர்பான மிகவும் பொதுவாகக் கேட்கப்படும் கேள்விகள் கீழே உள்ளன:1) நியூட்டனின் முதல் விதி வெளிப்புற சக்திகள் இல்லாத நிலையில் பொருட்களின் இயக்கத்தை எவ்வாறு விளக்குகிறது?2) நியூட்டனின் முதல் விதியின்படி ஒரு பொருள் சமநிலையான சக்திகளை அனுபவிக்கும் காட்சிகளின் உதாரணங்களை வழங்க முடியுமா?3) நியூட்டனின் முதல் விதியுடன் மந்தநிலை எவ்வாறு தொடர்புடையது என்பதை விளக்கி உதாரணங்களை வழங்கவும்.4) நியூட்டனின் இரண்டாவது விதியின்படி, ஒரு பொருளின் நிறை எவ்வாறு வெளிப்புற சக்திகளுக்கு அதன் எதிர்வினையை பாதிக்கிறது?5) நியூட்டனின் விதிகளின் பின்னணியில் நிறை மற்றும் எடையை ஒப்பிட்டுப் பார்க்க முடியுமா?6) ஒரு பொருள் நிகர விசையை அனுபவிக்கும் ஆனால் முடுக்கிவிடாத சூழ்நிலையை விவரிக்கவும்.7) எந்த சூழ்நிலைகளில் F = ma என்ற சமன்பாட்டைப் பயன்படுத்துவது பொருத்தமானது, மேலும் ஒவ்வொரு மாறிகளும் எதைக் குறிக்கின்றன?8) நியூட்டனின் மூன்றாவது விதியின்படி செயல் மற்றும் எதிர்வினை சக்திகள் எவ்வாறு செயல்படுகின்றன?9) அன்றாட வாழ்வில் நியூட்டனின் மூன்றாவது விதியை விளக்கும் உதாரணங்களை வழங்கவும்.10) சமநிலை விசைகளில் காணப்படுவது போல், இயக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தாமல் சக்திகள் ஏன் ஒன்றையொன்று ரத்து செய்யலாம் என்பதை விளக்குங்கள்.11) நிகர விசையின் கருத்து நேர்கோட்டு மற்றும் வட்ட இயக்கத்திற்கு எவ்வாறு பொருந்தும்?12) நியூட்டனின் விதிகள் மற்றும் இயக்கத்தில் அதன் தாக்கம் தொடர்பாக உராய்வு பங்கு பற்றி விவாதிக்கவும்.13) ஒரு கயிறு அல்லது சரத்தில் உள்ள பதற்றம் மற்றும் அது நியூட்டனின் விதிகளுடன் எவ்வாறு தொடர்புடையது என்பதை விளக்க முடியுமா?14) இயக்கத்தை தீர்மானிப்பதில் காற்று எதிர்ப்பு ஒரு குறிப்பிடத்தக்க காரணியாக இருக்கும் சூழ்நிலைகளை விவரிக்கவும்.15) புவியீர்ப்பு விசை பூமியில் உள்ள பொருட்களை எவ்வாறு பாதிக்கிறது, அது நியூட்டனின் விதிகளுடன் எவ்வாறு தொடர்புடையது?16) நிலையான மற்றும் இயக்க உராய்வுக்கு இடையிலான வேறுபாட்டை விளக்கவும், ஒவ்வொன்றின் உதாரணங்களையும் வழங்கவும்.17) காலப்போக்கில் சக்தியின் பயன்பாடு உந்துவிசை மற்றும் உந்தத்தின் கருத்துடன் எவ்வாறு தொடர்புடையது என்பதைப் பற்றி விவாதிக்கவும்.18) முனைய வேகம் மற்றும் அது நியூட்டனின் விதிகளுடன் எவ்வாறு இணைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது என்பதை விளக்க முடியுமா?19) சூரியனைச் சுற்றும் கோள்கள் போன்ற வான உடல்களின் இயக்கத்திற்கு நியூட்டனின் விதிகள் எவ்வாறு பொருந்தும்?20) பொறியியல் மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்பத்தில் நியூட்டனின் சட்டங்களின் நடைமுறை பயன்பாடுகளைப் பற்றி விவாதிக்கவும்.இந்தக் கேள்விகள் நியூட்டனின் இயக்க விதிகளின் பல்வேறு அம்சங்களை உள்ளடக்கி, தலைப்பின் விரிவான கண்ணோட்டத்தை வழங்குகிறது."},{"question":"Shin batun me ake magana a wannan mai zuwa? \\"Simon Lalong ya yi alkawarin kawo sauyi a jihar Filato\\". (a) Lafiya(b) Afirka(c) Najeriya(d) Siyasa(e) Duniya","answer":"Jumlar : \\"Simon Lalong ya yi alkawarin kawo sauyi a jihar Filato\\" na batu ne a kan siyasa."},{"question":"Heeso qoraal ah Farxiyo Fiska iyo Faarax Murtiile.Han iyo Dookh.","answer":"Hibooy hodaalayeeyhilaac muuqda tahoohabkii hodan baa tahoohilaac quruxda uga egxishoodka huwanehagoogta asluubta xiranhooyadii so korisaybaahufnana lagu dheehayoohorjooga iyo heybadanahidaha diintena iyohiba iyo qurux ba u dheerhablaha somaliyeedhawenka aduunka jirahormuudkoodi bey noqdeenhibana qurux ba u dheerninkii helaa cawa lehanigu ku hanweyniyoohadaan kumanaan habeenhaasaawaha ila wadoohortana aanaan is araghibooy hadalkaga wacanmarnaba kama haabayeeheybow hoodaale wiilhalyeey geesi ba tahehogaan xidhanayay iyogo,aan huwanayay baa tahelabada hooyadu dhasheehoraad wada nuugtay baaisaga hilib dhawnahoohadh iyo geed beynu neehido iyo dhaqan beynu nahehal iyo nirig beynu nahehan iyo dookh beynu nahesinaba uma kala harneeanigu kuu han weyniyohadaad kumanaan habeenmudana aan is aragogow hadalkaga wacanheybow kama haadayee"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'ingat ranting yang akan melenting, dahan yang akan mencucuk, duri yang akan mengait'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud ketika membuat sesuatu pekerjaan hendaklah sentiasa berhati-hati terhadap segala bahaya dan rintangan"},{"question":"Menene yarinyar da aka haifa bayan maza biyu ko fiye da ake magana a kai a kasar Hausa?","answer":"Kande ake kiranta."},{"question":"Chifukwa chiyani kulimbana ndi malungo kukuvuta ku Malawi?","answer":"Kugawidwa kwa malungo, ndi zomwe zimafalisa malungo ndi kukula kwa matenda ndi kulemetsa kwa matenda m'Malawi sizinadziwike bwino, monga momwe zimakhalira m'mayiko ambiri omwe akudwala malungo."},{"question":"Вопрос: какой домен имеет больше индивидов, чем все другие домены вместе взятые? Ответ:","answer":"Домен верхнего уровня, который имеет больше индивидуальных доменов, чем все остальные домены вместе взятые, - это домен \\".com\\" (commercial). Домен \\".com\\" является одним из самых популярных и широко используемых доменов в Интернете и обычно используется для коммерческих веб-сайтов."},{"question":"Sempurnakan penggalan teks di bawah ini sehingga menjadi artikel yang utuh dan koheren.Penggalan artikel:Sebuah koridor udara adalah suatu wilayah udara khusus tempat sebuah pesawat terbang harus tetap berada di sana selama perhentiannya melintasi daerah tertentu. Koridor udara diberlakukan berdasarkan persyaratan militer atau diplomatik. Selama Blokade Berlin ...Jawaban:","answer":"Teks utuh dengan kalimat lanjutan dari penggalan artikel di atas adalah:Sebuah koridor udara adalah suatu wilayah udara khusus tempat sebuah pesawat terbang harus tetap berada di sana selama perhentiannya melintasi daerah tertentu. Koridor udara diberlakukan berdasarkan persyaratan militer atau diplomatik. Selama Blokade Berlin, misalnya, pilot-pilot yang terbang melintasi wilayah udara Jerman yang diawasi Soviet diminta mempertahankan posisi tertentu di dalam koridor udara yang ditetapkan oleh komandan bertugas dalam penyaluran udara. Penerbangan selanjutnya, militer dan sipil, antara Jerman Barat dan Berlin selama Perang Dingin diminta tetap berada pada koridor khusus atau jika tidak, risikonya adalah ditembak jatuh."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" akoholahy mikokokoko akohovavy, ................................... \\" ","answer":"\\"  akoholahy mikokokoko akohovavy,tsy hanina havoky fa voninahitra ifanomezana \\" "},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : ఒక బీకరులోని నీటిలో కోడిగుడ్డును వేయండి. మరొక బీకరులోని నీటికి కొంచెం ఎక్కువ మోతాదులో ఉప్పును కలిపి, ఇప్పుడు ఆ గుడ్డును ఈ నీటిలో వేయండి. మీ పరిశీలనలను నమోదు చేయండి.","answer":"ఒక బీకరు తీసుకొని దానిలో నీరు పోసి కోడిగుడ్డుని వేశాను. కోడిగుడ్డు నీటిలో మునిగిపోయింది. మరొక బీకరు తీసుకొని దానిలో ఉప్పు నీటిని తీసుకొని కోడిగుడ్డు వేశాను. ఆశ్చర్యంగా అది నీటిలో తేలడం గమనించాను. గుడ్డు రెండు బీకర్లలో ఒకే బరువు కలిగి ఉన్నప్పటికీ ఒక దాంట్లో మునిగి, రెండో దాంట్లో తేలటం ఆశ్చర్యంగా ఉంది. గుడ్డు నీటిలో తేలడానికి, నీటిలో కలిపిన ఉప్పు కారణమని భావిస్తున్నాను."},{"question":"Tohizo ity ohabolana ity: \\"Rafotsibe mangataka omby: raha mahazo, manan-karena indray andro_\\".","answer":"\\"Rafotsibe mangataka omby: raha mahazo, manan-karena indray andro; tsy mahazo, ny omby angaha fangataka?\\"."},{"question":"Namakan jenis cendawan yang boleh dimakan. ","answer":"Cendawan yang boleh dimakan termasuklah Cendawan Taugeh / Cendawan Tali, Cendawan Kukur, Cendawan Enokitake, Cendawan Tiram dan Cendawan Butang."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा--कामापुरता मामा","answer":"\\"कामापुरता मामा आणि ताकापुरती आजी\\" ह्याचा अर्थ आपले काम करून घेईपर्यंत गोड गोड बोलणे."},{"question":"هيٺين سوال جو جواب ڏيو. جيڪو گذريل  ڇنڇر رات لائيو تي ڳايو","answer":"ٻاراڻو گيمبينو"},{"question":"ශ්‍රීලංකාව වෙනුවෙන් එක්දින ජාත්‍යන්තර ක්‍රීඩාවල වැඩිම ලකුණු 200ට වැඩි සබඳතා වලට හිමිකම් කියන පිතිකරුවන් යුගලය කවුද?","answer":"උපුල් තරංග සහ ටී එම් ඩිල්ෂාන්"},{"question":"问：江苏的省会是哪个城市？","answer":"答：江苏省的省会城市是南京。"},{"question":"Iza no anaran'ilay mpitondra rallye frantsay malaza, tompondaka eran-tany sivy ary tompon'ny anaram-boninahitra WRC?","answer":"Ny anaran'ilay mpitondra rallye frantsay malaza, tompondaka eran-tany sivy ary tompon'ny anaram-boninahitra WRC dia Sébastien Loeb."},{"question":"පැයක කාලය  යන්නට තනි වචනයක් දෙන්න.","answer":"හෝරාව "},{"question":"14 صديءَ جي 98 هين سال ۾ ڪير اقتدار ۾ آيو؟ پوئين سوال کي نظر ۾ رکندي ، هڪ تناظر لکو جنهن ۾ جواب شامل آهي. اهو 1 - 20 جملا ٿي سگهي ٿو. پس منظر:","answer":"جيان وين ايمپائر کان تخت جي غصب ۾ (r. 1398 - 1402) ، يونگلي شهنشاهه کي ٻڌ ڌرمي راهب ياو گوانگشياؤ جي مدد ڪئي وئي ، ۽ هن جي پيءُ وانگر ، هانگوو شهنشاهه ، يونگلي شهنشاهه \\"بوذزم جي طرف سٺو موقف رکندڙ\\" هو ، روزابي دعويٰ ڪئي. 10 مارچ 1403 تي ، يونگلي شهنشاهه ڊشين شيڪپا ، 5 هين ڪرمپا لاما (1384-1415) کي پنهنجي درٻار ۾ دعوت ڏني ، جيتوڻيڪ چوٿين ڪرمپا هانگوو شهنشاهه جي دعوت کي رد ڪري ڇڏيو هو. 16 هين صديءَ ۾ هڪ تبتي ترجمي ۾ يونگل شهنشاهه جو خط محفوظ آهي ، جيڪو ايسوسيئيشن فار ايشين اسٽڊيز جو نوٽ آهي ته ڪرماپا جي طرف مهذب ۽ تعريف ڪندڙ آهي. دعوت نامي ۾ لکيل آهي،"},{"question":"विश्व अणुपरमाणुंचे बनले आहे हा सिध्दांत कोणी मांडला ?","answer":"विश्व अणुपरमाणुंचे बनले आहे हा सिध्दांत महर्षी कणाद ने मांडला."},{"question":"हिमालय क्षेत्रका गुरुङ घरहरूको परम्परागत वास्तुकला र वातावरणमा यसको अनुकूलनको वर्णन गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"गुरुङ घरहरूमा ढुङ्गाको पर्खाल, खरको छाना र कठोर पहाडी वातावरणमा अनुकूल पशुधन खोरहरू छन्।"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"belum beranak sudah berbesan\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud membahagi-bahagi keuntungan yang belum lagi di tangan."},{"question":"Wace kasa ce mafi girman tattalin arziki a Afirka?","answer":"Kasar da tafi kowacce kasa karfin tattalin arziki a Afrika itace Nigeria."},{"question":"சீர்மைகொள் வீடு சுவர்க்கம் நரகீறாஈர்மைகொள் தேவர் நடுவாமற் றெப்பொருட்கும்வேர்முதலாய் வித்தாய்ப் பரந்து தனி நின்றகார்முகில்போல் வண்ணன்என் கண்ணனைநான் கண்டேனே.மேலே உள்ள பாடலின் பொருளை எழுதுங்கள்","answer":"வீடு என்னும் சீர்மை, சுவர்க்கம் (இன்ப உலகம்), நரகம் (துன்ப உலகம்), தேவர் உலகம் (அன்பு கொண்டோர் உலகம்), மற்றுமுள்ள எல்லாப் பொருள்கள் ஆகிய அனைத்துக்கும் வேராகவும், முதலாகவும், வித்தாகவும், பரந்து நிற்பவன் என் கண்ணன். அவனை நான் கண்டேன் – என்கிறார், ஆழ்வார்."},{"question":"Wọn ti mu Jide, ọkan ninu awọn ogbologboo adigunjale to n yọ awọn eeyan Akurẹ lẹnu","answer":"Ọkan ninu awọn ogbologboo adigunjale to n yọ awọn eeyan ilu Akurẹ lẹnu lọwọ awọn ọlọpaa ti tẹ lọsẹ to kọja yii.Afurasi ọhun ti wọn porukọ rẹ ni Jide Adewale lọwọ tẹ lẹyin toun atawọn ẹgbẹ rẹ ninu iwa ọdaran tun lọọ ja ileepo nla kan  l’Akurẹ lole owo nla atawọn ẹru mi-in nnkan bii aago mẹfa idaji ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ to kọja lọhun-un.Ni kete ti wọn ti fi iṣẹlẹ ọhun to awọn ọlọpaa leti ni wọn ti n tọpasẹ awọn oniṣẹẹbi naa ti wọn si n sọ wọn lọwọ lẹsẹ titi tọwọ fi tẹ ọkan ninu wọn.Lati bii oṣu meji sẹyin lara o ti rọ okun mọ ti ko si tun rọ adiyẹ niluu Akurẹ, akọlu tawọn adigunjale n ṣe sawọn ileepo kan ti ilẹ ba ti n su lọ.Gbogbo ileepo ti ikọ awọn adigunjale naa n ṣabẹwo si ni wọn ti n ko wọn lẹru pẹlu obitibiti owo, ti wọn si tun n yinbọn pa gbogbo ọlọdẹ ti wọn ba ti laju ri.Ibẹru akọlu tawọn janduku naa n ṣe lo ṣokunfa bi ẹgbẹ awọn alagbata epo ṣe fohun ṣọkan lati maa ti lẹkun ileepo wọn laago meje alẹ."},{"question":"من أول من توفت من بنات الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم؟","answer":"السيدة رقية"},{"question":"नेपालमा दशैं पर्वमा लगाउने परम्परागत लुगाहरू के के हुन्?","answer":"दशैंमा लगाउने परम्परागत लुगामा पुरुषका लागि \\"दौरा सुरुवाल\\" र महिलाहरूको लागि \\"गुन्यो छोलो\\" समावेश छ।"},{"question":"கதை + என்ன – இதனைச் சேர்த்து எழுதக் கிடைக்கும் சொல் ……………………………கதைஎன்னகதையன்னகதையென்னகதயென்ன","answer":"விடை : கதை + என்ன – இதனைச் சேர்த்து எழுதக் கிடைக்கும் சொல் …………கதையென்ன"},{"question":"Escribe la continuación de este texto - La Operación de las Naciones Unidas en el Congo (ONUC) fue una fuerza de mantenimiento de la paz de las Naciones Unidas en la República del Congo (Leopoldville) que fue establecida en virtud de la Resolución 143 del Consejo de Seguridad de la ONU, aprobada el 14 de julio de 1960. La misión fue lanzada para ayudar a restaurar la estabilidad en el Congo después de que cayó en conflicto y desorden... ","answer":"Después de la independencia. ONUC fue la primera misión de mantenimiento de la paz de la ONU con un componente militar importante."},{"question":"次のタイトルに基づいて、最大500語の段落を書いてください： ロボットを使って5000km離れた場所で手術をする実験","answer":"愛知県の大学とシンガポールの大学の間で、手術を手伝うロボットを使った実験がありました。藤田医科大学の教授たちが、シンガポール国立大学でロボットを動かしました。そして5000km以上離れた藤田医科大学に置いた人工の胃からがんを取る手術を行いました。2つの場所は専用のインターネットでつながっています。教授たちはロボットの動き方の速さや、正しく動いているかをチェックしていました。手術を行った教授は「実験はうまくいきました。0.1秒ぐらい時間の差がありましたが、だんだん慣れて問題はありませんでした」と話しました。藤田医科大学は、離れた場所の手術を手伝って、医療の技術を高くすることに役に立ちたいと考えています。"},{"question":"શૂન્ય પાલનપુરીની 'કોઈની મદીલી નજર' ગઝલ લખો","answer":"“આપ મારી વફા નહીં સમજોઆંખ નિજના પડળ ના જોઈ શકે,દોષ છે ‘શૂન્ય’ સૌ સુકાનીનોનાવ પોતે વમળ ના જોઈ શકે.”કોઈની મદીલી નજર છે ને હું છું,આ ખુમારી ભરેલું જીગર છે ને હું છું.નથી ના ખુદાને, ખુદા પર ભરોસો,હવે નાવડી છે, ભવર છે ને હું છું.નડે છે અનાદીથી ચંચળતા મનની,આ વિરામ જીવન સફર છે ને હું છું.જનારા ગયા ને ગયું સર્વ સાથે,હવે ‘શૂન્ય’ વિરાન ઘર છે ને હું છું."},{"question":"جاوب على السؤال: وين مقاطعة كنتاكي؟","answer":"باتريك هنري"},{"question":"Суроо: Маалыматтар базасын программалоодо «SQL» эмнени билдирет?","answer":"Жооп: Маалыматтар базасын программалоодо \\"SQL\\" \\"Структураланган суроо тили\\" дегенди билдирет. SQL реляциялык маалымат базаларын башкаруу жана манипуляциялоо үчүн колдонулган доменге тиешелүү тил. Бул маалымат базалары менен өз ара аракеттенүүнүн стандартташтырылган жолун камсыз кылат, анын ичинде маалыматтарды түзүү, жаңыртуу, суроо жана жок кылуу сыяктуу тапшырмаларды аткаруу."},{"question":"ශ්‍රීලංකාවේ බෞද්ධ කොඩිය ලොව සියළුම බෞද්ධයන්ගේ කොඩිය බවට පත් වූයේ කුමන වසරේදීද ? ","answer":"ශ්‍රීලංකාවේ බෞද්ධ කොඩිය ලොව සියළුම බෞද්ධයන්ගේ කොඩිය බවට පත් වූයේ ක්‍රි.ව 1951 දී ය "},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang paling sesuai untuk mengisi tempat kosong dalam ayat berikut: Cadangan saya untuk menambah kolam ikan di taman sains ditolak __ oleh guru besar. Pilihan:  A) mentah-mentahB)  masak-masakC) masing-masingD) molek-molek","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah A) mentah-mentah"},{"question":"Kitaabka Dhambaalada Quraanka?","answer":"(إِذۡ یَقُولُ لِصَـٰحِبِهِۦ لَا تَحۡزَنۡ إِنَّ ٱللَّهَ مَعَنَاۖ )[Surah At-Tawbah 40] \\"Markii uu saxiibkii ku lahaa ha murugoon, Alle Ayaa inala jira'e \\".Waqtiyada qaar ayaynu cidhiidhi dareenaa kadibna waxaa Ina soo gaadha weedho naxariis Huwan oo inaga fayda Dhibkii ina ragaadiyay. Waqtiyada badhkood qalbi jab ayaa innagu habsada kadib Waxaa inna soo gaadhaa Weedh Kabniin innoo noqota. Mar kale murugo ayaynu dareennaa kadib hadal Qumman Ayaa innooga yimaadda qof ehelka ah oo waynu faraxnaa. \\"Dunida marti ayaynu ku nahay waxaa waajib ah in aynu is Kaashano.\\" Bogga 92.Kitaabka Dhambaalada Quraanka."},{"question":"cual es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿Cuál equipo Lebron James derrotó para ganar su tercer campeonato en la NBA?","answer":"El tema principal de esta pregunta es determinar qué equipo LeBron James derrotó para ganar su tercer campeonato en la NBA."},{"question":"Sheeg magaca saddexan ee halgame Xalane, meesha uu ku geeriyooday iyo            sanadkii  uu geeriyooday","answer":" Waa Max’ed Cabdulle Xalane waxa uu ku geeriyooday Tog Wajaale sanadkii 1964"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو النادي الذي يشار إليه أحيانًا ب ( إف سي هوليود)؟","answer":"الإجابة: بايرن ميونخ"},{"question":"नेपालमा के साहसिक कार्य गर्न सकिन्छ ?","answer":"पदयात्रा र चुचुरो आरोहण नेपाल आउने पर्यटकहरु माझ सबैभन्दा लोकप्रिय गतिविधि हो। यो देश नौसिखिया र अनुभवी पर्वतारोहीहरूको लागि स्वर्ग हो, चुनौतीपूर्ण 8,000 मिटर हिमाल आरोहणको रोमाञ्चक अनुभव गर्ने अवसर प्रदान गर्दछ। यसको विविध भूगोल र संस्कृति, साथै यसको अचम्मको प्राकृतिक सौन्दर्यले नेपाललाई पदयात्राको लागि उपयुक्त गन्तव्य बनाउँछ। नेपालको हिमालयमा एक पदयात्राले तपाईंलाई संस्कृति अवलोकन गर्न र प्रकृतिको सौन्दर्यको आनन्द लिन अनुमति दिन्छ। हिमालयन नदीहरूमा सेतो वाटर र्याफ्टिङ पनि एक लोकप्रिय गतिविधि हो, जसले शान्त जेड पानीमा आश्चर्यजनक दृश्यहरू वा गर्जने र्यापिडहरू मार्फत दौडने मौका प्रदान गर्दछ। बस्ती, घाटी, भर्जिन जङ्गल र वन्यजन्तुको माध्यमबाट नेपाललाई अन्वेषण गर्न र्याफ्टिङ एउटा उत्कृष्ट माध्यम हो।तराई क्षेत्रमा जंगल सफारीहरू नेपालको दुर्लभ जनावर र चराहरू हेर्नको लागि लोकप्रिय माध्यम हो। हात्तीको पछाडिको हरियाली जंगलको यात्रा, खोला र दलदल पार गर्दै, तपाईंलाई नेपालको वनस्पति र जीवजन्तु अवलोकन गर्ने र दुर्लभ जनावर र चराहरू भेट्ने अवसर प्रदान गर्दछ। शाही उपचारको लागि तयार हुनुहोस्, किनकि तपाईंले राजसी शाही बंगाल बाघ पनि देख्न सक्नुहुन्छ।नेपालको विविध भूभागले पनि यसलाई माउन्टेन बाइकिङको लागि उत्कृष्ट गन्तव्य बनाउँछ। यो पर्यावरण-मैत्री गतिविधिले तपाईंलाई देशको भव्य परिदृश्य र जीवन्त संस्कृति, साथै यसको उल्लेखनीय सम्पदा अन्वेषण गर्न अनुमति दिन्छ। विरलै भेटिने ग्रामीण गाउँहरूको लुकेका ट्रेलहरूमा पैदल यात्रा गर्दै, तपाईंले हँसिलो स्थानीयहरू शान्ति र सद्भावमा सरल जीवन बिताउने, आफ्नै संस्कृति अभ्यास गर्दै र आफ्नै बोली बोल्ने देख्नुहुनेछ।नेपालमा अर्को रोमाञ्चक गतिविधि बन्गी जम्पिङ हो, जुन हिमालयबाट बग्ने संसारको सबैभन्दा जंगली नदीहरू मध्ये एक, 160 मिटर अग्लो भोटे कोशी पुलमा अनुभव गर्न सकिन्छ। नेपालले अन्य साहसिक गतिविधिहरू पनि प्रदान गर्दछ जस्तै पक्षी अवलोकन, क्यानोनिङ, पर्वत अभियान, चट्टान आरोहण, शिखर आरोहण, घोडा सवारी, स्नोबोर्डिङ, माछा मार्ने, र मह शिकार पनि।अक्रोस हिमालय एक प्रसिद्ध र प्रतिष्ठित सरकारी इजाजतपत्र प्राप्त ट्राभल कम्पनी हो जसले यात्रुहरूका लागि धेरै वर्षदेखि इनामदायी साहसिक कार्यहरू आयोजना गर्दै आएको छ। एशियामा साहसिक खेलकुद र भ्रमणका लागि प्रसिद्ध गन्तव्यको रूपमा, नेपाल साहसिक यात्रीहरूका लागि शीर्ष विकल्प हो। हामी हरेक वर्ष हामीलाई भेट्ने सन्तुष्ट र दोहोर्याउने ग्राहकहरूको ठूलो संख्यामा गर्व गर्छौं, र हामी तपाईंसँग जीवनभरको साहसिक कार्य साझा गर्ने अवसर विस्तार गर्न तत्पर छौं।"},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai.  Ibu membuat __ pisang sebagai sarapan kami pada hari ini. Pilihan:  A) jala-jalaB) enak-enakC) jemput-jemputD) roti-roti","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah D) roti-roti"},{"question":"Qui était la deuxième épouse du roi Henry VIII ?","answer":"La deuxième épouse du roi Henry VIII était Anne Boleyn."},{"question":"படம் + கதை இச்சொற்களைச் சேர்த்து எழுதக் கிடைப்பது _________படம்கதைபடக்கதைபடகதைபடகாதை","answer":"விடை : படம் + கதை இச்சொற்களைச் சேர்த்து எழுதக் கிடைப்பது __படக்கதை"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe foko any Madagasikara?","answer":"Ny foko any Madagasikara dia vondron' olona heverina fa iray faritra niaviana, nanana fandaminana ara-pôlitika iraisany na nitoviany tamin'ny vanimpotoana faha mpanjaka, manana ny fomba fitenenany ny teny malagasy izay atao hoe fitenim-paritra, sns. Mahazatra ny maro anefa ny miteny hoe \\"foko valo ambin'ny folo\\" taorian'ny fanjanahan-tany, na dia tsy mifanandrify amin'ny tena marina izany. Ny foko sasany dia mety vondrom-poko raha ny tena marina noho ny faritra misy azy midadasika loatra."},{"question":"කේරල කොස් භෝජනයක් වන ඉදිචක්ක තෝරන් පිළියෙළ කරන්නේ කොහොමද?","answer":"ඉදිචක්ක තෝරන් (Idichakka Thoran) පිළියෙළ කර ගනු ලබන්නේ ඉතාම ළපටි, නොඉදුණු කොස් ගෙඩි යොදා ගනිමින්ය. මෙම කොස් ගෙඩියේ උල් සහිත ඝන පොත්ත තියුණු පිහියකින් සහිනු ලබන අතර පසුව එය ඉතා කුඩා කැබලි වලට කපා, අවශ්‍යතරමට වතුර එකතු කර තම්බා ගනී. පසු එයට හීනියට ගා ගත් පොල්, වියලි ගම්මිරිස්, ලුණු, වියලි කහ යනාදිය අවශ්‍යපරිදි දමා මද ගින්නේ පිස ගනී. එය තවත් රස කර ගැනීමට පොල්තෙලෙන් බැදගත් අබ ඇටද එක් කර ගත හැකිය."},{"question":"レストランなどでワインを運ぶ専門職のことを何というでしょう？","answer":"ソムリエです。"},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക.ചോദ്യം: ഓസ്‌കാറിന്റെ മികച്ച അന്താരാഷ്ട്ര ഫീച്ചർ ഫിലിം വിഭാഗത്തിലേക്ക് ഒരു മലയാള സിനിമയെ പരിഗണിക്കുന്നതിനുള്ള നടപടിക്രമം എന്താണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ഓസ്‌കാറിന്റെ മികച്ച ഇന്റർനാഷണൽ ഫീച്ചർ ഫിലിം വിഭാഗത്തിലേക്ക് പരിഗണിക്കുന്നതിന്, ഇന്ത്യയുടെ ഔദ്യോഗിക എൻട്രിയായി ഒരു മലയാള സിനിമ തിരഞ്ഞെടുക്കേണ്ടതുണ്ട്. ഫിലിം ഫെഡറേഷൻ ഓഫ് ഇന്ത്യയാണ് തിരഞ്ഞെടുപ്പ് നടത്തുന്നത്, തിരഞ്ഞെടുത്ത സിനിമ പിന്നീട് അക്കാദമിയുടെ പരിഗണനയ്ക്കായി സമർപ്പിക്കും."},{"question":"Diniho ity fanambarana manaraka ity: “Tiako ny mianatra momba ny kolontsaina sy fomban-drazana samihafa” Misy resaka fankahalana ve io fanambarana io?","answer":"Tsia. Maneho fankafizana na zavatra tiana manokana ity fanambarana ity."},{"question":"\\"Калың токой,Калың токойдун алды жар кабак,Жар кабактын алды чийме саз,Чийме саздын алды кайнар булак,Кайнар булактан ары шаркыратма,Шаркыратманын алды жалжайма,Жалжаймадан тик бурма\\".-табышмактын жандырмагы кандай? ","answer":"Табышмактын жандырмагы -\\"ЧАЧ, КАБАК, КАШ, КӨЗ, МУРУН, ОО3, ЭЭК\\". "},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи?","answer":"Албетте, мына сизге кызыктуу факты:Элазмотериум - байыркы Сибирдеги керик.Бул байыркы кериктердин көлөмү өтө чоң болгон.  Бул тукум курут болгон жаныбарлардын узундугу 6 метр, бийиктиги 3 метрге чейин жана массасы 5 тонна болгон.  Эласмотерийдин негизги айырмалоочу өзгөчөлүгү чекесиндеги чоң томпок проекция болгон.  Окумуштуулар анын узундугу 1,5 метр болгон коюу мүйүзү болгон деп божомолдошот."},{"question":"Ahoana no ahafahan'ny mpampianatra manatsara ny traikefa amin'ny fianarana ho an'ny mpianatra?","answer":"Ny mpampianatra dia afaka manatsara ny traikefan'ny mpianatra amin'ny alàlan'ny fampivoarana tontolo iainan'ny mpianatra sy mandrisika, mampiasa fomba fampianarana isan-karazany, mampifanaraka ny fampianarany amin'ny fomba fianarana samihafa, ary mandrisika ny fandraisana anjara mavitrika amin'ny mpianatra."},{"question":"வினா : வேர் இல்லாத தாவரம் எது ? இதன் வாழ்விடம் என்ன? ","answer":"விடை : வேர் இல்லாத தாவரம் இலுப்பை. இலுப்பை அல்லது இருப்பை அல்லது குலிகம் தமிழகத்தைத் தாயகமாகக் கொண்ட ஒரு மரமாகும். இதன் விதையிலிருந்து பிழிந்தெடுக்கப்படும் எண்ணெய், இலுப்பெண்ணெய் எனப்படுகின்றது. தாவரத்தின் குடும்பத்தைச் சேர்ந்தது. இலைகள் சப்போட்டா இலையை ஒத்திருக்கும். நூறு அடிக்குமேல் வளரக்கூடியது. சப்போட்டா குற்று செடி அல்லது குற்று மர வகையைச் சேர்ந்தது, ஆனால் இலுப்பை மிக உயரமாக வளரும்."},{"question":"ਖੋਜਕਰਤਾਵਾਂ ਨੇ ਸਿਧਾਂਤ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਬਤ ਕੀਤਾ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਖੋਜਕਰਤਾਵਾਂ ਨੇ ਸਿਧਾਂਤ ਨੂੰ ਵਾਪਸ ਲੈ ਲਿਆ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਵਿਅਕਤੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਸਿਧਾਂਤ ਨੂੰ ਮੰਨ ਲਿਆ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਵਿਅਕਤੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਸਿਧਾਂਤ ਨੂੰ ਮੰਨ ਲਿਆ।"},{"question":"Lẹyin to ti lo ọdun mẹta lẹwọn, kootu tu Malachy silẹ, wọn ni ko jẹbi","answer":"Ẹsun idigunjale ni awọn kan ka si ọkunrin kan torukọ ẹ n jẹ Tomas Malachy lẹsẹ niluu Iworoko-Ekiti, lọdun 2018, latigba naa lo si ti wa lẹwọn, ki kootu too gbọ ẹjọ rẹ tan lọsẹ to kọja yii, ti wọn si da a silẹ pe ko jẹbi.Ile-ẹjọ giga kan l’Ado-Ekiti lo da Tomas, ẹni ogoji ọdun silẹ, nigba ti Adajọ John Adeyẹye sọ pe awọn to pe e lẹjọ pẹlu ọlọpaa to ṣoju ko ri ẹri gidi fi gbe ẹsun ole jija naa lẹsẹ lasiko igbẹjọ. Titi di ọjọ ti idajọ si waye yii, ọrọ wọn ko ṣee tẹle, nitori ko kunna to.Oṣiṣẹ ileeṣẹ mọnamọna ni Malachy Tomas, ohun to gbe e de kootu ko too dero ẹwọn ni pe wọn ni lọjọ kẹrindinlogun, oṣu kọkanla, ọdun 2018, wọn lo dihamọra pẹlu ibọn ilewọ ibilẹ kan, o si lọọ ja ọkunrin kan torukọ ẹ n jẹ Kọlawọle Damilọla  lole ninu ile rẹ ni Iworoko-Ekiti, nijọba ibilẹ Ifẹlodun/Irẹpọdun.  Lara awọn ẹru ti wọn gba lọwọ Malachy nigba naa ni foonu, kọmputa alagbeletan ati ẹgbẹrun lọna aadọta naira.Nigba ti Adajọ Adeyẹye wo ṣaakun ẹsun ti olujẹjọ tori ẹ wa latimọle lati 2018, ti ko si si ẹri gidi to le mu ko gba pe ọkunrin naa jẹbi lo da a silẹ, o ni ko maa lọ sile rẹ lalaafia ara."},{"question":"Макал-лакап ","answer":"Адал өлсө—бир казан эт, арам өлсө — ит менен кушка жем.\\r"},{"question":"病気になっても症状が現れにくいことから「沈黙の臓器」とも呼ばれる、人体の中で最も大きい臓器は何でしょう？","answer":"肝臓"},{"question":"Mudantii ahweynkayMaxamed mooge","answer":"Mudantii haweenkaaymarwadii la sheegeedadku wada majiirtaaydumar lama mid dhigayeemuxubada kal gacalkaalaanyahay magoosheemidhihiyo caleentiyomanka lagu talaaleeubax lagu mariimeequrux lagu manaystaaymudo aan yarayn baankugu soo maqnaayooma ogtahay habeenadansida mayayga roobkoohadba maayad keenaaii muuqa taayeemuxibada kalgacalkahadba soo mir kacayaaMidhaha hadalku leeyeyereygiisa ma huraanwaana loo mashxaradaamidaa taaladeedaaigu mayracaysaamarti waa la sooraamagan waa la bixiyaahaw udhuran masuugemaahmaahda sheegtayoodhibtan ha igu madininemudo aan yarayn baankugu soo maqnaayooma ogtahay habeenadansida mayayga roobkoohadba maayad keenaaii muuqa taayomuxibada jacaylkahadba soo mir kacayaaMasalooyin dhawroomahadhooyideedaankuu marinayaayemaqal waanadaydanoomiisaan warkeygoocaynkii xalaytoonwaaba midhiq ii odhanmadaxaanba duubteenaftu way ku maagtayookaa maar mi waydayeemudo aan yaraynbaankugu soo maqnaayooma ogtahay habeenadasida mayayga roobkoohadba maayad keenaaii muuqa taayomuxibada jacaylkaa"},{"question":"අසමත් යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"අසමත් යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය සමත් වේ. "},{"question":"පහත තේරවිල්ල විසඳන්න.ල්ලක දාගෙන යාහැකි රට","answer":"බුරුමය"},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Tỷ phú Bill Gates từng viết trong cuốn The Road Ahead rằng: \\"Chúng ta luôn quá quan tâm đến những thay đổi trước mắt, trong khi đó lại xem nhẹ những biến chuyển trong tương lai xa hơn\\". Chúng ta đang bắt đầu đi trên một con đường cực kỳ \\"gập ghềnh\\". Tự động hóa, AI, điện toán lượng tử và các tập đoàn đa quốc gia,... tham gia ngày càng sâu vào thi trường lao động và nền kinh tế toàn cầu. Cùng với đó, một cuộc khủng hoảng thất nghiệp với quy mô lớn chưa từng thấy trong lịch sử nhân loại sẽ xảy ra. Chưa có các số liệu chính xác, nhưng các ước tính cho thấy, tự động hóa có thể làm mất đi khoảng 800 triệu đến 2 tỷ việc làm trong 10 năm tới. Những biến động lớn về kinh tế và chính trị là không thể tránh khỏi. Còn cách mà chúng ta đối phó với cuộc khủng hoảng thất nghiệp này sẽ đi vào lịch sử, trở thành một nguồn cảm hứng hoặc một câu chuyện cảnh báo thảm khốc cho thế hệ tương lai. Vậy đâu là những công việc sẽ bị \\"xoá sổ\\" trong 10 năm tới? 1. Tài xế Để có thể hủy hợp đồng với người lao động, Uber và Lyft sẵn sàng chi hàng trăm triệu USD. Họ thậm chí còn \\"từ chối\\" gọi các tài xế của mình là nhân viên. Khi công nghệ phát triển, xe tự lái trở nên phổ biến và có thể thay thế bạn, vì vậy nên bạn đừng mong đợi các công ty vẫn sẽ đối xử tốt với mình. Dù là taxi truyền thống. Tài xế giao bánh pizza. Những người lái xe limo. Những người lái xe tải. Hay các tài xế giao hàng trọn gói của Amazon và Alibaba đều không có ngoại lệ. Sớm thôi, các đơn hàng của bạn sẽ được giao tới tận cửa bằng máy bay không người lái. 2. Nhân viên ngân hàng Xét cho cùng, ngành ngân hàng và nền kinh tế sản xuất không chung đường. Hiện nay, có khá nhiều ngân hàng đang chuyển sang hoạt động online. Điều này đồng nghĩa với 98% nhân viên cho vay sẽ mất việc. Ứớc tính, chỉ riêng ở Hoa Kỳ và Vương quốc Anh, đã có gần 2 triệu lao động trong lĩnh vực ngân hàng bị mất việc làm. 3. Kế toán và người quản lý sổ sách Bây giờ, chúng ta có thể tự khai báo thuế hay làm các loại giấy tờ khác thông qua hình thức online một cách dễ dàng. H&R Block hiện cũng đã sử dụng nền tảng AI của IBM, Watson để hỗ trợ khách hàng khai thuế thuận tiện, nhanh chóng hơn. Tất nhiên, đi cùng với đó là việc cắt giảm một lượng lớn nhân viên phụ trách mảng này. Ở Anh, hầu hết người lao động thậm chí không cần phải nộp hồ sơ vì máy móc và công nghệ đã tự động thực hiện thay họ rồi. 4. Tiếp thị điện thoại Thật khó tin khi vẫn có cả ngàn công ty tiếp thị qua điện thoại đang hoạt động mỗi ngày. Và chúng ta đã quá quen thuộc với những cuộc điện thoại mở đầu bằng: \\"Xin chào, anh chị có nhu cầu…\\". Tuy nhiên, những điều này sẽ có thể dần biến mất trong tương lai và bạn có thể yên tâm rằng mình sẽ không còn bị làm phiền bởi bất kỳ cuộc gọi rác nào nữa. Tờ The Guardian dự đoán, trong thập kỷ tới, có 99% khả năng việc tiếp thị qua điện thoại sẽ được tự động hóa. Doanh số bán hàng qua điện thoại quá thấp, thêm vào đó là đại đa số mọi người đang quen dần với việc tự tìm những gì họ cần trên mạng Internet sẽ khiến cho công việc này biến mất trong tương lai không xa. 5. Nhân viên thu ngân Hiện này, các chuỗi cửa hàng lớn, từ Kroger đến McDonald's đều muốn thay thế tất cả nhân viên tại quầy của họ bằng các quầy thanh toán tự động. Các công ty như Heck, Amazon và Whole Foods thậm chí còn đang loại bỏ chính các ki-ốt bán hàng của mình. Tương lai, cho dù muốn hay không, chúng vẫn phải quen dần với việc tự phục vụ. Hơn nữa, thực tế là mua sắm trực tuyến tiếp tục thống trị doanh số bán hàng cửa các hãng. Theo đó, sẽ có khoảng 97% khả năng hàng triệu người sẽ mất kế sinh nhai. Tuy nhiên, đây chưa phải là tất cả, trong những thập kỷ tới, có nhiều công việc khác cũng sẽ biến mất: - Đại lý du lịch (khi phần lớn mọi người sử dụng Booking.com và các trang web khác như Airbnb). - Trợ lý pháp lý (94% thay thế bằng tự động hóa) - Đầu bếp nấu đồ ăn nhanh (sử dụng robot) - Người viết nhạc (Google) - Biên dịch viên và thông","answer":"dịch viên (Google) - Thủ thư (Google) - Người bán sách (Amazon) - Công nhân khai thác than và dầu (thay thế bằng năng lượng tự nhiên: năng lượng mặt trời / gió...) - Giáo viên (các trường học trực tuyến như iTunes U) - Nhân viên trông giữ xe (không còn sự xuất hiện của con người, thay vào đó là sự giám sát của người máy) - Kiểm soát viên không lưu và phi công (máy bay không người lái và tàu sân bay không người lái) - Phóng viên báo chí (có lẽ đây là mất mát đáng buồn nhất) - Nhân viên rạp chiếu phim - Những người đánh cá… Và, những công việc mới sẽ xuất hiện, phải không? Chắc chắn rồi! Nhưng trong nền kinh tế ấy, những công việc trên có thể sẽ trở thành các công việc bán thời gian, được trả lương thấp hơn, tiếng nói trong xã hội cũng nhỏ bé hơn nhiều. Các công việc trong tương lai cũng sẽ đòi hỏi trình độ học vấn cao hơn đáng kể. Và đó có thể sẽ là cái bẫy lớn nhất từng được tạo ra. Khi có thêm hơn 2 tỷ người trên Trái đất vốn đã chật chội, liệu chúng ta có đủ khả năng để cung cấp việc làm với mức lương \\"đủ\\" sống cho tất cả mọi người mà không ảnh hưởng đến môi trường không? Ngoài ra, việc tạo ra các ngành công nghiệp hoàn toàn mới cần có thời gian. Những người thất nghiệp không có hàng chục năm để chờ đợi cho đến khi công việc mới xuất hiện và sau đó quay lại trường học ở độ tuổi 40 hoặc 50. Giai đoạn chuyển tiếp luôn chứa đựng nhiều nguy hiểm nhất. Có thể bạn đang làm việc trong những lĩnh vực \\"an toàn\\" mà tự động hóa chưa thể thay thế như: vật lý trị liệu, bác sĩ, bác sĩ phẫu thuật, giáo sĩ,...Nhưng đừng vội cho rằng: \\"Vậy thì điều này không ảnh hưởng đến tôi.\\" Đây là một suy nghĩa sai lầm. Bởi vì nó có ảnh hưởng đến bạn. Thứ nhất, tình trạng thất nghiệp sẽ tạo ra áp lực cạnh tranh lớn đối với các công việc vốn \\"an toàn\\" với tự động hóa. Thứ hai, ước tính cho thấy một nửa số nhiệm vụ công việc hiện tại có thể được tự động hóa. Vì vậy, ngay cả đối với những người không bị mất việc làm, tình trạng thiếu việc làm có thể sẽ trở nên phổ biến và mang tính hệ thống. Thứ ba, hàng chục triệu người đang trong quá trình chuyển đổi công việc, có nghĩa là nhà nước sẽ phải chi hàng nghìn tỷ đồng hỗ trợ nơi ở, giáo dục và định vị lại công dân. Các nước sẽ phải tăng thuế hoặc in thêm tiền, tăng giá hàng hoá và làm giảm sức mua của bạn . Có ý kiến cho rằng tự động hóa khiến nhiều người lao động mất việc và ngày càng khó khăn. Tự động hoá chỉ mang lại lợi ích cho những người giàu có. Tuy nhiên, chúng ta phải chấp nhận một sự thật rằng, hậu quả kinh tế mà nó mang lại là thứ mà tất cả chúng ta đều phải gánh chịu. Làm điều đúng đắn Chúng ta cần hỗ trợ mạnh mẽ hơn cho những người thất nghiệp, thiếu việc làm và những người có thu nhập thấp. Ở đây đang nói đến chi phí sinh hoạt và chi phí học tập cho đến khi họ vững vàng trở lại, có thu nhập cơ bản bền vững. Suy cho cùng, những người lao động đã tạo ra giá trị, của cải cho các ông chủ lớn. Vì vậy, được đối xử công bằng là quyền lợi mà họ đáng được nhận. Thế nhưng, vẫn còn phải xem liệu những ông chủ có chịu nhận ra điều đó hay không. Tất cả chúng ta đều cần mở rộng trái tim và \\"ví tiền\\" của mình để dành nhiều chỗ hơn cho những người khác. Nếu không, chúng ta sẽ thấy đường phố xa hoa LA, New York, và hàng ngàn thành phố khác tràn ngập những người thất nghiệp. Hãy vui vẻ chấp nhận, thích nghi với bất kỳ nghề nghiệp hay nền kinh tế nào giữa tình trạng hỗn loạn đó. (Theo Survivingtomorrow.org)"},{"question":"ઇસુભાઈ ગઢવી ની \\"કાન તને રાધા ગમે કે મીરાં?\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"કાન તને રાધા ગમે કે ગમે મીરાં?એકે કાળજ કરવત મેલ્યાં, એકે પાડ્યા ચીરા!કાન તને રાધા ગમે કે મીરાં?એકે જોબન ઘેલી થઈને તુજને નાચ નચાવ્યો;એકે જોબન ઘૂણી માથે તારો અલખ જગાવ્યો.એકે તુજને ગોરસ પાયાં, એકે ઝેર કટોરા!કાન તને રાધા ગમે કે મીરાં?પચરંગી પાનેતર તું વિણ રાધે કદી ન પહેર્યા;મખમલિયો મલીર મીરાંનાં અંગે કદી ન ઓઢીયાં.એકે ઓઢી શ્યામ ઓઢણી, એકે ભગવત લીરા!કાન તને રાધા ગમે કે મીરાં?મલક બધાનો મેલી મલાજો રાધા બની વરણાગણ;ભરી ભાદરી મેલી મહેલા તો મીરાં બની વીજોગણ.એક નામની દરદ દીવાની, બીજી શબદ શરીરા!કાન તને રાધા ગમે કે મીરાં?કીધું ક્રિષ્નએ પૂછો એટલું મળે ક્યાંય જો રાધા;મળે ક્યાંય તો પૂછો મીરાંને કોને વહાલો માધા?મોરે અંતર રાધા વેણુ વગાડે, ભીતર મીરાં મંજીરા!કાન કહે મારે બે સરખાં રાધા-મીરાં!કાન તને રાધા ગમે કે મીરાં?"},{"question":"ጥያቄ፦ በዓለም ላይ ብዙ ቡና የሚያመርተው የትኛው አገር ነው? መልስ፦ ","answer":"ብራዚል"},{"question":"أريد أن أتعلم الشعر. أنشيء قصيدة حزينه من بحر الكامل.","answer":"حسناً بالتأكيد: إِن لَم أُطِع هِمَماً وَأَعصِ عَواذِلاًقُلِبَت صَوامِتُها عَلَيَّ مَقاوِلاوَأُجيعُ أَعياساً وَأُشبِعُ صارِماًوَأَعُلُّ خُرصاناً وَأُظمىءُ صاهِلاوَلَرُبَّ مَصحوبٍ شَرِقتُ بَلُؤمِهِفَلَفَظتُهُ قَبلَ الإِساغَةِ عاجِلاوَلَّيتُهُ زُجَّ القَناةِ مُوَزَّعاًفَكَأَنَّما أَعمَلتُ فيهِ عامِلاوَمَنَحتُهُ أَروى القَوافي عاتِباًفَاِكتَنَّ في جَنبَيهِ سُمّاً قاتِلاوَكَسَوتُ مَن مورِ المَلامِ جَنانَهُقَبلَ العِقابِ فَصارَ فيهِ جَنادِلاوَهَزَزتُ أَغصانَ المَخاوِفِ دونَهُفَاِجتازَ يَحسَبُها ظُبىً وَذَوابِلا."},{"question":"كم هي عدد آيات القرآن الكريم؟\\t","answer":"هو 6236 آية."},{"question":"Pilkasis vilkas","answer":"Pilkasis vilkas (Canis lupus) – stambiausias iš visų laukinių šuninių (Canidae) šeimos žinduolis, visų naminių šunų protėvis."},{"question":"\\"গ্রিনল্যান্ড কিন্তু সবুজে ঘেরা ভূমি নয়\\" শিরোনামে গ্রিনল্যান্ডের পরিচিতিমূলক একটি অনুচ্ছেদ লেখ।","answer":"গ্রিনল্যান্ড কিন্তু সবুজে ঘেরা ভূমি নয়।উত্তর আটলান্টিক ও আর্কটিক মহাসাগরের মধ্যে অবস্থিত বিশ্বের সুবৃহৎ দ্বীপ গ্রিনল্যান্ড। নামে গ্রিনল্যান্ড বা সবুজভূমি হলেও সমগ্র দ্বীপের প্রায় চার ভাগের তিনভাগ শুভ্র বরফে ঢাকা। এর তাপমাত্রা সাধারণত মাইনাস ৮-৭ ডিগ্রি সেন্টিগ্রেড। দ্বীপটির আয়তন ২১,৭৫,৬০০ বর্গ কিমি। পৃথিবীর বৃহত্তম জাতীয় উদ্যান 'নর্থ-ইস্ট গ্রিনল্যান্ড ন্যাশনাল পার্ক' এ দ্বীপেই অবস্থিত। জীববৈচিত্র্যের অনন্য এ লীলাভূমিতে প্রায় ৩১০ প্রজাতির ভাস্কুলার উদ্ভিদের দেখা মেলে, যার মধ্যে ১৫ প্রজাতির উদ্ভিদ পৃথিবীর আর কোথাও দেখা যায় না। এখানকার বড় আকারের স্তন্যপায়ী প্রাণীর মধ্যে রয়েছে মাস্ক ষাঁড়, রেইনডিয়ার, মেরু ভাল্লুক, আর্কটিক নেকড়েসহ আরও অনেক প্রাণী। এখানকার সাগর উপকূলে প্রায় ২০ লক্ষ সিল দেখা যায়। এদের সাথে বিচরণ করে হাতির মতো লম্বা দাঁতের ওয়ালরাস। অন্যান্য জলজ স্তন্যপায়ী প্রাণীর মধ্যে রয়েছে নীলতিমি, গ্রিনল্যান্ড তিমিসহ নয় প্রজাতির তিমি। গ্রিনল্যান্ডকে মুখরিত করে রাখে পেরেগ্রিন ফ্যালকন, বড় পানকৌড়ি, আইসল্যান্ড গাংচিলসহ রং-বেরংয়ের নানান প্রজাতির পাখির সুমধুর সুরের লহরী। সব মিলিয়ে গ্রিনল্যান্ড জীববৈচিত্র্যের সত্যিকার এক স্বর্গভূমি।"},{"question":"Schrijf een voortzetting van de paragraaf: Op 11 oktober 1945 benoemde paus Pius XII hem tot aartsbisschop van Palermo en tijdens het consistorie van 18 februari 1946 werd hij tot kardinaal gecreëerd. Hij kreeg de \\"Santa Sabina\\" als titelkerk. Hij nam deel aan het Conclaaf van 1958","answer":"dat leidde tot de verkiezing van paus Johannes XXIII en aan dat van 1963, waarbij paus Paulus VI werd gekozen."},{"question":"ඇමෙරිකා  එක්සත් ජනපදයට අයත් , එරටින් පිට විශාලතම හමුදා  කඳවුර පිහිටුවා ඇති භූමිය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"Diego Garcia කඳවුර අක්කර 7000 යි. එය විශාලත්වයෙන් 4 වැනි විශාලම කඳවුර කියා සැලකෙන්නේ.නමුත් විශාලතම හමුදා කඳවුර තියෙන්නෙ ග්‍රීන්ලන්තයේ. එය අක්කර 233,000 ක්. Thule Air Base."},{"question":"Qual é o papel de um Cerimonialista de Casamentos?","answer":"Um Cerimonialista de Casamentos planeja e coordena todas as atividades,  numa Cerimônia de Casamento, garantindo que tudo ocorra conforme o planejado."},{"question":"Who ruled Russia in 1914? How did he manage his empire?","answer":"Tsar Nicholas II was ruling over Russia during the revolution.He was an autocrat.Though he created ‘Duma’ after the Revolution, he never cared for it.He was carrying the war against the wishes of the people.He worked under a monk called Rasputin."},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Shinida Imisa Indhood Ayey Leedahay?","answer":"Jawaab: Shinida Waxay Leedahay Shan (5) Indhood."},{"question":"دانشمند داده کیست؟","answer":"به شاغلین در حوزهٔ علم داده، دانشمند داده (data scientist) می‌گویند. این اصطلاح توسط دی جی پاتیل و جف همربارکر ابداع شده‌است در صورتی که سال‌ها قبل از آن که آن‌ها استفاده از اصطلاح فوق را به‌طور عمومی مطرح کنند، از آن استفاده شده‌ است. دانشمند یا متخصص علم داده با عمیق شدن در چندین رشتهٔ علمی، مسائل پیچیدهٔ مطرح شده در حوزهٔ داده را حل می‌کنند. به‌طور کلی انتظار می‌رود که متخصصین علم داده قادر باشند در بخش‌هایی از علوم ریاضیات و آمار و علوم کامپیوتر کار کنند. یک متخصص علم داده می‌بایست در یک یا دو رشته تخصص داشته باشد و در دیگر حوزه‌ها دارای مهارت کافی باشد. نتایج نظرسنجی‌ها حاکی از این موضوع است که برای متخصص علم داده شدن ۵ تا ۸ سال زمان لازم است."},{"question":"નીચેના ગુજરાતી ઉખાણાં નો જવાબ આપો:હાથી ઘોડા ફર્યા કરે પણ, પગ એમના ચાલે ના સવાર પીઠે ઘૂમ્યા કરે, ને ફરવાની મજા લીધા કરે","answer":"ચકડોળ"},{"question":"Mikä on influenssa?","answer":"Influenssa on influenssavirusten aiheuttama äkillinen ylempien hengitysteiden tulehdus. Influenssaepidemioita esiintyy joka talvi.Tartunnan saaneiden ja sairastuneiden määrät vaihtelevat suuresti kausittain. On arvioitu, että vuosittain Euroopassa sairastuu 4–50 miljoonaa ihmistä influenssaan. Tautiin kuolee ennenaikaisesti noin 15 000–70 000 ihmistä.On myös arvioitu, että valtaosa tartunnan saaneista on oireettomia.Sairastumisen todennäköisyyteen ja vakavuuteen vaikuttavat monet tekijät: virustyyppi ja  tartunnan saaneen ihmisen terveydentila sekä hänen kykynsä muodostaa suojaa aiempien viruskohtaamisten ja rokotusten pohjalta."},{"question":"ਕੀ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਸੁਸ਼ਮਾ ਸਵਰਾਜ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹੋ?","answer":"ਸੁਸ਼ਮਾ ਸਵਰਾਜ (ਜਨਮ 14 ਫਰਵਰੀ 1952-ਮੌਤ 6 ਅਗਸਤ 2019) ਇੱਕ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਸਿਆਸਤਦਾਨ ਸੀ ਜੋ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਸੁਪਰੀਮ ਕੋਰਟ ਦੀ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਵਕੀਲ ਰਹੀ ਅਤੇ 26 ਮਈ, 2014 ਤੋਂ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ ਮਾਮਲਿਆਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਸੀ। ਇੱਕ ਨੇਤਾ ਦੇ ਤੌਰ ਤੇ ਸੁਸ਼ਮਾ ਸਵਰਾਜ ਇੰਦਰਾ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ ਮਾਮਲਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਬਣਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਦੂਜੀ ਔਰਤ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਸੰਸਦ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਦੇ ਤੌਰ 'ਤੇ ਸੱਤ ਵਾਰ ਅਤੇ ਵਿਧਾਇਕ ਸਭਾ ਦੇ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਵਜੋਂ ਤਿੰਨ ਵਾਰ ਚੁਣੀ ਗਈ ਸੀ। 1977 ਵਿੱਚ 25 ਸਾਲ ਦੀ ਉਮਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਹ ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਦੀ ਕੈਬਨਿਟ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਬਣੀ। ਉਸਨੇ 1998 ਵਿੱਚ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਦੀ 5ਵੀਂ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਦੇ ਤੌਰ 'ਤੇ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ।2014 ਦੀਆਂ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਆਮ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੱਧ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿਦਿਸ਼ਾ ਹਲਕੇ ਤੋਂ ਚੋਣ 400,000 ਵੋਟਾਂ ਦੇ ਫਰਕ ਨਾਲ ਜਿੱਤੀ। ਸੁਸ਼ਮਾ ਸਵਰਾਜ ਨੂੰ ਅਮਰੀਕੀ ਵਾਲ ਸਟਰੀਟ ਜਰਨਲ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ 'ਸਰਵਸ੍ਰੇਸ਼ਠ ਰਾਜਨੀਤੀਵਾਨ ਦਰਜਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ।ਏਮਜ਼ ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਦੇ ਡਾਕਟਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ, 6 ਅਗਸਤ 2019 ਦੀ ਰਾਤ ਨੂੰ ਦਿਲ ਦਾ ਦੌਰਾ ਪੈਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਸਵਰਾਜ ਦੀ ਦਿਲ ਦਾ ਦੌਰਾ ਪੈਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਗਈ। ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਜਨਤਕ ਮਾਮਲਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ 2020 ਵਿੱਚ ਮਰਨ ਉਪਰੰਤ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਦੂਜੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੇ ਨਾਗਰਿਕ ਪੁਰਸਕਾਰ, ਪਦਮ ਵਿਭੂਸ਼ਣ ਨਾਲ ਸਨਮਾਨਿਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ।== ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤੀ ਜੀਵਨ ਅਤੇ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ==ਸੁਸ਼ਮਾ ਸਵਰਾਜ (née ਸ਼ਰਮਾ) ਦਾ ਜਨਮ 14 ਫਰਵਰੀ 1952 ਨੂੰ ਅੰਬਾਲਾ ਛਾਉਣੀ, ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਵਿਖੇ ਇੱਕ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਬ੍ਰਾਹਮਣ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹਰਦੇਵ ਸ਼ਰਮਾ ਅਤੇ ਸ਼੍ਰੀਮਤੀ ਲਕਸ਼ਮੀ ਦੇਵੀ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਇੱਕ ਪ੍ਰਮੁੱਖ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਸਵੈਮ ਸੇਵਕ ਸੰਘ ਦੇ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਸਨ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਾਤਾ-ਪਿਤਾ ਲਾਹੌਰ, ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਧਰਮਪੁਰਾ ਇਲਾਕੇ ਦੇ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਸਨ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਅੰਬਾਲਾ ਛਾਉਣੀ ਦੇ ਸਨਾਤਨ ਧਰਮ ਕਾਲਜ ਤੋਂ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਸਕ੍ਰਿਤ ਤੇ ਰਾਜਨੀਤੀ ਸ਼ਾਸਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੇਜਰਸ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਬੈਚਲਰ ਦੀ ਡਿਗਰੀ ਹਾਸਲ ਕੀਤੀ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਯੂਨੀਵਰਸਿਟੀ, ਚੰਡੀਗੜ੍ਹ ਤੋਂ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਦੀ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਕੀਤੀ। ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਦੇ ਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਵਿਭਾਗ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਆਯੋਜਿਤ ਇੱਕ ਰਾਜ-ਪੱਧਰੀ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਯੋਗਿਤਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸਨੂੰ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਤਿੰਨ ਸਾਲਾਂ ਲਈ ਸਰਵੋਤਮ ਹਿੰਦੀ ਸਪੀਕਰ ਦਾ ਪੁਰਸਕਾਰ ਜਿੱਤਿਆ ਗਿਆ।== ਵਕਾਲਤ ਕਰੀਅਰ ==1973 ਵਿੱਚ, ਸਵਰਾਜ ਨੇ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀ ਸੁਪਰੀਮ ਕੋਰਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਕੀਲ ਵਜੋਂ ਅਭਿਆਸ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤਾ। ਉਸ ਨੇ 1970 ਦੇ ਦਹਾਕੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਖਿਲ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਵਿਦਿਆਰਥੀ ਪ੍ਰੀਸ਼ਦ ਨਾਲ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਿਆਸੀ ਕਰੀਅਰ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਕੀਤੀ। ਉਸ ਦਾ ਪਤੀ, ਸਵਰਾਜ ਕੌਸ਼ਲ, ਸਮਾਜਵਾਦੀ ਨੇਤਾ ਜਾਰਜ ਫਰਨਾਂਡੀਜ਼ ਨਾਲ ਨੇੜਿਓਂ ਜੁੜਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਸੁਸ਼ਮਾ ਸਵਰਾਜ 1975 ਵਿੱਚ ਜਾਰਜ ਫਰਨਾਂਡੀਜ਼ ਦੀ ਕਾਨੂੰਨੀ ਬਚਾਅ ਟੀਮ ਦਾ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਬਣ ਗਈ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਜੈਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼ ਨਰਾਇਣ ਦੀ ਕੁੱਲ ਕ੍ਰਾਂਤੀ ਅੰਦੋਲਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਰਗਰਮੀ ਨਾਲ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਲਿਆ। ਐਮਰਜੈਂਸੀ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਹ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਜਨਤਾ ਪਾਰਟੀ 'ਚ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹੋ ਗਈ। ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਹ ਭਾਜਪਾ ਦੀ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਨੇਤਾ ਬਣ ਗਈ।== ਨਿੱਜੀ ਜੀਵਨ ==ਐਮਰਜੈਂਸੀ ਦੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਦੌਰਾਨ, 13 ਜੁਲਾਈ 1975 ਨੂੰ, ਸੁਸ਼ਮਾ ਸ਼ਰਮਾ ਨੇ ਸਵਰਾਜ ਕੌਸ਼ਲ ਨਾਲ ਵਿਆਹ ਕੀਤਾ, ਜੋ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀ ਸੁਪਰੀਮ ਕੋਰਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਸਾਥੀ ਅਤੇ ਸਾਥੀ ਵਕੀਲ ਸੀ। ਐਮਰਜੈਂਸੀ ਅੰਦੋਲਨ ਨੇ ਜੋੜੇ ਨੂੰ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕੀਤਾ, ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਫਿਰ ਸਮਾਜਵਾਦੀ ਨੇਤਾ ਜਾਰਜ ਫਰਨਾਂਡੀਜ਼ ਦੀ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਲਈ ਟੀਮ ਬਣਾਈ। ਸਵਰਾਜ ਕੌਸ਼ਲ, ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀ ਸੁਪਰੀਮ ਕੋਰਟ ਦੇ ਸੀਨੀਅਰ ਵਕੀਲ ਅਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਅਪਰਾਧਿਕ ਵਕੀਲ, ਨੇ 1990 ਤੋਂ 1993 ਤੱਕ ਮਿਜ਼ੋਰਮ ਦੇ ਰਾਜਪਾਲ ਵਜੋਂ ਵੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਕੀਤੀ। ਉਹ 1998 ਤੋਂ 2004 ਤੱਕ ਸੰਸਦ ਦੇ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਰਹੇ।ਇਸ ਜੋੜੇ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਧੀ, ਬੰਸੂਰੀ, ਹੈ ਜੋ ਆਕਸਫੋਰਡ ਯੂਨੀਵਰਸਿਟੀ ਤੋਂ ਗ੍ਰੈਜੂਏਟ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਅੰਦਰੂਨੀ ਮੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੈਰਿਸਟਰ ਹੈ।ਸੁਸ਼ਮਾ ਸਵਰਾਜ ਦੀ ਭੈਣ ਵੰਦਨਾ ਸ਼ਰਮਾ ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੜਕੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਇੱਕ ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਕਾਲਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਾਜਨੀਤੀ ਸ਼ਾਸਤਰ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਐਸੋਸੀਏਟ ਪ੍ਰੋਫੈਸਰ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਦਾ ਭਰਾ ਡਾ: ਗੁਲਸ਼ਨ ਸ਼ਰਮਾ ਅੰਬਾਲਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਥਿਤ ਇੱਕ ਆਯੁਰਵੇਦ ਡਾਕਟਰ ਹੈ।10 ਦਸੰਬਰ 2016 ਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਏਮਜ਼, ਦਿੱਲੀ ਵਿਖੇ ਇੱਕ ਕਿਡਨੀ ਟ੍ਰਾਂਸਪਲਾਂਟ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਅੰਗ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਜੀਵਤ ਗੈਰ-ਸੰਬੰਧਿਤ ਦਾਨੀ ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ਸਰਜਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਸਫਲ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ।== ਮੌਤ ==6 ਅਗਸਤ 2019 ਨੂੰ, ਸੁਸ਼ਮਾ ਸਵਰਾਜ ਨੂੰ ਕਥਿਤ ਤੌਰ 'ਤੇ ਸ਼ਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਦਿਲ ਦਾ ਦੌਰਾ ਪਿਆ, ਜਿਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਏਮਜ਼ ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਲਿਜਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ, ਜਿੱਥੇ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਿਲ ਦਾ ਦੌਰਾ ਪੈਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਉਸਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਗਈ। ਅਗਲੇ ਦਿਨ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਦੇ ਲੋਧੀ ਸ਼ਮਸ਼ਾਨਘਾਟ ਵਿਖੇ ਪੂਰੇ ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਸਨਮਾਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਉਸਦਾ ਅੰਤਿਮ ਸੰਸਕਾਰ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ।== ਅਹੁਦੇ ==1977–82 Elected as Member, Haryana Legislative Assembly.1977–79 Cabinet Minister, Labour and Employment, Government of Haryana.1987–90 Elected as Member, Haryana Legislative Assembly.1987–90 Cabinet Minister, Education, Food and Civil Supplies, Government of Haryana.1991–1996 Member of Rajya Sabha1996 [16 May – 1 June] – Union Cabinet Minister, Information and Broadcasting.2000–06 Member, Rajya Sabha (4th term).2006–09 [April 2006 -] Member, Rajya Sabha (5th term).2009–14 [16 May 2009 – 18 May 2014] Member, 15th Lok Sabha (6th term).2009-09 [3 June 2009 – 21 December 2009] Deputy Leader of the Opposition in the Lok Sabha.2009–2014 [21 December 2009 – 26 May 2014] Leader of Opposition in the Lok Sabha.2014–2019 [26 May 2014 – 24 May 2019] Member, 16th Lok Sabha (7th term).2014–2019 [26 May 2014 – 29 May 2019] Minister of External Affairs in the Union of India.== ਇਨਾਮ ਅਤੇ ਸਨਮਾਨ ===== ਰਾਜ ਸਨਮਾਨ === India:Padma Vibhushan (posthumously) (2020) Spain:Grand Cross of the Order of Civil Merit (19 February 2019)=== ਉਸ ਦੇ ਨਾਂ 'ਤੇ ਥਾਂਵਾਂ ===In 2020, Government of India renamed Foreign Service Institute of India after her as Sushma Swaraj Institute of Foreign Service.In 2020, Government of India renamed Pravasi Bharatiya Kendra after her as Sushma Swaraj Bhawan.The bus station of Ambala City is named after her in 2020.== ਹਵਾਲੇ ==== ਬਾਹਰੀ ਲਿੰਕ ==MEA : Profile of Minister of External AffairsDetailed Profile: Smt. Sushma SwarajOfficial Biographical Sketch in Lok Sabha Website"},{"question":"බෝසත් චරිතයේ එන  දෙව්දත් කුමරුගේ අරගල ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න.","answer":"හෙතෙම ක්‍ෂත්‍රියමානයෙන් මත් වූවෙකි සැඩ පරොස් පුද්ගලයෙකි. සිද්‍ධාර්ථ කුමාරයාණන් ඡන්න ආදී සේවකයන් ගේ දරුවන් හා මිත්‍ර ලීලාවෙන් ගැවසෙනු හේ නො ඉවසයි. තමාට පහත් අය හා සමාගම් නොපවත්වන්නැයි හේ බෝසතාණනට කියයි. බෝසතාණන්වහන්සේ ඔහු ගේ බසට කන් නො දෙති. එවිට දෙව්දත් කුමරා සුදොවුන් මහරජුන් වෙත ගොස් “සිදුහත් කුමරු පහත් කුලවලැ අය හා සමානයන් හා සේ එක් වැ ගැවසෙතැ”යි පැමිණිලි කෙරෙයි. බෝසතාණන්ගේ සැටි දන්නා රජ තුමා එයට කිසිවක් කියා ඔහු අස්වසයි."},{"question":"මෑඩ් මෙන් කතා මාලාව නිර්මාණය කලේ කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"මෑඩ් මෙන් (\\"Mad Men\\") රූපවාහිනී කතා මාලාව නිර්මාණය කරන ලද්දේ මැතිව් වීනර් (Matthew Weiner) විසිනි. එය 2007 ජූලි 19 වන දින AMC ජාලයේ තිරගත විය. 1960 ගණන්වල සිදුවන සිදුවීම දාමයක් මෙම කතාවට පදනම් වී ඇත. මූලික වශයෙන් නිව් යෝර්ක් නගරයේ මැඩිසන් ඇවනිව් හි  ස්ටර්ලිං කූපර් වෙළඳ ප්‍රචාරණ ආයතනයේ(ප්‍රබන්ධ), එහි සමාජීය ලක්ෂණ, විලාසිතා  සහ සංස්කෘතිය ඇතුළුව එම යුගයේ ලක්ෂණ සවිස්තරාත්මක සහ අව්‍යාජ ලෙස මෙමඟින් නිරූපණයවේ . මෙය කතා මාලාව වාර හතකට පසු 2015 මැයි 17 දින අවසන් විය."},{"question":"Tim Berners-Lee kimdir?","answer":"WWW'in babası olarak bilinen Tim Berners-Lee, 1989 yılında Avrupa Parçacık Fiziği Laboratuvarı CERN'deyken World Wide Web'i icat etti. 1990 yılında ilk web istemcisini ve sunucusunu yazdı. URI, HTTP ve HTML spesifikasyonları, Web teknolojisi yayıldıkça geliştirildi.Açık kaynaklı Solid platformunu kullanan, tanıtan ve geliştirmeye yardımcı olan bir teknoloji start-up'ı olan Inrupt.com'un kurucu ortağı ve CTO'sudur. Solid, web'in nasıl çalışması gerektiğine dair birçok varsayımı sorgulayarak insanlara verileri üzerinde kontrol ve yetki vermeyi amaçlıyor. Teknik olarak sağlam, web katmanında küresel tek oturum açma, evrensel erişim kontrolü ve evrensel veri API'si gibi orijinale hiçbir zaman dahil edilmeyen özellikler ekleyen ve böylece herhangi bir uygulamanın herhangi bir depolama alanında veri depolayabilmesini sağlayan yeni bir standart düzeyidir.Daha fazla bilgi için W3C sitesini ziyaret ediniz."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai balam dengan ketitir\\"?","answer":"Peribahasa ini bermaksud dua orang yang tidak dapat bermuafakat, membanggakan diri masing-masing."},{"question":"What are \\"Split Pins\\"?","answer":"\\"Split Pins\\" are sometimes called cotter pins, and they are made of annealed iron or brass wire. They are generally of semi-circular cross section and are used to prevent nuts from loosening. "},{"question":"Dümen kovanı neresi?","answer":"Dümen Kovanı: Dümen milinin içinden geçtiği dikey boru. Dümen Palası: Teknenin istenilen yönde gitmesini ve dönmesini sağlayan, kıç bodoslamaya takılan levha."},{"question":"உயர்திணை","answer":"உயர்திணை என்பது தமிழ் இலக்கணத்தில் தேவர், மாந்தர், நரகர் என்பவர்களை வகைப்படுத்தும் சொல்லாகும். இவர்களுக்கு உள்ளதெனக் குறிப்பிடப்படும் பகுத்தறிவு குறித்து இவ்வுயர்திணை என்ற பெயர் இடப்பட்டிருக்கலாம்"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'pacat hendak menjadi ular'? Berikan satu contoh ayat. ","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang miskin yang berlagak seperti orang kaya dan mengharapkan sesuatu yang tidak mungkin tercapai. Contohnya, kerenah Siti yang pacat hendak menjadi ular menyebabkannya kekurangan kawan kerana dia selalunya berlagak dan tidak menghormati orang lain. "},{"question":"* كم سنة عاش سيدنا عاش سيدنا إدريس ؟","answer":"83 سنة"},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang betul untuk soalan berikut: Apakah perkara yang perlu dirancang sebelum memulakan perjalanan?A. Makan sarapanB. Memeriksa keadaan kenderaanC. Mencuci kenderaan","answer":"Jawapannya ialah B. Memeriksa keadaan kenderaan"},{"question":"దాడిలో గాయపడ్డ బషీర్ ఖాన్ (36), సాదికా ఖాన్ (34), నజీర్ ఖాన్ (32), సందీప్ ఖాన్ (30)లను చికిత్స కోసం జింద్ ఆస్పత్రికి తరలించారు.ఈ సంఘటనకు సంబంధించి నలుగురు వ్యక్తుల మీద కేసు నమోదు చేసినట్లు డీఐజీ అశ్విన్ షేన్వీ బీబీసీకి తెలిపారు. దర్యాప్తు కొనసాగుతోందని, మరిన్ని వివరాలు దర్యాప్తులో తెలుస్తాయని చెప్పారు.బషీర్ ఖాన్ బీబీసీతో మాట్లాడుతూ.. ఏప్రిల్ 5వ తేదీ రాత్రి 9 గంటలకు అందరి లాగానే తాము కూడా తమదైన రీతిలో ప్రధానమంత్రి పిలుపును పాటిస్తున్నామని చెప్పారు. అయితే తమ ఇంటి వెలుపల ఉన్న ఒక బల్బును ఆర్పివేయలేదంటూ పొరుగింటి వ్యక్తి తమను అసభ్య పదజాలంతో దూషించారని పేర్కొన్నారు.అభ్యంతరకర భాష మీద ఆ రాత్రి తమ మధ్య వాగ్వాదం జరిగిందని, అది అంతటితో చల్లారిపోయిందని ఆయన చెప్పారు. మరుసటి రోజు ఉదయం తమ పొరుగింటి వ్యక్తి అభ్యంతరకర భాష వెనుక కారణాన్ని తెలుసుకోవటానికి తాము ప్రయత్నించామని.. వారంతా మళ్లీ తమ మీద విరుచుకుపడ్డారని తెలిపారు.కొంతసేపటి తర్వాత తమ ఇంట్లో కుర్చీలో కూర్చున్న తమ చిన్న తమ్ముడు సాదిక్ ఖాన్ మీద ఇరుగుపొరుగు వారు దాదాపు డజను మంది పదునైన ఆయుధాలతో దాడిచేశారని, అతడు తీవ్రంగా గాయపడ్డాడని, దీంతో ఇరు పక్షాల మధ్య ఘర్షణ జరిగిందని వివరించారు.‘‘మా నలుగురు సోదరులకూ తల, ముఖం, చేతులు, కాళ్ల మీద గాయాలయ్యాయి. మా చిన్న తమ్ముడికి తీవ్ర గాయాలయ్యాయి. విషమ పరిస్థితిలో ఉన్న అతడిని జింద్ జిల్లా ఆస్పత్రి నుంచి రోహతక్ లోని పీజీఐఎంఎస్ ఆస్పత్రికి తరలించారు’’ అని బషీర్ ఖాన్ చెప్పారు.తమ పొరుగున ఉండే హిందువులతో గొడవ జరగటం ఇది మొదటిసారి కాదని ఆయన పేర్కొన్నారు. దిల్లీలో నిజాముద్దీన్ కార్యక్రమానికి హాజరైన వారికి తాము ఆశ్రయం ఇచ్చినందుకు కూడా.. గ్రామస్తుల ఆరోగ్యాన్ని ప్రమాదంలోకి నెట్టారంటూ తమను లక్ష్యంగా చేసుకున్నారని ఆయన పేర్కొన్నారు.ఆదివారం రాత్రి 9 గంటలకు లైట్లు ఆర్పేయాలన్న ప్రధానమంత్రి పిలుపును గౌరవించకుండా సదరు ముస్లిం సోదరులు తప్పు చేయటం ఈ ఘర్షణకు దారితీసిందని ఖాన్ సోదరుల పొరుగున నివసించే సంజయ్ కుమార్ చెప్పారు.‘‘పొరుగిళ్ల వారు తమ లైట్లు ఆర్పేస్తే.. వారి బల్బు వెలుగుతూనే ఉంది. దానిని ఆర్పివేయాలని మేం వారికి చెప్పాం. అందుకు వారు స్పందించారు. ఆ తర్వాత.. వారు తమ కుటుంబ సభ్యుడు కాని ఒక బయటి వ్యక్తికి ఆశ్రయం ఇచ్చినట్లు మేం గుర్తించాం. దాని గురించి అడిగితే వారు మాతో గొడవకు దిగారు’’ అని ఆయన ఆరోపించారు.లైట్లు ఆర్పివేయాలన్న ప్రధాని పిలుపును... వినలేదని","answer":"హరియాణా: లైట్లు ఆర్పేయాలన్న మోదీ మాట వినలేదని.. నలుగురు ముస్లిం సోదరుల మీద దాడి"},{"question":"كم عدد الكروموزمات الصبغيات الموجودة في كل خلية؟","answer":"46 كروموزمة صبغية "},{"question":"\\"हरियो रसायन विज्ञान\\" को अवधारणा र दिगो र वातावरण मैत्री अभ्यासहरूमा यसको महत्त्व छलफल गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"हरियो रसायन विज्ञान रासायनिक प्रक्रिया र उत्पादनहरू डिजाइन गर्नमा केन्द्रित छ जसले वातावरणीय प्रभावहरूलाई कम गर्छ र स्थिरतालाई बढावा दिन्छ।"},{"question":"Ndàx man ngaa jubbanti mbind mii?Na nga bégal ña gëm tey jëf jëf yu sell, [xamal leen] ne am nañu àjjana joo xam ne ay dex a ngay daw ca suufam; saa su ñu leen xéewalee ci ay meññeet, muy la ñu leen wërsëgale, ñu naan: \\"Lii dey masoon nanu cee xéewlu ca bu jëkk [ca àddina]\\". Fekk dañu leen a jox lu nurook [la ñu xamoon ca àddina]; ñeel na leen it ca àjjana jooju ay jabar [soxna] yuñu laabal [ci bépp ayib], te ñoom dañu fay béel.","answer":"Waaw! Mi ngii:Na nga bégal ña gëm te'y jëf jëf yu sell, [xàmal léen] ne àm na ñu àjjana joo xàm ne ay dex a nga'y daw ca suufam; saa su ñu léen xéewalee ci ay meññeet, mu'y la ñu léen wërsagale, ñu naan: \\"Lii de masoon na nu cee xéewlu ca bu njëkk [ca àddina]\\". Fekk da ñu léen a jox lu nuroo'k [la ñu xàmoon ca àddina]; ñeel na léen ìt ca àjjana jooju ay jabar [soxna] yu ñu laabal [ci bépp ayib], te ñoom da ñu fa'y béel."},{"question":"Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa Eko ṣekilọ fawọn ọba alaye: Ẹ yee ṣonigbọwọ fawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun","answer":"Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko, CP Hakeem Odumosu, ti fi aidunnu rẹ han si bawọn ọba alaye atawọn olori ilu kan ṣe sọ ara wọn di agbodegba fawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun nipinlẹ Eko, o ni iwa to le ta epo s’aṣọ aala awọn ori ade naa ni.Odumosu fẹdun ọkan rẹ han nibi ipade itagbangba lori eto aabo agbegbe Ikorodu fun ọdun 2021, eyi to waye ni gbọngan apero ilu naa l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, yii.Odumosu ni ta a ba wo o lapapọ, eto aabo nipinlẹ Eko ti gbe pẹẹli si i, ṣugbọn ti agbegbe Ikorodu yii lo n fojoojumọ buru si i, tori laarin oṣu mẹfa pere, ojilenirugba ati meji (242) awọn afurasi adigunjale atọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun lọwọ awọn agbofinro tẹ lagbegbe Ikorodu nikan, ibọn mejidinlọgbọn (28) ati katiriiji ọta ibọn ti wọn o ti i yin bii ọgọfa (120) ni wọn ri gba lọwọ wọn.Laarin oṣu mẹfa yii kan naa, igba o din mẹjọ (192) lawọn iṣẹlẹ idaluru latọwọ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun to waye, mejidinlogun (18) ninu awọn iṣẹlẹ yii lo la itajẹsilẹ lọ, igba mẹẹẹdọgbọn (25) si lawọn ọlọpaa tu iṣẹlẹ idigunjale fo.Lati wa ojuutu si iṣoro yii, afi ki ijọba ibilẹ, awọn olori ilu, awọn ọba alaye atawọn baalẹ jọ fọwọsowọpọ lori ọrọ yii. O lo yẹ kawọn ori ade fi tinutinu dẹbi fun awọn ọmọ to n ṣẹgbẹ okunkun, dipo ti wọn aa fi maa ṣe koriya fun wọn, ti wọn aa maa bẹru wọn, tabi ki wọn fa wọn bọdi nigba mi-in, tabi ki wọn maa fi oye da wọn lọla.“Awọn oniṣẹṣe atawọn oloogun ibilẹ gbọdọ jawọ ninu ṣiṣe oogun abẹnugọngọ fawọn ẹlẹgbẹ okunkun, akoba nla ni aṣa naa n mu wa fun iṣẹ aabo ilu tawọn ọlọpaa n ṣe. Ọpọ igba lawọn ẹlẹgbẹ okunkun atawọn afurasi adigunjale n gboju le oriṣiiriṣii oogun abẹnugọngọ bii igbadi, ifunpa, onde, tira ti wọn so kọra lati ṣiṣẹ ibi wọn.“Ẹyin lanlọọdu ati lanledi, o yẹ kẹ ẹ ṣewadii gidi tawọn ọmọkọmọ wọnyi ba fẹẹ gba ile lọwọ yin. Ko yẹ kẹ ẹ da gbogbo ẹ da kiateka nikan. To ba si jẹ lẹyin ti wọn ti gba ile tan lẹ too fura, ki lo de tẹ o ki i jẹ kawọn agbofinro gbọ, ka si ran yin lọwọ nitori ibẹru?Ni ti awọn aṣaaju ẹsin, dipo ki iwaasu wọn da lori bawọn eeyan ṣe gbọdọ di olowo ati ọlọrọ, niṣe lo yẹ ki wọn kọ wọn lati jẹ eeyan alaafia, ki wọn si maa ṣi wọn leti nipa ibaṣepọ ati igbesi aye alaafia ati aabo.”Odumosu ni ko sẹni to mọ awọn agbegbe naa to awọn ọba alaye atawọn baalẹ adugbo, ati pe bi ina ko ba ni awo, ko le jo goke odo, bii owe Yoruba ṣe sọ.Lara awọn eeyan pataki to wa nikalẹ lọjọ naa ni Ayangburẹn tilu Ikorodu, Ọba Kabiru Shotobi, Adeboruwa ti ilu Igbogbo, Ọba Sẹmiudeen Kasali, Alaga ijọba ibilẹ Ikorodu, Ọnarebu Wasiu Adeṣina, atawọn ọba alaye mi-in."},{"question":"ما هو اسم السورة التي عرفت باسم أحد كواكب المجموعة الشمسية؟","answer":"الإجابة: سورة القمر."},{"question":"వినీత అసంభవ ఘటనల సంభావ్యత ‘1’ అని, ధనలక్ష్మి ఖచ్చిత ఘటనల సంభావ్యత ‘0’ అని, శిరీష ఏదేని ఘటనల సంభావ్యత 0 నుండి 1 వరకు ఉండునని చెప్పిన, వీరిలో ఎవరితో ఏకీభవిస్తావు ?","answer":"శిరీష సమాధానంతో ఏకీభవిస్తాను."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai kumbang putus tali\\"? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya. ","answer":"Ia bermaksud berasa gembira kerana baru terlepas dari seksaan. Contohnya, Chin Poh bagai kumbang putus tali apabila dia dibebas dari penjara."},{"question":"ઇન્સ્ટાગ્રામ પ્લેટફોર્મના  ઇતિહાસ વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"ઇન્સ્ટાગ્રામ એ એક અમેરિકન ફોટો અને વિડિઓ શેરિંગ સોશિયલ નેટવર્કિંગ સેવા છે જે મેટા પ્લેટફોર્મની માલિકીની છે.તે વપરાશકર્તાઓને મીડિયા અપલોડ કરવાની મંજૂરી આપે છે જે ફિલ્ટર્સ સાથે સંપાદિત કરી શકાય છે, હેશટેગ્સ દ્વારા ગોઠવી શકાય છે, અને ભૌગોલિક ટેગિંગ દ્વારા સ્થાન સાથે સંકળાયેલ છે.પોસ્ટ્સ સાર્વજનિક રૂપે અથવા પૂર્વવર્તી અનુયાયીઓ સાથે શેર કરી શકાય છે.વપરાશકર્તાઓ અન્ય વપરાશકર્તાઓની સામગ્રીને ટ s ગ્સ અને સ્થાનો દ્વારા બ્રાઉઝ કરી શકે છે, ફોટાઓ જેવી ટ્રેન્ડિંગ સામગ્રી જોઈ શકે છે, અને અન્ય વપરાશકર્તાઓને તેમની સામગ્રીને વ્યક્તિગત ફીડમાં ઉમેરવા માટે અનુસરી શકે છે.આઇઓએસ, એન્ડ્રોઇડ, વિન્ડોઝ 10 અને વેબ પર ઉપલબ્ધ મેટા સંચાલિત ઇમેજ-કેન્દ્રિત સોશિયલ નેટવર્કિંગ સેવા.વપરાશકર્તાઓ ફોટા લઈ શકે છે અને બિલ્ટ-ઇન ફિલ્ટર્સ અને અન્ય ટૂલ્સનો ઉપયોગ કરીને તેમને સંપાદિત કરી શકે છે, પછી તેમને ફેસબુક જેવા અન્ય સોશિયલ મીડિયા પ્લેટફોર્મ પર શેર કરી શકે છે.તે અંગ્રેજી, સ્પેનિશ, ફ્રેન્ચ, કોરિયન અને જાપાની સહિત 25 ભાષાઓને ટેકો આપે છે."},{"question":"\\"Terjemahkanlah penggalan teks dari Bahasa Jawa yang disadur dari kumpulan cerita anak dunia berikut ke teks dalam Bahasa Indonesia.\\"\\"Ayo dolan karo aku, Nga,\\"\\" ajake Citah. \\"\\"Cekelen aku yen isa!\\"\\" WUS! WUS! Citah mlayu. \\"\\"Emoh,\\"\\" wangsulane Singa. \\"\\"Mengko aku kalah.\\"\\"Terjemahan:\\"","answer":"\\"Hai, Singa, ayo sini main denganku,\\" ajak Citah. \\"Ayo, coba tangkap aku!\\" Set, set! Bunyi Citah berlari. \\"Aku tidak terlalu ingin bermain,\\" jawab Singa. \\"Toh aku akan kalah...\\""},{"question":"ලොව විශාලතම ඩයස්පෝරාව කුමක්ද?","answer":"ලොව විශාලතම ඩයස්පෝරාව ඉන්දියානු ඩයස්පෝරාව යි."},{"question":"\\"Ny basikety dia fomba tsara hijanonana ho mavitrika sy ho salama. Mitaky fifangaroan'ny fiaretana sy ny tanjaka ary ny hakingan-tsaina izy io, ka mahatonga azy io ho fanatanjahan-tena tsara ho an'ny fampandrosoana ara-batana. Ny filalaovana basikety tsy tapaka dia afaka manampy amin'ny fanatsarana ny fandrindrana, ny fifandanjana ary ny fahasalamana ankapobeny.\\". Inona ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io?","answer":"Ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io dia basikety."},{"question":"Napisz dalszy ciąg tego fragmentu: Po wcieleniu do brytyjskiej marynarki wojennej został skierowany na Morze Śródziemne, gdzie wszedł w skład amerykańskiej grupy okrętów US Task Force 85. W lipcu 1943 roku w składzie tej grupy wziął udział w operacji Husky...","answer":"... wspierając lądowanie wojsk amerykańskich na Sycylii. Następnie wspierał lądowanie wojsk alianckich pod Salerno w trakcie operacji Avalanche i w dniu 9 września 1943 roku został uszkodzony po wejściu na minę kontaktową."},{"question":"コップの下に敷くのはコースターですが、湯呑み茶碗に敷くものは何というでしょう？","answer":"茶托"},{"question":"వాక్యాలలో క్రియను గుర్తించడం :1. నేను బాగా చదువుతాను.2. ఎవరైనా ప్రశాంతంగా నిద్రపోవాలి.3. పోలీసును చూసి దొంగ పరుగెత్తాడు.4. భారతదేశంలో పేదరికాన్ని రూపుమాపాలి.5. దేవదత్తుడు వంటచేశాడు.","answer":"ఏ కాలంలోనైనా జరిగిన పనిని సూచించేది క్రియ.చదువుకొను, నిద్రించు, వచ్చు, పరుగెత్తు, వండు మొదలైనవి.1. చదువుతాను.2. ప్రశాంతంగా3. పరుగెత్తాడు.4. రూపుమాపాలి.5. వంటచేశాడు."},{"question":"भारत के विभिन्न भौगोलिक क्षेत्रों और उनकी विशेषताओं का विस्तार से वर्णन करें।","answer":"भारत विविध भौगोलिक विशेषताओं वाला देश है। हिमालय पर्वत उत्तर में स्थित है, जो ठंडे और बर्फीले क्षेत्र हैं। मैदानी क्षेत्र जैसे कि गंगा और ब्रह्मपुत्र के मैदान उपजाऊ और घनी आबादी वाले हैं। पश्चिम में थार मरुस्थल है, और दक्षिण में तटीय क्षेत्र और पठारी इलाके हैं।उत्तर:द रियल डील"},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජාතික ක්‍රිකට් කණ්ඩායම ටෙස්ට් ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩා කිරීම ආරම්භ කළේ කවදාද, ඔවුන් ක්‍රීඩා කළේ කාට එරෙහිවද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජාතික කණ්ඩායම 1982 දී ටෙස්ට් ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩා කිරීම ආරම්භ කළ අතර ඔවුන්ගේ පළමු ටෙස්ට් තරගය එංගලන්තයට එරෙහිව විය."},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Hồi giữa tháng 7, Bộ trưởng Quốc phòng Ukraine Aleksei Reznikov cho biết, Tổng thống Zelensky đã yêu cầu ông huy động 1 triệu binh sỹ để giải phóng miền Nam Ukraine. Gần đây, ông Sergiy Khlan - trợ lý Tổng thống Zelensky, nói rằng Kiev đã đạt bước ngoặt ở khu vực này và \\"chắc chắn sẽ giải phóng Kherson trước tháng 9\\". Với những tuyên bố mạnh mẽ của Ukraine, nhiều người cho rằng, tình hình chiến sự đang đảo chiều theo hướng bất lợi với Nga. Trong những tuần qua, các lực lượng Ukraine đã tập trung nỗ lực giành lại quyền kiểm soát Kherson. Ông Zelensky cho biết, quân đội Ukraine đang từng bước tiến tới việc chiếm lại khu vực phía Nam, sử dụng hệ thống pháo phản lực cơ động cao (HIMARS) để dội hỏa lực vào các mục tiêu của Nga và làm hư hại nghiêm trọng câu cầu bắc qua sông Dnipro. Việc mất cây cầu này có thể cản trở nỗ lực chiến đấu của quân đội Nga tại Kherson. ","answer":"Nước cờ táo bạo của Ukraine trong kế hoạch phản công Nga để giành lại Kherson"},{"question":"Emerson, Lake & Palmer nedir? ","answer":"Emerson, Lake & Palmer (ELP), 1970'te Londra'da kurulmuş bir progresif rock grubudur. Grup, Nice'den Keith Emerson (klavye), King Crimson'dan Greg Lake (vokal, bas, gitar, yapımcı) ve Atomic Rooster'dan Carl Palmer'dan (davul, perküsyon) oluşuyordu. Özellikle 1970'li yıllarda çok popüler olan grup, 40 milyondan fazla albüm satmış ve devasa konserlere imza atmıştır. "},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn dưới đây và sau đó trả lời câu hỏi sau đó ở cuối:  Bella Swan là một cô gái mười bảy tuổi, người chuyển từ Phoenix, Arizona đến Forks, Washington trên bán đảo Olympic để sống với cha cô, Charlie. Mẹ cô ấy, Renée đang đi du lịch với chồng mới của cô ấy, Phil Dwyer, một cầu thủ bóng chày ở giải đấu nhỏ. Bella được nhận vào trường trung học Forks, nơi cô kết bạn với nhiều học sinh. Là một cô gái hơi thiếu kinh nghiệm và nhút nhát, Bella bị bối rối bởi một số cậu bé cạnh tranh cho sự chú ý của cô.  Câu hỏi: Bella là một cô gái thiếu kinh nghiệm và có tính cách như thế nào?","answer":"Bella là một cô gái thiếu kinh nghiệm và có tính cách nhút nhát, nên Bella bị bối rối bởi một số cậu bé cạnh tranh nhau, dành sự chú ý của cô.  "},{"question":"Scrivi il continuo per il seguente paragrafo - Nel 2004-05 la Juventus si piazzò al primo posto (titolo che le verrà tuttavia revocato nel 2006) davanti al Milan, in un'annata che vide le due rivali battagliare sino alla fine per il tricolore. Le sfide si conclusero con uno 0-0 a Torino e un 1-0 a Milano per i bianconeri: proprio nello scontro diretto dell'8 maggio 2005, una Juventus corsara vinse di misura grazie a Trezeguet. Nel 2005-06","answer":"Juventus e Milan finirono si piazzarono nuovamente al primo e secondo posto, tuttavia entrambi subirono le decisioni della giustizia sportiva a seguito di \\"Calciopoli\\": i piemontesi vennero declassati all'ultimo posto e retrocessi in serie cadetta, mentre i lombardi furono penalizzati di 30 punti, sanzione che precluse loro la possibilità di fregiarsi di un titolo finito all'Inter terza classificata. In quella stagione i rossoneri s'imposero in casa per 3-1, mentre a Torino la gara si risolse a reti bianche. Nel 2008-09 i bianconeri si classificarono secondi, davanti al Milan terzo. Entrambe le squadre conclusero a quota 74 punti, ma la Juventus trasse vantaggio dai risultati maturati negli scontri diretti: vittoria 4-2 a Torino, e pareggio 1-1 a Milano."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk hati dan limpa goreng kunyit? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah secara terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan:  300 gm hati & limpa, 1 biji bawang besar, 3 ulas bawang putih, 4 batang kacang panjang, 3 biji cili padi, ½ sudu kecil serbuk kunyit, ½ sudu kecil garam, ½ sudu kecil sebuk lada hitam, Serbuk perasa, 3 sudu besar minyak masakCara penyediaan:1. Potong dadu hati, potong nipis limpa, kerana limpa lebih susah empuk berbanding hati. Rendam sekejap (10 minit) dalam air yang dicampur tepung gandum untuk menghilangkan bau hamis lembu. Kemudian bilas dan tuskan.2. Gaulkan hati dan limpa dengan serbuk kunyit, garam dan serbuk perasa (jika suka).3. Hiris bulat bawang besar dan hiris nipis bawang putih.4. Potong kacang panjang dan cili padi.Cara memasak:1. Masukkan hati dan limpa lembu ke dalam kuali. Masukkan air hingga tenggelam hati & limpa danmasukkan sesudu besar minyak. Rebus dengan api sederhana sehingga empuk.2. Setelah hati & limpa empuk dan air kering, masukkan minyak selebihnya. Goreng sambil mengacausehingga hati dan limpa garing mengikut citarasa anda.3. Masukkan kacang panjang, bawang putih dan lada hitam. Kacau sekejap. Kemudian masukkan hirisanbawang besar, cili padi dan kacau sehingga bawang layu.4. Matikan api, angkat dan hidangkan."},{"question":"Hãy chọn đáp án đúng nhất cho câu hỏi sau:Trong các thành phố dưới đây, ở đâu được coi là đô thị đặc biệt?a. Hà Nội, Đà Nẵng, TP HCMb. Hà Nội, TP HCMc. Hà Nội, Đà Nẵng, Phú Quốc, TP HCM","answer":"b. Hà Nội, TP HCMHà Nội và TP HCM là đô thị đặc biệtTheo Luật Quy hoạch đô thị, đô thị là khu vực tập trung dân cư sinh sống có mật độ cao và chủ yếu hoạt động trong lĩnh vực kinh tế phi nông nghiệp; là trung tâm chính trị, hành chính, kinh tế, văn hoá hoặc chuyên ngành, có vai trò thúc đẩy sự phát triển kinh tế - xã hội của quốc gia hoặc một vùng lãnh thổ, một địa phương.Nghị quyết số 1210/2016 của Ủy ban Thường vụ Quốc hội xếp đô thị thành sáu loại gồm: đặc biệt, loại I, loại II, loại III, loại IV và loại V. Việc phân loại theo các tiêu chí cơ bản: vị trí, chức năng, vai trò, cơ cấu và trình độ phát triển kinh tế - xã hội của đô thị; quy mô dân số; mật độ dân số; tỷ lệ lao động phi nông nghiệp; trình độ phát triển cơ sở hạ tầng. Đô thị đặc biệt được quy định có vị trí, chức năng, vai trò là thủ đô hoặc trung tâm tổng hợp cấp quốc gia, quốc tế về kinh tế, tài chính, văn hóa, giáo dục, đào tạo, du lịch, y tế, khoa học và công nghệ.Đô thị đặc biệt còn là đầu mối giao thông, giao lưu trong nước và quốc tế, có vai trò thúc đẩy sự phát triển kinh tế - xã hội của cả nước. Quy mô dân số đô thị đặc biệt từ 5 triệu người trở lên; khu vực nội thành đạt từ 3 triệu người trở lên.Hà Nội và TP HCM là hai thành phố được xếp loại đô thị đặc biệt. Thủ đô Hà Nội rộng hơn 3.358 km2 với dân số hơn 8,2 triệu người. TP HCM rộng 2.095 km2, dân số gần 10 triệu người (theo Tổng cục Thống kê, năm 2021)."},{"question":"1) දෙවියන්ට බාරයක් වී කාරණය ඉශ්ට වු පසු බාරය නිදහස් නොකලොත් වස් වදිනවද ?2) වස් වැදුනොත් කල යුත්තේ කුමක් ද ?","answer":"හොදම දේ භාරය ඔප්පු කිරීම, ඒක තමයි පහසුම දේ"},{"question":"கேள்வி:  தமிழ் உரைநடையின் தந்தை யார் ?","answer":"விடை : தமிழ் உரைநடையின் தந்தை ஆறுமுக நாவலர் ஆவார்.வாழ்க்கைக் குறிப்பு:தோற்றம்ஆறுமுக நாவலர் யாழ்ப்பாணம், நல்லூர் என்னும் ஊரில் 1822 டிசம்பர் 18 இல் புதன்கிழமை அவிட்ட நட்சத்திரத்தில் கந்தப்பிள்ளை - சிவகாமி அம்மையார் தம்பதிகளுக்கு இறுதி மகனாகப் பிறந்தார். நாவலரின் இயற்பெயர் ஆறுமுகம் என்பதாகும். தகப்பனார் ப. கந்தப்பிள்ளை, பேரன் பரமானந்தர், பூட்டன் இலங்கைக்காவல முதலியார் ஆகிய அனைவரும் தமிழ் அறிஞர்கள். அரசாங்கத்தில் வேலை பார்த்தவர்கள். நாவலருக்கு நான்கு மூத்த சகோதரர்களும் மூன்று சகோதரிகளும் இருந்தனர். சகோதரர்கள் நால்வரும் அரசாங்க உத்தியோகத்தர்கள். சகோதரிகளுள் ஒருவர் வித்துவசிரோமணி பொன்னம்பல பிள்ளை அவர்களின் தாயார்.கல்விஐந்தாவது வயதில் வித்தியாரம்பம் செய்யப்பெற்ற நாவலர், நல்லூர் சுப்பிரமணிய உபாத்தியாயரிடம் நீதிநூல்களையும் தமிழையும் கற்றார். ஒன்பதாவது வயதில் தந்தையை இழந்தார். மூத்த தமையனாரால் முதலில் சரவணமுத்துப் புலவரிடமும் பின்னர் அவரது குருவாகிய சேனாதிராச முதலியாரிடமும் உயர்கல்வி கற்க அனுப்பப்பட்டார். பன்னிரண்டாவது வயதிலேயே தமிழ், சமஸ்கிருதம் ஆகிய மொழிகளைக் கற்றுப் புலமை பெற்றார்.யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் அக்காலத்திலிருந்த முன்னணி ஆங்கிலப் பாடசாலையான வெஸ்லியன் ஆங்கிலப் பாடசாலையில் (இக்காலத்து யாழ்ப்பாணம் மத்திய கல்லூரி) கற்று ஆங்கிலத்திலும் திறமை பெற்றார். அவரது 19-ஆவது வயதில் (1841) அப்பாடசாலையில் ஆசிரியராகப் பணியேற்ற நாவலர், அப்பாடசாலையின் நிறுவனராயும், அதிபராயுமிருந்த பேர்சிவல் எனும் பாதிரியாருக்குக் கிறித்தவ விவிலியத்தைத் தமிழில் மொழி பெயர்க்கும் வேலைக்கு உதவியாக இருந்து பணியாற்றினார். பேர்சிவல் பாதிரியாருடன் சென்னைப்பட்டணம் சென்று அச்சிடுவித்துக் கொண்டு யாழ்ப்பாணம் திரும்பினார்.பணிகள்சமயப் பணிசைவத் தமிழ்ப் பண்பாட்டுக்கு இசைவான கல்வி, சைவசமய வளர்ச்சி, தமிழ் வளர்ச்சி ஆகிய நோக்கங்களுக்காகப் பணிபுரியத் தொடங்கினார் நாவலர். சைவ சமயம் வளரும் பொருட்டு பிரசங்கம் செய்வதெனத் தீர்மானித்தார். இவரது முதற் பிரசங்கம் வண்ணார்பண்ணை வைத்தீஸ்வரன் கோவிலில் டிசம்பர் 31, 1847-ஆம் நாள் நடைபெற்றது. பின்னர் ஒவ்வொரு வெள்ளிக்கிழமையிலும் பிரசங்கம் செய்தார். இப்பிரசங்கங்களின் விளைவாகப் பெரும் சமய விழிப்புணர்வு ஏற்பட்டது.வண்ணார்பண்ணையில் சைவப்பிரகாச வித்தியாசாலை என்ற பெயரில் ஒரு சைவப் பாடசாலையை ஆரம்பித்தார். சமய வளர்ச்சிக்குத் தமது முழு நேரத்தையும் செலவிடத் தீர்மானித்து செப்டம்பர் 1848-இல் தமது மத்திய கல்லூரி, 3 பவுன் மாதச் சம்பள, ஆசிரியப் பணியைத் துறந்தார்.அச்சுப் பணிசைவப்பிள்ளைகளுக்குப் பாடநூல்கள் அச்சிடுவதற்கு அச்சியந்திரம் வாங்குவதற்காக நல்லூர் சதாசிவம்பிள்ளையுடன் 1849 ஆடி மாதம் சென்னை சென்றார். அங்கு திருவாவடுதுறை ஆதீனத்தில் சைவப்பிரசங்கம் செய்து தமது புலமையை வெளிப்படுத்தி நாவலர் பட்டத்தைப் பெற்றார். சென்னையில் சிலகாலமிருந்து சூடாமணி நிகண்டையும் சௌந்தரியலகரி உரையும் அச்சிற் பதித்தபின் ஓர் அச்சியந்திரத்துடன் யாழ்ப்பாணம் திரும்பினார்.தமது இல்லத்தில் வித்தியானுபாலனயந்திரசாலை என்னும் பெயரில் ஓர் அச்சுக்கூடம் நிறுவி பாலபாடம், ஆத்திசூடி, கொன்றைவேந்தன் உரை, சிவாலயதரிசனவிதி, சைவசமயசாரம், கொலை மறுத்தல், நன்னூல் விருத்தியுரை, திருச்செந்தினிரோட்டக யமகவந்தாதியுரை, திருமுருகாற்றுப்படையுரை போன்ற பல நூல்களை அச்சிட்டார். திருத்தொண்டர் பெரியபுராணத்தை வசன நடையில் எழுதி அச்சிட்டார். ஞானக்கும்மி, யேசுமதபரிகாரம், வச்சிரதண்டம் ஆகிய நூல்களை வெளியிட்டார்.தமிழகப் பணிஇவரது பணி இலங்கையில் மட்டுமன்றித் தமிழ் நாட்டிலும் பரவியிருந்தது. சென்னையில் திருவாசகம், திருக்கோவையார் நூல்களை 1859 வைகாசி மாதம் வெளியிட்டார். பெரியதொரு அச்சியந்திரத்தை விலைக்கு வாங்கிச் சென்னை தங்கசாலைத் தெருவில் வித்தியானுபாலன இயந்திரசாலை என்ற அச்சகம் நிறுவிப் பல நூல்களையும் அச்சிட்டார். சென்னையிலும் திருவாவடுதுறை மற்றும் திருநாகைக்கோராணம் ஆகிய இடங்களில் தங்கிச் சைவப்பிரசங்கங்கள் செய்தபின் 1862 பங்குனியில் யாழ்ப்பாணம் திரும்பினார்.1863 மார்கழியில் மீண்டும் தமிழகம் சென்றார். அங்கு இராமநாதபுர சமஸ்தானத்தில் பிரசங்கம் செய்தார். அங்கிருந்து மதுரை சென்று மீனாட்சியம்மை சந்நிதானத்திலே பிரசங்கித்து மீனாட்சிக்கு அணிவிக்கப்பெற்ற பரிவட்டமும் பூமாலையும் அணிவிக்கப்பட்டு ஆசீர்வதிக்கப்பட்டார்.குன்றக்குடியிலுள்ள திருவண்ணாமை ஆதீனத்தில் அவர் செய்த பிரசங்கத்தை மெச்சி நாவலரைப் பல்லக்கில் ஏற்றித் தம்பிரான்கள், ஓதுவார்கள் சூழ்ந்து வரச் சகல விருதுகள், மங்கல வாத்தியங்களுடன் பட்டணப் பிரவேசம் செய்வித்தார்கள். அங்கிருந்து திருப்பெருந்துறை, திருப்புள்ளிருக்குவேளூர், சீர்காழி ஆகிய தலங்களை வணங்கிச் சிதம்பரம் சேர்ந்தார். அங்கு 1864 ஐப்பசியில் சிதம்பரம் சைவப்பிரகாச வித்தியாசாலையை நிறுவினார்.1866 மார்கழி மாதம் சென்னை திரும்பி சைவப்பிரசங்கங்கள் செய்வதிலும் நூல்கள் அச்சிட்டு வெளியிடுவதிலும் நாவலர் ஈடுபட்டார்."},{"question":"Báwo ni wọ́n ṣe máa ń kí babaláwo ní ilẹ̀ Yorùbá? ","answer":"A ó sọ pé \\"Aború bọyè oo\\", babaláwo náà yóò sì dáhùn pé \\"A bọyè bọ ṣíṣẹ ooo\\" "},{"question":"Gịnị bụ azịza gwam gwam gwam(riddle) aGwa m ihe gị na ya soro baa n'ọhịa, o buru gị ụzọ pụta","answer":"Ọ bụ Ntụ"},{"question":"Сформулюйте відповідь на питання: Коли Чарльз Хатчісон і Вільям К. Говард були активні в кіноіндустрії одночасно?","answer":"В період 1921-1946 рр."},{"question":"කුළු බඩු පිළිබඳ ඉතිහාසය ගැන කථා කරමු.","answer":"ශීතකරණ හෝ අධිශීතකරණ නොතිබුණ යුගයන්හි දී ලෝකයේ විවිධ කලාපවල ජීවත් වූ ජනයා තමන්ට ආවේණික වූ ස්වභාවික ක‍්‍රමයක් මඟින් ආහාර සංරක්ෂණයට පෙළඹී සිටියහ. විශේෂයෙන් යුරෝපීයයන්ට ශීතකාලයේදී තම ආහාර සංරක්ෂණය කරගැනීම ගැටළුවක් වූ අතර කුළු බඩු වර්ග භාවිතා කිරීමෙන් එම ගැටළුව විසඳා ගැනීමට ඔවුන් සමත්විය. මෙහිදී කුළු බඩු සඳහා බටහිර රටවල ඉතා ඉහළ ඉල්ලුමක් පැවතුණි. 15 වන ශතවර්ෂයට පෙර කුළු බඩු වෙළඳාම, අරාබි වෙළඳුන් විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලැබිණි. ලෝකයේ පෙරදිග කලාපයට අයත් රටවල්වල තිබුණු කුළු බඩු වර්ග ඒකරාශී කරමින් කොන්ස්තන්තිනෝපලය හරහා මධ්‍යධරණී වරායන් වෙත ගෙනඑමින් එම කුළු බඩු බටහිර රටවල් වෙත අළෙවි කිරීමේ කාර්යය දීර්ඝ කාලයක් පුරා අරාබි වෙළඳුන් විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලැබිණි. එ‍හෙත් නාවික කටයුතු ආරම්භ කිරීමත් සමඟ යුරෝපීයයන් නැගෙනහිර ප‍්‍රදේශවලට යාත‍්‍රා කල අතර පෙරදිග ඉන්දියා වෙළඳ සමාගම වැනි වෙළඳ සමාගම් මගින් අරාබීන් සතුව පැවති කුළු බඩු ඒකාධිකාරය බිඳ දමන ලදි. යුරෝපා ජාතිකයන් ලෝකයේ අප‍්‍රිකා සහ ආසියා මහද්වීප තුළ තම බලය පතුරුවන ලද අතර යුරෝපා වෙළඳපල තුළ කුළු බඩු සඳහා තිබුණු ඉහළ ඉල්ලුමට සරිලන දායකත්වයක් සැපයීම වෙනුවෙන් කැපවිය."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe famadihana ?","answer":"Ny atao hoe famadihana dia famonosana lamba vaovao ny razana izay efa maty na koa famongarana azy indray.Fomba fampitana ny maty ho amin’ny tontolon’ny razana.Marihina fa tsy ny rehetra no mamadika. Ohatra ny andriana. "},{"question":"13 neyi temsil eder?","answer":"13 sayısı, özellikle Hristiyanlık inancı tarafından uğursuz olarak kabul edilmiştir. 13 sayısı, 12'den sonraki ve 14'ten önceki bir tek tam sayıdır. 13, aynı zamanda bir asal sayıdır. Asal olmakla kalmaz, aynı zamanda bir ''lasa sayısı''dır."},{"question":"Sinds wanneer heeft de SR22 een glazen cockpit?","answer":"Sinds februari 2003 begon Cirrus SR22's aan te bieden met een glazen paneel. Eerst werd de Avidyne Entegra aan klanten aangeboden. Ook werden retrofits beschikbaar gesteld voor oudere SR-versies. In mei 2008 onthulde Cirrus de \\"Cirrus Perspective\\" glazen cockpit, die gebaseerd was op instrumenten gemaakt door Garmin. Tot op de dag van vandaag levert Cirrus Garmin glazen cockpits in haar vliegtuigen."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Saya berdiri di tepi jalan, sesiapa pun boleh bercakap dengan saya hanya dengan bayar saya, siapa saya?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah telefon awam. "},{"question":"شعور کی نوعیت کیا ہے، اور کیا اس کی مکمل وضاحت نیورو سائنس اور بیالوجی سے کی جا سکتی ہے؟","answer":"شعور کی نوعیت فلسفہ میں ایک پیچیدہ اور زیر بحث موضوع ہے۔ جب کہ نیورو سائنس اور حیاتیات نے دماغ کے میکانزم کو سمجھنے میں اہم پیش رفت کی ہے، شعور کا ساپیکش تجربہ، جسے اکثر \\"مشکل مسئلہ\\" کہا جاتا ہے، مضطرب ہے۔ صرف جسمانی عمل کے ذریعے شعور کی وضاحت کرنا اس بارے میں سوالات اٹھاتا ہے کہ آیا موضوعی تجربات کو مکمل طور پر اعصابی سرگرمیوں تک کم کیا جا سکتا ہے یا اگر شعور کا کوئی ایسا پہلو ہے جو مادی دائرے سے باہر ہے۔"},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Thiên Lam","answer":"10 phim truyền hình ăn khách nhất Hàn Quốc mọi thời"},{"question":"葉がカラスのように黒く、龍のつめのように曲がっていることから名がついた中国茶の一種は何でしょう？","answer":"ウーロン（烏龍）茶"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Luathstair na hÉireann. ","answer":" Thrácht an staraí Rómhánach Avienus ina shaothar Ora Maritima ar Éirinn mar insula sacra, is é sin, an t-oileán naofa. Bhí Avienus ag scríobh sa cheathrú haois i ndiaidh bhreith Chríost, ach má bhí, chuaigh sé go mór i dtuilleamaí seanfhoinsí Gréigise agus é ag tagairt d'Éirinn. Dúirt sé freisin gurbh iad gens hiernorum a bhí ina gcónaí san oileán, agus is dócha go raibh baint éigin le hainm na treibhe sin le Hibernia nó le hÉirinn. Is deacair a rá, áfach, an ionann an treibh sin agus na Ceiltigh, nó níl na saineolaithe féin ar aon fhocal faoi, an ainm Ceilteach é Éire nó Ériu ar dtús. Na Gréagaigh a bhreac síos na foinsí a bhí in úsáid ag Avienus, bhí siad beo timpeall ar lár na mílaoise deireanaí roimh bhreith Chríost, faoin am a raibh na Ceiltigh díreach ag déanamh a ngabháltais ar Éirinn. Ní féidir a bheith cinnte, mar sin, an raibh an t-ainm sin Ériu nó Éire ag tabhairt do dhream acu siúd a raibh cónaí orthu sa tír roimh theacht na gCeilteach, nó an dream Ceilteach ab ea iad siúd."},{"question":"வினா: முழவு + அதிர என்பதனைச் சேர்த்தெழுதக் கிடைக்கும் சொல் …………………….அ) முழவுதிரஆ) முழவுதிரைஇ) முழவதிரஈ) முழவு அதிர","answer":"பதில்: இ) முழவதிர"},{"question":"මෙන්න යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"මෙන්න යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය අන්න වේ.  "},{"question":"May tatlo akong mansanas, apat na pinya, at dalawang saging. Ilan ang lahat ng prutas ko?","answer":"Mayroon kang 3 + 4 + 2 = 9 o siyam na prutas."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai kera dapat canggung\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud \\"perihal orang yang telah ditolong mendampingkan dirinya kepada orang yang menolongnya\\"."},{"question":"Φράση 1: Η Siemens AG ήταν ο κύριος ανάδοχος, με τις Fiat Ferroviaria και ADtranz ως υπεργολάβους. Φράση 2: Προς το παρόν, η Siemens AG είναι ο κύριος εργολάβος και η Fiat Ferroviaria και η ADtranz οι υπεργολάβοι. Ερώτηση: Η φράση 1 και η φράση 2 εκφράζουν το ίδιο νόημα; - Ναι ή όχι;","answer":"Ναι."},{"question":"什麼是加密代幣？","answer":"加密代幣(Crypto Token)是在現有加密貨幣的區塊鏈上被代幣化的資產或利益的表示形式。加密代幣和加密貨幣有很多相似之處，但加密貨幣的目的是作為交換媒介、支付手段以及價值的衡量和儲存。加密代幣通常用於籌集項目資金，並且通常通過初始代幣發行（ICO）過程來創建、分發、銷售和流通，其中包括一輪群眾募資。"},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన పదంతో వాక్య ప్రయోగం చెయ్యండి:మైత్రి","answer":"దుర్జనులతో మైత్రి చేయవద్దు."},{"question":"Ngiyabonga sayitsheni. Ukube anifikanga ngabe indaba yamiisingumlando. Ngibonga kakhulu sayitsheni.Ubonga ngakhona Duma kodwa nguwe oyimbangela yalokhu.Usho ukuthini sayitsheni? Yimi yini ovimba intuthuko lapha kulendawo?Uyakhumbula ngikubuza ukuthi uyathathisa na enkosini umauzokwenza utho endaweni yayo? Wathini wena? Angithi wadazainkani? Nenhlangano yakho yaphinde yakuyala ngokuhlonipha inkosi,wena wenza okuthandwa nguwe. Bafile-ke manje abantu. UMbandlwasiyezwa ukuthi ubengungqa phambili ekutheni wenze lokhuobukwenza. Naye uDlamini kuyavela ukuthi ubethukuthela aze enzeizinto ezingalungile njengakho ukushaya uMbandlwa.Angimsoli-ke yena kakhulu ngoba ubehlukunyezwa ngukubona wenauthela inkosi yakhe ngothuli.(ukuzithoba kuyadlondlobala. Useze watshekisa ngisho nekhanda.Izandla zakhe ulokhu ezihlanganisa njengomuntu okhuluma nomuntuamhlonipha ngendlela exakile) Ngiyezwa sayitsheni. (athule kancane)Sekwenzekile-ke okubuhlungu sayitsheni. Ngiyaphinda ngithi velesekonakele. Manje, ngizocela nigcine ukuthula endaweni, minasengizowuyeka-ke lo msebenzi wobukhansela.(enyuse izwi ngenxa yentukuthelo) Uthini? Uyeke? Niqala izinto besenigabisa ngokuyeka uma sekonakele? Lutho! Wena yelekelelaekucisheni lo mlilo wothathe osuwokhele.Kahle sayitsheni. Ngizowucisha kanjani lo mlilo? Bazongibulala phelaabantu..1. Kwaba namthelela muni ukuba khona kukaDabula noFohloza empilweniyenkosi uShandu?","answer":"Babevikela inkosi nomndeni wayo njengoba kwakunesimo sodlame.√√/Inkosi yakwazi ukuqhubeka isebenze ngokukhululeka ngoba yayaziukuthi iphephile"},{"question":"Tổng (hiệu) chia hết cho 9 là:A. 1 215 + 1 356B. 6 543 – 1 234C. 1 . 2 . 3 . 4 . 5 + 27D. 1 . 2 . 3 . 4 . 5 . 6 + 27","answer":"Lời giảiVì 3 . 6 = 18 chia hết cho 9 nên theo tính chất chia hết của một tích ta có 1 . 2 . 3 . 4 . 5 . 6 chia hết cho 9  Lại có 27 có tổng các chữ số là 2 + 7 = 9 chia hết cho 9 nên 27 chia hết cho 9Do đó theo tính chất chia hết của một tổng ta có:1 . 2 . 3 . 4 . 5 . 6 + 27 chia hết cho 9.Chọn đáp án D."},{"question":"Sheeg sanadkii la-oofsaday rasuulka (NNKH)?","answer":"Waxa la-oofsaday 11-kii hijriyadda."},{"question":"Ano ang ibig sabihin kapag tinawag na \\"blooming\\" ang isang tao?","answer":"Ang ibig sabihin ng \\"blooming\\" sa pagtukoy sa isang tao, karaniwan sa mga babae, na masaya, maganda o kaaya-ayang tingnan. Maaaring ginagamit ang \\"blooming\\" bilang paghahalintulad ng issang taong masaya at may makulay na ekspresyon sa isang bulaklak na blooming o nagbubukas at nagiging makulay kapag sumiklab at tag-init. "},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia para esta categoría: Videojuegos. ","answer":"¿Blizzard creó la serie Diablo? Sí. "},{"question":"தட்டைப்புழுவின் விலங்கியல் பெயர்?","answer":"டீனியா."},{"question":"கேள்வி:சங்க இலக்கியம் ஓர் எடுத்துக்காட்டு எழுதுக.","answer":"பதில்:சங்க இலக்கியம் ஓர் எடுத்துக்காட்டுயாதும் ஊரே, யாவரும் கேளிர்;தீதும், நன்றும், பிறர் தர வாரா;நோதலும், தணிதலும், அவற்றோர் அன்ன;சாதலும் புதுவது அன்றே! வாழ்தல்இனிது என மகிழ்ந்தன்றும் இலமே! முனிவின்இன்னாது என்றலும் இலமே! மின்னொடுவானம் தண் துளி தலைஇ ஆனாது,கல்பொருது இரங்கும், மல்லல் பேர்யாற்றுநீர்வழிப் படூஉம் புனை போல், ஆருயிர்முறைவழிப் படூஉம் என்பது திறவோர்காட்சியில் தெளிந்தனம் ஆகலின், மாட்சியில்பெரியோரை வியத்தலும் இலமே!சிறியோரை இகழ்தல் அதனினும் இலமே!-கணியன் பூங்குன்றனார்(புறநானூறு - 192)"},{"question":"Ibi ti Ọlawale ti n kẹru ni ṣọọbu kan ni Surulere lawọn ọlọpaa ka a mọ","answer":"Ọjọ gbogbo ni t’ole, ọjọ kan ni tolohun. Ilẹ ọjọ kan ọhun lo mọ ba Ọlawale Samusudeen, ẹni ọdun mọkandilọgbọn to ko sakolo awọn ọlọpaa lalẹ Ọjọruu, ọjọ ki-in-ni, oṣu kẹsan-an yii, nibi to ti n ja oniṣọọbu kan lole.Ṣọọbu olowo nla kan to wa ni Opopona Eric Moore, ni iyana ọna Eric Moore, laduugbo Bọde Thomas, ni Surulere, la gbọ pe afurasi ọdaran naa ti n ko wọn lẹru lọwọ, oun nikan kọ lo lọ sibẹ, o pada jẹwọ pe awọn meji mi-in wa nitosi ti iṣẹ adigunjale jọ pa awọn pọ, awọn jọ ṣe ọpureṣan naa ni.Alukoro ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko, Adekunle Ajiṣebutu, to jẹ k’ALAROYE gbọ nipa iṣẹlẹ yii sọ pe nibi ti wọn ti n ṣiṣẹ ibi wọn lọwọ lawọn ọlọpaa to n patiroolu ti kọja ninu ọkọ wọn, lọkunrin to n taja ni ṣọọbu naa ba figbe ta, ariwo ‘ole, ole’ yii lo mu kawọn ọlọpaa bẹ silẹ ninu ọkọ wọn, wọn si sare sibi tiṣẹlẹ naa ti n waye.Wọn ni gbara tawọn gbewiri ẹda yii foju gan-an-ni awọn ọlọpaa lawọn naa ba ẹsẹ wọn sọrọ, meji ninu wọn sa lọ, ọkada ti wọn gbe wa ni wọn fi ja pa, Ọlawale lọwọ tẹ, oun naa si lolori ikọ adigunjale ọhun.Lara nnkan ija ti wọn ka mọ ọn lọwọ ni ibọn ibilẹ kan ti ọta wa ninu rẹ, katiriiji ọta ibọn ti wọn o ti i yin mẹta, oogun abẹnu gọngọ ati ọbẹ aṣooro kan.Nigba ti wọn wọ ọ de teṣan ọlọpaa, Ajiṣebutu ni afurasi ọdaran naa jẹwọ pe agbegbe Bọde Thomas lawọn ti n digunjale, o loun ra ibọn ti wọn ba lọwọ oun ni, agbegbe Ikorodu lo ni wọn ti ta a foun.Ṣa, Kọmiṣanna awọn ọlọpaa Eko, Hakeem Odumosu, ti ni ki wọn taari Ọlawale sọdọ awọn ọlọpaa ọtẹlẹmuyẹ ni Panti, Yaba, lẹyẹ-o-sọka lo si ti de ọdọ wọn.Wọn l’Odumosu sọ pe awọn maa foju ẹ bale-ẹjọ laipẹ tiwadii ba ti pari."},{"question":"\\"La kBox facilite les contractions isométriques et concentriques ainsi que l'entraînement excentrique.\\" Est-ce une paraphrase de la phrase suivante ? \\"La kBox facilite les contractions excentriques et concentriques ainsi que l’entraînement isométrique.\\" Oui ou Non ?","answer":"Non"},{"question":"A gbọdọ ṣewadii bawọn ijọba to lọ ṣe ta dukia araalu ni Kwara-Abdulrazaq","answer":"Ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii ni Gomina Abdulrahman Abdulrazaq tipinlẹ Kwara ṣe ifilọlẹ igbimọ ẹlẹni mẹfa kan lati ṣewadii bijọba to lọ labẹ idari Dokita Bukọla Saraki ati gomina ana, Abdulfatah Ahmed, ṣe ta dukia ijọba laarin ọjọ kọkandinlọgbọn, oṣu karun-un, ọdun 1999 si ọdun 2019.Adajọ-fẹyinti Ọlabanji Oriloniṣhe ni wọn fi ṣe alaga igbimọ naa. Awọn to maa ba a ṣiṣẹ  ni; Ọgbẹni Job Kọlawọle Buremọh; Isiaka AbdulKarem (mni); Safiya Usman; Alhaji Salihu Yaru; ati Muhammed Baba Orire (Akọwe).Atẹjade kan lati ọwọ Akọwe iroyin rẹ, Rafiu Ajakaye, ni igbimọ ọhun ni oṣu meji lati pari iwadii wọn, ki wọn si jabọ fun ijọba.Wọn yoo ṣewadii lori bijọba ana ṣe ta awọn dukia naa ati ilana ti wọn lo lati ta wọn; boya o ba ofin mu tabi bẹẹ kọ.Bakan naa, wọn yoo yẹ ẹ wo finnifinni boya o tọna bi wọn ṣe gbe awọn dukia naa ta, wọn yoo dabaa bijọba ṣe le ri awọn dukia ti wọn ta lọna ti ko bofin mu naa gba pada.Bakan naa ẹwẹ, gomina tun gbe igbimọ oluwadii kan kalẹ lati ṣewadii bi wọn ṣe ni owo kan n poora lapo ijọba ibilẹ. Awọn to yan sinu igbimọ naa ni; Adajọ fẹyinti Mathew Adewara (Alaga); aṣoju ajọ ọtẹlẹmuyẹ, (DSS) Halimah Bello; aṣoju ọlọpaa, DSP Adekunle Iwalaiye; aṣoju ajọ ti ki i ṣe tijọba, (The Corinth’s Humanitarian Foundation) Titilayọ Adedeji; aṣoju ajọ ICAN, Mohammed Baba Ibrahim; aṣoju ẹka eto idajọ, NBA, Bello Aisha Mohammed; aṣoju ẹgbẹ awọn oṣiṣẹ, NLC, Asmau Apalando;  ati akọwe agba kan, Abilekọ  Sabitiyu Grillo (Akọwe).Ọsẹ meji pere lo ni igbimọ naa ni lati pari iṣẹ naa."},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en esta categoría: Películas.","answer":"¿Qué película fue producida por Steven Spielberg y se estrenó en 1991? \\"Un Cuento Americano: Fievel va al oeste\\"."},{"question":"Ya ya sunan babban birnin jihar binuwai (Benue)?","answer":"Sunan babban birnin jihar Benue Makurdi."},{"question":"Gịnị bị myiriụdaume Igbo?","answer":"A naghị ekwu okwu mkpụrụedemede Igbo ghara ikwu maka myiriụdaume. Myiriụdaume bụ mkpụrụedemede Igbo ndị ahụ e si n’oghere imi akpọpụta. Ha dị naanị abụọ: ‘M’ na ‘N’ / ‘m’ na ‘n’Ha sokwa na mkpụrụedemede a na-akpọ mgbochiume, mana a na-ahụta ha dịka myiriụdaume mgbe ha nwere ike ịkwụrụ n’onwe ha ma nwee ụda aka ha dịka ụdaume na mkpọpụta. A na-ahụta ha dịka mgbochiume mgbe ha na-enweghị ụda na mkpọpụta ha. Ọ bụ ụdaume na-enye ha ụda ma ha nọrọ ọnọdụ mgbochiume. Myiriụdaume na-arụ ọrụ dịka ụdaume. Ha na-ebu ụdaolu, ma na-enwekwa nkejiokwu nke aka ha. Anaghị agbakwụnyere ya ụdaume ọzọ tupu a kpọpụta ya.Njirimara Myiriụdaume:-\\tỌ na-enwe ụda nke aka ya.-\\tA na-etinye akara ụdaolu n’elu ya.-\\tỌ bụ oghere imi ka e si akpọpụta ya.-\\tỌ na-ebido ma na-akwụsịkwa mkpụruokwu n’asụsụ Igbo.-\\tO nwere ike ịkwụrụ onwe ya dịka otu nkejiokwu.NDAGBA MYIRIỤDAUMENdagba Myiriụdaume bụ iwu na-egosi usoro mgbochiume si eso mgbochiume ibe ya n’imepụta mkpụrụokwu Igbo. Na ndagba myiriụdaume, e nwere mgbochiume ndị na-eso ‘M’ nakwa ‘N’ dịka myiriụdaume n’imepụta mkpụrụokwu Igbo.Mgbochiume  na-esote ‘M’ dịka myiriụdaume n’imepụta mkpụrụokwu Igbo bụ ndị a: 1.\\tMgbochiume ndị eji egbugbere ọnụ abụọ akpọpụta, dịka: Ọmụmaatụ:/b/\\t-\\tmbe, mba, dg./gb/\\t-\\tmgba, mgbu, dg./m/\\t-\\tmma, mmemme, dg./kp/\\t-\\tmkpa, mkpọ, dg./p/\\t-\\tmpe, mpaghara, dg.2.\\tMgbochiume ndị eji egbugbere ọnụ ala na eze elu akpọpụta, dịka:Ọmụmaatụ:/f/\\t-\\tmfe./v/\\t-\\tmvọ3.\\tMgbochiume ndị nwere ụdawayị, dịka:Ọmụmaatụ:/w/\\t-\\tmwepụ./y/\\t-\\tmyọ."},{"question":"Ẹmi kan lo n ti mi lati maa fipa b’awọn obinrin lo pọ, ma a ti ṣe e tan koju mi too walẹ ….. John","answer":"Ọkunrin ẹni ọdun mẹtalelọgbọn kan, Stephen John, lọwọ tẹ l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ to kọja yii, lori ẹsun fifipa b’awọn obinrin lo pọ niluu Ọrẹ, nijọba ibilẹ Odigbo.Gẹgẹ ba a ṣe gbọ, ọpọlọpọ awọn obinrin to wa lagbegbe Costain, niluu Ọrẹ, nitosi ibi ti ọkunrin ọmọ bibi ipinlẹ Cross River naa fi ṣe ibugbe ni wọn ti lugbadi ibalopọ tipatipa lọdọ rẹ, ṣugbọn ti itiju ko jẹ ki wọn le sọrọ sita.Inu oko ni wọn lo lọ maa n ka awọn iyawo oniyawo wọnyi mọ nigbakuugba to ba ti ṣakiyesi pe ẹni ọhun nikan lo wa nibẹ, lẹyin eyi ni yoo fa ada yọ si wọn lati fi dẹruba wọn, yoo si pa wọn lẹnu mọ titi yoo fi sohun to fẹẹ ṣe tan.Nnkan bii aago meje aarọ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọjọ karun-un, oṣu kẹjọ, ọdun ta a wa yii, ni wọn ni John tun ki ọmọdebinrin ẹni ọdun mẹẹẹdogun kan, Fatimọ Yahaya, mọlẹ, to si fipa ba a lo pọ karakara.Iṣẹ pajawiri kan ti iya rẹ, Abilekọ Oluwakẹmi Isaac,  ran an lọjọ naa ni wọn lo fẹẹ lọọ jẹ ko too pade ọkunrin oni kinni ko-mọ-ọmọde ọhun lojugbo kan to gba kọja, nibẹ naa lo ti ki i mọlẹ, to si fipa ṣe kinni fọmọ ọlọmọ.Nigba tọmọ dele to ṣalaye ohun toju rẹ ri fun iya rẹ, pẹlu ibinu lobinrin naa fi mori le teṣan ọlọpaa to wa niluu Ọrẹ lati fẹjọ rẹ sun.Ni ibamu pẹlu alaye ti Ọgbẹni Bọlaji Salami to jẹ kọmisanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ondo ṣe fawọn oniroyin, o ni ibi ti awọn ti n ọrọ wa ọdaran ọhun lẹnu wo lọwọ ni teṣan lawọn obinrin bii mẹta ti kọkọ yọju, ti wọn si n fidi rẹ mulẹ pe awọn naa wa lara awọn to waa yọ ada si nibi ti awọn ti n ṣiṣẹ ninu oko, to si fipa ba awọn lo pọ.O ni afurasi ọhun ko ni i pẹẹ foju bale-ẹjọ niwọn igba to ti fẹnu ara rẹ jẹwọ pe loootọ loun ṣe awọn nnkan ti wọn fẹsun rẹ kan an.Nigba ta a n fọrọ wa John lẹnu wo, ohun to n tẹnu mọ ni pe eedi lọrọ naa jọ loju oun, o ni ẹmi kan lo maa ba le oun leyii to ṣokunfa bi oun ṣe n siwa-hu.Ọpọ igba lo ni oun yoo ti ṣe kinni ọhun tan koju oun too walẹ."},{"question":"qoraal kan u samee ciwaan : nMadaxweyne Cyril Ramaphosa oo dhawaan hadlayay ayaa qiray in xisbigiisa ANC uu haatan marayo xilligii uu ugu liitay balse isaga qudhiisa ayaaba lagu dheggen yahay. Afar sano ka hor waxa uu xilka kala wareegay madaxweyne Jacob Zuma oo musuqmaasuq uu dhaawacay sumcadda maamulkiisa, wuxuuna xilligaasi ballanqaaday in uu la dagaallamayo musuqmaasuqa. Balse madaxweyne Cyril ayaa haatan la daalaa dhacaya fadeexado musuqmaasuq. Tan ugu daran ayaa ah muranka ka dhashay qarin la sheegay in uu qariyay burcad bishii Febaraayo ee sanadkii 2020 u dhacday beer uu ku leeyahay Phala Phala. Arrintani ayaa ku soo beegmeysa xilli xisbiga ANC lagu wado in sanadkan uu soo xusho murashaxiisa xilka madaxweynennimada ee doorashada dalka ka dhici doonta 2024, waana xilli madaxweyne Ramaphosa uu wajahayo cadaadis aad u xooggan. Kaddib in muddo ah oo ka caga jiidayay in uu ka hadlo ayuu ugu dambeyn Jimcihii dhowaa ka jawaabay su’aalo la xiriria dhacdadaas oo uu weydiiyay dacwad-oogaha ugu sarreeya dalka ee baaraya dhacdadaas. Kholeka Gcaleka ayaa madaxweynaha ugu hanjabay in uu u yeeri doono maaddaama uu horay ugu guul-darreystay in uu ka soo jawaabo su’aalaha ku gaadaaman dhacdadaas. Xogta ku saabsan dhacdada iyo sidii loola dhaqmay kooxdii burcadda ahayd oo markii dambe la qabtay ayaa bannaanka u soo baxday bishii Juun ee sanadkan, waxaana arrintaas shaaciyay madaxii hore ee sirdoonka qaranka, Arthur Fraser. Fraser oo ah nin aad ugu dhow madaxweynihii hore ee dalkaas Jacob Zuma ayaa madaxweyne Ramaphosa ku eedeeyay afduub, laaluush bixin iyo in si aan sharciga waafaqsanayn uu u amray in la soo qabto raggaas oo beertiisa ka dhacay lacag lagu qiyaasay 4,000,000 oo doollar. Fraser waxa uu intaasi ku daray in lacagtaas tirada badan oo sida la sheegay lagu dhex qariyay barkimo ay suurtagal tahay in markeedi horeba lagu kasbaday qaab sharcidarro ah, sida in musuqmaasuq ay ku soo gashay madaxweynaha. Dhacdadaas ayaa la sheegayaa in ay geysteen rag u dhashay dalka Namibia oo falkaasi la soo maleegay shaqaalihii beerta madaxweyne Ramaphosa. 'Wax dambi ah ma aanan geysan’ Maaddaama lacagta la xaday ay ahayd lacag qalaad, waxay arrintaa ka dhigan tahay in la jebiyay sharciyada xakamaynta sarrifka. Jawaabtii ugu horreysay ee uu bixiyay ayuu madaxweynuhu ku sheegay in \\"eedeymahaas aysan sal iyo baar toona lahayn\\". Xafiiska madaxweyne Ramaphosa ayaa xaqiijiyay in tuugo ay dhacday beertiisa oo ku taal gobolka Limpopo, \\"dhacdadaas oo keentay in la xado  dhaqaalihii ka soo xarooday iibinta ugaarta beertaasi\\", balse waxa uu muran ka keenay tirada uu sheegay madaxii hore ee sirdoonka qaranka Arthur Fraser. Qaar ka tirsan su’aalaha uu soo jeediyay xeer-ilaaliyaha guud ee qaranka ayaa la xiriira suurtagalnimada in madaxweynaha uu ku xadgudbay xeer-hoosaadka anshaxa iyo dastuurka, maaddaama uu qariyay xatooyada ka dhacay beertiisa. Waxa ay sidoo kale dooneysaa in ay ogaato tallaabooyinka uu madaxweynuhu qaaday si loo hubiyo in si fiican loo baaro xatooyadaas. Madaxweynaha ayaa ku gacan seyray eedeymaha Arthur Fraser oo uu ku tilmaamay olole sumcad-dil ah oo isaga ka dhan ah, kaa oo ay wadaan dadka kasoo horjeeda ajandihiisa la-dagaallanka musuqmaasuqa. Waxa uu sidoo kale aaminsan yahay in siyaasiyiinta isaga ka soo horjeedda ee gudaha xisbiga ANC aysan dooneyn in uu mar labaad qabto xilka madaxweynenimada dalka. Khudbad uu jeediyay labo toddobaad ka hor, ayuu Ramaphosa ku sheegay \\"in uu ballan-qaaday in uu si buuxda ula shaqayn doono baaritaanka ka dhanka ah dhacdadaas\\", uuna ku faraxsan yahay in lala xisaabtamo. Madaxweynuhu wuxuu sidoo kale sheegay in uusan oggolaan doonin in eedeymaha [musuqmaasuqa] ay ka hor istaagaan in uu sameeyo waxa loo baahan yahay in la sameeyo, si ay dib ugu dhisaan dhaqaalaha dalka, iyo in ay ka joojiyaan oo ay ka niyad-jabiyaan shaqadiisa. Hadalka Ramaphosa waxaa aad ugu farxay oo la dhacay taageerayaashiisa. Balse hadalkiisa wuxuu u muuqday in si sarbeeb ah uu dagaal gudaha ah ugu caddeysanayay xisbigiisa ANC. Sida uu qabo sharciga xisbiga ANC, qof kasta oo lagu soo oogo dacwad musuqmaasuq ama dambiyo kale waa in uu xilka isaga tago inta ay baaritaannadu socdaan. Inkastoo madaxweynaha aan si rasmi ah loogu soo oogin wax dambi ah, haddana taageerayaasha madaxweynihii hore ee dalka Jacob Zuma ayaa doonaya in uu xilka iska casilo. Bishii hore, boqollaal ka tirsan taageerayaasha Zuma ayaa ku hor mudaaharaaday xarunta xisbiga ANC, iyagoo dalbanaya in la soo xiro madaxweynaha iyo in uu xilka iska casilo. Zuma oo maxkamadeyntiisa musuqmaasuqa la xiriirta ay dib u billaaban doonto bishan, ayaa taageero ka helaya garabka bidix ee xisbiga ANC, waxaana taageerayaashiisa ay weli qaadan la’ yihiin  xabsigii uu sanadkii hore ku muteystay in uu ku guul-darreystay in uu ka qaybgalo baaritaan gaar ah oo ku saabsanaa musuqmaasuqa loo haystay ee la sheegay in uu dhacay xilligii uu madaxweynaha ahaa. Waxa uu xabsiga ku jiray ku dhowaad ​​labo bil oo ka mid ahaa 15-kii bilood ee lagu xukumay,  ka hor inta aan loo fidin cafis caafimaad. Dalabka is-casilaadda ah ee ay soo gudbinayaan taageeryaasha Zuma ayaa sii xoogeystay kaddib markii qaar ka tirsan wufuud ka qeybgaleysay shir ka dhacayay gobolka  KwaZulu-Natal - oo ah xarunta Zuma ay ku oriyeen Ramaphosa. 'Muuqaal dhaawacaya sumcadda dalka' Mucaaradka ayaa sidoo kale sii hurinaya cadaadiska siyaasadeed ee ka dhanka ah madaxweynaha. Bantu Holomisa, oo ah hoggaamiyaha Midowga Dhaqdhaqaaqa Dimuquraadiga ah, ayaa warqad u qoray afhayeenka baarlamaanka, waxa uuna ka dalbaday in shaqada laga joojiyo madaxweynaha ilaa iyo inta ay ka soo baxayaan natiijada baaritaanka ka dhanka ah madaxweynaha. \\"Eedaymahaas waxay si weyn u dhaawaceen sumcadda dalkeenna, waxa ayna u badan tahay in ay si xun u saamayso kalsoonida maalgashadayaasha, maaddaama madaxweyne Ramaphosa uu markii hore u dhaqmay sida halyey u taagan maamul wanaagga,\\" ayuu yiri Holomisa. Inkasta oo ay jiraan su’aalo ay tahay in madaxweyne Ramaphosa uu ka jawaabo oo la xiriira doollarka laga xaday beertiisa, haddana xilliga Fraser uu soo shaac-bixiyay arrintan ayaa loo arkaa mid laga shakin karo marka loo eego tartanka loogu jiro qabashada hoggaanka xisbiga ANC. Dadka reer Koonfur Afrika ayaa la qabsaday fadeexado musuqmaasuq, shirqool siyaasadeed iyo in la is-ceebeeyo ka hor tartanka loogu jiro hanashada jagada ugu sarreysa xisbiga ANC. Sanadkanna waxba kama duwana kuwii hore. Bisha Diseembar ee sanadkan ayuu xisbiga ANC qaban doontaa shir-weyne doorasho oo ay ku dooranayaan qofka noqon doona murashaxa madaxtinnimo ee xiga, waxaana hubaal ah in arrintaas ay xiisad ka dhalan doonto.","answer":"haye, ciwaan ku haboon qoraal ka aad itustay waa kan - Madaxweyne loo haysto maxaad u qarisay tuugadii kuu soo dhacday?"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Saya biasanya di atas kepala, duduk di sebelah kiri, kanan atau tengah, bercorak dan boleh menutup, siapa saya?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah topi. Topi adalah sejenis pakaian yang dikenakan di kepala. Topi biasanya memiliki bahagian melengkung yang tinggi dengan bahagian sisi. Topi boleh dikenakan di kepala atau, bagi beberapa jenis topi perempuan, dilengkapi dengan penyemat topi."},{"question":" உல்மனின் சொற்பொருள் மாற்ற வகைகளை விளக்குக?","answer":"சொற்பொருள் மாற்றங்களை நான்குவகை மாற்றங்களாகப் பின்வருமாறு வகைப்படுத்துகிறார் உல்மன்.1. உருவகமாக்கல் மாற்றம் (Metaphor)பொருள் ஒற்றுமை அடிப்படையில் இது தீர்மானிக்கப்படுகிறது.எ.கா:தழுவல் : ( தழுவுதல், தழுவல் இலக்கியம் )தண்ணி : ( தண்ணீர், மது )2. ஆகுபெயராக்கல் மாற்றம் (Metonymy)இம்மாற்றம் பொருள் தொடர்ச்சி அடிப்படையில் அமைகிறது.எ.கா:கண் : கண்ணேறு (இலக்கியம்), கண் வைத்தல்எழுத்து : எழுத்து, கடிதம் (Letter, post)கண்காணி : கண்காணித்தல், தொழிலாளர்களைக்          கண்காணிப்பவன் (watch, watchman)3. தேர்ந்தெடுத்த விளக்கத்தாலான மாற்றம் (popular etymology)இம்மாற்றம் அமைப்பு ஒற்றுமை அடிப்படையில் அமைவது.எ.கா :பாம்புராணி : அரணை, பாம்பின் ராணிஇங்கிலாண்டு : இங்கிலாந்து, இன்லேன்ட் கடிதம்4. பெயர்க் குறுக்கத்தாலான மாற்றம் (Ellipsis)தினசரி (பத்திரிகை) daily (paper)எ.கா:அறுவடையின் போது வந்தான்.அறுவடை (காலம்) ; அறிஞர் (அண்ணா) (அண்ணா- மேன்மை உடையவர்"},{"question":"ඉරිමා උදය යන්නෙහි තේරුම මොකක්ද?","answer":"උදය පාන්දර,ඉරිමා උදය,පභාතය,අරුණෝදය, අලුයම, සූර්ය මහෝදය මේ ඔක්කොගෙන් ම හදුන්වනවා අර සිංදුවකත් තියෙන්නේ සදලතා පායලා මල් වැට ගාව ඉරිමා උදේ... ඒ කියන්නේ උදේ පාන්දරකොස් ගහක තියෙන කොස් ගෙඩියක නටුව පේන මට්ටමට ඉර එළිය වැටුන උදැසන කලය"},{"question":"Qual é a vida útil de uma libélula?","answer":"A expectativa de vida típica de uma libélula é de aproximadamente 6 meses a partir do momento em que o ovo é posto até que morra como um adulto totalmente crescido, embora alguns tipos maiores possam viver até alguns anos. Muitos dos a vida de uma libélula é passada debaixo d'água como uma larva."},{"question":"Ogun miliọnu lawọn to ji Jimoh gbe ni Kwara n beere ","answer":"Awọn ajinigbe to ji Aburo Magaji Iyemọja, Jimoh Mujemu, gbe ni agbegbe Mandi Okoolowo, n’Ilọrin nipinlẹ Kwara, ti n beere fun ogun miliọnu (20 million) owo itu silẹ lọwọ mọlẹbi rẹ.Ni nnkan bii aago mẹwaa alẹ ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọṣẹ yii, ni awọn janduku ajinigbe ya bo agbegbe Mandi, l’Opopona Okoolowo, ti wọn si bẹrẹ si i yinbọn titi ti wọn fi wọle Magaji Iyemọja, ti wọn si ji Jimoh gbe lọ, ti ẹnikẹni ko si mọ ibi to wa.Ni bayii, awọn mọlẹbi arakunrin naa sọ pe awọn to ji i gbe ti pe ẹrọ ibanisọrọ awọn, wọn si n beere fun ogun miliọnu naira owo itu silẹ lọwọ awọn.Ẹgbọn arakunrin ọhun to ba ALAROYE sọrọ ni ọrọ awọn ajinigbe naa ti da iṣoro silẹ ninu ẹbi, tori pe awọn o ti i ri miliọnu kan, debi tawọn yoo ri ogun miliọnu naira ti wọn n beere."},{"question":"കാനഡയിലെ ജനസംഖ്യ എത്രയാണ്?","answer":"38.25 ദശലക്ഷം ജനസംഖ്യയുള്ള വടക്കേ അമേരിക്കയിലെ ഒരു രാജ്യമാണ് കാനഡ. രാജ്യത്ത് ജനവാസം കുറവാണ്, ബഹുഭൂരിപക്ഷവും 55-ാം സമാന്തരത്തിന്റെ തെക്ക് നഗരപ്രദേശങ്ങളിൽ താമസിക്കുന്നു. കാനഡയുടെ തലസ്ഥാനം ഒട്ടാവയാണ്, ടൊറന്റോ, മോൺട്രിയൽ, വാൻകൂവർ എന്നിവയാണ് ഏറ്റവും വലിയ മൂന്ന് മെട്രോപൊളിറ്റൻ പ്രദേശങ്ങൾ."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਾਝ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਅੰਦਰਿ ਹੀਰਾ ਲਾਲੁ ਬਣਾਇਆ ॥ਗੁਰ ਕੈ ਸਬਦਿ ਪਰਖਿ ਪਰਖਾਇਆ ॥ਜਿਨ ਸਚੁ ਪਲੈ ਸਚੁ ਵਖਾਣਹਿ ਸਚੁ ਕਸਵਟੀ ਲਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੧॥ਹਉ ਵਾਰੀ ਜੀਉ ਵਾਰੀ ਗੁਰ ਕੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਮੰਨਿ ਵਸਾਵਣਿਆ ॥ਅੰਜਨ ਮਾਹਿ ਨਿਰੰਜਨੁ ਪਾਇਆ ਜੋਤੀ ਜੋਤਿ ਮਿਲਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਇਸੁ ਕਾਇਆ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਬਹੁਤੁ ਪਸਾਰਾ ॥ਨਾਮੁ ਨਿਰੰਜਨੁ ਅਤਿ ਅਗਮ ਅਪਾਰਾ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਹੋਵੈ ਸੋਈ ਪਾਏ ਆਪੇ ਬਖਸਿ ਮਿਲਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੨॥ਮੇਰਾ ਠਾਕੁਰੁ ਸਚੁ ਦ੍ਰਿੜਾਏ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪਰਸਾਦੀ ਸਚਿ ਚਿਤੁ ਲਾਏ ॥ਸਚੋ ਸਚੁ ਵਰਤੈ ਸਭਨੀ ਥਾਈ ਸਚੇ ਸਚਿ ਸਮਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੩॥ਵੇਪਰਵਾਹੁ ਸਚੁ ਮੇਰਾ ਪਿਆਰਾ ॥ਕਿਲਵਿਖ ਅਵਗਣ ਕਾਟਣਹਾਰਾ ॥ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਸਦਾ ਧਿਆਈਐ ਭੈ ਭਾਇ ਭਗਤਿ ਦ੍ਰਿੜਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੪॥ਤੇਰੀ ਭਗਤਿ ਸਚੀ ਜੇ ਸਚੇ ਭਾਵੈ ॥ਆਪੇ ਦੇਇ ਨ ਪਛੋਤਾਵੈ ॥ਸਭਨਾ ਜੀਆ ਕਾ ਏਕੋ ਦਾਤਾ ਸਬਦੇ ਮਾਰਿ ਜੀਵਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੫॥ਹਰਿ ਤੁਧੁ ਬਾਝਹੁ ਮੈ ਕੋਈ ਨਾਹੀ ॥ਹਰਿ ਤੁਧੈ ਸੇਵੀ ਤੈ ਤੁਧੁ ਸਾਲਾਹੀ ॥ਆਪੇ ਮੇਲਿ ਲੈਹੁ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਸਾਚੇ ਪੂਰੈ ਕਰਮਿ ਤੂੰ ਪਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੬॥ਮੈ ਹੋਰੁ ਨ ਕੋਈ ਤੁਧੈ ਜੇਹਾ ॥ਤੇਰੀ ਨਦਰੀ ਸੀਝਸਿ ਦੇਹਾ ॥ਅਨਦਿਨੁ ਸਾਰਿ ਸਮਾਲਿ ਹਰਿ ਰਾਖਹਿ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸਹਜਿ ਸਮਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੭॥ਤੁਧੁ ਜੇਵਡੁ ਮੈ ਹੋਰੁ ਨ ਕੋਈ ॥ਤੁਧੁ ਆਪੇ ਸਿਰਜੀ ਆਪੇ ਗੋਈ ॥ਤੂੰ ਆਪੇ ਹੀ ਘੜਿ ਭੰਨਿ ਸਵਾਰਹਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮਿ ਸੁਹਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੮॥੫॥੬॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 112 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੇ ਹਰੇਕ ਸਰੀਰ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ (ਆਪਣੀ ਜੋਤਿ-ਰੂਪ) ਹੀਰਾ ਲਾਲ ਟਿਕਾਇਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ,(ਪਰ ਵਿਰਲੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲਿਆਂ ਨੇ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ (ਉਸ ਹੀਰੇ ਲਾਲ ਦੀ) ਪਰਖ ਕਰ ਕੇ (ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ) ਪਰਖ ਕਰਾਈ ਹੈ ।ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਹੀਰਾ ਵੱਸ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੀ ਪਰਖ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਕਸਵੱਟੀ (ਦੇ ਤੌਰ ਤੇ) ਵਰਤਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧।ਮੈਂ ਸਦਾ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਕੁਰਬਾਨ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ, ਜੋ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਵਿਚ ਵਿਚਰਦਿਆਂ ਹੀ (ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ) ਨਿਰੰਜਨ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਲੱਭ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਆਪਣੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਜੋਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਾਈ ਰੱਖਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧।(ਇਕ ਪਾਸੇ) ਇਸ ਮਨੁੱਖਾ ਸਰੀਰ ਵਿਚ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ) ਬਹੁਤ ਖਿਲਾਰਾ ਖਿਲਾਰਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ,(ਦੂਜੇ ਪਾਸੇ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਤੋਂ ਉਤਾਂਹ ਹੈ ਅਪਹੁੰਚ ਹੈ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਹੋਵੇ ?) ।ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹੀ (ਨਿਰੰਜਨ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ) ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ (ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਮਿਲਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।ਪਾਲਣਹਾਰਾ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਆਪਣਾ) ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਨਾਮ ਦ੍ਰਿੜ੍ਹ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ,ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਆਪਣਾ ਮਨ ਜੋੜਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਯਕੀਨ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹੀ ਸਭ ਥਾਵਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਮੇਰਾ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਸੇ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੀ ਮੁਥਾਜੀ ਭੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ।ਉਹ ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਾਪ ਤੇ ਔਗੁਣ ਦੂਰ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਤਾਕਤ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਪਿਆਰ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਧਿਆਨ ਧਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ । ਉਸ ਦੇ ਡਰ-ਅਦਬ ਵਿਚ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਨਾਲ ਉਸਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ (ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ) ਪੱਕੀ ਕਰਨੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ ।੪।ਹੇ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੇਰੀ ਭਗਤੀ (ਦੀ ਦਾਤਿ ਜੀਵ ਨੂੰ ਤਦੋਂ ਹੀ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ ਜੇ) ਤੇਰੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਹੋਵੇ ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ ! ਭਗਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਹੋਰ ਸੰਸਾਰਕ ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ ਦੀ ਦਾਤਿ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਦੇ ਦੇ ਕੇ ਉਹ) ਪਛਤਾਂਦਾ ਭੀ ਨਹੀਂ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਦਾਤਾਂ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਉਹ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਆਪ ਹੈ । ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ (ਜੀਵ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਵਲੋਂ) ਮਾਰ ਕੇ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ ।੫।ਹੇ ਹਰੀ ! ਤੈਥੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਮੈਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣਾ) ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ (ਸਹਾਰਾ) ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ । ਹੇ ਹਰੀ ! ਮੈਂ ਤੇਰੀ ਹੀ ਸੇਵਾ-ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ, ਮੈਂ ਤੇਰੀ ਹੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ ।ਹੇ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੋੜੀ ਰੱਖ । ਤੇਰੀ ਪੂਰੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਸਕੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।੬।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੇਰੇ ਵਰਗਾ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ । ਤੇਰੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਦੀ ਨਿਗਾਹ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ (ਜੇ ਤੇਰੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਦੀ ਦਾਤਿ ਮਿਲੇ ਤਾਂ ਮੇਰਾ ਇਹ) ਸਰੀਰ ਸਫਲ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਹਰੀ ! ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਭਾਲ ਕਰ ਕੇ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਵਲੋਂ) ਰਾਖੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ । (ਤੇਰੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ) ਜੇਹੜੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੭।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੇਰੇ ਬਰਾਬਰ ਦਾ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ । ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਰਚਨਾ ਰਚੀ ਹੈ, ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਨਾਸ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! (ਆਖ—ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ !) ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਘੜ ਕੇ ਭੰਨ ਕੇ ਸੰਵਾਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਆਪਣੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਜੀਵਨ) ਸੋਹਣੇ ਬਣਾਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ ।੮।੫।੬।\\""},{"question":"鯨を獲るときに使われる捕鯨船のことを英語で何というでしょう？","answer":"キャッチャー・ボートです。"},{"question":"පළමු FIFA ලෝක කුසලානය පැවැත්වූයේ කවදාද?","answer":"පළමු FIFA ලෝක කුසලානය 1930 දී පැවැත්විණි. මෙම මංගල ජාත්‍යන්තර පාපන්දු තරඟාවලිය ජූලි 13 සිට ජූලි 30 දක්වා උරුගුවේ හිදී  පැවැත්විණි. තරඟාවලියට කණ්ඩායම් 13 ක් සහභාගී වූ අතර උරුගුවේ අවසන් තරඟයේදී ආර්ජන්ටිනාව ගෝල 4-2 කින් පරාජය කරමින් ශූරයන් බවට පත් විය.මෙම සිදුවීම දැන් ගෝලීය වශයෙන් සමරනු ලබන FIFA ලෝක කුසලානයේ ආරම්භය සනිටුහන් කළ අතර එය එතැන් සිට ලෝකයේ වඩාත්ම කීර්තිමත් පාපන්දු තරඟාවලිය බවට පත්ව ඇත."},{"question":"Tarjamahkeun kalimah ieu tina basa Sunda kana basa Indonésia:Mentri Atikan keur nyiapkeun bantuan pikeun siswa ti masarakat miskin supados bisa sakola tepi ka sarjana.","answer":"Terjemahan: Menteri Pendidikan sedang menyiapkan bantuan bagi pelajar dari masyarakat miskin agar bisa bersekolah hingga sarjana."},{"question":"在加拿大，行驶在双行线的公路上，听到紧急车辆警笛响时，法律上要求你应？","answer":"尽快将车辆驶到公路的右边并停车"},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: \\"Tuy nhiên, trên con đường thực hiện quyết tâm của mình, không ít người mắc phải một số sai lầm khiến họ bị rời xa mục tiêu giảm cân của mình. Những sai lầm này là gì? Chuyên gia dinh dưỡng nổi tiếng Rujuta Diwekar chia sẻ trên Instagram những lỗi giảm cân cần tránh, như sau: 1. Đừng chỉ nói về cân nặng của bạn Có nghĩa là một người muốn giảm cân không chỉ nên tập trung vào mỗi việc giảm cân. Thay vào đó, họ nên chọn những điều tốt cho sức khỏe, tập trung vào tỷ lệ eo và hông, và đảm bảo eo nhỏ hơn hông khoảng 25,4 cm. 2. Đừng so sánh thời gian giảm cân hiện tại với kinh nghiệm trong quá khứ Kinh nghiệm trong quá khứ và kinh nghiệm của người khác không quan trọng; tận hưởng quá trình giảm cân của bạn trong thời điểm này. Đảm bảo giảm cân toàn diện và lành mạnh. 3. Đừng đổ lỗi cho bản thân khi thiếu kết quả Không có kỷ luật bản thân nào có thể bù đắp cho một kế hoạch ăn kiêng được thiết kế kém và việc tự trách bản thân khi bạn không thấy kết quả chẳng có ích gì, chuyên gia Diwekar khẳng định. 4. Đừng vội vàng giảm cân Hãy nhớ rằng cơ thể mất khoảng 12 tuần để thích nghi với bất cứ điều gì mới, chẳng hạn như thay đổi kế hoạch ăn kiêng, tập thể dục,… Vì vậy, hãy cho phép bản thân có chừng ấy thời gian.","answer":"Hãy biết rằng số cân bạn tăng lên không phải chỉ trong một sớm một chiều, vì vậy việc giảm cân cũng sẽ mất nhiều thời gian. 5. Đừng tập thể dục quá sức hoặc sử dụng nó như một hình phạt Điều quan trọng là duy trì hoạt động nhưng không quá sức. Khoảng 20-30 phút tập thể dục chuyên dụng mỗi ngày là đủ, ngay cả khi bạn không thể đi bộ 10.000 bước. Đừng bao giờ sử dụng tập thể dục như một cách để trừng phạt bản thân, vì điều đó có thể gây hại cho sức khỏe của bạn hoặc bạn có thể bị thương. 6. Không đánh giá thấp tầm quan trọng của giấc ngủ Hầu hết mọi người không nhận ra giá trị của giấc ngủ trong hành trình giảm cân của họ. Hãy nhớ ưu tiên giấc ngủ nếu bạn đang muốn thấy cơ thể mình bị mất đi vài cm. 7. Không chạy theo xu hướng ăn kiêng/những người có ảnh hưởng trên mạng xã hội Thay vào đó, hãy làm theo các mẹo truyền thống đã được kiểm nghiệm qua thời gian, được nhiều thế hệ làm theo. 8. Không cố định kích thước khẩu phần ăn Cảm giác thèm ăn là một thực thể chuyển động, hãy tôn trọng điều đó. Điều này có nghĩa là sự thèm ăn phụ thuộc vào cảm giác của bạn hàng ngày. Không cần thiết phải hạn chế khẩu phần mỗi ngày, vì điều đó có thể gây hại nhiều hơn lợi và khiến bạn thèm ăn những món không lành mạnh. Hãy tuân thủ nguyên tắc: 'ngồi và ăn', 'ăn từ từ', theo 'giác quan' của bạn và lưu tâm trong khi ăn. 9. Đừng trông đợi sự nhận ra của người khác về tiến bộ giảm cân của bạn Những thay đổi bạn nhận thấy ở bản thân, chẳng hạn như kinh nguyệt đều đặn, da sáng, tóc khỏe, giảm số cm cơ thể, vẫn tiến triển ngay cả khi không ai để ý đến chúng. Điều quan trọng là phải tiếp tục nỗ lực chăm sóc sức khỏe ngay cả khi không có xác nhận từ người khác."},{"question":"Biorąc pod uwagę następujące zdanie, nazwij części mowy:\\"Czerwony samochód zaparkował na przejściu dla pieszych\\".","answer":"Oto części mowy:Czerwony - przymiotniksamochód - rzeczownikzaparkował - czasownikna - zaimekprzejściu - rzeczownikdla - zaimekpieszych - rzeczownik"},{"question":"پوښتنه: واوره سړی په سهارنۍ کې څه خوري؟ ځواب: د ییخ شوي فلیکس! ستاسو په نظر پورته ټوکه څه ده؟","answer":"توضیح: یخ په سطح کې د منجمد اوبو بخار دی؛ دا د یخ او واورې ترمینځ یو ډول دی. د واورې سړي د واورې څخه جوړ شوي دي، کوم چې د یخ په څیر دی. د فلوټ فلیکس د سهار د ډوډۍ یو عام ډوډۍ ده. ایا تاسو کولی شئ د واورې سړي تصور کړئ چې غلې خوري؟ زه د کال په دې وخت کې د واورې د سړي ټوکې خوښوم. ښه وخورئ!"},{"question":"Apakah yang dimaksud dengan Pasar Persaingan Sempurna dalam sistem perekonomian?Buatlah artikel singkat untuk menjawab pertanyaan tersebut. Artikel tersebut harus menjawab beberapa aspek berikut:- deskripsi singkat mengenai Pasar Persaingan Sempurna- ciri-ciri Pasar Persaingan SempurnaJawaban: ","answer":"Pasar persaingan sempurna adalah pasar dengan banyak pembeli dan penjual, sehingga tidak ada satu pun dari masing-masing penjual atau pembeli yang dapat menentukan harga. Pada dasarnya tidak terdapat pasar yang mutlak sempurna di dunia ini. Akan tetapi salah satu contoh pasar yang mendekati adalah pasar beras, karena bentuk, warna dan tampilan lainnya relatif sama, serta penjual dan pembeli nya sangat banyak.Terdapat beberapa ciri-ciri yang membedakan pasar persaingan sempurna dengan pasar tidak sempurna. Berikut ini beberapa ciri-cirinya:1. Barang yang diperjualbelikan bersifat homogenAdanya sifat ini menyebabkan masing-masing barang memiliki sifat saling menggantikan (substitusi) satu dengan yang lainnya. Dengan demikian pembeli bebas membeli pada penjual manapun, sementara penjual tidak dapat menentukan harga yang berbeda dengan penjual yang lain karena barang yang dijual tidak bersifat unik.2. Terdapat banyak penjual dan pembeliTidak terdapat batasan mengenai jumlah penjual yang bisa berada di pasar dan jumlah pembeli yang membeli di pasar tersebut.3. Pembeli dan penjual berlaku sebagai penerima harga (price taker)Banyaknya jumlah penjual dan pembeli menyebabkan penjual dan pembeli memiliki sifat sebagai penerima harga (price taker), karena tidak dapat menentukan harga yang tercipta di pasar (price maker).4. Pembeli dan penjual bebas masuk dan keluar pasarTidak ada larangan bagi pembeli untuk membeli di pasar persaingan sempurna ini. Penjual juga dapat masuk dan menutup usahanya sekehendak hati. Misalnya jika penjual merasa mengalami kerugian selama berjualan di pasar tersebut, maka penjual tersebut dapat dengan mudah menghentikan usahanya.5. Informasi sempurnaBaik pembeli maupun penjual memiliki informasi yang sempurna mengenai harga, kualitas serta jumlah barang yang ada di pasar. Adanya informasi yang sempurna menyebabkan penjual tidak akan mengenakan harga yang lebih tinggi dibandingkan dengan penjual lainnya pada barang yang sama. Jika penjual melakukan hal ini maka pembeli akan meninggalkan penjual tersebut dan membeli barang yang sama pada penjual lainnya yang menjualnya sesuai dengan harga pasar yang berlaku6. Faktor produksi dapat bergerak secara bebasKarena tidak ada hambatan dalam memasuki pasar, maka penjual juga memiliki kebebasan unruk memindahkan faktor produksinya kemanapun.7. Laba maksimal dicapai pada saat penerimaan marginal (MR) sama dengan biaya marginal (MC)"},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Daoud och hela hans familj mördades 1978 då det afghanska kommunistpartiet tilltvingade sig makten genom en militärkupp (","answer":"Saur-revolutionen)."},{"question":"வினா: இந்தியாவின் முதல் பெண் ஐஏஎஸ் அதிகாரி யார்?","answer":"விடை: – அன்னா ராஜம் மல்ஹோத்ரா"},{"question":"பின்வருவனவற்றை சுருக்கமாகக் கூறுங்கள்: ஷெல்டிகள் வேலை செய்யும் நாய்களாக இருந்தனர், எனவே அவர்கள் பொறுப்புகளை அனுபவிப்பதை விரும்புகிறார்கள். உங்கள் வீட்டு வேலைகள் மற்றும் பிற செயல்களில் உங்கள் ஷெல்டினை ஈடுபடுத்த வழிகளை கண்டுபிடிக்க முயற்சிக்கவும். உதாரணமாக, நீங்கள் நடைபயிற்சிக்கு செல்லும் போது உங்கள் ஷெல்டி ஒரு இலகுவான முதுகெலும்பை அணியலாம், இதனால் அவர் உங்கள் விசைகளையும் தண்ணீர் பாட்டிலையும் எடுத்துச் செல்ல முடியும். அல்லது, நீங்கள் தோட்ட வேலை செய்யும்போது உங்களுக்காக நேரங்களை மீட்டெடுக்க உங்கள் ஷெல்டிக்கு பயிற்சி அளிக்கலாம். ஷெல்டிகள் சமூக நாய்கள், அவை பெரும்பாலும் தங்கள் உரிமையாளர்களுடன் \\"பேசும்\\". [அடிக்குறிப்புகள்] அவள் வெளியே செல்ல வேண்டும், உணவளிக்க வேண்டும், அல்லது கவனம் தேவைப்படலாம். உங்கள் ஷெல்டி குரைப்பதை ஒருபோதும் தண்டிப்பதில்லை. உங்களுடைய ஷெல்டி குரைப்பதில் உங்களுக்கு சலிப்பு இருந்தால், அவளுடைய குரைப்பதை நிறுத்துவதற்கு நேர்மறை வலுவூட்டலைப் பயன்படுத்துவதைக் கருத்தில் கொள்ளுங்கள். ஷெல்டிகள் புத்திசாலித்தனமான நாய்கள், எனவே அவர்களுக்கு நிறைய மன ஊக்கங்கள் தேவைப்படும். உங்கள் ஷெல்டிக்கு எப்போதும் சில பொழுதுபோக்கு பொம்மைகள் இருப்பதை உறுதி செய்து கொள்ளுங்கள். சில நல்ல பொம்மைகள் உங்கள் ஷெல்டிக்கு கொடுக்கப்படுகின்றன: புதிர் பொம்மைகள் மெல்லும் பொம்மைகள் சிரிக்கும் பொம்மைகள் கயிறு பொம்மைகள் ஷெல்டிகள் உடற்பயிற்சிக்காக சுற்றி ஓடுவதை விரும்புகின்றன, எனவே உங்கள் ஷெல்டிக்கு முற்றத்தில் அல்லது உங்கள் சுற்றுப்புறத்தில் ரோந்து செய்ய வாய்ப்பு இருப்பதை உறுதிப்படுத்திக் கொள்ளுங்கள். உங்கள் ஷெல்டியை ஒவ்வொரு நாளும் சில குறுகிய நடைப்பயணங்களுக்கு உங்கள் அருகில் அழைத்துச் செல்ல முயற்சிக்கவும். உங்கள் ஷெல்டி வெளியே இருக்கும்போது எப்போதும் ஒரு தையலில் அல்லது ஒரு மூடிய முற்றத்தில் வைத்திருங்கள். உங்கள் ஷெல்டி வெளியில் இருக்கும்போது அதை மேற்பார்வையிடுவதும் நல்லது, இதனால் அவள் பாதுகாப்பாக இருக்கிறாள் என்பதை நீங்கள் அறிவீர்கள். பெட்டி பயிற்சி உங்கள் ஷெல்டி சில பொருட்களை வரம்புகள் மற்றும் அது உங்கள் ஷெல்டி பயிற்சி ஒரு நல்ல வழி என்று கற்பிக்க உதவும். உங்கள் ஷெல்டிக்கு பெட்டி பயிற்சி அளிக்க முடிவு செய்தால், அவள் எழுந்து நின்று, படுத்து, திரும்பிப் பார்க்கும் அளவுக்கு பெட்டி பெரியதாக இருக்க வேண்டும் என்பதை நினைவில் கொள்ளுங்கள். இதை விட பெரியதாக இருக்கக் கூடாது. [பக்கம் 3-ன் படம்] நீங்கள் அதை பெற்ற பிறகு முதல் வாரம் அல்லது இரண்டு உங்கள் ஷெல்டி பெட்டியில் திறந்த விட்டு. உங்களுடைய ஷெல்டி தனது பெட்டியில் செல்ல விரும்புவதோடு, அவ்வாறு செய்யும்போது பாதுகாப்பாக உணர வேண்டும் என்பதே குறிக்கோள். ஒரு ஷெல்டி நாய்க்குட்டியை ஒரு பெட்டியில் இரண்டு மணி நேரத்திற்கும் மேலாக அடைக்காதீர்கள். நாய்க்குட்டிகள் தங்கள் சிறுநீர்ப்பைகளை நீண்ட நேரம் வைத்திருக்க முடியாது, மேலும் அவை பெட்டியை அழுக்குடன் முடிக்கும். ஒருபோதும் ஒரு பெட்டியில் உங்கள் ஷெல்டி தண்டிக்க ஒரு வழி பயன்படுத்த. உங்கள் ஷெல்டி அவரது பெட்டியில் செல்ல விரும்புகிறேன் வேண்டும், அது பயப்பட வேண்டாம்.. உங்கள் ஷெல்டிக்கு அடிப்படை கட்டளைகளை கற்பிப்பது, அவர் உங்கள் குடும்பத்தின் ஒரு நல்ல நடத்தை கொண்ட உறுப்பினராக இருப்பதை உறுதி செய்ய உதவும். உங்கள் ஷெல்டிக்கு கற்றுக்கொடுக்க சில நல்ல கட்டளைகள் அமர்ந்து, நின்று, படுத்து, குதித்து, அசைப்பது போன்றவை. உங்கள் ஷெல்டிக்கு பயிற்சியளிப்பதில் நினைவில் கொள்ள வேண்டிய சில நல்ல விஷயங்கள் பின்வருமாறுஃ நேர்மறையான வலுவூட்டலைப் பயன்படுத்துங்கள். அவள் கீழ்ப்படியவில்லை என்றால் உங்கள் ஷெல்டி அடிக்க அல்லது கத்தாதே. [அடிக்குறிப்புகள்] பயம் அடிப்படையிலான பயிற்சி முறைகளை விட இந்த நேர்மறையான வலுவூட்டல் உங்கள் நாயை மிகவும் ஊக்குவிக்கும். பயிற்சி நேரங்களை குறுகியதாகவும், வழக்கமாகவும் வைத்திருங்கள். நாய்கள் அதிக நேரம் கவனம் செலுத்த முடியாது, எனவே தினசரி 10 நிமிடங்கள் (அல்லது குறைவாக) அமர்வுகளில் ஒட்டிக்கொள்க. ஒரு நல்ல சமூகமயமாக்கப்பட்ட நாய்க்கு ஆக்கிரமிப்பு மற்றும் கவலை பிரச்சினைகள் ஏற்படுவதற்கான வாய்ப்பு குறைவாகவே உள்ளது, எனவே உங்கள் ஷெல்டிக்கு சமூகமயமாக்க நேரம் ஒதுக்குங்கள் அவள் ஒரு நாய்க்குட்டியாக இருக்கும்போது (எட்டு முதல் 20 வாரங்களுக்கு இடையில்). உங்கள் ஷெல்டியை உங்களுடன் வெளியே எடுத்துச் சென்று மக்களை அடிக்கடி அழைக்கவும், இதனால் உங்கள் ஷெல்டி நாய்க்குட்டி எல்லா வகையான விஷயங்களையும் சந்திக்கிறதுஃ குழந்தைகள் மற்றும் குழந்தைகள் ஆண்கள் மற்றும் பெண்கள் உரத்த சத்தங்கள் கூட்டங்கள் கார்கள் மற்றும் பைக்குகள் மற்ற நாய்கள் பூனைகள் விசித்திரமான ஆடை மற்றும் பாகங்கள்  சுருக்கம்:","answer":"உங்கள் ஷெல்டி ஒரு வேலை கொடுக்க. உங்கள் ஷெல்டி மீண்டும் பேச. உங்கள் ஷெல்டிக்கு தூண்டுதலான பொம்மைகளை வழங்குங்கள். உங்கள் ஷெல்டி ஓடி விளையாட இடம் இருப்பதை உறுதி செய்யுங்கள். உங்கள் ஷெல்டிக்கு அடிப்படை கட்டளைகளை கற்றுக்கொடுங்கள் உங்கள் ஷெல்டிக்கு சமூகமயமாக்குங்கள்"},{"question":"Tohizo ity ohabolana ity : “Ny tsiny toy ny rivotra tsy hita tarehy, ........................”","answer":"Toy izao ny ohabolana feno : “Ny tsiny toy ny rivotra tsy hita tarehy, potrany ka vao talanjona.”"},{"question":"স্বামী বিবেকানন্দের শিকাগো মহাসম্মোলন সম্পর্কে সংক্ষেপে লেখো ","answer":"১৮৯৩ সালের সেপ্টেম্বরে মার্কিন যুক্তরাষ্ট্রের শিকাগো শহরে বিশ্ব ধর্ম মহাসম্মলন অনুষ্ঠিত হয়। এই সম্মেলনে বিশ্বের বিভিন্ন ধর্মের প্রতিনিধিরা অংশগ্রহণ করেন। স্বামী বিবেকানন্দ এই সম্মেলনের ভারতীয় প্রতিনিধিদের মধ্যে একজন ছিলেন।স্বামী বিবেকানন্দের ভাষণ এই সম্মেলনের অন্যতম আলোচিত ঘটনা। তাঁর ভাষণে তিনি ভারতীয় হিন্দুধর্মের মর্মকথা তুলে ধরেন। তিনি বলেন, হিন্দুধর্ম সকল ধর্মের সমন্বয়ের ধর্ম। তিনি সকল ধর্মের মধ্যে মিল খুঁজে পেতে ও সকল ধর্মের মধ্যে সম্প্রীতি প্রতিষ্ঠার আহ্বান জানান। স্বামী বিবেকানন্দের ভাষণ বিশ্ববাসীর দৃষ্টি আকর্ষণ করে। তাঁর ভাষণের ফলে ভারতীয় হিন্দুধর্মের ওপর বিশ্ববাসীর ধারণা পরিবর্তিত হয়। স্বামী বিবেকানন্দকে এই সম্মেলনের \\"সূর্য সন্তান\\" বলে অভিহিত করা হয়।স্বামী বিবেকানন্দের ভাষণের গুরুত্বপূর্ণ দিকগুলি নিম্নরূপ:১ তিনি ভারতীয় হিন্দুধর্মের মর্মকথা তুলে ধরেন।২ তিনি সকল ধর্মের সমন্বয়ের ধর্ম হিসেবে হিন্দুধর্মের ভূমিকা তুলে ধরেন।৩ তিনি সকল ধর্মের মধ্যে মিল খুঁজে পেতে ও সকল ধর্মের মধ্যে সম্প্রীতি প্রতিষ্ঠার আহ্বান জানান।স্বামী বিবেকানন্দের শিকাগো মহাসম্মলন ভাষণ ভারতীয় হিন্দুধর্মের ইতিহাসে একটি গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ঘটনা। এই ভাষণের ফলে ভারতীয় হিন্দুধর্ম বিশ্ববাসীর কাছে পরিচিতি লাভ করে।"},{"question":"Halk oyunlarının amacı nedir?","answer":"Halk Oyunlarını amacı çocuklarda müzik ve ruh duygusunu bedensel hareketler ile kazandırmak ve kendi kültürümüzün bir parçasını sevdirerek öğretmektir."},{"question":"Inona no iantsoana ny renin'ny vady?","answer":"Rafozanbavy no iantsoana ny renin'ny vady."},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang betul untuk soalan berikut: Bilakah tali pinggang keledar perlu dipakai?A. Selepas sampai ke destinasiB. Ketika ternampak polisC. Sebelum memulakan perjalanan","answer":"Jawapannya ialah C. Sebelum memulakan perjalanan"},{"question":"آیا دوربین عکاسی حتما باید لنز قابل تعویض داشته باشد؟","answer":"دوربین‌ها در یک تقسیم‌بندی کلی به دو دسته تقسیم می‌شوند: دوربین‌هایی با لنز قابل تعویض و دوربین‌هایی که لنز آن‌ها به بدنه چسبیده و قابل تعویض نیست. برای این که ببینید کدام یک از این دو نوع مناسب شماست باید دقیقا مشخص کنید که این دوربین را برای چه استفاده‌ای تهیه می‌کنید؟ اگر هدف شما ثبت تصاویر با کیفیت از سفرها، مناظر طبیعی و سوژهای مختلف است و عکاسی را به صورت تخصصی دنبال نمی‌کنید لزومی ندارد دوربین شما لنز قابل تعویض داشته باشد."},{"question":"Mikä on listeria? ","answer":"Listeria (Listeria monocytogenes) on yleinen maaperässä ja vedessä elävä bakteeri.Listeria voi aiheuttaa ihmiselle listerioosi-nimisen taudin bakteerilla saastuneiden elintarvikkeiden välityksellä. "},{"question":"Ọkọ obinrin ti oju rẹ yatọ ti yọju o, o loun ko kọ iyawo oun o","answer":"Abdulwasiu Ọmọ-Dada, ọkọ obinrin toun atawọn ọmọ rẹ ni ẹyin oju to yatọ, Risikatu Abdulazeez, ti loun ko kọ obinrin naa silẹ nitori ẹyin oju rẹ ati tawọn ọmọ rẹ to yatọ.O ni nitori ẹyin oju rẹ gan-an loun ṣe fẹ ẹ. O lo waa ya oun lẹnu bo ṣe n sọ kiri pe oun le e jade nile.Wasiu ṣalaye pe nigba tawọn ri ara awọn, oun nifẹẹ rẹ, oun si gba ọna to tọ lọ lati fẹ ẹ sile.Baale ile yii ni nigba to bimọ akọkọ tiyẹn naa si gbe iru ẹyin oju rẹ waye, oun ko tori rẹ pa a ti, tabi sa lọ fun un. O ni ẹgbẹrun marundinlogoji loun tu jọ lati fi sanwo ileewosan nigba naa.Baale ile yii ni awọn obi Risikatu lo maa n sọ pe oun n fiya jẹ ọmọ awọn, ṣugbọn ko ri bẹẹ. O ni oun maa n ra ounjẹ sile, oun si n ṣe iwọnba ti agbara oun mọ lati maa tọju rẹ.Wasiu ni o ṣi n ya oun lẹnu bi wọn ṣe n gbe e kiri pe oun kọ ọ silẹ. O loun gba pe ohun to fẹẹ fi san ifẹ toun ni si i niyẹn, oun si ti gba f’Ọlọrun.Ṣugbọn, Risikatu ni irọ patapata ni Wasiu n pa. O ni lẹyin toun bi awọn ọmọ mejeeji lawọn obi rẹ ko si i ninu, to si bẹrẹ si i ṣiwa-hu soun.“Ko ni i wa sile, ko tun fowo ounjẹ silẹ. Ṣe lo yipada si mi patapata”."},{"question":"Хаббл телескопунун мааниси эмнеде?","answer":"Жооп: Хаббл телескобу алыскы галактикалар жана аалам жөнүндө укмуштуудай сүрөттөрдү жана баалуу маалыматтарды берип, космосту түшүнүүбүздү олуттуу түрдө өркүндөттү."},{"question":"问题：地球的自转周期是多久","answer":"答案：地球的自转周期大约24小时"},{"question":"(uhleka inhlinini.) Ehhe! Ingani ukhuluma kahle nje? Njengobasenginekhono lokukubhonya nje ngenxa yokungephucaamakhasimende ami ngoba ugabe ngokuthi unekhono lokwakhaeledlula elami ...(ugwabula imolontshisi ngokushesha yona lena elenga enqulwininebikade ilokhu ibanjwe ibhande lokhalo. Umbhokla ngayo emhlane.)(uze akhanule khathi egadla ephindelela.) Ehhe! Awungizwe!E-(egalela.) E-(egalela.) Awungizwe lapho ngihamba khonakwerekwere ndini. Yikhona uzophindela kwelakini lapho wavelakhona ngoba sewucacelwe okwangempela ukuthi ngeke siphindesizwane ... (Athi noma ezama ukumhesha ngethilofolo likasemendeuChivenga, avele abuyele eceleni uMdaluli maqedane aqhubekenokumgokloza umhlane uMdaluli. Aphelelwe ngamandla umlisa lonaadiyazele abonakale esewa phansi.)(uyamemeza, usikhuluma ubukwerekwere isiZulu.) Ngelekeleleni bo!Nakhu ngidikadikwa ichalaha ngingaphethe mbhulanja.(ngezwi eliphezulu elinesankahlu.) Kanti usaqhubeka ngempelanokungeyisa namanje wena mlisa? Yimina njalo wonke lona ombizangechalaha? (amgqeme ikhanda.) Nakho! (amphinde.) Nakhu-ya!Yikho lokhu! Tha-tha!(uyakhala, uyadazuluka.) Maye babo!1. Yini inhloso yombhali yokwethula indikimba yodlame kulo mdlalo? Sekelaimpendulo yakho.","answer":"Inhloso yombhali ukuqwashisa ukuthi abantu besimame nezingane kanyenabokufika mabangahlukunyezwa/mabangathuli kodwa ababikeemaphoyiseni nakwabezenhlalakahle njengoba uMdaluli ayehlukumezaumndeni wakhe kanye nomuntu wokufika onguChivenga."},{"question":"Complete the following phrase:  Đại hội Thể thao Đông Nam Á 1993 đã tạo nền tảng cho cuộc cạnh tranh sôi nổi trong môn bóng đá nam tại Singapore. Thời gian diễn ra của sự kiện này kéo dài từ ngày 7 đến ngày 19 tháng 6 năm 1993. Bóng đá nam","answer":" là một phần quan trọng của sự kiện thể thao quy mô khu vực này, góp phần thúc đẩy tinh thần thể thao và cùng nhau thi đấu. Đại hội Thể thao Đông Nam Á 1993 đã là cơ hội để các đội bóng đến từ các quốc gia tham gia cạnh tranh, chứng tỏ tài năng và thể lực của họ. Sự kiện này đã tạo cơ hội cho các cầu thủ bóng đá nam thể hiện khả năng thi đấu xuất sắc và cống hiến cho đội tuyển quốc gia của mình trong bối cảnh cạnh tranh sôi nổi."},{"question":"Malaza amin’ny tora-pasika tsara tarehy sy ny rano madio kristaly i Madagasikara. Inona no anaran'ny nosy lehibe indrindra eto amin'ny vondronosy Madagasikara, fantatra amin'ny tora-pasika fotsy? ","answer":"Nosy Be no nosy lehibe indrindra eto amin’ny vondronosy Madagasikara izay fantatra amin'ny tora-pasika fotsy."},{"question":"Amin'ity fehezanteny manaraka ity, vinavinao ny anjara asan'ny teny tsirairay : \\"Afaka fanadinana izy satria nianatra tsara\\".","answer":"Ireo ny anjara asan'ny teny tsirairay amin'io fehezanteny \\"Afaka fanadinana izy satria nianatra tsara\\" io : \\"Afaka\\" : matoanteny\\"fanadinana\\" : anarana\\"izy\\" : mpisolo tena\\"satria\\" : mpampitohy\\"nianatra\\" : matoanteny\\"tsara\\" : mpamari-toetra"},{"question":"Python හි විචල්‍ය දෙකක් මාරු කරන්නේ කෙසේද?","answer":"a = 5b = 10a, b = b, aprint(a, b)  # Outputs: 10 5"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਾਝ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਨਿਰਮਲ ਸਬਦੁ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਹੈ ਬਾਣੀ ॥ਨਿਰਮਲ ਜੋਤਿ ਸਭ ਮਾਹਿ ਸਮਾਣੀ ॥ਨਿਰਮਲ ਬਾਣੀ ਹਰਿ ਸਾਲਾਹੀ ਜਪਿ ਹਰਿ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਮੈਲੁ ਗਵਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੧॥ਹਉ ਵਾਰੀ ਜੀਉ ਵਾਰੀ ਸੁਖਦਾਤਾ ਮੰਨਿ ਵਸਾਵਣਿਆ ॥ਹਰਿ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦਿ ਸਲਾਹੀ ਸਬਦੋ ਸੁਣਿ ਤਿਸਾ ਮਿਟਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਨਿਰਮਲ ਨਾਮੁ ਵਸਿਆ ਮਨਿ ਆਏ ॥ਮਨੁ ਤਨੁ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਮਾਇਆ ਮੋਹੁ ਗਵਾਏ ॥ਨਿਰਮਲ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਵੈ ਨਿਤ ਸਾਚੇ ਕੇ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਨਾਦੁ ਵਜਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੨॥ਨਿਰਮਲ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਗੁਰ ਤੇ ਪਾਇਆ ॥ਵਿਚਹੁ ਆਪੁ ਮੁਆ ਤਿਥੈ ਮੋਹੁ ਨ ਮਾਇਆ ॥ਨਿਰਮਲ ਗਿਆਨੁ ਧਿਆਨੁ ਅਤਿ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਬਾਣੀ ਮੰਨਿ ਵਸਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੩॥ਜੋ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਸੇਵੇ ਸੁ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਹੋਵੈ ॥ਹਉਮੈ ਮੈਲੁ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦੇ ਧੋਵੈ ॥ਨਿਰਮਲ ਵਾਜੈ ਅਨਹਦ ਧੁਨਿ ਬਾਣੀ ਦਰਿ ਸਚੈ ਸੋਭਾ ਪਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੪॥ਨਿਰਮਲ ਤੇ ਸਭ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਹੋਵੈ ॥ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਮਨੂਆ ਹਰਿ ਸਬਦਿ ਪਰੋਵੈ ॥ਨਿਰਮਲ ਨਾਮਿ ਲਗੇ ਬਡਭਾਗੀ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਨਾਮਿ ਸੁਹਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੫॥ਸੋ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਜੋ ਸਬਦੇ ਸੋਹੈ ॥ਨਿਰਮਲ ਨਾਮਿ ਮਨੁ ਤਨੁ ਮੋਹੈ ॥ਸਚਿ ਨਾਮਿ ਮਲੁ ਕਦੇ ਨ ਲਾਗੈ ਮੁਖੁ ਊਜਲੁ ਸਚੁ ਕਰਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੬॥ਮਨੁ ਮੈਲਾ ਹੈ ਦੂਜੈ ਭਾਇ ॥ਮੈਲਾ ਚਉਕਾ ਮੈਲੈ ਥਾਇ ॥ਮੈਲਾ ਖਾਇ ਫਿਰਿ ਮੈਲੁ ਵਧਾਏ ਮਨਮੁਖ ਮੈਲੁ ਦੁਖੁ ਪਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੭॥ਮੈਲੇ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਸਭਿ ਹੁਕਮਿ ਸਬਾਏ ॥ਸੇ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਜੋ ਹਰਿ ਸਾਚੇ ਭਾਏ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮੁ ਵਸੈ ਮਨ ਅੰਤਰਿ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਮੈਲੁ ਚੁਕਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੮॥੧੯॥੨੦॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 121 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਪਵਿੱਤ੍ਰ ਜੋਤਿ ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਸਮਾਈ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ । ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦਾ ਸ਼ਬਦ (ਸਭ ਨੂੰ) ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ । ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ (ਸਭ ਨੂੰ) ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਹੈ । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਮੈਂ ਉਸ ਹਰੀ ਦੀ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ । ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪ ਕੇ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਈਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ) ਮੈਲ (ਮਨ ਵਿਚੋਂ) ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਲਈਦੀ ਹੈ ।੧। ਮੈਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਹਾਂ ਕੁਰਬਾਨ ਹਾਂ, ਜੇਹੜੇ ਸੁੱਖ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਮੈਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ । ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਹੀ ਸੁਣ ਕੇ ਮੈਂ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ) ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਮਿਟਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ) ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਆ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮਨ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਤਨ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਗੁਣ ਸਦਾ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜਿਵੇਂ ਜੋਗੀ ਨਾਦ ਵਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ) ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦਾ (ਮਾਨੋ) ਨਾਦ ਵਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨। ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਾਮ-ਜਲ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ,ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਆਪਾ-ਭਾਵ ਮੁੱਕ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ, ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਰਹਿ ਜਾਂਦਾ ।(ਜਿਉਂ ਜਿਉਂ ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਵਾਲੀ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਬਾਣੀ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਬਣਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜਦੀ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ (ਹੋਰ) ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ ।੩। ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ (ਆਪ ਭੀ) ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ,ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਉਹ (ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚੋਂ) ਹਉਮੈ ਦੀ ਮੈਲ ਧੋ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਇਕ-ਰਸ ਲਗਨ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਬਾਣੀ ਆਪਣਾ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਪਾਈ ਰੱਖਦੀ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਉਹ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ ਸੋਭਾ ਪਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ (ਨਾਮ-) ਛੁਹ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਰੀ ਲੁਕਾਈ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ।(ਜਿਉਂ ਜਿਉਂ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰੋਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਤਿਉਂ ਤਿਉਂ ਉਸ ਦਾ) ਮਨ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਵੱਡੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਹੀ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੫। ਉਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜੇਹੜਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮਨ ਮਸਤ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਤਨ (ਭਾਵ, ਹਰੇਕ ਗਿਆਨ-ਇੰਦ੍ਰਾ) ਮਸਤ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਨ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ) ਮੈਲ ਕਦੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਲਗਦੀ । ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮੂੰਹ (ਲੋਕ ਪਰਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ) ਉਜਲਾ ਕਰ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੬। ਪਰ ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ ਮਸਤ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮਨ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੈਲ ਨਾਲ) ਮੈਲਾ (ਹੀ) ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।(ਉਹ ਲਕੀਰਾਂ ਕੱਢ ਕੱਢ ਕੇ ਬੇਸ਼ੱਕ ਸੁੱਚੇ ਚੌਂਕੇ ਬਣਾਏ, ਪਰ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਦਾ) ਚੌਂਕਾ ਮੈਲਾ ਹੀ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਉਹ ਦੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਸਦਾ) ਮੈਲੇ ਥਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਟਿਕੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ) ਮੈਲ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਆਪਣੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਖ਼ੁਰਾਕ ਬਣਾਈ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਜਿਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਹੋਰ ਹੋਰ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ) ਮੈਲ ਵਧਾਂਦਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ) ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ) ਮੈਲ (ਵਧਾ ਵਧਾ ਕੇ) ਦੁੱਖ ਸਹਾਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੭। (ਪਰ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਕੀਹ ਵੱਸ ?) ਵਿਕਾਰੀ ਜੀਵ ਤੇ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ-ਆਤਮਾ ਜੀਵ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਵਿਚ (ਹੀ ਤੁਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ) । ਜੇਹੜੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਹਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਪਿਆਰੇ ਲੱਗ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਦੱਸੇ ਰਾਹ ਉੱਤੇ ਤੁਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਵਿਕਾਰ ਆਦਿਕਾਂ ਦੀ) ਮੈਲ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੮।੧੯।੨੦।\\""},{"question":"\\"වසන්තයේ මල් සුපිපුණ\\" ගීතයේ ඉතිරි පද සම්පූර්ණ කරන්න.","answer":"වසන්තයේ මල් සුපිපුණසුන්දරතාවය ඉහිරුණහද මඬලට කවුදෝ ආවාහද දුක ගාවා කවුදෝ ආවාමල්පෙති සිඹ සිනා රැගෙනමල සිඳ බිඳ යන්ට ගියාහද දුක ගාවා කවුදෝ ආවාහස අංගනාවන්සේසඳ දිය මැද කිමිදීකිරි සිහිනෙක මා රඳවාකොහිදෝ බැඳුනේනීල කැලුම් ගලා හැලෙනඉඳුනිල් මිණි දෑස වසාමගෙ දෝතට නෑවිත් නුඹකොහිදෝ බැඳුනේහිරු මැලවුණ හැන්දෑවේ අඳුරට ගුලි වීමධු බඳුනට හාදු දිදී හිඳිනා යාමේනෙතු කඳුලින් බොඳ කළ ඒඅතීතයේ හීන පැලටමා කැඳවා යන්නට නුඹඇයිදෝ ආවේඉමාන් පෙරේරාතිළිණ රුවන් මලලසේකරරංජිත් සුධර්මන් "},{"question":"Wanene ya gabatar da Musulunci ga Hausa?","answer":"An shigar da addinin Musulunci a kasar Hausa (Kano dai dai) a zamanin Sarki Yaji a tsakiyar karni na 15 miladiyya."},{"question":"Deputa ihe anọ gbasara Steeti Kebbi ?.","answer":"Steeti Kebbi  bu steeti di n'ime obodo Naịjirịa.Emepụtara ya n'abalị iri abụọ na asaa nke ọnwa Ọgọọst nke afọ 1991. Isi obodo steeti Kebbi  bụ Birnin Kebbi. Ahọpụtara ya dịka steeti iri abụọ na atọ kachasị na Naịjirịa. "},{"question":"வினா:சரியான விடையைத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்து எழுதுக.மரபியலின் தந்தை யார் ?1.கிரிகர் கோகன் மெண்டல்2.கார்ல் லின்னேயஸ்3.ஹிப்போகிறேட்டஸ்4.சாமுவேல் ஹானிமன்","answer":"  விடை:மரபியலின் தந்தை  1.கிரிகர் கோகன் மெண்டல்.கிரிகோர் யோவான் மெண்டல்  (சூலை 20, 1822 – சனவரி 6, 1884), மரபியல் குறித்த அடிப்படை ஆய்வுப் பணிகளுக்காக அறியப்படும் ஆத்திரிய நாட்டைச் சேர்ந்த ஒரு அகத்தீனிய அவைத் துறவி. இவரை மரபியலின் தந்தை என்று அழைக்கிறார்கள்.மெண்டல், தனது ஆர்வத்தின் காரணமாக தனிப்பட்ட முறையில் ஆய்வு மேற்கொண்டார். தன் தோட்டத்தில் இருந்த பட்டாணிச் செடிகளில், முறைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட மகரந்தச் சேர்க்கை நடைபெறச் செய்தார். அதன் விளைவுகளை புள்ளியியல் அடிப்படையில் விளங்கிக்கொள்ள முற்பட்டபோது, மரபுப் பண்புகள் சில குறிப்பிட்ட விதிகளுக்கு உட்பட்டே ஒரு சந்ததியில் இருந்து அடுத்த சந்ததிக்கு எப்படி கடத்தப்படுகின்றன என்பதைக் கண்டறிந்தார். பிற்காலத்தில், இவ்விதிகள் மெண்டலின் விதிகள் எனப் பெயரிடப்பட்டு அழைக்கப்பட்டன. 1866ல் இது குறித்த ஆராய்ச்சிக்கட்டுரை ஒன்றினை எழுதினார். எனினும், இக்கட்டுரையின் முக்கியத்துவத்தை, அவர் வாழ்நாளில் எவரும் உணரவும் இல்லை; ஏற்கவும் இல்லை. 1900ல் கார்ரேன்ஸ், டி வரீஸ், டிஸ்சர்மாக் என்ற மூன்று தனிப்பட்ட ஆய்வாளர்கள் மெண்டல் எழுதிய கட்டுரையின் முக்கியத்துவத்தை உணர்ந்தனர். இன்று, மெண்டல் வரையறுத்த கோட்பாடுகள் மரபியலின் அடிப்படையாக விளங்குகின்றன."},{"question":"السؤال: اشمن حيوان عنده القلب دياله في الراس ؟","answer":"الإجابة:القيمرون"},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Hôm 17/6 vừa qua, Fabio Vieira chia tay Porto sau 14 năm gắn bó để chuyển sang đầu quân cho Arsenal với phí chuyển nhượng 35 triệu bảng. Ngôi sao 22 tuổi gắn bó với đội chủ sân Emirates theo hợp đồng có thời hạn 5 năm và mang áo số 21. Hiện vẫn chưa rõ Fabio Vieira và Carina Raquel hẹn hò nhau từ thời điểm nào.","answer":"Người đẹp 21 tuổi hiện đang là sinh viên chuyên ngành kinh tế tại 1 trường đại học ở quê nhà Bồ Đào Nha. Carina Raquel có niềm đam mê với du lịch. Trên trang Instagram cá nhân có hơn 33.300 người theo dõi, cô thường đăng tải những hình ảnh nóng bỏng check in ở những địa điểm du lịch nổi tiếng. Một số hình ảnh của Carina Raquel:"},{"question":"次の段落は何について話しているのか？ ロシアの攻撃があって、ウクライナの人たちはとても大変な生活をしています。冬が近くなって、寒いときに着るあたたかい服などを送ってほしいとオデーサ市から横浜市に今月、連絡がありました。横浜市とオデーサ市は50年以上前から市と市の交流を続けています。このため、横浜市はあたたかい服を約2000セットと、靴の中に入れて足をあたたかくするカイロを約1万セット送ることを決めました。新しく買って送る服には、「横浜市はオデーサ市を応援しています」という意味の英語の字が縫ってあります。服やカイロは、12月にオデーサ市に着く予定です。","answer":"横浜市　ウクライナのオデーサ市にあたたかい服などを送る"},{"question":"متى أكتشف الإيريديوم ؟","answer":"1804"},{"question":"Non dago herriko agintaria? Aurreko galdera kontuan hartuta, idatzi testuinguru batean erantzuna. Esaldi 1-etik 20 esalditara. ","answer":"Herriko agintaria Bermeon dago. Hara joan zen Bilbon hitzaldi bat eman ondoren. Bilboko jendeak asko eskertu zuen herriko agintaria hara joatea."},{"question":"『花鏡（かきょう）』や『風姿花伝（ふうしかでん）』といった理論書を残している、父の観阿弥とともに能の大成者となった人物は誰でしょう？","answer":"世阿弥（ぜあみ）"},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : ఏరకమైన నేలలు వ్యవసాయానికి ఎక్కువ అనుకూలం?","answer":"మైదాన ప్రాంతంలోని ఒండ్రు (డెల్టా), నల్లరేగడి నేలలు వ్యవసాయానికి ఎక్కువ అనుకూలం. నేలలతోపాటు నీటిసౌకర్యం కూడా ప్రధాన పాత్ర పోషిస్తుంది."},{"question":"बंधन आणि मुक्ती","answer":"मनुष्याची सफल जीवन यात्रा यातच आहे की त्याला खरा अमर्याद आनंद  प्राप्त होणे. पण जीवनात जेही सुख किंवा आनंद मिळतात ते क्षणभंगुर ठरतात. येणाऱ्या सुखांना आपण कितीही सांभाळून ठेऊ इच्छीले तरी ते फार थोड्या वेळाचे असतात टिकून राहात नाही. कारण बाहेरून मिळणारे सुख कोणत्यातरी निमित्ताने आलेले असतात.ते निमित्त टिकाऊ नसते. जशी मनुष्याचे आयुष्य एक सारखे व टिकाऊ नाही. देहातील शक्ती,इंद्रियातील शक्ती हि सुद्धा सारखी व टिकाऊ नसते. यात जसा बदल होत जातो तसाच निमित्ताने येणारे सुख व आनंद कसा टिकून राहणार ? मनुष्याला जे काही बाहेरून प्राप्त होईल ते टिकाऊ नसतेच. म्हणून त्याला जीवनाच्या सफलते साठी अशी वस्तूची गरज आहे कि त्यात आनंद वाटेल व त्यापासून दूर होणार नाही.प्राणी आणि पदार्थात तसेच किती तरी प्रकारच्या कर्मात मनुष्य जन्मापासून बांधला असतो. उदा. एखादा कागदाचा तुकडा घेऊन त्याला दोरा बांधून मोकळ्या जागेवर सोडून दिल्यांनतर काही दिवसांनी त्याला आपोआप गोलाकार येतो. याच प्रमाणे आपले मन बाहेरच्या तुष्णेने गोलाकार रूप घेतो. लहानपणी आपली  बुद्धी,विवेक, ज्ञान तेवढे जागृत नसते. जिकडे चांगे वाटते तिकडेच मन भटकते.  दु:ख वाटते ते नको असते सुख वाटते ते हवे हवेसे असते. नको असते त्याचा राग येतो द्वेष वाटते नको असलेल्याच वस्तूचे चिंतन सुरु होते, त्याच प्रमाणे जीवनात द्वेषभावनेने, बंधन पडत जाते. हेच राग-द्वेष, कामक्रोध याच चक्कर मध्ये मनुष्याचे जीवनभर दु:ख भोगत राहतो. जो पर्यंत त्याचा विवेक जागृत होत नाही तो पर्यंत प्रकृती सांभाळणे कठीण होते. हि प्रकृती दिसूनही पडत नाही, व शांत ही होत नाही.  हीच प्रकृती आपल्या नियमा नुसार मशीन प्रमाणे चालत राहते, हीच प्रकृती सार्या विश्वाला उत्पन्न करते, स्थिर करते व नाश करते. सतत वाहत राहणारी कृती म्हणजेच ”प्रकृती”.प्रकृतीची  सदा न कदा काही तरी कृती सुरूच असते.हीच ईश्वराची माया होय. आनंद, चेतन, ज्ञान हे कोऱ्या कागदा प्रमाणे आहे.परंतु हि माया त्याला अश्या चक्राने फिरविते कि प्रत्येकाला त्याचे निरनिराळे रूप दाखविते. मनुष्य, प्राणी, वृक्ष-वेली हे सर्व परिवर्तनशील आहेत यांची अवस्था अगदी बदलत असते, हे स्वाभाविक आहे.परंतु मनुष्या वरील बंधन फार मजबूत आहे. माया म्हणेल प्रेम करा तर प्रेम करू माया म्हणेल वैर करा  तर वैर करू. मान मोह, राग, द्वेष, संशय, भय, किंवा खोटे कर्म तेही करू. परंतु या बंधनात बाहेरील सुखात मनुष्य आतून खोकला होऊन जातो.हे लक्षातही राहात नाही. यात मनुष्याचा श्वास सुद्धा सुखाने चालत नाही, आणि इंद्रिय हि बरोबर काम करीत नाही. त्या शरीरात सुख नाही त्याला कितीही धन-दौलत,मित्र-परिवार, आदर-सत्कार, गौरव-अधिकार प्राप्त होत असतील त्याला काहीच अर्थ उरत नाही. काही काळ बरे वाटेल. परंतु एक क्षण असा येतो कि, सर्व सुख, धन, परिवार राहूनही त्याला ते नकोस वाटायला लागेल, कारण त्या सुखा मागोमाग तेवढेच दु:ख प्रगट होतात. शेवटी तोच मनुष्य म्हणतो , कि आता मला या सर्व गोष्टींचा कंटाळा आला आहे. आता मला याच्यात काही सुख नाही. हा प्रकृतीचा नियम आहे, त्यावर फिरणाऱ्या मायेचा खेळ होय. या खेळात मनुष्य ईतका उत्साहित होतो. या बाहेरील आनंदात तो हे विसरून जातो त्याच्या अंतरात्मातील ज्ञानशक्ती तेवढ्याच तेजीने भटकलेली आहे. आणि क्रियाशक्ती ही भटकलेली आहे.  ज्ञानशक्ती द्वारा त्याला जे जाणायचे होते त्यावर श्वास कधी केंद्रित झालाच नाही.जे सुख मानून बसलो त्यातच श्वास भटकला. हे जाणले कि हा माझा वैरी आहे, त्यावर क्रोध आला, कधी हे जाणले कि यात माझी भलाई आहे त्याला दोस्त मानला जे समजत गेलो त्यावरच कामदेवाने काम केले, ज्ञानदेव दूर भटकले त्यातच जीवन संपूर्ण गमावले हीच बंधने मनुष्याला दु:खावस्थेत घालतात. कधी कधी मनुष्य म्हणतो कि चिंता सोडून देतो. परंतु ती सोडणे काय त्याच्या हाती आहे ? मन एवढे बंधनात असते, बंधनात असलेला मन ज्या रस्त्याने वळते तिकडे मनुष्य जातो. पण या जखडलेल्या बंधनातून सुटण्याचा प्रयत्न झाला. तर काय गाढ झोपेतल्या स्वप्नातून एकदम जागा झाल्यागत. अरे हे तर स्वप्नच होते हे समजून सत्याच्या मार्गावर वाटचाल करू शकतो पण त्यासाठी आपली ईच्छाशक्ती प्रबळ व्हायला हवी.या साठी उत्तमगती म्हणजे ज्ञान आणि त्याची भटकत असलेली शक्ती हे एकत्रित होऊन आपल्या देहात या दोन शक्तींचे प्रतिनिधी असलेले म्हणजे समज आणि प्राणशक्ती हि बाहेर भटकायला नको.कधी कधी हि प्राणशक्ती भटकली की मनुष्याला भर युवा अवस्थेत सुद्धा झोप येत नाही. त्याच सोबत त्याची प्राणशक्ती व क्रियाशक्ती भटकलेली असते. त्याला सुद्धा झोपेसाठी गोळ्या खाव्या लागतात. याचा परिणाम म्हणजे  हृद्य रोग, पोटातील रोग उत्पन्न होतात. या बिमारीत मनुष्य प्राण सुद्धा गमाउन बसतो. या बंधनाला तोडण्यास मनुष्याने जप, प्राणायाम याचा अवश्य लाभ घ्यावा. त्यामुळे ज्ञान बंधनात पडतो. या ज्ञानाद्वारे आपले निकामी कर्म बंधनातून तुटू लागतात, व्यक्तीला अंतरात्मा- मातील सत्यज्ञानाची प्रचीती होण्याचा लाभ होतो. तेव्हा जप-तप, प्राणायाम हेच शुद्धज्ञान प्राप्त करून देते."},{"question":"How does inheritance work in OOP?","answer":"Inheritance allows a class (subclass or derived class) to inherit properties and behaviors from another class (base class or superclass), facilitating code reuse and promoting a hierarchical structure."},{"question":"انساني جسم مختلف نظامن تي مشتمل هوندو آهي جيڪي خاص سيلز، بافتن ۽ عضون مان ٺهيل هوندا آهن. انهن مان هر هڪ خاص ڪم آهي جيڪو انساني نسل جي بقا ۾ مدد ڪري ٿو. پيدائش ۾ ڪهڙا عضوا استعمال ٿيندا آهن؟ ھيٺين مان چونڊيو. [ع] دماغ، ريڙهه جي ڪنڊ ۽ اکيون؛ [ب] ڦڦڙن، esophagus، ۽ دل؛ [ج] وات، معدي ۽ ڳلي جو مثانو. [ڊي] بيضي، رحم، ۽ فيلوپيئن ٽيوب؛","answer":"[ڊي]"},{"question":"మఱ్ఱి చెట్టు నిస్వార్ధ బుద్ధితో పక్షులకు, మానవులకు ఎలాంటి సహాయాన్ని అందిస్తోందో మీ మాటల్లో చెప్పండి.","answer":"మఱ్ఱిచెట్టు నిస్వార్థ బుద్ధితో మానవులకు, పక్షులకు ఆశ్రయం కల్పించింది. మానవులకు చెట్టు కింద నీడ నిచ్చింది. పక్షులు చెట్టుపైన గూళ్లు కట్టుకొని నివసించేలాగా ఆశ్రయం కల్పించింది."},{"question":"Wendy Hiller","answer":"Dame Wendy Margaret Hiller ni a bini ọjọ karun dilogun óṣu August ni ọdun 1912 ti o si ku ni ọjọ kẹfa dilogun óṣu May ni ọdun 2003 (15 August 1912 – 14 May 2003) jẹ óṣèrè óritage èdè gẹẹsi ti o si tin ba iṣẹ naa bọ lati ọgọta ọdun. Wendy duró gẹgẹbi óṣèrè oritage pẹlu gbogbo akitiyan rẹ ninu siṣè ere.Wendy ni a bisi ilẹ Bramhall ti o si jẹ ọmọbinrin Frank Watkin Hiller ati Marie Stone. Óṣèrè naa kẹkọ ni Ilè ẹkọ Ilè Winceby, nigba ti arabinrin naa pẹ ọmọ ọdun mejidinlogun ódarapọ mọ Ilè iṣẹ Repertory Manchester nibi ti o ti ṣè ere fun ọdun pipẹ. Joel Hirschorn ṣe apejuwe wendy gẹgẹbi óṣèrè lobinrin ti o gba gbẹrẹ ti o si ma duró bi akinkanju ninu awọn èrè rẹ. Ni ọdun 1937, Wendy fẹ akọ ere kalẹ Ronald Gow ti o jẹ senior rẹ fun ọdun ọdun marun dilogun ti wọn si jọ tọ awọn ọmọ meji Ann ati Anthony ni ilẹ ti oun jẹ Spindles.Wendy je osere to gba Ebun Akademi bi Obinrin Osere Keji Didarajulo. Ni ọdun 1959, Wendy gba Oscar ninu ere Seperate Tables nibi ti o jẹ óludari hotel ati Misitrẹẹsi ti Burt Lancaster. Ni ọdun 1975. arabinrin naa jẹ Apaṣẹ Dame. Ni ọdun 1984, Arabinrin naa gba ami ẹyẹ doctorate lati Ilè iwe giga manchester. Ni ọdun 1996, Ere critics circle ti ilu london da Hiller lọla Ami ẹyẹ Dilys Powell fun akitiyan rẹ ni ere ilẹ british."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai awak tikus hendak menampar kepala kucing\\"?","answer":"Maksud \\"bagai awak tikus hendak menampar kepala kucing\\" ialah ingin melakukan sesuatu, tetapi tidak mampu."},{"question":"次の文章を読んで、その内容に適したタイトルを付けてください： 大阪府などは、カジノなどが入ったリゾート「IR」を、海の近くの夢洲という場所に作ることを計画しています。28日、夢洲が見える役所で大阪府とIRを運営する会社のトップが出席して、計画にサインをする式を行いました。2030年の秋ごろにオープンする予定です。式の中で、吉村知事は「大阪の海のそばに、世界でもすばらしいIRを作りたいです。今日はそのための大事な日です」と言いました。運営する会社のトップは「IRができることで大阪の経済ももっとよくなるでしょう」と話しました。これから運営会社はカジノを行う免許を国に申請します。国が免許を認めると、オープンへの準備が進む予定です。","answer":"カジノが入ったIR　大阪に2030年秋ごろオープンの計画"},{"question":"கேள்வி : வைணவ உரைகள் யாவும் எந்நடையில் அமைந்தவை?","answer":"பதில்  :  மணிப்பிரவாள நடை.விளக்கம் மணிப்பிரவாள நடை என்பது தமிழோடு வடமொழியும் விரவி நடக்கும் தமிழ் உரைநடை. இது தமிழோடு 13 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டில் இணைந்தது. இரத்தினம்-பவளம் என்ற நேரடிப் பொருளுடைய மணிப்பிரவாளம் என்னும் சொல், தென்னிந்தியாவில் வடமொழி்யும், திராவிட மொழியொன்றும் கலந்து எழுதப்பட்ட ஒரு இலக்கிய நடையைக் குறிக்கும். மணியும், பவளமும் சேர்த்து உருவாக்கப்பட்ட மாலை போல இரண்டு மொழிகள் கலந்து உருவான இலக்கிய நடை என்பது இதன் பொருளாகும். மணிப்பிரவாள நடை என்பது தமிழோடு வடமொழியும் விரவி நடக்கும் தமிழ் உரைநடை.சங்க காலத் தொகைநூல்களில் ஒன்று அகநானூறு. இது மூன்று பகுதியாகப் பகுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. அவற்றுள் ஒன்று ‘மணிமிடைப் பவளம்’. இப்பகுப்பில் உள்ள 180 பாடல்களும் நீலநிற மணியோடு செந்நிறப் பவளம் சேர்த்துத் தொடுத்தாற்போன்ற அமைதியினைக் கொண்டிருப்பதால் இதற்கு மணிமிடைப் பவளம் எனப் பெயர் சூட்டினர். இந்த ‘மணிமிடைப் பவளம்’ என்னும் சொல் நாளடைவில் ‘மணிப்பிரவாளம்’ என மருவி வழங்குகிறது.பன்னிரண்டு ஆழ்வார்களில் ஒருவரான நம்மாழ்வார் இயற்றிய திருவாய்மொழி நூலிலுள்ள பாடல்களுக்கு ஐந்து பேர் எழுதிய பழமையான ஈடு உரைகள் உள்ளன. திருவாய்மொழி ஈடு உரை மணிப்பிரவாள நடையில் அமைந்துள்ளது. திருவாய்மொழி வேதத்தின் சாரமாகவும், தத்துவக் களஞ்சியமாகவும் விளங்குகிறது. இவற்றை வெளிப்படுத்தும் வகையில் இதன் உரைகள் உள்ளன.சோழப் பேரரசுக் காலத்திலும் அதன் பின்னரும், இன்றைய கேரளத்தையும் உள்ளடக்கியிருந்த தமிழ் நாட்டில் ஒருசில வட்டாரங்களில் வடமொழிச் செல்வாக்கு மிகுந்திருந்தது. வடமொழி உயர்வானதாகவும், இறைவனுடைய மொழியாகவும் கற்பிக்கப்பட்ட காலம் அது. தமிழில் வடமொழியைக் கலந்து எழுதுவது உயர் நடையாக அவ்வட்டாரங்களில் எண்ணப்பட்டது. ஆழ்வார்களுக்குப் பின்னர், அவர்களுடைய நூல்களுக்கு உரை எழுதிய இராமானுசருடைய ஆக்கங்கள் [மேற்கோள் தேவை] மணிப்பிரவாள நடையிலேயே அமைந்திருந்தன. சோழர்காலத்தில் வடமொழியின் வழி புகுந்த சமயக் கருத்துருக்களும், தமிழில் எழுந்த வடமொழித் தழுவல் நூல்களும் இத்தகைய போக்குக்கு வாய்ப்பாக அமைந்தன.அன்றைய சேர நாட்டில், மணிப்பிரவாளத்தின் தாக்கம் கடுமையாக இருந்ததால் சேர நாட்டுத் தமிழ், இன்று மலையாளம் என அழைக்கப்படும் புதிய மொழியாக மாறிவிட்டது.மணிப்பிரவாள நடையின் பாங்குதிருவாய்மொழி இரண்டாம்-பத்து எட்டாம்-திருவாய்மொழி பத்தாம் பாடலையும் அதற்கு ஈடு முப்பத்தாறாயிரப் படி தந்துள்ள மணிப்பிரவாள நடை உரையையும் இங்குக் காணலாம்.பத்தாம் பாட்டு – ‘இவர்களை விடீர், நாம் முந்துமுன்னம் இவர்களைப் போலே யாகாதே அவனை அனுபவிக்கப் பெற்றோமிறே’ என்று ஸ்வலாபாநுஸந் தாகத்தாலே ஹ்ருஷ்டராகிறார்.சீர்மைகொள் வீடு சுவர்க்கம் நரகீறாஈர்மைகொள் தேவர் நடுவாமற் றெப்பொருட்கும்வேர்முதலாய் வித்தாய்ப் பரந்து தனி நின்றகார்முகில்போல் வண்ணன்என் கண்ணனைநான் கண்டேனே.[சீர்மைகொள் இத்யாதி] ஸர்வப்ரகாரத்தாலும் நன்றான பரமபதம், பரிமிதஸுகமான ஸவர்க்கம், நிஷ்க்ருஷ்டதுர்க்கமேயான நரகம், இவை முடிவாக, ஈரப்பாடுடையரான தேவர்கள் நடுவாக, மற்றுமுண்டான திர்யகாதிகளுக்கும், [வேர்முதலாய் வித்தாய்] த்ரிவிதகாரணமும் தானேயாய், [பரந்து] \\"தத்ஸ்ருஷ்ட்வா ததேவாநுப்ராவிசத் ததநுப்ரவிச்ய ஸச்சத்யச்சாபவத்\\" என்கிறபடியே முந்துற இவற்றையுடைய உண்டாக்கி, பின்னை இவற்றையுடைய வஸ்துத்வநாம பாக்த்துவங்களுக்காக அநுப்ரவேசித்து, இப்படி ஜகதாரகராய்நின்று, [தனிநின்ற இத்யாதி] இப்படி ஜகச்சரீரனாய் நின்றவளவேயன்றிக்கே, தன்னுடைய வ்யாவ்ருத்தி தோன்றும்படி ஸ்ரீ வைகுண்டத்திலே வர்ஷுகவலாஹகம் போலே யிருக்கிற அழகிய திருமேனியை யுடையனாயிருந்தவைத்து க்ருஷ்ணனாய் வந்து அவதரித்து எனக்குக் கையாளனானவனை நான் முந்துற முன்னம் கண்டநுமவிக்கப் பெற்றே னென்கிறார்,இதில்கையாளன் ஆனவன் = கையாள், எடுபிடி-வேலையாள்,அன்றிக்கே = அல்லாமலும்போன்ற தமிழ் வழக்கையும் காணமுடிகிறது.மணிப்பிரவாள நடை    தமிழில் வடமொழிச் சொற்களைப் பயன்படுத்திப் பேசுவதோ அல்லது எழுதுவதோ மணிப்பிரவாள நடை எனப்படும்.  எடுத்துக்காட்டாக தமிழில் உள்ள வார்த்தையான பல்கலைக்கழகம் என்பதை வலிந்து வடமொழிச் சொற்களைப் பயன்படுத்தி சர்வகலாசாலை என மாற்றியமைக்கப்படுகிறது.  சர்வகலாசாலை என்ற வார்த்தையில் சர்வம் என்ற வடமொழிச் சொல்லுக்கு அனைத்தும் என்றும் கலா என்ற வடமொழிச் சொல்லுக்கு கலை என்றும் பொருள்படுகிறது.  பாடல் சொல்லும் பொருள்வீடு என்னும் சீர்மை, சுவர்க்கம் (இன்ப உலகம்), நரகம் (துன்ப உலகம்), தேவர் உலகம் (அன்பு கொண்டோர் உலகம்), மற்றுமுள்ள எல்லாப் பொருள்கள் ஆகிய அனைத்துக்கும் வேராகவும், முதலாகவும், வித்தாகவும், பரந்து நிற்பவன் என் கண்ணன். அவனை நான் கண்டேன் – என்கிறார், ஆழ்வார்.எடுத்துக்காட்டுஅக்காலத்திய மணிப்பிரவாள நடைக்கு எடுத்துக்காட்டாக \\"உபதேசரத்னமாலை\\" என்னும் நூலிலிருந்து ஒர் பகுதியைக் கீழே காணலாம்.மணவாளமாமுனிகள் தமக்காசார்யரான பிள்ளையுடைய ப்ரசாதத்தாலே, க்ரமாசுதமாய் வந்த அர்த்த விசேஷங்களைப் பின்பற்றாருமறிந்து உஜ்ஜீலிக்கும் படி, ப்ரபந்தரூபேன உபதேசித்து ப்ரகாசிப்பிக்கிறோமென்று ச்ரோத்ரு புத்தி ஸமாதாநார்த்தமாக ப்ரதிஞ்ஞை பண்ணி யருளுகிறார்.வடமொழி ஒலிகளை குறிக்க கிரந்த எழுத்துக்கள் பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டன. தமிழ் மணிப்பிரவாள நடையில் தமிழ் எழுத்துக்களும், கிரந்த எழுத்துக்களும் கலந்து எழுத்தப்பட்டன. கீழே மேற்கூறிய பகுதி எவ்வாறு கிரந்தம் கலந்து எழுதப்பட்டது என்பதை காணலாம்.மணிப்பிரவாளத்தின் தோற்றத்தை குறித்து மு.வரதராசரின் கருத்து“நாட்டில் இரு மொழியையும் கற்றுத்தேர்ந்த புலவர் பரம்பரையுடன், வடமொழியை மட்டும் கற்ற புலவர்களும் தமிழ்மட்டுமே கற்ற புலவர்களும் வாழந்து வந்தனர்.அந்த நிலையில் தமிழறிவு ஒரு புறமும் வடமொழி அறிவு மற்றொரு புறமும் தனித்து இருப்பதை அறிந்த அறிஞர்கள் சிலர் ஒரு புது முயற்சியில் ஈடுபட்டார்கள். சமஸ்கிருத சொற்களையும் தமிழ் சொற்களையும் கலந்த ஒரு மொழிநடையைப் படைத்து மணிப்பிரவாளம் என பெயரிட்டு எழுதத் தொடங்கினார்கள். அதன் வாயிலாக, வடமொழிக்கும் தமிழுக்கும் நெருங்கிய உறவு ஏற்படும் என்றும் வடமொழிப்புலவர்களும் தமிழ்ப் புலவர்களும் ஒன்று பட முடியும் எனவும் நம்பினார்கள். மணிப்பிரவாளத்தை வளர்த்தவர்களின் நோக்கம் நல்ல நோக்கமே. தமிழ் நாட்டில் வீணான பிளவு வளர்வதை விரும்பாமல் அறிவுலகத்தில் ஒரு நல்ல ஒற்றுமை ஏற்படுத்துவதற்கு அது உதவியாகும் என நம்பினர். ஆனால், ஒரு நாட்டு மக்களின் வாழ்விலும் சிந்தனையிலும் வழிவழியாக ஊறி, வளர்ந்துவிட்ட மொழியின் தன்மையை படித்தவர்கள் சிலர் சேர்ந்து முயற்சி செய்து மாற்றிவிட முடியாது என்பதை அவர்கள் உணரவில்லை. நல்ல நோக்கம் கொண்டதே ஆயினும், மொழி இயல்புக்கு மாறானது ஆகையால், அவர்களின் நோக்கம் தோல்வியை கண்டது.”"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਾਝ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਮਾਇਆ ਮੋਹੁ ਜਗਤੁ ਸਬਾਇਆ ॥ਤ੍ਰੈ ਗੁਣ ਦੀਸਹਿ ਮੋਹੇ ਮਾਇਆ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪਰਸਾਦੀ ਕੋ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਬੂਝੈ ਚਉਥੈ ਪਦਿ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੧॥ਹਉ ਵਾਰੀ ਜੀਉ ਵਾਰੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਮੋਹੁ ਸਬਦਿ ਜਲਾਵਣਿਆ ॥ਮਾਇਆ ਮੋਹੁ ਜਲਾਏ ਸੋ ਹਰਿ ਸਿਉ ਚਿਤੁ ਲਾਏ ਹਰਿ ਦਰਿ ਮਹਲੀ ਸੋਭਾ ਪਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਦੇਵੀ ਦੇਵਾ ਮੂਲੁ ਹੈ ਮਾਇਆ ॥ਸਿੰਮ੍ਰਿਤਿ ਸਾਸਤ ਜਿੰਨਿ ਉਪਾਇਆ ॥ਕਾਮੁ ਕ੍ਰੋਧੁ ਪਸਰਿਆ ਸੰਸਾਰੇ ਆਇ ਜਾਇ ਦੁਖੁ ਪਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੨॥ਤਿਸੁ ਵਿਚਿ ਗਿਆਨ ਰਤਨੁ ਇਕੁ ਪਾਇਆ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪਰਸਾਦੀ ਮੰਨਿ ਵਸਾਇਆ ॥ਜਤੁ ਸਤੁ ਸੰਜਮੁ ਸਚੁ ਕਮਾਵੈ ਗੁਰਿ ਪੂਰੈ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਵਣਿਆ ॥੩॥ਪੇਈਅੜੈ ਧਨ ਭਰਮਿ ਭੁਲਾਣੀ ॥ਦੂਜੈ ਲਾਗੀ ਫਿਰਿ ਪਛੋਤਾਣੀ ॥ਹਲਤੁ ਪਲਤੁ ਦੋਵੈ ਗਵਾਏ ਸੁਪਨੈ ਸੁਖੁ ਨ ਪਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੪॥ਪੇਈਅੜੈ ਧਨ ਕੰਤੁ ਸਮਾਲੇ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪਰਸਾਦੀ ਵੇਖੈ ਨਾਲੇ ॥ਪਿਰ ਕੈ ਸਹਜਿ ਰਹੈ ਰੰਗਿ ਰਾਤੀ ਸਬਦਿ ਸਿੰਗਾਰੁ ਬਣਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੫॥ਸਫਲੁ ਜਨਮੁ ਜਿਨਾ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਪਾਇਆ ॥ਦੂਜਾ ਭਾਉ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦਿ ਜਲਾਇਆ ॥ਏਕੋ ਰਵਿ ਰਹਿਆ ਘਟ ਅੰਤਰਿ ਮਿਲਿ ਸਤਸੰਗਤਿ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੬॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਨ ਸੇਵੇ ਸੋ ਕਾਹੇ ਆਇਆ ॥ਧ੍ਰਿਗੁ ਜੀਵਣੁ ਬਿਰਥਾ ਜਨਮੁ ਗਵਾਇਆ ॥ਮਨਮੁਖਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਚਿਤਿ ਨ ਆਵੈ ਬਿਨੁ ਨਾਵੈ ਬਹੁ ਦੁਖੁ ਪਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੭॥ਜਿਨਿ ਸਿਸਟਿ ਸਾਜੀ ਸੋਈ ਜਾਣੈ ॥ਆਪੇ ਮੇਲੈ ਸਬਦਿ ਪਛਾਣੈ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮੁ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਤਿਨ ਜਨ ਕਉ ਜਿਨ ਧੁਰਿ ਮਸਤਕਿ ਲੇਖੁ ਲਿਖਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੮॥੧॥੩੨॥੩੩॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 129 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਜਗਤ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਆਪ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ, ਸਾਰੇ ਹੀ ਜੀਵ ਤਿੰਨਾਂ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਹੇਠ ਹਨ, ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ ।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਕੋਈ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਇਸ ਗੱਲ ਨੂੰ) ਸਮਝਦਾ ਹੈ । ਉਹ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਤਿੰਨਾਂ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੀ ਮਾਰ ਤੋਂ ਉਤਲੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਜੋੜੀ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਮੈਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਸਦਾ ਸਦਕੇ ਹਾਂ ਕੁਰਬਾਨ ਹਾਂ, ਜੇਹੜੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਸਾੜ ਦੇਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਸਾੜ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ) ਨਾਲ ਆਪਣਾ ਚਿਤ ਜੋੜ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਹਜ਼ੂਰੀ ਵਿਚ ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਪਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਇਹ ਮਾਇਆ ਹੀ (ਭਾਵ, ਸੁਖਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਾਮਨਾ ਤੇ ਦੁਖਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਡਰ) ਦੇਵੀਆਂ ਦੇਵਤੇ ਰਚੇ ਜਾਣ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਹੈ,ਇਸ ਮਾਇਆ ਨੇ ਹੀ ਸਿਮ੍ਰਿਤੀਆਂ ਤੇ ਸ਼ਾਸਤ੍ਰ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੇ (ਭਾਵ, ਸੁਖਾਂ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤੀ ਤੇ ਦੁੱਖਾਂ ਦੀ ਨਿਵਿਰਤੀ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਤਰ ਹੀ ਸਿਮ੍ਰਿਤੀਆਂ ਸ਼ਾਸਤ੍ਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਕਰਮ ਕਾਂਡ ਰਚੇ ਗਏ) ।ਸਾਰੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਸੁਖਾਂ ਦੀ ਲਾਲਸਾ ਤੇ ਦੁਖਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਡਰ ਦਾ ਜਜ਼ਬਾ ਪਸਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਜੀਵ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਦੇ ਗੇੜ ਵਿਚ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਦੁਖ ਪਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ।੨।ਇਸ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ (ਹੀ) ਇਕ ਰਤਨ (ਭੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਹੈ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਦਾ ਰਤਨ ।(ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਉਹ ਰਤਨ) ਲੱਭ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਰਤਨ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ (ਪ੍ਰੋ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ),ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪੂਰੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ, ਮਾਨੋ, ਸਦਾ ਟਿਕੇ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਜਤ ਕਮਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਸਤ ਕਮਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਸੰਜਮ ਕਮਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ।੩।ਜੇਹੜੀ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਇਸ ਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਭਟਕਣਾ ਵਿਚ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਕੁਰਾਹੇ ਪਈ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈਉਹ (ਸਦਾ) ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਮਗਨ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਆਖ਼ਿਰ ਪਛੁਤਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ।ਉਹ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਇਹ ਲੋਕ ਤੇ ਪਰਲੋਕ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਗਵਾ ਲੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸੁਪਨੇ ਵਿਚ ਭੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਨਸੀਬ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ ।੪।ਜੇਹੜੀ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਇਸ ਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ ਖਸਮ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ) ਸੰਭਾਲ ਰੱਖਦੀ ਹੈ,ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਗ-ਸੰਗ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਵੇਖਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ,ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ-ਰੰਗ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦਾ) ਸਿੰਗਾਰ ਬਣਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ।੫।ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ (ਵਡ-ਭਾਗੀ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ) ਨੂੰ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲ ਪਿਆ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਮਨੁੱਖਾ-ਜਨਮ ਕਾਮਯਾਬ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ,ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ ਉਹ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਸਾੜ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦੀ ਯਾਦ) ਹੀ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੬।ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਪਰਨਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੈਂਦਾ, ਉਹ ਦੁਨੀਆ ਵਿਚ ਜਿਹਾ ਆਇਆ ਜਿਹਾ ਨਾਹ ਆਇਆ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਸਾਰਾ ਜੀਵਨ ਫਿਟਕਾਰ ਜੋਗ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਆਪਣਾ ਮਨੁੱਖਾ ਜਨਮ ਵਿਅਰਥ ਗਵਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਚਿਤ ਵਿਚ (ਕਦੇ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਵੱਸਦਾ, ਨਾਮ ਤੋਂ ਖੁੰਝ ਕੇ ਉਹ ਬਹੁਤ ਦੁੱਖ ਸਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੭।(ਪਰ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਕੀਹ ਵੱਸ ?) ਜਿਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਜਗਤ ਰਚਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਹੀ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਦੀ ਇਸ ਖੇਡ ਨੂੰ) ਜਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਲੋੜਾਂ) ਪਛਾਣ ਕੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਮਿਲਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਉਹਨਾਂ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੱਥੇ ਉੱਤੋਂ ਧੁਰੋਂ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ (ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤੀ ਦਾ) ਲੇਖ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੮।੧।੩੨।੩੩।\\""},{"question":"Ahitsio izay diso tsipelina ato anatin'ity fehezanteny manaraka ity:\\"Nisy mpifakatia roa nifanaraka teny fa tsy hifandao mandrakizay. Kanefa indray andro tratra nampirafy ny ray tamin'izy reo ka dia tsy maintsy notaperina ilay fiaraana mamy dia mamy. Eny ontsa dia ontsa ny fò fa atao aona moa.\\"","answer":"Ito ilay fehezanteny miaraka amin'ny tsipelina efa voahitsy:\\"Nisy mpifankatia roa nifanaraka teny fa tsy hifandao mandrakizay. Kanefa indray andro tratra nampirafy ny iray tamin'izy ireo ka dia tsy maintsy notaperina ilay fiarahana mamy dia mamy. Eny ontsa dia ontsy ny fò fa atao ahoana moa. \\""},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 静岡県富士市に富士山が見える岩本山公園があります。この公園には、30種類、300本ぐらいの梅の木が植えてあって、今、梅の花がきれいに咲いています。富士市では紙をたくさん生産していて、公園には紙で作ったものが飾ってあります。木の周りには紙の傘があって、木には紙のちょうちんがついています。夜は明るくライトアップしています。公園に来た人たちは、光できれいに見える傘の花の模様や、ちょうちんで明るくなった夜の景色を楽しんでいました。男の子は「初めて見ました。とてもきれいだと思いました」と話していました。夜のライトアップは、23日まで楽しむことができます。雨のときは中止です。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。"},{"question":"సందర్శించిన ఒక ప్రదేశాన్ని గూర్చి వివరిస్తూ మిత్రునికి లేఖ.","answer":"హైద్రాబాదు,x x x x xప్రియ మిత్రుడు శంకరు,నేను క్షేమంగా ఉన్నాను. మీరంతా క్షేమమని తలుస్తాను. నేను ఇటీవల ఆగ్రా వెళ్ళివచ్చాను. అక్కడి విశేషాలు నీకు వివరిస్తాను.ఆలో ముఖ్యంగా చూడదగ్గది తాజ్ మహల్. షాజహాన్ దంపతుల పవిత్ర ప్రణయానికి శాశ్వత చిహ్నమే తాజమహల్. దాన్ని చూసి నేను పొందిన ఆనందం అంతా ఇంతా కాదు. అది ఒక ఎత్తైన వేదిక మీద ఉన్న చలువరాతి కట్టడం. దానికి నాలుగువైపులా నాలుగు చంద్రకాంత శిలా స్తంభాలున్నాయి. ప్రధాన భవనం లోపల గోడలు మణులతో చెక్కబడి ఉన్నాయి. యమునా నదీతీరంలో ఉన్న ఆ తాజ్ మహల్ సౌందర్యం చూసి ఆనందించవలసిందే గాని చెప్పడానికి వీలుకాదు. అందుకే ప్రపంచంలోని ఏడు వింతలలో తాజ్ మహల్ కూడా చోటు చేసుకుందని చెప్పవచ్చు. నీవు కూడా అవకాశం దొరికినప్పుడు తాజ్ మహల్ తప్పక చూడవలసిందిగా కోరుతున్నాను.ఇట్లు,నీ ప్రియమిత్రుడు,ఆర్ శ్రీనివాస్.చిరునామా :కె. శంకరరావు,S/O సత్యనారాయణరావు గారు,ఆర్.ఆర్. నగర్,విజయవాడ – 520 012."},{"question":"Pamela Adie","answer":"Pamela Adie jẹ́ ònkàtàn, olùbá ọ̀pọ̀ èrò sọ̀rọ̀, ato ajìjàn-n-gbara fún ẹ̀tọ́ àwọn LGBT ní orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Pamela di ìlú mọ̀ọ́ká pẹ̀lú akitiyan rẹ̀ lórí ẹ̀tọ́ awọ LGBTQ ní orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Iṣẹ́ ìwádí rẹ̀ ni ó dá lé LGBT rights in Nigeria lọ́rísiríṣi, lára ìwé rẹ̀ tí ó ti kọ ni Under the Rainbow eré tí ó fi ìrírí rẹ̀ hàn. Lára eré rẹ̀ ni ó ti ṣe àfihàn eré tí ó jọ mọ́ bí Obìnrin ṣe ń ṣọkọ obìnrin tí wọ́n pe ní Ìfé . Òun ni Adarí agbà fún ajọ tí kìí ṣe ti ìjọba tí wọ́n pè ní Equality Hub.Lóòtọ́ ni ó ṣe ìgbéyàwó ọkọ rẹ̀ ọkùnrin kan, amọ́ ó sọ ní gbangba wípé òlúfẹ́ obìrin bíi tìrẹ̀ ni oun tí àwọn gẹ̀ẹ́sì ń pe ní lesbian, ìkéde yí ni ó ṣe ní ọdún 2011 nígbà tí ó ṣe ìpàdé pẹ̀lú àwọn ẹbí rẹ̀. She hails from Calabar, Cross River State.Pamela kẹ́kọ́ nípa ìmọ̀ òfin ní ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ Webster University tí ó sì parí ẹ̀kọ́ ọ̀mọ̀wé Masters degree rẹ̀ ní ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ University of Baltimore. Ó tún kẹ́kọ́ gboyè akọ́kọ́ ní inú ìmọ̀ ìṣàkóso okòwò Business administration láti ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ University of Wisconsin-Superior. Ó tún lọ kẹ́kọ́ nípa ẹ̀tọ́ LGBT tí ó sìntibẹ̀ di obìrin akọ́kọ́ntí ó jẹ́ a jànfẹ́tó àwọ LGBT ní orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Bá kan náà ni ó kópa nibi àpérò okòwò àgbáyé ní ọdún 2017 tí ó sì sọ̀rọ̀ nípa ẹ̀tọ́ àwọn LGBT ní inú àpérò náà níbi tí ó ti sọ̀rọ̀ nípa pàtàkì Àwọn LGBT ní ibi iṣẹ́.Ó ti kọ ìtàn tí wọn ti sọ di eré tí ó sí tún jẹ́ adarí eré náà tí wọ́n pe ní Under te Rainbow, eré tí ó da lé bí Obìnrin ṣe ń ṣọkọ obìnrin, irúfẹ́ akọ́kọ́ irú rẹ̀ tí wọn yóò gbé jáde ní orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Eré yí ni ó da lè ìṣẹ̀lẹ̀ ìgbésí ayé rẹ̀. Ní ọdún 2019, wọ́n yàn fún amì-ẹ̀yẹ Mary Chinwa Award tí orúkọ nrẹ̀ sì jáde níbiẹ̀ ní ọdún 2018.ÌféÀyọkà olórí: ÌféPamela fi èrò rẹ̀ han nípa gbígbé eré kan jáde tí yóò da lè bí Obìnrin ṣe ń ṣọkọ obìnrin tí ó lè ní Ìfé. Orísiríṣi àríwísí ni ó wáyé lórí eré tí ó ní oun fẹ́ gbé jáde náà látàrí bí ìjọba orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà lábẹ́ ìṣèjọba Goodluck Jonathan ti fòfin de étọ́ LGBT. Oun ati gbajú-gbajà òṣèré Uyaiedu Ikpe-Etim pẹ̀lú ajọ Equality Hub ni wọ́n jọ pawọ́pọ̀ gbé eré náà jáde. Eré yí ni ó jẹ́ eré akọ́kọ́ tí yóò da lè bí Obìnrin ṣe ń ṣọkọ obìnrintabí LGBT ní orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Eré náà rí ìdádúró oríṣiríṣi látàrí ayẹ̀wó tó gbórín lọ́wọ́ àjọ tí ó ń ṣe ayẹ̀wò eré sì ni má agbéléwò ní orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Kódà àjọ náà fi àtimọ́lé dún kòkokò mọ́ àwọn òṣèré náà bí wọ́n bá gbé eré náà jáde."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk spaghetti carbonara? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah yang terperinci.","answer":"Bahan: 1 paket 500 gm spaghetti / vermicilli / fettuccine, 1 dada ayam tanpa tulang, 1 tin besar (420 gm) Campbell's Cream of Mushroom Soup (atau seumpamanya), 1 tin besar (420 gm) cendawan butang, 1 biji bawang besar, 3 ulas bawang putih, 1 sudu kecil lada hitam, 2 sudu besar minyak masak, Mentega, GaramCara penyediaan:1. Bersihkan dan potong kecil isi ayam.2. Cencang bawang putih dan potong dadu bawang besar.3. Hiris nipis cendawan butang.4. Tumbuk kasar lada hitam.Cara memasak:1. Didihkan air dalam periuk, kemudian masukkan satu sudu besar garam dan kemudian masukkanspaghetti.2. Kacau supaya spaghetti tidak melekat.3. Bila spaghetti lembut, angkat dan tuskan."},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Francisco de Zurbarán. ","answer":" Infotaula de personaFrancisco de ZurbaránCuir in eagar ar WikidataBeathaisnéisBreith\\t7 Samhain 1598Fuente de Cantos Cuir in eagar ar WikidataBás\\t27 Lúnasa 166465 bliana d'aoisMaidrid Cuir in eagar ar WikidataFaisnéis phearsantaGrúpa eitneach\\tSpáinnighGníomhaíochtRéimse oibre\\tPéintéireachtSuíomh oibre\\tMaidrid (1658–1664)Sevilla (1614–1658) Cuir in eagar ar WikidataGairm\\tpéintéir Cuir in eagar ar WikidataTréimhse oibre\\t1614 –  1664Seánra\\tÁbhar neamhbheo, religious painting (en) Aistrigh, portráid, péintéireacht staire, péintéireacht seánra agus pictiúr miotaseolaíochtaGluaiseacht\\tBarócachCritical catalogue (en) Aistrigh\\tFrancisco de Zurbarán, 1598-1664 (en) Aistrigh (2009) Cuir in eagar ar WikidataMac/iníon léinn\\tJosé de SarabiaTeangacha\\tAn SpáinnisSaotharSaothar suntasach(1627) Crucifixion of Christ (en) Aistrigh(1632) Immaculate Conception (en) Aistrigh(1655) St. Hugh in the Refectory of the Carthusians (en) Aistrigh Cuir in eagar ar WikidataTeaghlachCéile\\tMaría PáezBeatriz de MoralesLeonor de Torder Cuir in eagar ar WikidataPáiste\\tJuan de Zurbarán ( ) Cuir in eagar ar WikidataMusicbrainz: 1ea75fda-d017-4d18-bfb3-d2765766a837 Discogs: 2278316 Find a Grave: 7339012 Cuir in eagar ar WikidataEalaíontóir ó Ré Órga na Spáinne ab ea Francisco de Zurbarán (Fuente de Cantos, Badajoz, 7 Samhain, 1598 - Maidrid, 27 Lúnasa, 1664).Is comhaimseartha agus cara le Velázquez é, Zurbarán ar fheabhas sa phéintéireacht reiligiúnach, ina nochtann a stíl neart amhairc iontach agus misteachas domhain. Bhí sé ina ealaíontóir ionadaíoch ar an bhFrith-Reifirméisean. Faoi thionchar Caravaggio ina laethanta tosaigh, tháinig forbairt ar a stíl chun na péintéirí Mannerist na hIodáile a chomhfhogasú. Bogann a phictiúir ó réalachas Velázquez agus tá a chuid cumadóireachta tréithrithe ag samhaltú chiaroscuro le toin níos aigéadaí."},{"question":"ඉන්දියාවට පැමිණීමට පෙර ආර්‍යයන්ගේ වාසභූමිය වූයේ කුමක්ද?","answer":"ඉන්දියාවට පැමිණීමට පෙර ආර්‍යයන්ගේ වාසභූමිය වූයේ මධ්‍යම ආසියාවේ ස්ටෙප්ස් තණබිම්ය."},{"question":"\\"Темага байланыштуу Ибни Аббастан келген бир риваятты эскерте кетүүнү туура көрдүм: Алла Таала Обо энени Адам атанын сол жак кабыргасынан жаратты. Адам ата ал учурда  ....\\"-окуяны кандай улантсак болот ? ( 2-4 сүйлөм болушу мүмкүн )","answer":"Окуянын мындайча өнүгүшү мүмкүн :\\"Темага байланыштуу Ибни Аббастан келген бир риваятты эскерте кетүүнү туура көрдүм: Алла Таала Обо энени Адам атанын сол жак кабыргасынан жаратты. Адам ата ал учурда уйкуда болчу. Ойгонуп, жанында жаткана Обо энени көрүп, жүрөгү жылый ага колун узатты. Периштелер: “– Эй, Адам, ага жакындаба! Силердин никеңер кыйыла элек!” - деп тоскоол болушту. \\""},{"question":"અહીં નરસિંહ મહેતા રચિત કૃતિ એક \\"રાધિકા સુંદરી !\\" ના શરૂઆતની પંકતિઓ આપેલ છે:\\"રાધિકા સુંદરી ! સકલ શિરોમણી, વેઠ્ઠલા - વલ્લહી માન માગું,ક્ષણુએક નાથને બાથ અળગી કરો, મેલ મમ નાથને પાય લાગું. - રાધિકા. \\"આ કૃતિની આગળની પંકતિઓ લખો.","answer":"રાધિકા સુંદરી ! સકલ શિરોમણી, વેઠ્ઠલા - વલ્લહી માન માગું,ક્ષણુએક નાથને બાથ અળગી કરો, મેલ મમ નાથને પાય લાગું. - રાધિકા. અજિત તેં જિતિયો, અબંધ તે બાંધિયો નેહભર શામ-શુ કેલિ કરતા,તા હરું ચલણ દીસે ઘણુંઘર વિષે, સમુદ્રતનયા હિંડે અંક ભરતા - રાધિકા. પુરુષને પુરુષનો સ્નેહ શું કામનો ? નારીને પુરુષનો સંગ રૂડો,જેની માયા વિષે વિશ્વ બૂડી રહ્યું, તેહ હરિ રાધિકા સંગ બૂડ્યો - રાધિકા. છેલ ચંચળ ! અહંકાર નવ કિજિયે, જાય અહંકાર ત્ જોત જોતાં,ભણે નરસૈયો : 'મેલ મમ નાથને, નીકળશે કાદવ કોઠી ધોતા' - રાધિકા. "},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Pahlawan dari timur, susah untuk mengesan mereka.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah ninja"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੧ ॥ਹਉਮੈ ਕਰਤ ਭੇਖੀ ਨਹੀ ਜਾਨਿਆ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਭਗਤਿ ਵਿਰਲੇ ਮਨੁ ਮਾਨਿਆ ॥੧॥ਹਉ ਹਉ ਕਰਤ ਨਹੀ ਸਚੁ ਪਾਈਐ ॥ਹਉਮੈ ਜਾਇ ਪਰਮ ਪਦੁ ਪਾਈਐ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਹਉਮੈ ਕਰਿ ਰਾਜੇ ਬਹੁ ਧਾਵਹਿ ॥ਹਉਮੈ ਖਪਹਿ ਜਨਮਿ ਮਰਿ ਆਵਹਿ ॥੨॥ਹਉਮੈ ਨਿਵਰੈ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦੁ ਵੀਚਾਰੈ ॥ਚੰਚਲ ਮਤਿ ਤਿਆਗੈ ਪੰਚ ਸੰਘਾਰੈ ॥੩॥ਅੰਤਰਿ ਸਾਚੁ ਸਹਜ ਘਰਿ ਆਵਹਿ ॥ਰਾਜਨੁ ਜਾਣਿ ਪਰਮ ਗਤਿ ਪਾਵਹਿ ॥੪॥ਸਚੁ ਕਰਣੀ ਗੁਰੁ ਭਰਮੁ ਚੁਕਾਵੈ ॥ਨਿਰਭਉ ਕੈ ਘਰਿ ਤਾੜੀ ਲਾਵੈ ॥੫॥ਹਉ ਹਉ ਕਰਿ ਮਰਣਾ ਕਿਆ ਪਾਵੈ ॥ਪੂਰਾ ਗੁਰੁ ਭੇਟੇ ਸੋ ਝਗਰੁ ਚੁਕਾਵੈ ॥੬॥ਜੇਤੀ ਹੈ ਤੇਤੀ ਕਿਹੁ ਨਾਹੀ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਗਿਆਨ ਭੇਟਿ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਹੀ ॥੭॥ਹਉਮੈ ਬੰਧਨ ਬੰਧਿ ਭਵਾਵੈ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਰਾਮ ਭਗਤਿ ਸੁਖੁ ਪਾਵੈ ॥੮॥੧੩॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 226 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(“ਮੈਂ ਧਰਮੀ ਹਾਂ ਮੈਂ ਧਰਮੀ ਹਾਂ” ਇਹ) “ਮੈਂ ਮੈਂ” ਕਰਦਿਆਂ (ਨਿਰੇ) ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਭੇਖਾਂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਕਦੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਨੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਾਈ । ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਹੀ (ਭਾਵ, ਗੁਰੂ ਅੱਗੇ ਆਪਾ-ਭਾਵ ਤਿਆਗਿਆਂ ਹੀ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਵਿਚ ਮਨ ਗਿੱਝਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਅਜੇਹਾ ਆਪਾ-ਭਾਵ ਤਿਆਗਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਕੋਈ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਹੀ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।(ਮੈਂ ਵੱਡਾ ਧਰਮੀ ਹਾਂ, ਮੈਂ ਵੱਡਾ ਰਾਜਾ ਹਾਂ, ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹੀ) ਮੈਂ, ਮੈਂ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ (ਕਦੇ) ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਮਿਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ ਜਦੋਂ ਇਹ ਹਉਮੇ ਦੂਰ ਹੋਵੇ, ਤਦੋਂ ਹੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਚਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਦਰਜਾ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਸਕੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(“ਅਸੀ ਵੱਡੇ ਰਾਜੇ ਹਾਂ,” ਇਸੇ) ਹਉਮੈ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਹੀ ਰਾਜੇ ਇਕ ਦੂਜੇ ਦੇ ਦੇਸਾਂ ਉਤੇ, ਕਈ ਵਾਰੀ ਹੱਲੇ ਕਰਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਆਪਣੇ ਵਡੱਪਣ ਦੇ ਮਾਣ ਵਿਚ ਦੁਖੀ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ (ਸਿੱਟਾ ਇਹ ਨਿਕਲਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਯਾਦ ਭੁਲਾ ਕੇ) ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਦੇ ਗੇੜ ਵਿਚ ਪਏ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੨।ਜੇਹੜਾ (ਵਡ-ਭਾਗੀ) ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚਾਰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਆਪਣੇ ਸੋਚ-ਮੰਡਲ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ) ਉਸ ਦੀ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈਉਹ (ਭਟਕਣਾ ਵਿਚ ਪਾਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਆਪਣੀ) ਹੋਛੀ ਮਤਿ ਤਿਆਗਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਕਾਮਾਦਿਕ ਪੰਜਾਂ ਵੈਰੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਨਾਸ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਵੱਸਦਾ) ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਅਡੋਲ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਸਾਰੀ ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਦੇ ਮਾਲਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨਾਲ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾ ਕੇ ਉਹ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਚੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੪।ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਦੀ ਭਟਕਣਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੂਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਨਿੱਤ-ਕਰਮ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈਉਹ ਨਿਰਭਉ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਸਦਾ ਆਪਣੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਜੋੜੀ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ।੫।“ਹਉਂ, ਹਉਂ; ਮੈਂ, ਮੈਂ” ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤ ਹੀ ਸਹੇੜੀਦੀ ਹੈ, ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਛੁਟ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ ਆਤਮਕ ਗੁਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਭਦਾ । ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਰਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੇ ਇਸ ਟੰਟੇ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਮੁਕਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੬।ਹਉਮੈ ਦੇ ਆਸਰੇ ਜਿਤਨੀ ਭੀ ਦੌੜ-ਭੱਜ ਹੈ ਇਹ ਸਾਰੀ ਦੌੜ-ਭੱਜ ਕੋਈ ਆਤਮਿਕ ਲਾਭ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੁਚਾਂਦੀ । ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਗੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ) ਗਿਆਨ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੭।ਹਉਮੈ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮੋਹ ਦੇ) ਬੰਧਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਬੰਨ੍ਹ ਕੇ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਦੇ ਗੇੜ ਵਿਚ ਪਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਉਹ ਹਉਮੈ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ) ਸੁਖ ਪਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੮।੧੩।\\""},{"question":"آب و هوای شهر تهران چگونه است؟","answer":"تهران دارای اقلیم نیمه‌خشک است. شمال شهر به دلیل ارتفاع بیشتر، خنک‌تر از دیگر مناطق شهر است. همچنین بافت نامتراکم، وجود باغ‌های کهن، بوستان‌ها، فضای سبز حاشیهٔ بزرگراه‌ها و کم بودن فعالیت‌های صنعتی در شمال شهر کمک کرده‌اند تا هوای مناطق شمالی به‌طور متوسط ۲ تا ۳ درجهٔ سانتی‌گراد خنک‌تر از مناطق جنوبی شهر باشد."},{"question":"8-3 egal konbyen?","answer":"8-3 egal 5."},{"question":"Ci ban kembaar la réwum Bahamas nékk","answer":"Réwum Bahamas mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Amerique"},{"question":"नेपालीमा योमरी पुन्ही भनेको के हो ?","answer":"योमरी पुन्ही नेवारी समुदायका लागि शुभ दिन हो । यस दिन काठमाडौं उपत्यकाका बासिन्दाले अन्नपूर्ण बाली र अन्नकी देवी अन्नपूर्णको पूजा गर्ने र राम्रो धान फसलको कामना गर्ने गर्दछन् ।"},{"question":"O ṣoju mi koro (Apa Kin-in-ni)","answer":"Bẹẹ, awọn Boko Haram ko ni i gba Naijiria mọ wa lọwọ bayiiỌsẹ to kọja yii la ba pe ni ọsẹ ẹkun oun oṣe ni Naijiria. Ojumọ kan, iṣẹlẹ aburu kan ni, bi wọn ti n jiiyan gbe, bẹẹ ni wọn n pa awọn mi-in. Ni ipinlẹ Borno, awọn Boko Haram si wọ inu oko irẹsi kan, nibi ti awọn araalu naa ti n ja irẹsi, wọn si pa eeyan mẹtalelogoji lẹẹkan. Wọn ka wọn mọbẹ, wọn si n bẹ wọn lori nikọọkan. Ko sẹni ti yoo gba wọn, ko si sẹni ti wọn le ke si ninu oko nibẹ, ko si ọlọpaa, ko si ṣọja, titi ti wọn fi pa awọn eeyan naa tan. Bi ọrọ yii ti jade lawọn ọmọ Buhari ti sare gbe iwe jade, wọn loun lo kọ ọ, o ni iku awọn eeyan naa ka oun lara, o dun oun gan-an ni, awọn maa ṣeto lati ri i pe iru iku bẹẹ ko tun waye mọ. Bo ba jẹ iru ọrọ yii lo jade lati ẹnu Buhari, eeyan kan ko le ka iye igba ti baba to wa ni Aso Rock yii ti sọ iru ọrọ bẹẹ jade. Ọrọ kan naa ti i maa i sọ jade lẹnu niyẹn: bi wọn ba pa oogun eeyan, yoo ni o dun oun, bi wọn pa ọgbọn eeyan, yoo ni o dun oun, bi wọn pa wọn ni Sokoto, ọrọ kan naa ni, bi wọn pa wọn ni Kafanṣa, ọrọ kan naa ni, bo si jẹ ilẹ Yoruba tabi ilẹ Ibo, ọrọ kan naa ni. Lati ọjọ ti Buhari ti waa n sọ pe oun yoo wa nnkan kan ṣe si i, ko ri kinni kan ṣe o. Ohun to n ṣẹlẹ ni pe, ki i ṣe Buhari lo n kọ awọn ọrọ yii, boya lo si mọ pe iru nnkan bẹẹ ṣẹlẹ. Idi ni pe bi Buhari ba mọ ni, itiju yẹ ko mu oun naa, pe irọ ojoojumọ ti oun n pa fawọn ọmọ Naijiria yii ko daa. Gbogbo igba to ba ti ni oun yoo ṣe kinni kan si ọrọ naa, ko si kinni kan to maa n ṣe, nibẹ ni ọrọ naa yoo si dakẹ si titi ti awọn Boko Haram yii yoo fi tun pa ẹlomi-in jẹ. Wọn ti pariwo titi pe ki Buhari le awọn olori ologun ẹ lọ, pe wọn ko kun oju oṣuwọn, tabi bawo ni awọn ọmọ ogun afẹmiṣofo ti wọn ko le to ẹgbẹrun marun-un (5000) ninu igbo wa yoo ṣe koju awọn ṣọja tiwa ti wọn le ni ẹgbẹrun lọna ọọọdunrun (300,000), ti wọn yoo si maa bori wọn ni gbogbo igba. O han pe apa awọn ṣọja wa ko ka awọn Boko Haram, bẹẹ ni ki i ṣe pe awọn ṣọja wa ko le jagun, awọn ti wọn fi ṣe olori wọn ni wọn n ṣe katikati. Sibẹ, bi gbogbo aye ti n pariwo to yii, Buhari ni awọn olori awọn ologun yii naa loun yoo maa lo lọ, nitori ko si kinni kan to ṣe wọn. Bẹẹ mẹwaa n ṣe awọn olori ologun yii, tabi bi nnkan kan ko ba ṣe wọn, bawo lawọn Boko Haram yoo ṣe maa ṣe bayii fun wa, ti wọn  yoo si maa fojoojumọ pa awọn alaiṣẹ, ti wọn yoo maa fi ẹmi wọn ṣofo bayii, ti ko si ni i si ẹni ti yoo gba wọn kalẹ. Afi ki ẹ ba wa bẹ Buhari ko ji giri, ki ẹ si fi ẹnu epe ba awọn ti wọn n purọ funfun lojoojumọ sọrọ, ki Ọlọrun gbe bukaata to ju agbara tiwọn naa lọ le wọn lọwọ, ki ẹ waa sọ fun Buhari pe ko wa nnkan ṣe si ọrọ eto aabo ilẹ yii, awọn to ba yẹ ko yọ niṣẹ, ko yọ wọn, ko si fi awọn ti yoo yanju iṣoro Boko Haram yii ṣe olori awọn jagunjagun wa. Ẹ tete sọrọ o, ki gbogbo ilu tete sọrọ. Nitori bi a ko ba sọrọ, ti ẹsẹ awọn Boko Haram yii ba rinlẹ daadaa tan nilẹ Hausa, gbogbo orilẹ-ede Naijiria ni wọn yoo kari. Ọlọrun ma jẹ ki Boko Haram gba Naijiria lọwọ gbogbo wa o.Sultan, Lai Muhammed ni kẹ ẹ ranṣe si oSultan ilu Ṣokoto, Ọba Sa’ad Abubakar, sọrọ lọsẹ to kọja yii pẹlu itara. Bo ti n sọrọ naa lo n laagun, bẹẹ, agbalagba to n sọrọ, to n laagun, ẹkun gidi lo n sun. Sultan ni eto aabo ni gbogbo ilẹ Hausa ti dorikodo pata, ko ṣeni kan ti ẹmi ẹ de nibẹ mọ, ko si si ibi kan to lewu ju lati gbe ni gbogbo Naijiria lasiko yii ju ilẹ Hausa lọ. O ni awọn janduku ọmọ Boko Haram ti gba gbogbo ilẹ Hausa to jẹ lọsan-an gangan lo ku ti wọn n rin wọ inu ọja ati ile onile pẹlu ibọn lọwọ wọn, awọn agbofinro aa si maa wo wọn lai le ṣe ohunkohun fun wọn. O ni nnkan yoo buru fun Naijiria gan-an bi ọrọ ba n ṣe bayii lọ. Imọran tiwa ni pe ki Sultan wa aaye, ko lọọ ri Buhari funra ẹ. Ko ma ranṣẹ si i o! Bo ba ranṣẹ si i, irọ buruku lawọn olorikori to yi i ka yoo lọọ pa fun un, wọn yoo sọ pe ko si ogun mọ, ko si ọtẹ mọ nilẹ Hausa, koda, gbogbo Boko Haram lo ti sa lọ tan pata nigba ti wọn gbọ orukọ oun Buhari. Ko too lọọ ri Buhari paapaa, afi ko kọkọ ranṣẹ si Lai Muhammed pe ko waa ri oun o. O yẹ ko gbọrọ lẹnu ọkunrin aturọta-bii-elubọ yii nitori lati bii ọdun karun-un sẹyin ni Bọọda Lai ti n sọ pe ko si Boko Haram ni Naijiria mọ, apa ijọba Buhari ti ka wọn. O daju pe bi eeyan ba pe Lai bayii naa, ọrọ kan naa ti yoo sọ ni pe Buhari ti kapa awọn Boko Haram. Ki i ṣe pe o debẹ tabi o mọ ohun to n lọ nibẹ o, irọ-pipa kan rọ oun lọrun bii nnkan kan ni. Ohun to si ba aye ijọba Buhari jẹ niyi, nitori nibi yoowu ti wọn ba ha Buhari funra rẹ mọ, ko sẹnikan to n sọ ododo fun un. Irọ nla nla ni wọn maa n pa fun un, ti wọn yoo si ni ko si ohun kan to n ṣẹlẹ si awọn ọmọ  Naijiria, awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ alatako kan n pariwo lasan ni. Buhari nilo ẹni ti yoo sọ ootọ fun un, ẹni ti yoo ba a sootọ ọrọ, iru awọn Sultan yii lo si le ṣe e. Nnkan n daru, nnkan si n bajẹ, bẹẹ ilẹ Hausa ni gbogbo atẹgun buruku yii ti n fẹ wa. Bi Sultan ba mọ pe ọrọ yii ka oun lara bo ti n wi yii, ko lọọ ri Buhari, ko si sọ fun un funra ẹ, boya ọkunrin naa yoo gbọ ọrọ si i lẹnu. Bi ko ba ṣe bẹẹ, bo ba jẹ bi nnkan ti n lọ yii naa lo n lọ, ọrọ ti Sultan sọ yoo ṣẹlẹ, awọn Boko Haram yoo gba ilẹ Hausa tan pata, koda, wọn yoo le awọn ọba wọn kuro lori oye, nigba naa ni kaluku yoo mọ pe aburu to wa ninu ijọba yii ju ti Boko Haram yii paapaa lọ. Sultan, tete! Ọjọ n lọ o.Ṣe ẹyin naa ti wọ reluwee awọn ọmọ BuhariLọdun to kọja, nigba ti minisita fun eto igbokegbodo ọkọ, Chibuike Rotimi Amaechi, n pariwo kiri pe Buhari ti ṣe ohun tẹni kan ko ṣe ri, o ti ra ọkọ oju-irin rẹpẹtẹ tuntun-n-tuntun lati maa rin, ko maa ko ero, ki awọn ọmọ Naijiria le maa jẹ anfaani ịjọba dẹmokiresi ti Buhari yii gbe de. Gbogbo alaye ti Amaechi n ṣe nigba naa, nitori pe ibo ti sun mọle ni. Ohun to si ṣe ni lati lo ọrọ reluwee naa lati fi tan awọn eeyan jẹ, ati lati tan Buhari funra ẹ, ki wọn le dibo fun ijọba wọn, ki Buhari paapaa si le ro pe minisita oun yii n ṣiṣẹ gan-an niyẹn. Amaechi lọ sọdọ awọn Ṣiana, awọn si ta awọn aloku ọkọ reluwee fun un, o si kun ọkọ naa lọda, o ko wọn wa si Naijiria, wọn waa ko awọn oloṣelu ati awọn araalu jọ, wọn ni ki wọn waa wo ara ti Buhari da, o ti ṣe bẹẹ, o ko reluwee de jigan. Ṣugbọn ko ju oṣu mẹta ti reluwee ti Amaechi ni oun ra ni tuntun fi bẹrẹ si i ku soju ọna, eefin buruku to dudu kirimu ati ikọ oorekoore leeyan yoo fi da ọkọ oju-irin Amaechi mọ, ko si tọjọ, ko toṣu, tawọn eeyan fi mọ pe aloku pata ni gbogbo reluwee ti ọkunrin yii ko wa, bẹẹ owo tuntun ni wọn gba lọ. Reluwee aloku ni wọn kun lọda, wọn kan waa fi ṣe arumọjẹ fawọn ọmọ Naijiria ni. Boya ni oṣu meji yoo kọja ki reluwee Amaechi yii too ku si oju ọna, eyi to si ṣẹlẹ lọsẹ to kọja yii buru debii pe Ọlọrun lo yọ awọn ero ti reluwee naa ko. Nitori laarin oru, ninu igbo ni reluwee naa da iṣẹ silẹ, bo ba si jẹ awọn Boko Haram gba agbegbe naa kọja ni, wọn yoo maa ko wọn bii adiẹ sinu ago ni. Bawo ni ijọba kan yoo ṣe maa fi ẹmi awọn araalu rẹ wewu bayii!  Bawo ni ijọba kan yoo ṣe kuku koriira awọn eeyan ti wọn n ṣejọba le lori bayii! Bawo ni minisita kan yoo ṣe ko aloku reluwee kalẹ pe ki awọn ọmọ Naijiria maa lo o pẹlu irọ buruku ti wọn n pa fun wọn. Bo ba jẹ loootọ ni Buhari mọ ohun to n lọ, ko si idi kan ti ko fi gbọdọ le ọkunrin Amaechi yii danu lẹsẹkẹsẹ. Ki i ṣe ki wọn le Rotimi Amaechi yii kuro lẹnu iṣẹ ijọba nikan ni o, ijọba Buhari gbọdọ ba a ṣẹjọ, ki wọn beere bo ṣe nawo ti wọn ko fun un, ki wọn beere idi to fi ko ẹmi awọn ọmọ Naijiria sinu ewu bayii! Ko si ohun to yẹ ko kangun ọrọ rẹ ju ko kuro nile ijọba, ko di ero itimọle lọ. Bi eleyii ba ṣẹlẹ si oun, awọn mi-in to ba fẹẹ ṣejọba ni Naijiria yoo bẹru lati purọ fun araalu, lati ko owo wọn jẹ, ati lati fi owo irinṣẹ ati ohun-eelo tuntun ra aloku fun wọn. O di dandan ki ijọba Buhari fiya to tọ jẹ Amaechi, lara ohun to le mu Naijiria daa niyẹn!Ki lo n ṣe awọn eeyan yii bayii oNi ọsẹ to kọja, awọn agbofinro Hisbah ti wọn wa ni Kano kọ iwe kan si ileeṣẹ redio CoolFM ni Kano, iwe naa jẹ iyanu fun awọn eeyan ti ki i ṣe Naijiria paapaa, awọn ti wọn si jẹ ọmọ Naijiria n sọ laarin ara wọn pe ki waa ni orilẹ-ede yii da bayii o. Awọn Hisbah yii ki i ṣe ọlọpaa o, ọlọpaa Sharia ni wọn pe ara wọn, pe ko si ẹni to gbọdọ lodi si ofin Sharia lagbegbe awọn. Awọn ni wọn n fọ ṣọọbu awọn ọlọti, ti wọn si n gbogun ti awọn aṣẹwo ati awọn onitẹtẹ. Eleyii daa daadaa, ṣugbọn ohun to buru ninu iwa wọn ko ju ki wọn ma jẹ ki awọn ẹlẹsin mi-in ṣe ẹsin wọn lọ, tabi aṣeju baba aṣetẹ to mọ awọn eeyan wa lara lapa Oke-Ọya. Ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, to kọja yii ni wọn n pe ni Black Friday ni gbogbo aye. Ilu Amẹrika lo ti bẹrẹ, ko si si ohun ti wọn fi n ṣe ju ọjọ ti wọn n na ọja ni ọpọ lọ. Nitori pe ọjọ naa bọ si ọjọ keji ọjọ Idupẹ (Thanksgiving) lọdọ wọn lọhun-un, wọn maa n fi ọjọ naa ta ọja gbogbo ni owo pọọku. Ko si ọja ti eeyan ko ni i ra ni ọjọ naa lowo pọọku. Awọn ọlọja gbogbo aa si maa polowo ọja wọn, ki awọn eeyan le lọọ ra a. Awọn onileeṣẹ yii ni wọn n polowo ọja lori redio ni Kano, lawọn agbofinro Sharia yii ba kọwe si wọn ni redio yii, wọn ni ki wọn yee darukọ Black Friday lori redio wọn, pe ti wọn ko ba sinmi, ohun ti wọn yoo ri yoo le ju ohun ti wọn ro lọ. Ofin to da ileeṣẹ ibanisọrọ gbogbo silẹ ko fi aaye gba ẹnikẹni lati halẹ mọ wọn, tabi lati ṣe wọn nibi, ṣugbọn awọn Hisbah yii fẹẹ ṣe bẹẹ, wọn ni nitori Kuraani ti sọ pe ọjọ mimọ ni ọjọ Friday. Bẹẹ ni Saudi Arabia, ni ibi to jẹ ikorita ẹsin Islam, wọn n ṣe ipolowo ọja loriṣiiriṣii, ti wọn si n pariwo Black Friday lori redio ati tẹlifiṣan wọn. Bakan naa ni ọrọ naa si kun ori ẹrọ ayelujara, bi eeyan si tẹ “Black Friday in Saudi Arabia” sori Google, yoo ri oriṣiiriṣii nnkan ti wọn n ṣe. Ṣugbọn wahala tiwa pọ nibi yii gan-an, o pọ gan-an ni o. Ọrọ ti ko kan wa rara la oo maa tori ẹ ja, ti a oo maa tori ẹ yọ ara wa lẹnu. Bi wọn ba n ṣe Black Friday ni ilẹ awọn Larubawa gbogbo, kin ni ti awọn eeyan wa nilẹ Hausa nibi lati maa mura ija nitori eyi. Tabi awọn eeyan yii mọ ẹsin yii ju awọn ti wọn mu un wa fun wọn lọ ni. Ko si ohun meji ti awọn tọdọ wa yii n ṣe ju ki wọn fi jale, ki wọn fi rẹ awọn eeyan jẹ, ki wọn si fi fi ọgbọn gba nnkan wọn kuro lọwọ wọn lọ. Bakan naa ni wọn ko tun orukọ ẹsin Islam ṣe loju awọn eeyan, wọn ko fi ẹsin naa han bii ẹsin ifẹ, wọn n fi ẹsin naa han bii ẹsin to ni iwa ika ninu, ti ko si si aanu nibẹ. Ohun ti awọn Hisbah ati awọn ẹlẹgbẹ wọn mi-in n ṣe nilẹ Hausa niyi. Naijiria ki i ṣe orile-ede ẹlẹsin kan gẹgẹ bo ṣe wa ninu ofin wa, ẹsin to ba si wu kaluku lo le ṣe, ti ko sẹni kan to gbọdọ yọ ọ lo lẹnu. Ohun to maa n da wahala silẹ ni pe ijọba ki i da si iru ọrọ bayii nigba to ba yẹ, o digba to ba da rogbodiyan silẹ ki wọn too bẹrẹ si i soyinbo ẹgbẹ. Ijọba gidi gbọdọ ji giri si iru eyi, ki wọn pe awọn ti wọn kọ lẹta naa, ki wọn si kil̀ọ fun wọn, ki wọn ṣalaye fun wọn pe ofin wa lo faaye gba ki kaluku sin ẹsin to ba wu u, ki ẹnikẹni ma si ṣe fi ẹsin rẹ ko ẹlomi-in laya jẹ. O ba ni, ko bajẹ. Ẹ pe awọn Hisbah yii, ẹ ba wọn sọrọ, ẹ jẹ ki wọn mọ pe Naijiria ki i ṣe orilẹ-ede ẹlẹsin kan o!"},{"question":"Adigunjale pade iku ojiji nibi to ti n ji ọkada gbe sa lọ l’Akurẹ","answer":"Ogbologboo adigunjale kan pade iku ojiji nibi to ti n gbiyanju lati ji ọkada ọlọkada gbe sa lọ niluu Akurẹ lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ ta a wa yii.Ọkunrin adigunjale ọhun ti ko sẹni to ti i mọ ibi to ti wa ni wọn lo da ọlọkada kan lọna lagbegbe ileetura Sunview, to wa ni Alagbaka, to si fipa ja ọkada rẹ gba, to n sa lọ.Ariwo ti ẹni to ja lole n pa lawọn ọlọkada ẹgbẹ rẹ gbọ ti wọn fi bẹrẹ si i le ogboju ọlọsa ọhun kaakiri agbegbe naa.Ibi to ti n wa gbogbo ọna ti yoo fi raaye sa mọ awọn to n le e lọwọ lo ti subu lori ọkada to n gun, to si ku loju ẹsẹ.Awọn eeyan agbegbe naa ni wọn lọọ fi iṣẹlẹ yii to awọn agbofinro leti, ilẹ si ti su daadaa ki wọn too gbe igbesẹ ati gbe oku rẹ kuro lẹgbẹẹ titi ibi to ku si."},{"question":"السؤال: من كفل النبي صلى الله عليه وسلم بعد وفاة أمه؟","answer":"الإجابة: جده عبد المطلب"},{"question":" Sheeg Isha Ugu Muhiimsan Ileyska (Iftiinka)","answer":" Isha Ugu Muhiimsan Ileyska (Iftiinka) Waa Qoraxda."},{"question":"\\"Nahazo antso an-telefaona tsy nampoizina avy amin'ny namana iray efa ela aho:\\"Inona no mety ho hiafaran'ny tantara teo aloha?A. Nihaona indray izahay ary nahatsiaro ny fahatsiarovana niraisanay.B. Tranga diso ny maha-izy azy, ary diso olona ilay niantso.","answer":"Ny mety ho hiafaran'ny tantara teo aloha dia nihaona indray izy ire ary nahatsiaro ny fahatsiarovana niraisany fahiny."},{"question":"iPhone'larda şifre nereden değiştirilir?","answer":"iPhone, iPad, veya Apple Watch'unuzda Apple Kimliğinizin parolasını değiştirmek için Ayarlar > [adınız] > Giriş Yapma ve Güvenlik'e dokunun. Parolayı Değiştir'e dokunun. Geçerli parolanızı veya aygıt parolanızı girin, ardından yeni bir parola girip bu parolayı onaylayın. "},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి భావం రాయండి:తే॥గీ॥ ఱాల నిద్రించు ప్రతిమల మేలుకొలిపియులిని సోకించి బయటికిఁ బిలిచినావు;వెలికి రానేర్చి నీ పేరు నిలపకున్నెశాశ్వతుడ వోయి నీవు నిశ్చయముగాను.","answer":"భావం :బాళ్ళల్లో దాగియున్న (నిద్రపోతున్న) బొమ్మలను, నీ ఉలిని తాకించి వాటిని మేల్కొలిపి బయటకు పిలిచావు. ఆ శిల్పాలు బయటకు వచ్చి, నీ పేరు నిలబెట్ట కుండా ఉండవు. నీవు నిశ్చయంగా చిరంజీవివి."},{"question":"शिक्षामा फ्लिप गरिएको कक्षाकोठाको अवधारणाको अन्वेषण गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"फ्लिप गरिएको कक्षाकोठाहरूले परम्परागत शिक्षण विधिहरू उल्टाउँछन्, विद्यार्थीहरूले भिडियोहरू मार्फत घरमै सामग्री सिकाउँछन् र कक्षाको समयमा गतिविधिहरू, छलफलहरू, र समस्या समाधानहरूमा संलग्न हुन्छन्। यो दृष्टिकोणले सक्रिय सिकाइ र विद्यार्थी संलग्नता बढाउँछ।"},{"question":"ਵਿਦਿਆਰਥੀ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਗਣਿਤ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕੀਤੀ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਸ ਨੇ ਕੈਲਕੁਲੇਟਰ ਕੱਢਿਆ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਹ ਉਲਝਣ ਵਿਚ ਪੈ ਗਿਆ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਹ ਉਲਝਣ ਵਿਚ ਪੈ ਗਿਆ।"},{"question":"அகர வரிசைப்படி சொற்களைச் சீர்செய்து எழுதுக.(1) கொன்றை, கெண்டை, கண், கீரன், காடை(2) கெண்டை, கீரன், கொன்றை, காடை, கண்(3) கண், காடை, கீரன், கெண்டை, கொன்றை(4) கண், கீரன், காடை, கொன்றை, கெண்டை","answer":" விடை :(3) கண், காடை, கீரன், கெண்டை, கொன்றை."},{"question":"கேள்வி: இக்கபானா என்பது என்ன?","answer":"பதில்: இக்கபானா  என்பது பூக்கள், மொட்டுகள், இலைகள் மற்றும் தண்டுகளை அழகாக அமைக்கும் ஜப்பானிய கலை.இது அறிவியல் சார்ந்தது ."},{"question":"Мындай үлгү берилди: сапаттуу:сапатсызУшуну карап туруп, төмөнкү варианттардын кайсынысы туура келээрин аныктап бер:(А) өндүрүм : продукт(Б) инфляция : кредит(В) сурам : сунуш(Г) заказ : товар","answer":"Үлгүдө берилген \\"сапаттуу\\" жана \\"сапатсыз\\" деген сөздөр бири-бирине карата толук антонимдер. Үлгүдөгү сөздөрдөй болуп толук антоним байланышта болгон варианттарды караштырабыз. Эгерде (А) вариантын карасак, анда \\"өндүрүм : продукт\\" деген жуп кыргызча сөздүн орус тилине котормосу берилип жатат. (Б) вариантында каржы багытындагы сөздөр берилип жатат, бирок алар бири-бирине антоним эмес. (Г) варианты болсо орус тилиндеги сөздөр берилип жатат, бирок алар дагы бири-бирине антоним эмес. Ошондо толук антоним болгон бир гана вариант \\"(В) сурам : сунуш\\" болуп жатат. Ошентип, туура жооп төмөнкү болду: (В) сурам : сунуш"},{"question":" હરીન્દ્ર દવે દ્વારા લખાયેલી \\"માઘમાં મેં મોકલ્યાં તેડાં\\" કવિતા નો બાકીનો ભાગ લખો.માઘમાં મેં મોકલ્યાં તેડાં તો આવે ગોરીફાગણમાં રમીએ ગુલાલેચૈતર ચઢેને અમે આવશું હો રાજતારે ધૂળિયે આંગણ કોણ મ્હાલે. માઘમાં …આવો તો રંગ નવો કાલવિયે સંગ સંગછલકાવી નેણની પિયાલીવેણ કેરી રેશમની જાળમાં ધરે ન માયઆ તો છે પંખિણી નિરાળી. માઘમાં …","answer":"આ કવિતા નો આગળ નો ભાગ નીચે મુજબ છે:આવે તો આભ મહીં ઊડીએ બે આપણેને ચંદરનો લૂછીએ ડાઘ રેનાનેરી જિંદગીની ઝાંઝેરી ઝંખનાનોમારે ન ગાવો કોઈ રાગ રે. માઘમાં …આવો કે અમથી ઉકેલી ન જાયતમે પાડી’તી ગાંઠ જે રૂમાલેઆવું બોલે તો મને ગમતું રે વાલમાઆવ્યા વિના તે કેમ ચાલે. માઘમાં …"},{"question":"Waa Maxay Magacuyaal Su’aaleed Ee Naxwaha?","answer":"Magacuyaal Su’aaleed:Kee, tee, kuwee, yaa.Tusaale:- Kee baa yimid shalay?- Tee baa dhashay inanka?- Kuwee baad ku aragtay gegida dayuuradaha?- Yaa la yiraahdaa Mahad? Magacuyaal noqod, waa ”is” oo falka xagga hore ka raaca.Ridii way Tnuugtey, nin baa Tdilay.Carruurtii way Maayeen, nimankii way irwareysteen."},{"question":" ඉන්දියාවේ ජාතික ජලජ සත්වයා කුමක්ද?","answer":"ගංගා නම් නදිහි ඩොල්ෆින්ය."},{"question":"10వ తరగతిలో హాజరైన 30 మంది విద్యార్థులలో 18 మంది ఏకరూప దుస్తుల లో, మిగిలినవారు విభిన్న దుస్తులలోను హాజరైనారు. ఎన్నుకొన్న విద్యార్థి ఏకరూప దుస్తులు ధరించుటకు గల సంభావ్యత ఎంత ?","answer":"n(S) = 30, n(U) = 18 .∴ P(U) = n(U)/n(S) = 18/30 = 3/5"},{"question":"Nu picc mi gën a ndaw tudd?","answer":"Ramatu"},{"question":"اكمل الجملة التالية: لم يختف فيروس \\"سارس-كوف-2\\" التاجي الذي يقف خلف جائحة \\"كوفيد-19\\" بعد، ولا يقتصر الأمر على أنه لا يزال يصيب البشر على نطاق واسع، ولكن وفقا لدراسة جديدة، فإنه قد","answer":"انتقل من البشر إلى الغزلان ذات الذيل الأبيض، حيث يبدو أنه يتطور بسرعة. وهذا يشكل خطوره على المنظومه البيئيه برمتها حيث قد يصيب حشرات وحيوانات اخرى قد تعود بالضرر على الانسان في المستقبل"},{"question":"Ipinlẹ Ogun lawọn ọmọ keekeeke yii ti n ṣẹgbẹ okunkun, Eko lọwọ ti ba wọn","answer":"Ọmọọdun mẹẹẹdogun pere ni Sunday Dare ati Ayọmide Sanni Babatunde, ọmọọdun mẹrinla ni Ọlayinka Jubril ni tiẹ, Tosin Balogun lo ti pe ọmọ ọdun mejidinlogun, ṣugbọn ohun kan to da gbogbo wọn pọ yatọ si pe ọjọ ori wọn o ti i pe ogun ọdun ni pe, ọmọ ẹlẹgbẹ okunkun lawọn mẹrẹẹrin lati ipinlẹ Ogun, ọwọ ọlọpaa si ti ba wọn l’Ekoo lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee.ALAROYE gbọ pe ileewe girama ti wọn n pe ni Ọdẹwale Community High School, niluu Ijoko, nipinlẹ Ogun, ni wọn ni Tosin ati Jubril n lọ, Babatunde n lọ sileewe aladaani Tunik International School, to wa lagbegbe Dalekọ, nipinlẹ Ogun, kan naa, ṣugbọn ọmọ ẹkọṣẹ ni Dare Sunday, iṣẹ telọ ni wọn loun n kọ lọwọ ni Dalekọ.Olobo kan lo ta awọn agbofinro nipa igbesẹ ti wọn lawọn afurasi ọdaran yii fẹẹ gbe to jẹ ki wọn ri wọn mu, wọn lawọn ọmọ wọnyi n mura ija, wọn fẹẹ lọọ gbẹsan lara awọn ọmọ ẹlẹgbẹ okunkun mi-in ti wọn wa nileewe Junior Secondary School, laduugbo Akinyẹle, l’Alakukọ, nipinlẹ Eko.Bawọn ọlọpaa ṣe gbọ nipa ọrọ yii ni wọn tete lọ sileewe JSS, Alakukọ ti wọn darukọ ọhun, awọn ọlọpaa ti o wọṣọ ni o, wọn lugọ de awọn afurasi yii, ọwọ si ba wọn ki wọn too dana ijangbọn sileewe naa.Boya tori iṣẹ dudu ti wọn fẹẹ ṣe ni o, boya yunifọọmu ẹgbẹ wọn si ni, ẹwu polo dudu kirimu lawọn mẹta ninu wọn wọ lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee tọwọ tẹ wọn.Iyalẹnu lo jẹ pe bi wọn ṣe mu wọn, ti wọn yẹ ara awọn ọmọ ti awọn obi n run owo le lori lati kawe wọnyi wo, wọn ba ada mọnbe oriṣiiriṣii, egboogi oloro ti wọn fura pe igbo ni, awọn oogun abẹnu gọngọ ti wọn faṣọ pupa we, ọbẹ aṣooro atawọn nnkan ija mi-in ni wọn n ko kiri.Nigba tawọn ọlọpaa n beere ọrọ lọwọ wọn, awọn majeṣin ẹlẹgbẹkẹgbẹ yii jẹwọ pe ko ti i pẹ tawọn dọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun, wọn ni ọkan lara awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ awọn to wa nileewe JSS ni awọn kan fiya jẹ, tori kawọn le ba a kọya lawọn ṣe wa.Wọn lawọn o ni i lọkan lati da wahala silẹ o, tori awọn ti kọkọ wa sileewe naa tẹlẹ, awọn si ti sami si awọn tawọn fẹẹ kọ lu, awọn tawọn ba lẹjọ lawọn fẹẹ fiya jẹ.Ṣa, ọlọpaa ti ko awọn mẹrẹẹrin, wọn si ti taari wọn sọdọ awọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ ni Panti, Yaba, ẹka kan wa nibẹ to n bojuto ọrọ awọn majeṣin to ya ipanle, ibẹ ni wọn ko wọn lọ, iṣẹ iwadii si ti n lọ lori wọn bayii."},{"question":"Berikan jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Binatang yang ganas tetapi malas kerana suka tidur jek.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah singa. "},{"question":"Steve Ayorinde","answer":"Steve Olúṣẹ̀yí Ayọ̀rìndé /θj/ (tí wọ́n bí lọ́dún 1970) jẹ́ kọmíṣọ́nnà-àná fún ètò ìrìn-afẹ́, iṣẹ́-ọ̀nà àti àṣà tí Ìpínlẹ̀-Èkó lórílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Ṣáájú àkókò yìí, ó jẹ́ kọmíṣọ́nnà nípa ìròyìn àti ọgbọ́n-ọnnú nígbà ìṣèjọba gómìnà-àná tí Ìpínlẹ̀ náà, Akinwunmi Ambode lọ́dún 2015, Bákan náà, ó ti fìgbà kan jẹ́ Ọ̀gá-àgbà tí ilé-isé ìwé-ìròyìn National Mirror, àti olóòtú ìwé-ìròyìn The Punch ní Nàìjíríà.Bákan náà, Ayorinde jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára gbajúmọ̀ lámèyító nípa sinimá àti iṣẹ́-ọ̀nà, ti ó sì tún ti jẹ́ adájọ́-aláṣàyàn fún àmì-ẹ̀yẹ àgbáyé bíi Toronto International Film Festival, Cannes Film Festival, Berlin International Film Festival, AMAA àti Mumbai International Film Festival."},{"question":" Hình thang cân có:A. 1 cạnh bênB. 2 cạnh bênC. 3 cạnh bênD. 4 cạnh bên","answer":"Trả lời:Hình thang cân có 2 cạnh bên.Đáp án cần chọn là: B"},{"question":"Китептерди 📚 көп окуган 📖 зыяндуубу?","answer":"Тарыхты, илимди изилдегенде, китептерге билим үчүн кайрылабыз. Китеп окуудан эс тутум, мээнин иштеши, көздүн көрүүсү жакшырат, эмпатияга үйрөнөбүз, мүмкүнчүлүгүбүз жетпеген тажрыйбаларды \\"алабыз\\". Бирок мунун баары чеги менен. Мага төрт жыл мурун бирөө \\"Китептерден тажап калбайын десең, аз оку\\" деген болчу. Ал сөздү кийин түшүндүм."},{"question":"Jox ma péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Yàlla xàm na séen i jëf.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Yàlla xàm na séen i jëf.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Yàlla: PROPNxàm: VERBna: AUXséen: PRONi: DETjëf: NOUN.: PUNCT"},{"question":"How does Colombo celebrate its maritime heritage through the Port City project?","answer":"The Port City project is a testament to Colombo's ambition and commitment to embracing its maritime heritage. This reclaimed land is transforming into a modern urban center, featuring state-of-the-art infrastructure, residential complexes, and recreational spaces. It not only enhances Colombo's skyline but also symbolizes the city's journey towards becoming a global hub."},{"question":"Awọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ n wa ọga agba Fasiti Ọyẹ Ekiti, wọn lo n gbowo-oṣu lọna meji","answer":"Bii ere ori itage lọrọ ri ni ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee,  ọsẹ yii, laarin ọga agba yunifasiti tijọba apapọ niluu Oye-Ekiti, Purofẹsọ Abayọmi Fashina, atawọn ọlọpaa ọtẹlẹmuyẹ ti wọn waa mu un lati Alagbọn, niulu Eko.Awọn akẹkọọ fasiti ti ọrọ naa ṣoju wọn  sọ f’ALAROYE  pe awọn ọlọpa bii meje ti wọn dihamọra ni wọn de si ọgba ile-iwe naa latilu Eko, ni deede agogo mẹrin ọsan ọjọ yii, lati waa fi pampẹ ọba mu ọga agba ọhun lori lẹta ifẹhonu han kan ti awọn olukọ fasiti naa atawọn oṣiṣẹ ibẹ kọ sawọn ọlọpaa. Ẹsun ikowojẹ ni wọn fi kan ọga wọn yii.Wọn ni lẹyin oṣu kẹrin to ti gba ipo ọga agba yunifasiti naa, o tun n gba owo ni yunifasiti ti ipinlẹ, niibi to ti n ṣiṣẹ tẹlẹ ko too gba ipo ọga agba fasiti tijọba apapọ niluu Oye.Wọn ni bawọn ọlọpaa yii ṣe de geeti ọgba ile-iwe naa, ti wọn ni awọn wa lati ilu Eko lati waa ṣe iwadii ẹsun ikowojẹ atawọn ẹsun mi-in ti wọn fi kan ọga agba yii, lọgan lawọn ẹṣọ wọnyi sọ pe awọn ko ni i gba ki wọn wọnu ọfiisi ọga agba yii, ayafi ti wọn ba lọọ sọ fun un pe awọn ọlọpaa n beere ẹ. Ṣugbọn lẹyin alaye ati awuyewuye yii, awọn ọlọpaa naa fagidi wọle, bo tilẹ jẹ pe wọn ko mọ pato ibi tọfiisi rẹ wa.Ti ẹ ko ba gbagbe, ọrọ bi ọga yii ṣe n gbowo oṣu lọna meji yii ti kọkọ di awuyewuye nigba ti wọn n ṣe ifọrọwanilẹnuwo lati yan an sipo to wa ọhun.Ọkunrin yii ni wọn lo wa ninu ọfiisi rẹ lasiko tawọn agbofinro yii kọkọ de si ayika ọgba naa, wọn ni awọn oṣiṣẹ rẹ kan ni wọn dọgbọn fẹyin pọn ọn jade, inu igbo ṣuuru kan to wa layiika ọgba ọhun ni wọn lo lọọ ba mọ, ki wọn to waa fi mọto kan ti ko ni nọmba idanimọ gbe e jade nigba to ya.Lẹyin tawọn ọlọpaa naa ti wa a fun ọpọ wakati ni wọn fibinu ko marun-un lara awọn ẹṣọ fasiti yii si mọto ti wọn gbe wa, wọn si wa wọn lọ, wọn lawọn ko ni i fi wọn silẹ afi ti wọn ba wa ọga fasiti ọhun jade.Nigba to n fesi lori iṣẹlẹ yii, Olubadamọran lori eto iroyin si ọga agba naa, Ọgbẹni Folusho Ogunmọdẹde, sọ pe igbesẹ ati ihuwasi awọn ọlọpaa yii ko yatọ si tawọn ajinigbe, o ni niṣe ni wọn fẹẹ ji ọga agba naa lọ.Ẹ oo ranti pe ni kete ti ọga agba yii gba ipo ọhun lo yọ ọga agba lẹka eto igbaniwọle sileewe naa nipo, bẹẹ lo tun yọ olusiro owo agba, Arabinrin Bọlatito Akande nipo, to si fi ẹsun ikowojẹ kan awọn mejeeji."},{"question":"වගා කිරීම අස්වැන්න නෙළා ගැනීම තරම් පහසු නොවේ","answer":"ගතාරේ"},{"question":"１８４０年にイギリスで発行された、世界で一番古い切手を、その色から何と呼ぶでしょう？","answer":"ブラックペニーです。"},{"question":"¿Quién fue Manuel Manquilef?","answer":"Manuel Segundo Manquilef González fue un intelectual y político mapuche de orientación liberal que desarrolló su producción escrita en el contexto histórico de las reducciones de las tierras de las comunidades mapuche por parte del Estado chileno.Manuel Manquilef nació el 31 de mayo de 1881, hijo del cacique Fermín Trekamañ Manquilef y de la cautiva chilena Trinidad González de Villagra. Vivió sus primeros años bajo el cuidado de su abuela paterna, en Pelal, territorio cercano a la comunidad de Quepe."},{"question":"Ẹni to ba fẹẹ fiku ṣere nikan lo maa sọ pe ko sohun to n jẹ Korona – Sanwo-Olu","answer":"Ikilọ ti lọ sọdọ awọn olugbe ipinlẹ Eko latọdọ Gomina Babajide Sanwo-Olu nipa arun Koronafairọọsi pe ki wọn ma fi arun naa ṣere rara, pẹlu bawọn kan ṣe n sọ pe arumọjẹ ni. Sanwo-Olu ni afi ẹni to ba fẹẹ fiku ṣere nikan lo maa sọ pe ko sohun to n jẹ Korona, o ni arun naa wa gidi, ki i ṣe arumọjẹ rara.Ọjọ Aiku, Sannde yii, ni Babajide ke tantan bẹẹ nigba to n sọrọ nipa ibi ti nnkan de duro lori iṣapa ijọba rẹ lati dena itankalẹ arun aṣekupani naa, o ni iyalẹnu lo jẹ foun lati maa gbọ pe awọn kan n sọ pe ko sohun to n jẹ Koro, arun arumọjẹ lasan ni, Sanwo-Olu ni ko sohun to yara paayan bii aimọkan ati afojudi.O bẹ awọn olugbe Eko lati ma ṣe gba ahesọ yii gbọ, tori arun to n ṣọṣẹ gidi ni Korona, ohun to si yẹ ni lati sa fun un, lati pa awọn eewọ ẹ ati alakalẹ ijọba lori ẹ mọ. Gomina ni o san keeyan ma lugbadi arun ọhun ju keeyan fara kaaṣa tan ko too gbagbọ pe o wa lọ.Amọ ṣa o, gomina ni yatọ si bi awọn to n lugbadi Koro ẹlẹẹkeji ṣe n pọ si i, awọn ni iroyin ayọ fawọn ti wọn n gba itọju nileewọsan ti wọn ti n bojuto arun yii, o lawọn ti ṣe idasilẹ ileeṣẹ afẹfẹ ti wọn n fẹ simu, (oxygen) to maa pese ọọdunrun (300) afẹfẹ ọsijin loojọ, fawọn ti ti wọn nilo itọju pajawiri, lati doola ẹmi wọn. O lawọn ṣi maa kọ iru ileeṣẹ bẹẹ si i laipẹ.Ṣaaju ni Igbakeji gomina Eko naa, Ọbafẹmi Hamzat, ti ṣekilọ pe arun Korona to tun n gberi bayii ko mọ ọjọ-ori tabi ipo rara, tọmọde tagba lo wa ninu ewu ẹ. Ninu ọrọ rẹ ọhun lo ti fẹnu ara rẹ kede pe arun Korona lo pa aburo oun, Dokita Haroun Hamzat, to doloogbe lọsẹ to kọja yii.O ni ko ti i sọna abayọ lori arun yii ju keeyan maa kiyesara, ko si pa awọn ofin to rọ mọ ọn mọ, tori oju lalakan fi n sọri lọrọ ọhun gba bayii."},{"question":"キリスト教の原理のひとつで、人間が生まれながらにして持っている罪のことを何というでしょう？","answer":"原罪"},{"question":"Devlet Hastanesi MR randevusu nasıl alınır?","answer":"Hastanelerden randevu almak için iki yöntem bulunuyor. '' Alo 182'' çağrı merkezini arayarak bağlanacağınız canlı operatöre TC kimlik numaranızı vererek randevunuzu oluşturabilirsiniz. Diğer yöntem ise www.mhrs.com.tr'den randevunuzu oluşturmak."},{"question":"翻译下面的古文：僧珍在任，平心率下，不私亲戚。从父兄子先以贩葱为业，僧珍既至，乃弃业欲求州官。僧珍曰：“吾荷国重恩，无以报效，汝等自有常分，岂可妄求叨越，但当速反葱肆耳。”僧珍旧宅在市北，前有督邮廨，乡人咸劝徒廨以益其宅。僧珍怒曰：“督邮官廨也，置立以来，便在此地，岂可徙之益吾私宅！”姊适于氏，住在市西，小屋临路，与列肆杂处，僧珍常导从卤簿到其宅，不以为耻。","answer":"吕僧珍在位期间，公平对待属下，不徇私情。堂兄的儿子吕宏起先以贩葱为业，在吕僧珍就任以后，就放弃贩葱业想求他在州里安排个官当当，吕僧珍说：“我蒙受国家大恩，没有什么可以报效的。你们本来有适合自己身份地位的职业，怎么可以胡乱要求得到不该得的职份！还是应当赶快回到葱店去吧。”吕僧珍老家在市北，前面建有督邮的官署，乡人都劝他迁移官署来扩建住宅。吕僧珍恼怒地说：“督邮这官署，从建造以来就一直在这里，怎么可以迁走它来扩建我的私宅呢?”他姐姐嫁给于氏，住在市西，小屋面临马路，又混杂在各种店铺中间，吕僧珍经常引带着仪仗队到她家，并不觉得辱没了身份。"},{"question":"Lee el pasaje siguiente y luego responda a la pregunta posteriormente en el mismo idioma que el pasaje:  La mañana siguiente, el 26 de octubre, Kennedy informó al EXCOMM que creía que solo una invasión eliminaría los misiles de Cuba. Fue persuadido de dar tiempo al asunto y continuar con la presión militar y diplomática. Estuvo de acuerdo y ordenó que los vuelos a baja altitud sobre la isla aumentaran de dos por día a uno cada dos horas. También ordenó un programa de emergencia para instituir un nuevo gobierno civil en Cuba si una invasión se llevaba a cabo.  Pregunta: ¿En qué país estaban las ojivas?","answer":"En Cuba. "},{"question":"ගෞතම බුදුසසුනේ \\" පරිපූර්ණ වීර්‍යය ඇති භික්ෂූන් අතරින් අග්‍ර \\" තනතුර දැරූ මහ රහතන් වහන්සේ කවුද ?","answer":"සෝණ මහරහතන් වහන්සේ "},{"question":"A palavra jardim tem quantas sílabas?","answer":"A palavra jardim tem 2 sílabas: jar-dim."},{"question":"\\"Күн күркүрөшүнө эмне себеп болот?\\"","answer":" \\"Абанын кеңейишин катуу үндүү толкун пайда болот, ал катуу күркүрөөгө окшош болот жана күн күркүрөгөндөй үн чыгарат, көбүнчө аны чапкырык, жарылуу же күн күркүрөө деп аташат\\". "},{"question":"كمل الفقرة:وبالتزامن مع تلك الانتصارات البحرية المملوكية كانت الدولة العثمانية تتوسع في الأناضول والبلقان ببطء، وقد أوْلى سلاطينُها اهتمامَهم للأساطيل البحرية، لاسيما بعد فتح","answer":"مدينة برصة/بروسة واتخاذها عاصمة لهم 717هـ/1317م؛ فتجددت بقوتهم البحرية عهود فتوح الإسلام في أول دولتهم المترامية، وجهود الدفاع البحري عن سواحل المسلمين في أواخرها."},{"question":"\\"Кесип алса, кан чыкпаган\\" дегенди кандай түшүнөсүң? ","answer":"Зыкым, сараң, колунан эч нерсе чыкпаган, бышык адам. Арабызда кесип алса да кан чыкпаган байлар бар."},{"question":"\\"Matetika ny vakodrazana malagasy no ahitana fomban-drazana am-bava sy fitantarana nolovaina tamin'ny taranaka nifandimby. Ny angano sy angano ary angano dia anisan'ny literatiora malagasy, maneho ny finoana sy ny soatoavina ara-kolontsainan'ny vahoaka.\\"Inona avy ireo karazana fomba amam-panao am-bava sy tantara hita matetika ao amin'ny vako-drazana malagasy, maneho ny finoan'ny vahoaka?","answer":"Mazàna ny angano  izay maneho ny finoana sy ny soatoavina ara-kolontsainan'ny vahoaka no matetika ao amin'ny vakoka malagasy."},{"question":"焼いた餅にきな粉をまぶしたものを、それが名物だった静岡県の川から何というでしょう？","answer":"安倍川餅（あべかわもち） ※安倍川（あべかわ）のみでＯＫ。です。"},{"question":"السؤال: ما السورة التي لم تبدأ بالبسملة؟","answer":"الإجابة : التوبة."},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy: Kilka dni później P-34 dotarł do Takao na Formozie, skąd więźniowie zostali przetransportowani do obozu jenieckiego Ōfuna, a następnie do więzienia w Ōmori pod Tokio. W drodze do Japonii rozbitkowie zostali jednak rozdzieleni – 3 oficerów spędziło ją na pokładzie niszczyciela, pozostali zaś popłynęli na pokładzie krążownika. Wszyscy jednak byli już o wiele lepiej traktowani, gdyż jak wyjaśnił zapytany o to przez O’Kane dowódca japońskiego niszczyciela – eskortowiec P-34 nie należał do cesarskiej marynarki wojennej. Już jednak w Ōfunie ich sytuacja ponownie zmieniła się – więźniowie zostali poinformowani, że Ōfuna nie jest obozem jenieckim, funkcjonuje jako nieznany aliantom i organizacjom humanitarnym tajny obóz śledczy, oni sami zaś nie są tu jeńcami wojennymi i nie przysługują im prawa jeńców wojennych. Więźniowie byli głodzeni, wielokrotnie bici i poddani nieludzkiemu traktowaniu, w końcu zostali przeniesieni do więzienia w Ōmori, gdzie doczekali wyzwolenia po kapitulacji Japonii","answer":"i w stanie skrajnego wycieńczenia fizycznego przetransportowani do Stanów Zjednoczonych."},{"question":"¿Ha muerto algún presidente estando en el cargo? Considera la nación de Estados Unidos. ","answer":"Sí, algunos presidentes de los Estados Unidos han muerto mientras estaban en el cargo. A lo largo de la historia de Estados Unidos, ha habido cuatro presidentes que murieron mientras ejercían su mandato:1. William Henry Harrison: Fue el noveno presidente de Estados Unidos y asumió el cargo el 4 de marzo de 1841. Sin embargo, murió el 4 de abril de 1841 (Neumonía), solo 31 días después de asumir la presidencia, lo que lo convierte en el presidente con el mandato más corto de la historia.2. Zachary Taylor: Fue el duodécimo presidente de Estados Unidos y asumió el cargo el 4 de marzo de 1849. Falleció el 9 de julio de 1850, aproximadamente un año y cuatro meses después de asumir la presidencia, por uns gastroenteritis aguda.3. Abraham Lincoln: Fue el decimosexto presidente de Estados Unidos y asumió el cargo el 4 de marzo de 1861. Lincoln fue asesinado el 14 de abril de 1865, recibió un disparo en la parte trasera de la cabeza, aproximadamente cuatro años después de haber asumido la presidencia, convirtiéndose en el primer presidente en ser asesinado.4. James A. Garfield: Fue el vigésimo presidente de Estados Unidos y asumió el cargo el 4 de marzo de 1881. Fue herido gravemente por un pistolero el 2 de julio de 1881 y finalmente murió debido a sus heridas el 19 de septiembre de 1881.5. William McKinley: Fue el vigésimo quinto presidente de Estados Unidos y asumió el cargo el 4 de marzo de 1897. Fue víctima de un atentado el 6 de septiembre de 1901 y murió a causa de sus heridas el 14 de septiembre de 1901.6. Warren G. Harding: Fue el vigésimo noveno presidente de Estados Unidos y asumió el cargo el 4 de marzo de 1921. Harding murió el 2 de agosto de 1923, por un infarto al corazón.7. Franklin D. Roosevelt: Fue el trigésimo segundo presidente de Estados Unidos y asumió el cargo el 4 de marzo de 1933. Roosevelt murió el 12 de abril de 1945, aproximadamente tres meses después de comenzar su cuarto mandato, lo que lo convirtió en el presidente que más tiempo ha servido en la historia de Estados Unidos, falleció a causa de una hemorragia cerebral. 8. John F. Kennedy: Fue el trigésimo quinto presidente de Estados Unidos y asumió el cargo el 20 de enero de 1961. Trágicamente, fue asesinado el 22 de noviembre de 1963, mientras realizaba una visita a Dallas, Texas.Estos presidentes murieron trágicamente mientras ocupaban la presidencia, y sus fallecimientos tuvieron un impacto significativo en la historia de Estados Unidos."},{"question":"Sos lada hitam ialah gandingan hebat untuk ayam panggang, chop ayam dan ayam panggang. Apakah resipi untuk sos lada hitam? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah terperinci. ","answer":"Terdapat pelbagai resipi untuk menyediakan sos lada hitam yang enak.Cubalah resipi contoh berikut:Bahan: 1½ sudu besar lada hitam, 3 sudu besar mentega, 4 sudu besar gandum, 1 cawan air, 1 cawan susu, 1 kiub stok ayam, Garam secukup rasaCara penyediaan:1. Kisar lada hitam (kasar atau halus terpulang kepada citarasa).Cara memasak:1. Panaskan mentega di dalam kuali dengan api perlahan sehingga cair dan jernih.2. Taburkan gandum ke atas mentega. Kacau menggunakan whisk selama kira-kira lima minit sehingga ia berwarna keperangan. Langkah ini penting untuk hilangkan rasa gandum mentah.3. Masukkan susu sedikit demi sedikit serta kacau.4. Kemudian masukkan air, lada hitam, kiub stok ayam dan garam. Kacau sehingga campuran licin sebati dan tiada ketulan.5. Reneh sehingga mencapai kepekatan yang diingini.6. Tutup api dan angkat"},{"question":"வண்ணத்துப்பூச்சிக்கு சுவையை உணரும் உறுப்பு அதன் உடலில் எங்கு அமைந்துள்ளது? 1. காதுகளில்.2 .கண்களில்.3. கால்களில்.4. வாயில்","answer":"3. கால்களில்."},{"question":"Ẹyà àrà wò ni o wà fún irìràn?","answer":"Ojú"},{"question":"Halima Abubakar","answer":"Halima Abubakar ni wọ́n bí ní ọjọ́ Kejìlá oṣù Kẹfà ọdún 1985. jẹ́ òṣèré ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Ní ọdún 2011, ó gba àmì-ẹ̀yẹ ti Afro Hollywood Best Actress award.Wọ́n bí Abubakar ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Kánò , àmọ́ ọmọ bíbí Ìpínlẹ̀ Kogí ni. ó sì tún lọ sí ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ alákọ̀ọ́bérẹ̀ ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Kano. Ó tún kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ gboyè ìmọ̀ àkọ́kọ́ ní ú ìmọ̀ Sociology ní ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ Bayero University ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Kano. Abubakar fidí rẹ̀ múlẹ̀ wípé òun ṣì ní ìbálé ní oṣù kẹwàá ọdún 2018.Ní inú oṣù Kẹ́rin ọdún 2020, ó kéde pé òun bímọ ọkùnrin.Ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ eré tíátà ní ọdún 2001, níbi tí ó ti kópa nínú eré Rejected. Ó kópa bí olú-èdá ìtàn nínú eré Gangster Paradise. 9un ló dá iṣẹ́ Modehouse Entertainment, tí ó jẹ́ ilé-iṣẹ́ ìgbórin jáde.ÀWỌN FÍÍMÙ RẸ̀Slip of FateTears of a ChildSecret ShadowsGangster ParadiseArea MamaMen in LoveRejectedLove CastleEntrappedDangerous IvyReturn of White Hunters"},{"question":"Beqil ma mbind mii:[Séytaane] tarxiisloo na leen, génne leen fa ñu nekkoon. Nu ne leen: \\"Wàccleen; di noonuwante. Te itam dangeen am ci kaw suuf ay dëkkuwaay ak i jumtukaay as ndiir\\".","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:[Séytaane] tarxiisloo na leen, génne léen fa ñu nekkoon. Nu ne léen: \\"Wàccléen; di noonoonte. Te ìtam da ngéen àm ci kaw sùuf ay dëkkuwaay ak i jumtukaay as ndiir\\"."},{"question":"கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து மசால் வடை செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:1 கப் கடலை பருப்பு3 பெரிய வெங்காயம்3 பச்சை மிளகாய்2 காய்ந்த மிளகாய்4 பூண்டு பல்1 இஞ்சி துண்டு1 பட்டை துண்டு1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி சோம்புதேவையான அளவு உப்புதேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய்சிறிதளவு கருவேப்பிலைசிறிதளவு கொத்தமல்லிசிறிதளவு புதினா","answer":"செய்முறை:1. முதலில் கடலை பருப்பை நன்கு கழுவி சுத்தம் செய்து அதை சுமார் 3 மணி நேரம் வரை ஊற வைக்கவும். பின்பு வெங்காயம், பச்சை மிளகாய், இஞ்சி, கொத்தமல்லி, புதினா, மற்றும் கருவேப்பிலையை நறுக்கி, மற்றும் பூண்டை தட்டி எடுத்து வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.2. அடுத்து ஒரு மிக்ஸி ஜாரை எடுத்து அதில் சோம்பு, பட்டை, காய்ந்த மிளகாய், மற்றும் இஞ்சியை போட்டு அதை ஒரு சுற்று சுற்றி கொள்ளவும்.3. பின்பு அதில் நாம் ஊற வைத்திருக்கும் கடலை பருப்பில் இருந்து 2 மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு கடலை பருப்பை எடுத்து தனியாக ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் வைத்து மீதமுள்ள கடலை பருப்புகளை போட்டு அதை அரைத்து கொள்ளவும்.4. இந்த பருப்பை கொரகொரப்பான பதத்திற்கு அரைத்தால் போதும் அதை நன்கு நைசாக அரைத்து விடக்கூடாது.5. இப்பொழுது ஒரு கிண்ணத்தை எடுத்து அதில் இந்த அரைத்த கலவையை போட்டு அதனுடன் நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் வெங்காயம், பச்சை மிளகாய், தட்டி வைத்திருக்கும் பூண்டு, எடுத்து வைத்திருக்கும் கடலை பருப்பு, கொத்தமல்லி, கருவேப்பிலை, புதினா, மற்றும் தேவையான அளவு உப்பை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கிளறி விடவும்.6. இந்த கலவையை நன்கு கிளறி விட்ட பின் அதிலிருந்து சிறிதளவு மாவை எடுத்து அதை உருண்டையாக உருட்டி பின்பு அதை கையில் வைத்து பக்குவமாக தட்டி அதை தட்டையான வடிவிற்க்கு மாற்றி ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.7. இவ்வாறு மீதமுள்ள மாவுகளையும் உருட்டி பின்பு தட்டி தயார் செய்து தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.8. பின்னர் ஒரு கடாயை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் இந்த வடைகளை போட்டு பொரித்து எடுப்பதற்கு தேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி அதை சுட வைக்கவும்.9. எண்ணெய் சட்ட பின் அதில் நாம் தட்டி வைத்திருக்கும் வடைகளை வடசட்டியின் அளவிற்கேற்ப பக்குவமாக எடுத்து எண்ணெய்யில் போடவும்.10. பின்பு அது ஒரு புறம் பொன்னிறமானதும் அதை மறு புறம் திருப்பி விட்டு அது பொன்னிறம் ஆகும் வரை அதை வேக விடவும்.11. வடை இரு புறமும் பொன்னிறமானதும் அதை ஒரு ஜல்லி கரண்டியின் மூலம் எடுத்து எண்ணெய்யை நன்கு வடித்து அதை ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து சுட சுட பரிமாறவும்.12. இவ்வாறு மீதமுள்ள வடைகளையும் எண்ணெய்யில் போட்டு பொரித்து எடுத்து கொள்ளவும்.13. இப்பொழுது உங்கள் சூடான மற்றும் நன்கு மொறு மொறுப்பாக இருக்கும் மசால் வடை தயார். இதை கட்டாயம் உங்கள் வீட்டில் செய்து பார்த்து உங்கள் குடும்பத்தாருடன் சேர்ந்து உண்டு மகிழுங்கள்.கடலைப் பருப்பு என்பது கொண்டைக் கடலையிலிருந்து உருவாக்கப்படும் உணவுப்பொருளாகும்.இது மஞ்சள் நிறத்துடன் இருக்கும்.இதை ஊற வைத்து அரைத்து வடை சுடுவார்கள். சட்னி,துவையல் செய்யப் பயன்படும்.மேலும் பல வகையான கூட்டுகளிலும் பயன்படுத்தப்படும். இதை வறுத்த பின் வறுகடலை அல்லது பொட்டுக் கடலை எனவும் வழங்குவர். வறுகடலையைச் சட்னியிலும் குருமாவிலும் பயன்படுத்துவர்.இது சத்தான உணவுப்பொருள்."},{"question":"ما العنصر الغذائي الذي لا بوجد في حليب؟","answer":"الحديد."},{"question":"\\"ഞാൻ വളരെക്കാലമായി കാണാത്ത വളരെ അടുത്ത സുഹൃത്തിനെ കണ്ടുമുട്ടി:\\"മുമ്പത്തെ കഥയ്ക്ക് സാധ്യമായ സമാപ്തി എന്താണ്:എ. എന്റെ സുഹൃത്ത് എന്നെ തിരിച്ചറിഞ്ഞില്ല.ബി. ഞങ്ങൾ അര മണിക്കൂർ സംസാരിച്ചു ചിരിച്ചു","answer":"ഓപ്ഷൻ ബി ആണ് ഏറ്റവും സാധ്യതയുള്ള സമാപ്തി."},{"question":"Ijamba ina ba dukia olowo nla jẹ niluu Bode Saadu","answer":"O kere tan, ṣọọbu mẹsan-an pẹlu awọn ọja olowo nla to wa ninu ẹ lo jona raurau lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii, ninu ọja Bode Saadu, lọna Jẹbba, nijọba ibilẹ Moro, nipinlẹ Kwara.Ina ọhun la gbọ pe o ṣẹ yọ ni nnkan bii aago meji ku iṣẹju mẹẹẹdogun Lord.Alukoro ileeṣẹ panapana nipinlẹ Kwara, Ọgbẹni Hassan Hakeem Adekunle, ṣalaye pe Musbaudeen lo ta ileeṣẹ awọn lolobo nipa iṣẹlẹ naa lori foonu.O ni laarin aadọta ṣọọbu to wa ninu ọja naa, mẹsan-an ni ina naa jo. O ṣalaye pe akitiyan awọn oṣiṣẹ awọn lati tete pa ina naa ni ko jẹ ki kinni ọhun burẹkẹ ju bẹẹ lọ.O rọ araalu lati maa kiyesara, ki wọn si ṣọra fun ohun to le fa ijamba ina lasiko ọgbẹlẹ yii."},{"question":"අපගේ සෞරග්‍රහ මණ්ඩලයේ දීර්ඝතම දිනය වාර්තාවන්නේ කුමන ග්‍රහයාගේ ද?","answer":"අපගේ සෞරග්‍රහ මණ්ඩලයේ දීර්ඝතම දිනය සිකුරු ග්‍රහයාගේ (පෘතුවි දින 243ක දිග) දිනයෙන් වාර්තා වේ."},{"question":"Kinsa ang labing hinigugma nga atletang Filipino nga usa ka boksidor?","answer":"Si Manny Pacquiao ang labing hinigugma nga atletang Filipino nga usa ka boksidor."},{"question":"戦いにいどむときに勇み立って体が震えるのは何ぶるい？","answer":"武者ぶるいです。"},{"question":"नेपालमा जंगल सफारी।","answer":"विशेषगरी नेपालको तराई क्षेत्रमा अवस्थित राष्ट्रिय निकुञ्जले विश्वभरका पर्यटकलाई आकर्षित गर्छ । यी पार्कहरूको भ्रमणमा विभिन्न माध्यमहरू-खुट्टा, डगआउट क्यानो, जीप र हात्तीको पछाडि खेल्ने खेलहरू समावेश छन्। प्रत्येक हात्ती सफारीमा एक वा दुई सिङ्गे गैँडा देख्न बाध्य छन्। गैंडाका अलावा जङ्गली बँदेल, साम्बुर, स्पटेड डियर, स्लोथ भालु, चार सिङ्गे मृग पनि प्रायः देखिन्छन्। रोयल बेङ्गाल टाइगरले तपाईंलाई आफ्नो भव्य रूपले चकित पार्न सक्छ।"},{"question":" waa maxay saarka ? ","answer":" Saarku waa hees luqadeedu sikale tahay isla kolkaasna leh jiib dabataal okoox kale Kuluqeynayso. Qorayaas"},{"question":"Зат атоочтун табиятына карай бөлүнүшү","answer":"1) Конкреттүү заттарМисалы: суу, шекер,мөндүр, кар2) Абстрактуу заттарМисалы: бакыт, ой,акыл, санаа, уйку"},{"question":"ਆਮ ਲੋਕ ਤਕਰੀਬਨ ਏਨਾ ਕੁ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਸਾਹਨੀ ਹਿੰਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਜਗਤ ਦਾ ਬਹੁਤ ਵਧੀਆ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਨੇ 135 ਦੇ ਲਗਪਗ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਨਿਵੇਕਲੀ ਛਾਪ ਛੱਡਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਏ। ਉਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਬਹੁਤੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਮਕਬੂਲ ਹੋਈਆਂ ਪਰ ਇਹ ਸਫ਼ਰ ਏਨਾ ਟੇਢਾ ਮੇਢਾ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ਵਾਲਾ ਸੀ ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਕਿਆਸ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ। ਪੰਜਾਬੀਅਤ ਨੂੰ ਅੰਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ ਇੱਕ ਮਈ 1913 ਨੂੰ ਰਾਵਲਪਿੰਡੀ ਵਿਖੇ ਹੋਇਆ। ਪੁਰਖਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਪਿੰਡ ਭੇਰਾ ਸੀ। ਬਲਰਾਜ, ਰਾਵਲਪਿੰਡੀ ਦੇ ਬੜੇ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਕਾਰੋਬਾਰੀ ਹਰਬੰਸ ਲਾਲ ਸਾਹਨੀ ਅਤੇ ਸ੍ਰੀਮਤੀ ਲਕਸ਼ਮੀ ਦੇਵੀ ਦਾ ਪੰਜਾਂ ਧੀਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਜੰਮਿਆ ਪੁੱਤਰ ਸੀ। ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਨਾਂ ਯੁਧਿਸ਼ਟਰ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਨਾਂ ਲੈਣਾ ਔਖਾ ਹੋਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਬਦਲ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ। ਘਰ ਦਾ ਮਾਹੌਲ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਵੇਖਣਾ ਵੀ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਮਨ੍ਹਾ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਨੂੰ 'ਗੁਰੂਕਲ ਪੋਠੋਹਾਰ' ਵਿੱਚ ਪੜ੍ਹਨੇ ਪਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ। ਫਿਰ ਚੌਥੀ ਜਮਾਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਡੀ.ਏ.ਵੀ. ਸਕੂਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਾਖਲ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸਾਲ1930 ਵਿੱਚ ਡੀ.ਏ.ਵੀ. ਕਾਲਜ ਰਾਵਲਪਿੰਡੀ ਤੋਂ ਇੰਟਰਮੀਡੀਏਟ ਪਾਸ ਕੀਤੀ। ਇਸ ਕਾਲਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੋਫੈਸਰ ਜਸਵੰਤ ਰਾਏ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਪਰਕ ਹੋਇਆ ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਛੋਟੀ ਭੈਣ ਦਮਯੰਤੀ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਦਾ 1936 ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿਆਹ ਹੋਇਆ।ਸਾਲ 1930 ਵਿੱਚ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਗੌਰਮਿੰਟ ਕਾਲਜ ਲਹੌਰ ਦਾਖਲ ਹੋਇਆ ਜਿੱਥੋਂ ਉਸ ਨੇ 1934 ਵਿੱਚ ਕਾਲਜ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਨੇ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਹਾਣੀਆਂ ਲਿਖੀਆਂ।  ਗੌਰਮਿੰਟ ਕਾਲਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੜ੍ਹਦਿਆਂ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਯਥਾਰਥਵਾਦੀ ਰੰਗਮੰਚ ਬਾਰੇ ਪਤਾ ਲੱਗਾ, ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਾਤਰ ਸੁਭਾਵਕ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਦੇ ਲਹਿਜ਼ੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੋਲਦੇ ਸਨ। ਪਾਰਸੀ ਰੰਗਮੰਚ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਚੱਲਤ ਨਾਟਕੀ ਅੰਦਾਜ਼ ਦੀ ਨਕਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਨ ਕਰਦੇ। ਸੰਨ 1934 ਵਿੱਚ ਲਾਹੌਰ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਦੀ ਐਮ.ਏ. ਕਰਨ ਉਪਰੰਤ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਵਾਪਸ ਰਾਵਲਪਿੰਡੀ ਆ ਗਿਆ ਤੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਨਾਲ ਵਪਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੱਗ ਪਿਆ। ਇਨ੍ਹੀਂ ਦਿਨੀਂ ਹੀ ਦਵਿੰਦਰ ਸਤਿਆਰਥੀ ਇੱਕ ਮਹੀਨਾ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਕੋਲ ਘਰ ਰਿਹਾ। ਛੇਤੀ ਹੀ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਵਪਾਰ ਤੋਂ ਉਕਤਾ ਗਿਆ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੋਈ ਨਵੀਂ ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਅੰਗੜਾਈਆਂ ਲੈ ਰਹੀ ਸੀ।  ਫਿਰ ਓਧਰੋਂ ਦਮਯੰਤੀ ਦੀ ਕੁੱਖੋਂ ਵੱਡਾ ਬੇਟਾ ਪ੍ਰੀਕਸ਼ਤ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਮੀਆਂ ਬੀਵੀ ਨਾਟਕਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ  ਦਿਲਚਸਪੀਆਂ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਰਹੇ। ਇੱਕ ਦਿਨ ਅਚਾਨਕ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਆਪਣਾ ਬੋਰੀਆ ਬਿਸਤਰਾ ਵਲ੍ਹੇਟ ਕੇ ਕਲਕੱਤੇ ਨੂੰ ਤੁਰ ਪਏ ਤੇ ਉੱਥੇ ਰਵਿੰਦਰ ਨਾਥ ਟੈਗੋਰ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ ਨਿਕੇਤਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਕਰ ਲਈ। ਉੱਥੇ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹਾ ਵਾਤਾਵਰਣ ਸੀ, ਸੋਹਣਾ ਤੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਨ ਟੈਗੋਰ ਵਰਗੀ ਰੂਹ ਦੇ ਦਰਸ਼ਨ। ਉੱਥੇ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਹੋਰਾਂ ਬਰਨਾਰਡ ਸ਼ਾਹ ਦਾ ਨਾਟਕ 'ਆਰਮਜ਼ ਐਂਡ ਦੀ ਮੈਨ' ਖੇਡਿਆ। ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ ਨਿਕੇਤਨ ਦੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਖਾਸ ਗੱਲ ਇਹ ਰਹੀ ਕਿ ਟੈਗੋਰ ਨੇ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀ ਮਾਂ ਬੋਲੀ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਲਿਖਣ ਲਈ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਿਆ। ਸਾਲ 1940 ਵਿੱਚ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਅਤੇ ਦਮਯੰਤੀ ਇੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਲਈ ਰਵਾਨਾ ਹੋ ਗਏ, ਜਿੱਥੇ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਨੇ ਚਾਰ ਸਾਲ ਬੀ.ਬੀ.ਸੀ. ਲੰਡਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਕੀਤੀ। ਇਹ ਉਹ ਸਮਾਂ ਸੀ ਜਦ ਰੋਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਜਰਮਨ ਜੰਗੀ ਜਹਾਜ਼ ਲੰਡਨ ਉਤੇ ਬੰਬਾਰੀ ਕਰਦੇ ਸਨ। ਬੇਟਾ ਪ੍ਰੀਕਸ਼ਤ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਦਾਦਾ-ਦਾਦੀ ਕੋਲ ਰਿਹਾ। ਜਦ ਬਲਰਾਜ 1944 ਵਿੱਚ ਲੰਡਨ ਤੋਂ ਮੁੜਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਜੰਗ ਦੀ ਭਿਆਨਕਤਾ ਵੇਖ ਆਇਆ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਹੁਣ ਕਲਾ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਤਬਦੀਲੀ ਨਾਲ ਜੋੜ ਕੇ ਵੇਖਦਾ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਬੰਬੇ ਚਲਾ ਗਿਆ ਚੇਤਨ ਆਨੰਦ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਰੋਲ ਕਰਨ ਤੇ ਉੱਥੇ ਉਹ ਇੰਡੀਅਨ ਪੀਪਲਜ਼ ਥੀਏਟਰ ਐਸੋਸੀਏਸ਼ਨ (ਇਪਟਾ) ਦਾ ਸਰਗਰਮ ਆਗੂ ਕਲਾਕਾਰ ਬਣ ਗਿਆ, ਜੋ ਨਾਟਕ ਨੂੰ ਇਨਕਲਾਬੀ ਲਹਿਰ ਦੇ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਦਾ ਹਥਿਆਰ ਸਮਝਦੀ ਸੀ।ੇ ਦਮਯੰਤੀ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਉਪਰੰਤ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਬਹੁਤ ਫਿਟਕਾਰਾਂ ਪਾਈਆਂ, ਜਿਹੜਾ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਭਾਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਸਕਿਆ। ਸਾਲ 1949 ਵਿੱਚ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਆਪਣੀ ਭੂਆ ਦੀ ਕੁੜੀ ਸੰਤੋਸ਼ ਨਾਲ ਹੋਇਆ। ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਦੋ ਹਫ਼ਤੇ ਪਿੱਛੋਂ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਨੂੰ ਗ੍ਰਿਫਤਾਰ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ। ਇਨਕਲਾਬੀ ਨਾਟਕੀ ਸਰਗਰਮੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਦੋਸ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਛੇ ਮਹੀਨੇ ਜੇਲ੍ਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਗੁਜ਼ਾਰੇ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃਬਲਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ ਕਦੌਂ ਨੂੰ ਹੋਇਆ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ ਇੱਕ ਮਈ 1913 ਨੂੰ ਹੋਇਆ। "},{"question":"Carolyn Bertozzi ක්ලික් රසායන විද්‍යාව නව තලයකට ගෙන ගියේ කෙසේද?","answer":"Carolyn Bertozzi විසින් ග්ලයිකන් ලෙස හඳුන්වන සෛල මතුපිට වැදගත් නමුත් නොපෙනෙන ජෛව අණු සිතියම්ගත කිරීම සඳහා ජීවී ජීවීන් තුළ සිදු විය හැකි bioorthogonal ප්‍රතික්‍රියා වර්ධනය කිරීමෙන් ක්ලික් රසායන විද්‍යාව නව මට්ටමකට ගෙන ගියේය."},{"question":"Rekor bağış kim yaptı?","answer":"Geleneksel Türk hayırseverliğinde bir bağış rekorunu Kurucumuz Kadir Has gerçekleştirmiştir. Kurucumuz Sayın Kadir Has, 2007 yılında, Akbank'taki ortaklık payından, o günkü değeri 150 trilyon TL'ye ulaşan Akbank hisse senetlerinin bir kısmını Vakfımıza bağışlamıştır."},{"question":"إقرأ المقال التالي ، ثم أجب على السؤال الذي يليه: مَملَكة البَحرَين دولة جزيرية عربية في الخليج العربي على الجهة الشرقية من شبه الجزيرة العربية وعاصمتها المنامة. ترتبط مملكة البحرين مع المملكة العربية السعودية بجسر صناعي يسمى جسر الملك فهد، وهناك مخطط لربطها بجسر آخر مع دولة قطر. بلغ عدد سكانها إحصاء عام 2010 ما يقارب 1,234,571 نسمة، منهم 666,172 نسمة من غير المواطنين. نالت البحرين استقلالها عن بريطانيا عام 1971، وتم إعلانها كدولة مستقلة، لكن في سنة 2002 وبعد استفتاء شعبي عام على ميثاق العمل الوطني أصبح اسم البلاد مملكة البحرين.اعتباراً من عام 2012، كانت البحرين في (المرتبة 48 في العالم) في مؤشر التنمية البشرية، ومعترف بها من قبل البنك الدولي كاقتصاد الدخل المرتفع. البلاد هي عضو في الأمم المتحدة، ومنظمة التجارة العالمية، وجامعة الدول العربية وحركة عدم الانحياز ومنظمة المؤتمر الإسلامي وكذلك أحد الأعضاء المؤسسين لمجلس التعاون لدول الخليج العربية.[5] وعينت مملكة البحرين حليف رئيسي خارج حلف الناتو من قبل إدارة الرئيس الأمريكي السابق جورج دبليو بوش في عام 2001.تم اكتشاف أول بئر نفط في البحرين عام 1932، وهي أول بئر تم اكتشافها في المنطقة. منذ أواخر القرن 20، سعت البحرين إلى تنويع اقتصادها كي تصبح أقل اعتماداً على النفط من خلال الاستثمار في قطاعي المصارف والسياحة.العاصمة البحرينية المنامة هي موطن لكثير من الهياكل المالية الكبيرة، بما في ذلك مركز البحرين التجاري العالمي ومرفأ البحرين المالي. وقد أعلنت قلعة البحرين (الميناء ورأس المال من الأرض القديمة دلمون) وصيد اللؤلؤ في البحرين درب مواقع التراث العالمي لليونسكو في عام 2005 و2012 على التوالي. صيغة البحرين سباق الجائزة الكبرى أحد يأخذ مكان في حلبة البحرين الدولية.متى تم اكتشاف أول بئر نفط في البحرين؟","answer":"تم اكتشاف أول بئر نفط في البحرين عام 1932."},{"question":"Сакалдуу башы менен деген сөз эмнени түшүндүрөт?","answer":"Сакалдуу башы менен деген сөз төмөндөгүдөй маанини билдирет:Жашы улгайганына карабай, абийирине карабай, уялбай.Сакалдуу башы менен башкарма акем эмне болду? (Убукеев)."},{"question":"Sheeg Magaca Loo-Yaqaano Geedka Aanu Shimbiruhu Ku Dagan?","answer":"Waa Geedka Loo-Yaqaano Baxar Saafka."},{"question":"Qual è la domanda a: \\"Il mio sport preferito è il nuoto. Mi piace perché è un'attività che coinvolge tutto il corpo, mi aiuta a mantenersi in forma e allo stesso tempo è rilassante. Nuotare mi dà una sensazione di libertà e mi permette di staccare la mente dallo stress quotidiano.\\"","answer":"La domanda è: \\"Qual è il tuo sport preferito e perché?\\""},{"question":"السؤال: حكم ترك التسوية في صلاة الجماعة ؟","answer":"الإجابة: مكروه"},{"question":"Schreiben Sie eine Fortsetzung für den folgenden Absatz - \\"Monaco und Burke schrieben „Only Forever“ für den Film \\"Rhythm on the River\\" (1940, Regie: Victor Schertzinger). In den Hauptrollen agieren Mary Martin und Bing Crosby, der den Song vorstellt. Monaco und Burke erhielten für \\"Only Forever\\" 1941 eine Oscar-Nominierung...\\"","answer":" in der Kategorie \\"Bester Song\\". Den Oscar gewannen sie allerdings nicht."},{"question":"క్రింది ప్రశ్నకి ఒక్కమాటలో జవాబునివ్వండి.  దొడబెట్ట శిఖరం ఎత్తు ఎంత?","answer":"2637 మీ"},{"question":"\\"සියවසරක හුදෙකලාව\\" පොත ලිව්වේ කවුද?","answer":"\\"සියවසරක හුදෙකලාව\\" ග්‍රන්ථය රචනා කරන ලද්දේ Gabriel García Márquez විසිනි."},{"question":"可以提供一下加密貨幣的歷史嗎？","answer":"1983年，美國密碼學家David Chaum構想了一種名為電子貨幣的加密電子貨幣。後來，於1995年，他通過Digicash實現了這種加密電子支付的早期形式。 Digicash需要用戶軟件才能從銀行提取紙鈔並指定特定的加密密鑰，然後才能發送給接收方。這使得數字貨幣無法被第三方追蹤。1996年，美國國家安全局發表了一篇名為《如何製造一個鑄幣廠：匿名電子現金的密碼學》的論文，描述了一個加密貨幣系統。該論文首次發表在麻省理工學院的郵件列表上，並於1997年後期發表在《美國法律評論》上。1998年，Wei Dai描述了“b-money”，一個匿名的分佈式電子現金系統。不久之後，Nick Szabo描述了bit gold。像比特幣和其他隨後的加密貨幣一樣，bit gold被描述為一個需要用戶完成工作證明功能，解決方案被以密碼方式合併並發布的電子貨幣系統。2009年1月，由化名開發者Satoshi Nakamoto創建了比特幣。它在其工作證明方案中使用了SHA-256，一種密碼雜湊函數。在2011年4月，Namecoin被創建，試圖形成一個去中心化的DNS。在2011年10月，Litecoin被推出，它使用scrypt而不是SHA-256作為其雜湊函數。Peercoin於2012年8月創建，使用了工作證明和股權證明的混合。加密貨幣經歷了多個增長和縮減的時期，包括多次泡沫和市場崩潰，例如在2011年，2013-2014-15年，2017-2018年和2021-2023年。2014年8月6日，英國宣布其財政部委託對加密貨幣進行研究，以及它們在英國經濟中可能扮演的角色，如果有的話。研究還應該報告是否應該考慮監管。其最終報告於2018年發布，並於2021年1月就加密資產和穩定幣發布了諮詢。2021年6月，薩爾瓦多成為第一個將比特幣視為法定貨幣的國家，經過立法議會以62-22的投票通過了總統納伊布·布克萊提交的法案。2021年8月，古巴也發布了第215號決議，承認並規管比特幣等加密貨幣。2021年9月，中國政府，全球最大的加密貨幣市場，宣布所有加密貨幣交易都是非法。這完成了對先前禁止在中國運營中介機構和礦工的打壓。2022年9月15日，當時全球第二大加密貨幣以太坊完成了共識機制從工作證明（PoW）到股權證明（PoS）的升級過程，這一過程被稱為“合併”。根據以太坊的創始人，該升級可以將以太坊的能源消耗和二氧化碳排放減少99.9%。2022年11月11日，加密貨幣交易所FTX Trading Ltd.，同時運營加密對沖基金，並被估值為180億美元，申請破產。這次崩潰的財務影響超出了FTX客戶群，如報導所述，而在路透社的一次會議上，金融業高管表示“監管機構必須介入保護加密貨幣投資者”。技術分析師Avivah Litan評論了加密貨幣生態系統，稱“在用戶體驗、控制、安全性和客戶服務方面，一切都需要有顯著改善”。"},{"question":"Algumas toneladas de medicamentos para uso humano e veterinário são produzidas por ano. Os fármacos são desenvolvidos para serem estáveis, mantendo suas propriedades químicas de forma a atender a um propósito terapêutico. Após o consumo de fármacos, parte de sua dosagem é excretada de forma inalterada, persistindo no meio ambiente. Em todo o mundo, antibióticos, hormônios, anestésicos, anti-inflamatórios, entre outros, são detectados em concentrações preocupantes no esgoto doméstico, em águas superficiais e de subsolo. Dessa forma, a ocorrência de fármacos residuais no meio ambiente pode apresentar efeitos adversos em organismos aquáticos e terrestres.Qual ação minimiza a permanência desses contaminantes nos recursos hídricos?a) Utilização de esterco como fertilizante na agricultura.b) Ampliação das redes de coleta de esgoto na zona urbana.c) Descarte dos medicamentos fora do prazo de validade em lixões.d) Desenvolvimento de novos processos nas estações de tratamento de efluentes.e) Reúso dos lodos provenientes das estações de tratamento de esgoto na agricultura.","answer":"A resposta correcta é a alternativa: d) Desenvolvimento de novos processos nas estações de tratamento de efluentes."},{"question":"Welke van deze zijn automerken: Ferrari, Fiat, Batavus, Philips, Renault, BMW, IKEA en MG","answer":"Fiat, Ferrari, Renault, BMW en MG zijn automerken. Batavus heeft meestal fietsen, Philips maakt verschillende soorten elektronica, en IKEA is een meubelzaak."}]`),x={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:B},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:S,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},I={class:"search-container"},C={class:"card-container"},H=["disabled"],O={key:0},K={key:1};function L(e,a,s,k,t,u){const m=y("PoemCard");return i(),o("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",I,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),b(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=r=>t.searchQuery=r),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[c,t.searchQuery]])]),n("div",C,[(i(!0),o(w,null,p(u.filteredPoems,(r,d)=>(i(),j(m,{key:d,poem:r},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),u.hasMorePoems?(i(),o("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:t.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...r)=>u.loadMore&&u.loadMore(...r))},[t.isLoading?(i(),o("span",K,"Loading...")):(i(),o("span",O,"See more"))],8,H)):f("",!0)])}const P=g(x,[["render",L],["__scopeId","data-v-3d02b08b"]]),R=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"chatai/23.md","filePath":"chatai/23.md"}'),E={name:"chatai/23.md"},G=Object.assign(E,{setup(e){return(a,s)=>(i(),o("div",null,[v(P)]))}});export{R as __pageData,G as default};
